<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>ThreeFold - aci</title>
	<subtitle>Our global digital backbone</subtitle>
	<link href="https://www3.threefold.io/categories/aci/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://www3.threefold.io"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2021-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://www3.threefold.io/categories/aci/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>How ThreeFold Can Truly Decentralize Blockchain</title>
		<published>2021-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/10/post-5/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/10/post-5/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The topic of decentralization is commonly tied to blockchain and cryptocurrencies. Blockchain doesn’t store any of its information in a central location, rather it is copied and spread across a network of computers. And the most popular name in the blockchain space, Bitcoin, was intended as an alternative payment system free of central control.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But many blockchains are facing the same challenge: How can they escape the monopolies of centralized cloud providers for their own workloads, as well as for the dApps built on top of them? The key question is, is a blockchain truly decentralized if it is being hosted on a centralized solution? We say: no.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An example to illustrate this challenge is the fact that up to 60% of Ethereum (the world’s second most-popular blockchain) nodes run on centralized cloud providers and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;aws.amazon.com&#x2F;blockchain&#x2F;&quot;&gt;25% of them run on Amazon Web Services (AWS)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the topic is being addressed, it isn’t being solved at scale. The good news is that ThreeFold can play a large part in solving it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-should-blockchains-make-this-move&quot;&gt;Why should blockchains make this move?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The blockchain movement, as mentioned, is very heavily tied to the movement around decentralization. Cryptocurrencies represent the move away from centralized banks as the authorities and gatekeepers around money – just as ThreeFold and similar projects represent the move away from centralized clouds as the authorities and gatekeepers around data. The thing is, if blockchains are to rely on centralized cloud for hosting, they aren’t truly embodying decentralization.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understandably, many blockchains have chosen centralized cloud providers in the past because there wasn’t much of an alternative. But now, the Decentralized Cloud (DeCloud) movement has changed all of that.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how some specific audiences can benefit:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;for-node-operators&quot;&gt;For Node Operators&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any full node or validator node can run on ThreeFold’s &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cloud.threefold.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Peer-to-Peer (P2P) Cloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, making that particular Blockchain even more community-owned, and more decentralized from an IT&#x2F;cloud level. Any node operator can choose to run their nodes from any farmer location on the ThreeFold Grid, totally &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;what_is_peer_to_peer&#x2F;&quot;&gt;peer-to-peer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; between the chosen farmer and the node operator. The deployed workloads are computed in a P2P manner, no middle party involved.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;for-dapp-developers&quot;&gt;For dApp Developers&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Web3&#x2F;Blockchain developers can use ThreeFold’s P2P Cloud - offering both compute and storage - to build and power their applications in a truly decentralized cloud infrastructure, both blockchain-native and cloud-native. A strong advantage here is that developers have the ability to leverage Kubernetes, Docker, S3, and other cloud-native tools (all compatible &#x2F; integrated with the ThreeFold) to power and optimize their data processing capabilities, as well as the overall functionality of their dApps. But the sweet spot is that it is deployed on a decentralized IT infrastructure, close to where users would be located.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;but-why-choose-threefold-over-other-decloud-projects&quot;&gt;But why choose ThreeFold over other DeCloud projects?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There may be bigger names in the space, but ThreeFold’s technology and offerings are much more comprehensive than the rest. ThreeFold provides decentralized storage, compute, and network all under one roof (whereas most other projects offer only one of the three) and as mentioned, we have created an environment for developers which is highly-compatible to the developer tools and solutions they use today. Further, ThreeFold is building new infrastructure &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;an_intro_to_the_threefold_grid&#x2F;&quot;&gt;from the ground up&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (rather than relying on extra space in data centers) and the technology is truly peer-to-peer.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We already have &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;partners&#x2F;blockchain&quot;&gt;a number of partners in the space&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; who recognize these advantages.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any blockchain protocol or dApp, whether operating DeFi, NFTs, DEXs, etc, will at some point need to leverage the power of the decentralized cloud and escape from centralized cloud providers. We’re seeing some of that adoption from a decentralized storage side with IPFS, which has been adopted by many dApps, and others – but as a developer, you will have to think twice, not just about where your&#x2F;your users’ data is being stored, but also about how (and where) your app is computed and powered.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Participate now in our quest to fully decentralize the Internet by &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;farm&quot;&gt;becoming a node&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on our grid or &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tft&quot;&gt;buying TFT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>A Journey Into ThreeFold</title>
		<published>2021-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/09/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/09/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you’re part of the ThreeFold Movement, we’re sure you’ve seen Scott in a demo, or in the chats or forums. Scott is new-ish to the team but he’s been active in the community for quite a while. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In this video, Sam, based in Turkey, and Scott, based in the Pacific Northwest (USA), have a conversation about Scott’s journey into ThreeFold. They speak about how he found out about the project and started contributing (and how you can do the same), the technology, the mission, vision, and values, the people, and what Scott is most looking forward to in the short, medium, and long-term.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;embed&#x2F;eXpXtHRSji0&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;&#x2F;iframe&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Eager to contribute? Find us on our forums, chats, or on GitHub!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Main Chat&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldfarmers&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Farmers Chat&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldtesting&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Testing Chat&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;threefoldfoundation&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Foundation GitHub&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;threefoldtech&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Tech GitHub&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Art &amp; Culture in VR: Coming to the ThreeFold Grid</title>
		<published>2021-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/08/post-2/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/08/post-2/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last year at a ThreeFold gathering, a few of us on the team had the pleasure to meet a man named Vasily, a creative mind with a big heart and proud founder of Artheon. Artheon, in its essence, was a virtual reality museum experience focused on bringing fine art and culture from around the world directly to people. The concept was immediately captivating, and the demo brought it to life for us. The graphics were already solid, and being able to walk around a museum and interact with the artwork was a unique experience to say the least. We talked about the implications and his greater vision around access and education, and it was very clear we needed to partner up. Not long after, Artheon and ThreeFold joined forces.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-what-is-the-partnership-all-about&quot;&gt;So what is the partnership all about?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together with ThreeFold, Artheon aims to create the world’s largest open art database – made for everyone, and owned by everyone. We will provide access to art and cultural heritage to people around the world, without borders. Not just access, but a high-quality and high-resolution virtual reality experience where people can really immerse themselves in their surrounding environment. With Artheon, people can now even touch and hold paintings or artifacts, something that would clearly not be possible in real life. And while today, only a select few (relative to the total global population) have the opportunity to travel and to experience museums and cultural &amp;amp; sacred sites, Artheon will change that!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
It’s not only about experience, though, it’s also about community and education and providing a more equal access to art and cultural objects. We’ll bring together a global community of museums, artists, and art seekers who can not only enjoy, but also teach and learn about the art and cultural objects housed within the Artheon universe. For Artheon, it’s imperative
that people are able to access information about the artists and the art itself, and then make and share their own perceptions as well. No need or pressure to follow the direction of the current system’s ideology. This is a different angle from how we traditionally learn at school, where narrow or accepted views and concepts are imposed upon us. A key aim of Artheon is to bring different perspectives through collective, participatory, and experiental teaching and learning.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Looking ahead, the vision is that people will be able to create their own virtual spaces and expose them on Artheon. They can create something from scratch or even re-imagine a historical site as it was long ago and share it with the community.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-does-threefold-benefit-artheon&quot;&gt;How does ThreeFold benefit Artheon?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the start, there was a clear connection between Artheon and ThreeFold from a vision, values, and ethos perspective. But there are also some more specific reasons why Artheon chose and benefits from ThreeFold, which mainly revolve around the decentralized nature of the ThreeFold Grid.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Virtual and augmented reality (VR and AR) provide significant benefits to our new digital reality. These technologies open new ways of sharing information in areas such as the arts in the case of Artheon, allowing for upgraded and immersive experiences for users.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Decentralized clouds have been associated with the promise of new digital applications and services that come with a hyper-connected life. Because the graphics of VR&#x2F;AR experiences require heavy rendering, on-device processes are augmented by splitting workloads between the VR&#x2F;AR device and a decentralized cloud. So, graphics rendering on a decentralized cloud like what the ThreeFold Grid provides would be significantly improved by achieving a much lower latency. Another advantage of the ThreeFold Grid is that it provides an extremely high level of security and privacy, empowering Artheon and its users with real data sovereignty.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
And finally, Artheon experienced an unfortunate event earlier this summer where their servers suffered from an intense heat wave and essentially burned up. There was no backup, and this would have been catastrophic in the scenario of them having millions of users. Good thing they aren’t live yet, but this is a great example of how centralized models fail. With a decentralized infrastructure like ThreeFold, this type of situation would not have occured, as data would be hosted on many locations.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
So, by distributing the computing power closer to their users, a VR experience such as Artheon would not only improve their latency speed, security, and privacy, but also the resilience of their business model. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-the-status-of-artheon-and-its-partnership-with-threefold&quot;&gt;What is the status of Artheon (and its partnership with ThreeFold)?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past year, Artheon has been making incredible improvements to the graphics and experience, and adding as many new pieces of art as possible into the universe. As you can imagine, the possibilities really are endless, but here are some of the milestones planned for the rest of this year:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Planning to add partial DLC (downloadable content) support and photogrammetry-scanned locations for users to experience&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New UI for desktop (Windows, MacOS, Linux)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implementation of desired social features such as follower and friend system&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People will be able to see who of their friends or people they follow are online – from that, they can connect to a server and join them to share experiences together&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People will also be able to see how many people are online at the moment and where they are located on the globe (if permissions are allowed)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow the possibility for museums to host free or closed paid exhibitions&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Artheon will be hosted on the ThreeFold Grid!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-can-you-do-now-to-get-involved&quot;&gt;What can you do now to get involved?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re reading this section, we’re thrilled you are interested in what is happening with Artheon! We are, too! As Artheon is not yet live, the best option for you is to join &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;artheon&quot;&gt;the Artheon Early Access chat on Telegram&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; where you can stay tuned there for updates and ask questions directly to Artheon’s creators and contributors.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>This ThreeFold Farm Keeps Veggies Warm</title>
		<published>2021-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/07/post-5/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/07/post-5/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Somewhere in the Netherlands, a ThreeFold Farm is supporting the growth of vegetable crops such as tomatoes, peppers and cucumbers. By directing the excess heat generated from the hardware operations to the greenhouse next door, they are able to achieve an incredible model that benefits both hardware and vegetables. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Jeroen Burks, CEO of Blockheating, tells us everything we need to know about their sustainable farming operations. As far as he can remember, Jeroen has always been a protagonist of the “no waste” approach. He started by recycling material previously used by the tech industry, mainly in the cloud market. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
“By default, most data center operations replace their power supplies every 3 years, no matter the state they are in. They are being replaced to counter any possible downtime.” 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
By refurbishing and repurposing “old” power units from data centers, he gives them a second life as electric tractor chargers, lithium ION pack chargers, and more. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
“You just need to trick the unit into thinking it is still powering servers, add some cables here and there, and it is ready for duty.” 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
His quest towards sustainability started when he was challenged on a pilot project. His friend had bought a new building and was looking for the most sustainable approach to heating it. Jeroen came up with the idea of putting two server racks in the basement and using the heat from that operation, to heat the offices and spaces above. While this project was a success, Jeroen realised that it could be way more efficient, if done with other structures. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
He quickly engaged with a second pilot project where he used two server racks to heat a small greenhouse. This model turned out to be a great combination, which benefited both hardware, as well as farming operations. And so sprouted ‘Blockheating’ – a data center that provides heat for tomatoes, peppers and cucumbers. Why specifically these vegetables? Well, the Netherlands has a fair amount of greenhouses cultivating them, and these ‘veggies’ need that heat during summer nights. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Right now Blockheating has around 400 compute nodes with direct cooling that stores all the heat in a buffer throughout the day, which is then released into the greenhouses during the night hours.
“By doing it the way we do, we grow the internet grid, help grow vegetables and curb fossil fuel usage – in carbon negative compute power!” 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Right now, Blockheating has a portion of their data center dedicated to ThreeFold Farming for a few reasons:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The alignment of values is huge&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ThreeFold Farming is easy to manage&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ThreeFold Farming counters wasteful behavior of internet resources, so it’s a triple win&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Blockheating envisions to scale up-to three data centers of this kind, in an interconnected way, with a fiber ring between them. By doing so, they will be able to increase their offering and have a larger impact on countering the wasteful patterns of the cloud industry. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold is proud to have Blockheating as a ‘State-of-the-Art’ Farmer and Partner, and hopes to see many more people and companies inspired by Blockheating around the world, to expand the ‘People’s Internet’ in a regenerative way. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find out more about Blockheating here: &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;blockheating.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;blockheating.com&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find out more about our partners here: &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;partners&quot;&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;partners&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Into the Fold – The ThreeFold Movement</title>
		<published>2021-07-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-07-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/07/post-4/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/07/post-4/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s not by mistake that you’re here, reading this post. You, like I, understand that today’s systems need to change. You know that decentralization is needed for better wealth distribution and equal opportunities. And that we need better solutions for our planet. You can feel that a global shift is happening. And you want to do something about it. You want to be a part of it.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
You’ve dreamt of a different world. A world where people trust and treat each other with respect – and where everyone has equal chances to learn and to thrive. A world where we’re not just cogs in a machine that serves only the few, rather we work and co-create as part of systems that benefit all. A world where solutions are sustainable for our planet, or even better, regenerative. This world is not just a dream, though – and you’re not alone. Each day, more and more like-minded people are coming together. Welcome into the fold.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;meet-the-movement&quot;&gt;Meet the Movement&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To understand ThreeFold, you should first understand where we came from. Since the late 90’s, some of the ThreeFold co-founders have worked on Internet storage and cloud technology. And after years of building, and many successful launches, they came to understand that they were part of a broken system that was productizing people and damaging the planet. Despite this, they knew that the Internet held and holds the key to a better world, and that the only way to have a truly sovereign, secure, and energy-efficient Internet was to start from scratch. So we did.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
This is how our story began – and over the past four years we have grown and expanded a team of like-minded and passionate people from around the world to bring ThreeFold to life. But for us, we are still in the beginning of something much bigger to come.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We don’t consider ourselves a company, rather a group of humans helping other humans – and our planet. We believe the world needs to change, and we choose to not just talk, but act, to make that change happen. We cannot and would not want to do this alone. There is a strong, passionate, and growing community around us – partners, farmers, ambassadors, technology testers, other contributors, and supporters just like you.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;our-mission-vision-and-values-drive-us-forward&quot;&gt;Our Mission, Vision, and Values Drive us Forward&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our mission is to build and expand a data-sovereign and planet-positive Internet owned by the people, for the people. This will enable equal chances for people around the world to learn, partake and succeed, and will help to heal our planet.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Engrained into the work that we do are three key values or principles:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We believe in &lt;strong&gt;sovereignty&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, and in protecting people. Everyone should own their data, and no one else, not even ThreeFold. Our peer-to-peer technology allows every user to be data sovereign – giving them 100% control over their data.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We believe that everyone should be given &lt;strong&gt;equal chances&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; to learn, partake and succeed. Internet access is a human right, and at ThreeFold we commit to scale our technology to new regions to empower the unconnected.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
And we unify our practices, partnerships, and products around a single mission – to &lt;strong&gt;heal our planet&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. By making our technology actionable, we enable a collective approach to have an impact together.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;together-we-invite-the-world-into-the-fold&quot;&gt;Together, We Invite the World Into the Fold&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s important for others to understand who we are. Thus, we identify with and embody three key attributes as a collective, to show the world what the movement is all about:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold is purposeful.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; We exist to help humanity thrive. Our mission is bold and motivates every step we take. We adapt to our evolving environment and passionately strive for excellence.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold is empowering.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; We help people find themselves and do what they love. We provide support to people and projects that help build a better world, whether they have moonshot visions or down-to-earth ambitions. We aren’t the hero of our story – they are.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold is approachable.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; ThreeFold keeps it real. We’re open and honest, avoiding upstage corporate language and phony marketing spins. We don’t see ourselves as a company, but more like humans helping other humans. So being genuine, friendly, and loving comes naturally.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In its essence, the movement is open and inviting. We’ve created &lt;strong&gt;a participatory Internet economy&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, where anybody around the world can plug in a 3Node and add capacity to the ThreeFold Grid. Together, we’re expanding a data sovereign and planet positive Internet infrastructure, owned by the people, across geographical and cultural borders.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We believe in &lt;strong&gt;collaboration, not competition&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. Our technology serves as a responsible underlying layer on top of which anybody can build and create. We have &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;partners&quot;&gt;beautiful partners&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; already on board – and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;aci&quot;&gt;an alliance&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of conscious people and organizations who share our vision – and we are constantly expanding our ecosystem across industries.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
And while the ThreeFold Foundation is currently the driving force behind the ThreeFold Movement, we believe in &lt;strong&gt;decentralization&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. We have open channels like &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&quot;&gt;a forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;a two-way Telegram chat&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, Github (&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;threefoldfoundation&quot;&gt;Foundation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;threefoldtech&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Tech&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;), and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;threefold_io&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, where people can and do contribute, ask questions and provide feedback that goes into our everyday decision-making and actions.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
As I said at the start, you’ve dreamt of a different world. And so have I. John Lennon once said, “A dream you dream alone is only a dream. A dream you dream together is reality.” Thank you for dreaming with us. Together, this will happen!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Photo by Ahmad Odeh on Unsplash.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>The ThreeFold Grid is by the People, For the People</title>
		<published>2021-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/07/post-2/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/07/post-2/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What do you think of when you hear the word Internet? For many, it’s the websites and applications we consume online as end users. But the Internet is much more than this. And ultimately, every action we take online goes through a complex set of automated processes and protocols to store, run, and transmit data (e.g. photos, videos, messages, other files) across the global Internet infrastructure.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Today, this infrastructure consists of massive, power-hungry data centers, and is largely privatized and owned by tech giants such as Facebook, Google and Amazon – who also happen to own the biggest online “free” platforms. But there’s a catch. By owning both the infrastructure and the digital experiences we consume for free, we were actually turned into products of their business models. Our data is being collected and isn’t owned by us anymore. While data has become the most valuable commodity on earth, don’t you think it’s wrong that we don’t own the value of our data today? 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Today, every individual is worth between US $1,000 and $20,000 online, per year. The Internet and Cloud Industry is worth trillions, yet all this value is centralized to a handful of companies. This has to change.”&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold’s open source technology powers the peer-to-peer Internet revolution that holds the premise to disrupt the global Internet in many ways.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;an-internet-by-the-people&quot;&gt;An Internet By the People&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ThreeFold Grid is formed by people from all around the world that connect Internet capacity to a peer-to-peer Infrastructure owned by humanity. Together, we expand a data-sovereign and planet-positive Internet infrastructure that puts people back in control of their data, and their digital lives. ThreeFold’s infrastructure can store all of humanity’s data – from personal data to public datasets and security archives – and can run all emerging technologies such as blockchain, IoT, and Big Data – with more efficiency and security.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold flips the current data center model upside-down, and allows people around the globe to connect Internet capacity in the form of hardware, and earn income for it. This decentralized approach means that anyone can take part in the world’s largest and fastest growing economy – the Internet and Cloud. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
You can see now how this new Internet is by the people, but how about the latter? What does the ThreeFold Grid enable?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;an-internet-for-the-people&quot;&gt;An Internet For the People&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now anyone, anywhere can connect to the ThreeFold Grid and use capacity with some key advantages:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-world-where-we-own-the-value-of-our-data&quot;&gt;A World Where we Own the Value of Our Data&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, all of the data we create online sits inside of centralized data centers and we do not own it. ThreeFold turns terms &amp;amp; conditions on their head and gives us, the people, full control of our data rather than third parties. We can keep our data private, decide with whom to share it, and even decide on where it’s stored and located. And considering that our personal data is worth between US $1,000 and $20,000 per year, ThreeFold offers a direct way for us to own our digital life and the value attached to it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;we-exchange-value-without-intermediaries&quot;&gt;We Exchange Value Without Intermediaries&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The “People’s Internet” is peer-to-peer. This means connections between senders and recipients are completely end-to-end, eliminating the need for any form of intermediaries from the model. Can you imagine what the world would look like without intermediaries? Let’s take an example like Airbnb.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Today, if you are looking for a place to stay on vacation, you will probably end up using the services of Airbnb. But did you know that Airbnb charges both consumers and property owners for using their service? In a peer-to-peer world, this wouldn’t be necessary. You’d simply access a database of property owners (possibly through a peer-to-peer marketplace) and be able to complete the transaction yourselves. No hidden fees, just a direct exchange of value!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;applications-run-on-the-edge&quot;&gt;Applications Run on the Edge&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In its essence, edge computing brings compute and storage closer to people (and the devices where it’s being gathered) rather than relying on a centralized data centers located on the other side of the planet. This is the essence of the ThreeFold Grid. So, data doesn’t suffer any latency issues (performance) and it’s far more efficient &#x2F; money-saving. Further, the distributed nature of the Grid allows for true privacy and security. Edge computing is not just a growing trend but, because of the growing number of connected devices and global Internet usage, it’s becoming a real necessity.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;but-what-about-the-planet&quot;&gt;But what about the planet?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been following us, you must already know that the Internet is responsible for 10% or more of the world’s energy consumption. And with decades of experience in the Internet and Cloud industry, ThreeFold co-founders knew how to turn this around. We developed a lightweight operating system and infrastructure, removing unnecessary layers of complexity from the traditional and Web3 models (actually, blockchains are making it even more complex). The ThreeFold technology is always geared towards maximum efficiency while maintaing performance. And with these advancements, we can already save up-to 90% energy on storage workloads.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Additionally, the distributed nature of the Grid uses less bandwidth (see above re: edge computing). It’s been reported that Netflix alone takes up 15% of the Internet’s bandwidth. What if Netflix were to leverage the ThreeFold Grid? If stored closer to watchers, we could reduce network usage considerably.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Our commitment to the planet goes beyond the technology. Through a partnership with Take Action Global (TAG), we aim to take three times more CO2 out of the air compared to what we put in. Imagine regenerating the earth while using the Internet?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
At ThreeFold, we believe that it’s time for us to take back control. As the world turns more and more digital due to the pandemic and even just the natural progression of technology, it’s time that we not just realize the problems of today’s Internet, but that we do something about it.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
This will happen! So join in, and spread the word! &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Response - The Internet is Destroying Our Brains, but We Can&#x27;t Quit</title>
		<published>2021-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/07/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/07/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The other day, I came across &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;africa.businessinsider.com&#x2F;strategy&#x2F;the-internet-is-destroying-our-brains-but-we-cant-quit-its-a-factory-were-forced-to&#x2F;z4drxf5&quot;&gt;a poignant article&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; written by &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;_pem_pem&quot;&gt;P.E. Moskowitz&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; entitled “The internet is destroying our brains, but we can’t quit. It’s a factory we’re forced to work in without any pay.” As someone who started out in social media advertising (read: trying to capture peoples’ attention to get them to buy or do something often by using their data against them), worked in influencer marketing in its early days, and has now gone 180º to help to build a decentralized Internet by people and for people (where people are digitally sovereign), it really resonated with me.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
It’s commonly-discussed (see: The Social Dilemma) and quite obvious if you use or have used the Internet and specifically social media, that we are addicted to being online. In fact, we’re actually even chemically triggered by social media and other online experiences. Said Jeff Orlowski, director of The Social Dilemma, “Social media powerhouses like Facebook, Twitter and Instagram are “designed” to exploit users’ brain chemistry in order to keep them glued to their phones… They were designed to get us to come back. It’s to figure out how to reverse-engineer what we’re most vulnerable to, most susceptible to, to come back. And what we are seeing is a dopamine response in the brain.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In their article, Moskowitz points out how the Internet is not just like a toxic relationship or junk food, where you can leave or stop yourself from eating, rather it’s “an all-encompassing technology, our main economic engine, the tool we are forced to use to meet others and mediate our entire lives.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The truth is that the Internet &lt;em&gt;has&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; become more than an addiction, it’s become a necessity to keep up in today’s increasingly-digital world. Yet the Internet is not even accessible to about 40% of the global population – and for those who &lt;em&gt;do&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; have access, it does not serve us. It’s actually the other way around. We are the product.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
“We produce the memes, tweets, posts, and pictures that keep us tethered to the internet, and then that content is monetized in the form of advertisements - revenue users help produce, but do not usually see a penny of,” says Moskowitz. We have become cogs in a machine that uses us for its own benefit. Or as they call it, “a factory we’re forced to work in without any pay.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
“Our entire society has been reformulated around the internet, much like it was centered around the factory during the Industrial Revolution. If there’s an Amazon Web Services outage, much of our society stops functioning. Without the internet, we couldn’t find jobs, or, at this point, even friends.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-what-do-we-do&quot;&gt;So, what do we do?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moskowitz is correct in their thinking when they say the following, “A solution to our current internet-use crisis cannot come at an individual level anymore than one person quitting their job would solve capitalism’s poor working conditions. If we want any hope of making the internet less stressful, less back-breaking, and more fulfilling, content creators, gig economy workers, and even casual internet users need to push for a systemic solution.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Simply pending less time on the Internet or using certain apps instead of others is not going to make much of a difference in the end. There are billions of people on the Internet today to make up for the loss. And the underlying system is still massively flawed and can be manipulated. Bold, widespread, systemic change is indeed what we need. A revolution, perhaps.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As pointed out recently &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;tgdaily.com&#x2F;web&#x2F;6-dfinity-threefold-are-leading-an-internet-decentralization-revolution&#x2F;&quot;&gt;in TGDaily&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, ThreeFold is that revolution.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold is the engine for a &lt;em&gt;new&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; Internet, driven by a movement of people who care about a better future. With more than two decades of direct knowledge of the Internet and Cloud industries, we flipped today’s Internet on its head. We rebuilt the architecture from the ground up, with people and our planet at the center of our focus. Instead of relying on centralized hyper-scale data centers owned by a few private corporations, we provide the opportunity for people across the world with access to a network connection and electricity to plug in hardware and provide local capacity, and earn income while they are at it.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In our model, we prioritize simplicity, security, efficiency, and privacy. The technology runs autonomously, removing human error and malicious intent from the equation. Connections are peer-to-peer, meaning no middlemen get in the way of our content, our transactions, or other data. And importantly, people own their data. What we produce is ours. We decide where it gets stored and we decide who can access it (and for what value). In fact, it’s basically impossible from a technical standpoint for anybody to access someone’s data without their consent – including us.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
On top of the technology, we provide experiences. People will have one single log-in and verifiable identity, and gain access to the tools (experiences) they need for communication and for work. As we are a decentralized movement, soon, anybody will be able to build anything they like on top of ThreeFold – but it is our vision and belief that the Internet should not be addictive. Rather a tool for all of humanity to connect, learn, and prosper – with people at the center, not treated as products.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
To the author’s concern, content creators and gig economy workers would clearly benefit from such a digital world as well. Of course services like Airbnb or Uber or Etsy or even YouTube provide value as they are crowded marketplaces both for providers and customers. That said, they profit from people, typically on both sides of the transaction. In a peer-to-peer world, we can create fair and equal marketplaces where the content or product is owned completely by the person listing it there and the value goes 100% directly from person to person. This means no hidden fees, no uncertainty over ownership, no censorship or control from a third party. Of course it’s not all predetermined at this moment, but what I can say is that our biggest concerns in what we create are and will always be fairness and equality (and sustainability &#x2F; regeneration). So, together, we will bring all of this tolife in the best interest of people.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;join-the-movement&quot;&gt;Join the Movement&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In their article, Moskowitz concluded that “perhaps it is only a matter of time before enough of us say ‘enough,’ and protest the internet’s totalizing grasp on our labor and our lives.” But where does protest lead without a viable solution? Maybe this is the type of systemic change Moskowitz could imagine and could stand behind. It’s not a band-aid approach, rather a total re-imagination and re-execution of today’s flawed and manipulative Internet. It’s an Internet by people, for people. Instead of working in the factory, we become the factory co-owners – and the Internet works for us.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
If you believe in what we are building, we invite you to join the movement:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;farming&quot;&gt;Become a farmer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldnews&quot;&gt;Stay updated on ThreeFold News&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;Join the conversation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldtesting&quot;&gt;Test the technology&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;threefold_io&quot;&gt;Follow us on Twitter&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;threefold__how_to_buy_and_sell&quot;&gt;Buy the ThreeFold Token&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are a growing group of people from around the world who not only believe what many of you believe, but we are doing something about it. Let’s grow the People’s Internet, together.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>How ThreeFold Will Give Internet to 43% of the World’s Population</title>
		<published>2021-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/06/post-3/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/06/post-3/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The United Nations publicly ruled Internet access to be a human right in 2016. Proper access to the Internet helps to protect people’s freedom of speech and thought, as well as other fundamentals such as access to knowledge and information.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Nonetheless, as of 2019, about 43% of humanity remains unconnected to the Internet, creating huge inequalities in access to information and knowledge. It is essential to take the necessary steps to strengthen the relationship between governments and people while still upholding all human rights.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold created an infrastructure that is easily affordable and jointly operated by network peers to make the modern Internet open and fair to everyone. Anybody with a network connection and electricity can add capacity to the ThreeFold Grid. We’re looking for farmers around the globe and we’re also partnering with farming cooperatives to develop localized strategies and meet the specific needs of their region. Plus, the Foundation will incentivize and sponsor the extension and scope to areas that require Internet capacity the most, to ensure a fair and equitable delivery of the Internet to all.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Want to join the biggest internet revolution? &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;farming.threefold.io&quot;&gt;Be part&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of it, today.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>It&#x27;s Time We Stand Up For Our Data</title>
		<published>2021-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/06/post-2/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/06/post-2/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Do a quick search for “data leak” on your search engine of choice, and you’ll likely see headlines like this:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personal Details of Over 3.3M Volkswagen Customers Exposed in Data Leak&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Billions of emails and passwords appear in largest data leak ever&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Here’s How the IRS Could Have Prevented the Tax Data Leak&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time to Change Your Password: Tips on Protecting Yourself from Online Scams
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Week after week, month after month, year after year, companies are being hacked, private consumer data is being compromised and released, and we somehow begin to think that this is the reality of our world, something we just have to deal with.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Internet security, cyber attacks, and data leaks are a global threat – and increasingly so as the world moves more digital, and smart people with malicious intent try to take advantage. But this is not normal, nor should it be. As consumers, we should be able to trust that our data is truly safe and secure. And today, we cannot. It’s time we stand up for what is ours.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
That’s where ThreeFold comes in.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Many of today’s issues around cyber security and data privacy come from the lack of innovation in the IT industry over the last decades and the reliance on centralized hyper-scale data centers. ThreeFold has disrupted this model in a few ways:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
First, we started from the ground up. Some ThreeFold co-founders have been working in the cloud &amp;amp; storage space for over two decades, having built components of the cloud and Internet still used today. They knew that the only way to have a truly secure and data sovereign Internet was to rebuild the architecture and the technology components from scratch. So they did. A few years down the line, we’ve created a new operating system, a smart contract for IT, and a peer-to-peer network that can be scaled to anywhere by anyone.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Second, we removed people from the equation. IT has become so overly-complex that people are required in order to maintain it. Because of this, “backdoors” are needed to allow these gateholders to enter the systems and make necessary fixes. But this can lead to human error, and also allows people with malicious intent to make their way in as well. With Autonomous IT powering the ThreeFold Grid, the technology runs and heals itself, and drastically reduces the opportunity for humans to interfere.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
And lastly, your data is owned by you. Rather than relying on centralized data centers, the ThreeFold Grid is an Internet grid made up by independent ThreeFold “Farmers” from around the world who plug in capacity from their home or office. While they own the hardware, they do not own the data inside. User data is stored across multiple devices, and proprietary data storage algorithms ensure that the data cannot be retrieved by anyone besides the user – not the farmer, and not even us.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
As Einstein said, “We can’t solve our problems with the same level of thinking that created them.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a lot more information in &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;&quot;&gt;our wikis&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; about the technology, but what we want to emphasize here with you is that we don’t have to accept data leaks and hacking. There is an answer to the cybersecurity issues the world is facing. And that answer is ThreeFold.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>How You Can Join the People&#x27;s Internet</title>
		<published>2021-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/06/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/06/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yes, that’s right. With ThreeFold, you &lt;em&gt;can&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; become the Internet! Let me quickly explain. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Today’s Internet is powered by hyper-scale data centers which are owned by large corporations. With +80% of the global infrastructure and +60% of the global Internet networks owned by a bunch of companies, the Internet became a real business with us humans being the products of that business model.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold creates an entirely new Internet economy that is owned by all of us and makes the traditional cloud model of building data centers obsolete. With ThreeFold, independent people called “Farmers” plug in 3Nodes (hardware) from their homes or offices anywhere around the world. And they earn income for it. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Together, they power a new, data-sovereign, and planet-positive Internet owned and powered by the people. This is a game-changer.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-how-do-i-get-a-3node&quot;&gt;So, how do I get a 3Node?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can buy one of the ready-made nodes from cooperatives around the world. This is a good and very easy way to support the ThreeFold project and to “BE THE INTERNET.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Today you can buy a 3Node via our website. We are also working with our farming cooperatives to decentralize the provisioning and distribution of hardware to a glocal approach (a global network of local networks). 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
But what if 3Nodes are not immediately available? For example, last week we had a huge influx of orders for our Titan V2 3Nodes and sold out the entire batch with 3,000 extra orders. We’re now talking with many hardware distributors to make sure we can satsify all these orders, but this could take a while.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
So if you are a little bit more adventurous, and want to build your 3Node from the ground up, yourself, here’s how to do it:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
To “become the Internet” is fairly simple (but does take some technical knowledge and effort). Here’s what you’ll need:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A computer with an INTEL or AMD brain, some memory, and some storage cabilities.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A smartphone on which you can download and run the “ThreeFold Connect” app. This will provide you with a wallet (to receive your farmed TFT and to pay a very small amount of TFT to get started).&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A laptop &#x2F; desktop (and USB stick) to launch your online 3Bot, configure your farm, download your bootloader and burn the bootloader to a USB stick.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some technical knowledge, interest and 45 minutes of time.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are still here and reading, we’re good to go! I go through the whole process in a 3-minute video which will give you a quick overview of how to set up your farm. (Click through to the video on YouTube and find helpful links in the description.)
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;embed&#x2F;uxIZcsEsOUE&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;&#x2F;iframe&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prefer a different format? We also have forum topics live about &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;requirements-to-set-up-your-own-3node&#x2F;831&quot;&gt;the pre-requirements&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;how-to-set-up-your-own-3node&#x2F;833&quot;&gt;how to set up your 3Node&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (the steps I share in the video).
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you, thank you, thank you for reading this post and we hope to have you as part of our growing, global farming community. If you have any questions, please head to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;c&#x2F;farming&#x2F;diy-farming&#x2F;&quot;&gt;our forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or feel free to join us on &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldfarmers&quot;&gt;our ThreeFold Farmer chat&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on Telegram.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo by &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;unsplash.com&#x2F;@nickxshotz?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Nicholas Green&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on Unsplash&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>A Smart Contract for all IT workloads</title>
		<published>2021-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/05/post-4/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/05/post-4/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold was inspired by the blockchain burst when it was created in 2016. After doing a comprehensive scan of the technological space we realized that Blockchain holds the best technology to store (1) Smart Contracts and (2) Transactions in an immutable way. We created our own blockchain database: Rivine to host the Smart Contract layer before switching to the Parity Substrate of Polkadot and our Transactional blockchain to the Stellar Network.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
While we use blockchain technology, ThreeFold is much more than just “a blockchain project” as we apply many more revolutionary technologies. We decided to use Parity Substrate as we don’t see the need to create something if there’s already great technologies out there that we can already use. Today we’re proud of our Smart Contract for IT layer and approach the ThreeFold Grid v3.0 release this year which will expose its full potential to interact with the primitives of the grid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-what-is-this-smart-contract-for-it-about&quot;&gt;So what is this Smart Contract for IT about?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Smart Contract for IT allows you, your company or your community to execute the storage and running of your files and applications securely with consensus and automatic billing. You could compare it as a fingerprint check and your data would be accessible only if presenting your private key (fingerprint). Let’s maybe go through the process for a better idea of how this works.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The smart contracts are like recipes for chefs to cook exactly what you want. In that sense they need to be very accurate and as descriptive as possible to deliver what you need. In the case of ThreeFold, the smart contracts would define different sets of Internet resources you would need to store files, run applications, or communicate across the network.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Whenever you want to reserve more resources to store your latest album or run your applications, you will define the resources you need to your 3Bot or Digital Twin (your personal virtual system administrators) which will then look at different smart contracts that are available and choose the most appropriate package. For e.g. Reserve 3 PB of Storage in Switzerland across 7 nodes. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Following that, your 3Bot or Digital Twin will create and register the smart contract in the blockchain database in a few seconds, providing you with all your specific needs. It will also store and secure some instructions to the BCDB for the nodes to meet smart contract completion. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold had to make sure that user data would remain ultra-secure. Inspired by storage and communication algorithms used in space, we integrated it between the Smart Contract layer and Zero OS. The algorithm splits data into unrecognizable ‘slices’ that are distributed via network connections to different nodes locally or across the world, and that can be reconstructed only with your fingerprint. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;more-than-the-average-smart-contract&quot;&gt;More than the average Smart Contract&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Via your Smart Contract for IT, you can also define a consensus mechanism and create multi-signatures for smart contract execution or completion to deliver appropriate digital services in for example work related activities. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The beauty of the Smart Contract for IT is that it can work with thousands of connected nodes for the proper execution of any digital requirements on the infrastructure, verify if consensus was reached or not, download the right files to execute the smart contract and verify them, make sure that no hacker or outsider can ever gain access or influence its execution and more. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
If you want to learn more about ThreeFold’s Smart Contract for IT, read more &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold&#x2F;#&#x2F;internet4__smartcontract_it&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>How ThreeFold offers Data Sovereignty</title>
		<published>2021-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/05/post-3/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/05/post-3/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you’ve seen &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=uaaC57tcci0&quot;&gt;The Social Dilemma&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, you know all too well that today, people are being turned into products. Everything we do online – all of the data we upload and all of our digital activities – is tracked and oftentimes used against us. Targeted advertising is just the beginning.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Personal data is used by algorithms to make incredible important decisions, like whether someone should receive financial or health support or benefits. In China, people are now even receiving “scores” for their behaviors. It sounds like Black Mirror, but it’s real life.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
That’s the scary part. The good news is that things don’t have to be this way. ThreeFold is building the engine for an Internet where people can finally be data sovereign.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
With &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;threefold__why_intro?id=everyone-should-be-autonomous&quot;&gt;today’s Internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, infrastructure is centralized. Companies provide services in exchange for your personal data, which is stored on servers in hyper-scale data centers owned by private companies.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In ThreeFold’s model, those servers are called &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;threefold__3node&quot;&gt;3Nodes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and rather than sitting inside centralized data centers, they sit inside the homes or offices (or small data centers) owned by independent people and organizations called &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;threefold__farming_intro?id=what-is-3node&quot;&gt;Farmers&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. But the data inside is owned by the person or persons who put it there. They maintain access right as well. From a technical standpoint, data is dispersed across 3Nodes by &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold&#x2F;#&#x2F;threefold__part5_ultra_efficient_storage?id=the-space-algorithm-of-storage&quot;&gt;an algorithm&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that makes it such that nobody can access it. In addition, connections are peer-to-peer, meaning data goes directly between sender and recipient rather than passing through intermediaries as it does today – bringing further levels of security.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Thus, people can finally be data sovereign, knowing their data is safe, and truly theirs.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold’s Planet Positive Plan</title>
		<published>2021-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/05/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/05/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There’s no question that climate change is one of the biggest, if not the biggest threats facing humanity today. If we care at all about future generations and the health of our planet, we have no choice but to address these threats, and fast. That’s why one of our biggest aims is to lower the energy usage of our digital lives. But ThreeFold is taking not just a sustainable approach, we’re setting the plan for a planet positive Internet.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Recently, we released information on how our infrastructure saves up-to-90% on energy consumption compared to existing models. We achieve this mainly thanks to an extremely efficient storage system and the concept of a Digital Twin.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
From &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;threefold__energy_savings_storage&quot;&gt;a storage standpoint&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, we reduce energy by avoiding copies, implementing a multi-layer system, not using fast disks, through read&#x2F;write caching, and more. With &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;threefold__energy_savings_digital_twin&quot;&gt;Digital Twin&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, we have taken a very different approach to how we exist in today’s digital world. Rather than existing 100 times in a huge system of client-server architecture, now we exist only once. We believe that we can run 25 Digital Twins with &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;threefold__bulb_comparison_twin&quot;&gt;the same energy&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as used by one light bulb.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Saving energy is one thing, but there will still be remaining energy. This needs to be offset by carbon credits. Now, in order to regenerate our planet, we &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;threefold__carbon_negative&quot;&gt;work together with Take Action Global&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to let students farm carbon credits. This has the potential to offset energy usage 100% by the end of 2021, and we have, as an aim to take 2x more carbon out of the air than we put in.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Our planet needs better solutions across industries. No more talking. Now is the time to act.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>We Need a More Inclusive Internet</title>
		<published>2021-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/01/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/01/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Today, more than 40% of the world is without access to the internet, a tool which brings incredible access to knowledge (education) and important information, communication tools that keep loved ones connected and are crucial for emergencies, and economic opportunities. And over the last year, as the world is spending more time at home, digital economies are booming and education is going remote. With an uncertain future, we need to fix the digital divide or we risk leaving billions of people even further behind.
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-data-center-problem-cost-proximity&quot;&gt;The Data Center Problem: Cost &amp;amp; Proximity&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The centralized data centers that power today’s Internet are located “strategically” mainly in North America, Europe, and select parts of Asia. For populations living in these regions, Internet is accessible and generally relatively affordable. But the further you travel from these data centers, the less available and more expensive the internet becomes. Internet access is mostly an issue Sub-saharan Africa, throughout Asia, and some parts of South America.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Of course some data centers can be and are being built in and near developing and remote regions, but for reasons including cost and audience, this hasn’t been a huge priority to date. Beyond that, the data center model as a whole simply cannot scale to meet the future demands of the internet nor is it sustainable for our planet, so this is not the right option.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-internet-shutdown-problem-control-manipulation&quot;&gt;The Internet Shutdown Problem: Control &amp;amp; Manipulation&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lack of internet access isn’t always just an availability or affordability problem. Today’s internet can be limited or even shut down at any point, by the right people. Take a quick look at &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;netblocks.org&#x2F;reports&quot;&gt;NetBlocks.org&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, an organization that reports on global internet disruptions or outages. Typically governments are enacting these measures during times of unrest or protest or  important political moments. Even in the United States, the Executive Branch of the government has &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.klemchuk.com&#x2F;ip-law-trends&#x2F;government-power-to-shut-down-the-internet&quot;&gt;the power to shut down the internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in a case of a national emergency.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Cutting the internet or restricting certain services based on region (a common practice as well) is not only not right, it’s dangerous. People rely on the internet for information and communication and no government or entity should have the ability to shut the internet down at their discretion.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-threefold-solution-fair-neutral-internet-for-all&quot;&gt;The ThreeFold Solution: Fair &amp;amp; Neutral Internet for All&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2016, the United Nations declared internet access to be a human right, yet today if you are reading this post, you are privileged. All humans deserve access to the internet and ThreeFold has the solution.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
With the ThreeFold model, nodes can be set up anywhere in the world where an existing internet connection and electricity are present. By putting physical infrastructure at the edge (close to users), greater levels of access can be reached.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Further, the ThreeFold Grid cannot be shut down or manipulated. It is a neutral internet owned by the people, where autonomous technology heals and runs itself and requires minimal human intervention.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Today we are working with partners in the clean energy and network &#x2F; connectivity to build the solutions that are needed to provide fair and uninterrupted internet access with all corners of the world.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Of course we will need new safe, secure, and private solutions for people to collaborate online. Many of these are already live and deployable via ThreeFold Now Community Solutions. We are working with partners in the education space as well to build toolsets for students to enrich their lives.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We need a more inclusive internet, and that is what we are building.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>A Better Solution for Our Planet</title>
		<published>2020-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2020/12/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2020/12/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Today, the global Internet and IT infrastructure requires enormous amounts of energy, responsible for about 10% of annual global energy consumption. This makes the IT industry amongst the most pollutive industries in the world (along with the often-discussed airline industry, for comparison).
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We believe IT can be sustainable. Actually, it should be! That&#x27;s why energy efficiency has always been a key focus of ours. With climate change and sustainability as some of the most pressing issues of our times, new green solutions need to be our priority. It has been key to ThreeFold since the very beginning of its story to enable a technological infrastructure that can reduce the Internet’s carbon footprint drastically. 
&lt;h2 id=&quot;simplicity-is-the-key-to-unlock-a-better-future&quot;&gt;Simplicity is the key to unlock a better future&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over time, integration suites, middleware solutions, and enterprise service busses have been invented and implemented to cover integration challenges within the current internet. This has further complicated IT architectures, resulting in a loss of actual end user workload performance.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold reworked the whole approach to IT architectures and eliminated the layers of complexity. The result is a cloud stack that presents minimal overhead and that requires less hardware – reducing heat generation and eventually cooling requirements. By reducing the need for power, the net result is an energy-efficient Internet grid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;improving-resilience-and-efficiency-through-self-healing-it&quot;&gt;Improving resilience and efficiency through Self-Healing IT&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping systems up and running is a major requirement in modern day IT. Leading vendors earn most of their margin by selling maintenance contracts, performance guarantees, and professional services. Their business models bring no incentive to make things simple and efficient for consumers.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Creating a self-healing environment requires only minimal manual intervention to replace broken hardware components. Broken hardware components are inevitable, and the Zero-OS distributed node architecture deals with such failures by turning off broken components and provisioning unused capacity. By removing the need to ship broken parts back and forth, and linking to the corresponding installation knowledge (engineers), a lower carbon footprint can be achieved.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;no-painkiller-approach-we-tackle-the-root-issue&quot;&gt;“No painkiller” approach. We tackle the root issue&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a specific piece of software or hardware is not delivering the required performance or reliability, we should analyze the core design&#x2F;algorithm and its usage of soft&#x2F;hard components to determine the root causes of persistent issues to be solved.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Currently, most storage vendors follow the path of least resistance when trying to improve on performance. Their solution for meeting performance targets is to use faster components (CPU, memory, network card, proprietary acceleration) rather than looking at the core algorithms that drive the utilization of those components. Swapping components for faster ones perpetuates a cycle of cutting corners and focuses reliance on innovation from hardware component providers rather than solving the more fundamental and underlying issues. That’s a “painkiller” approach.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Zero-OS was designed to solve root problem issues by design. While still using high-performance hardware components on the ThreeFold Grid, the algorithm of Zero-OS maximizes utilization possibilities. This enables greater performance and sustainability. Some key examples how this is achieved:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eliminating-unnecessary-elements-from-standard-architectures&quot;&gt;Eliminating unnecessary elements from standard architectures&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Virtualization adds a layer of software between the actual end-user workload and physical hardware. It also allows for multiple workloads to run on the same hardware by using excess capacity. There is definitely merit in building a virtualization solution. Building an effective virtualization solution that does not require abundant context switching is key and this is why Zero-OS has been developed. Zero-OS uses a minimal Linux kernel that allows for a number of user spaces to co-exist. In these user spaces, containerized versions of software can be run, eliminating the need for hypervisors, virtual OS to fuel the virtual machines, and guest operating systems. This also minimizes the required overhead for the host OS.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;minimizing-network-connections-usage&quot;&gt;Minimizing network connections usage&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supercomputing delivered many new technologies. But, not all of them are usable solutions for everyday workloads. One technology invented to make supercomputers performant is the use of Remote Direct Memory Access (RDMA). RDMA allowed physical CPU boards (containing both CPUs and memory) to access other CPU boards in memory stored data over a dedicated channel. This eliminated the need to transport data between CPU nodes over network connections (or other mainstream means to exchange data). The result was a considerable reduction in overhead created when allowing distributed end user workloads to operate over multiple physical cores. The leading server and storage solutions brands have never considered nor implemented such mechanisms. This resulted in an increased need for faster networks - increasing complexity, costs, efforts and resources needed to operate solutions.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
RDMA is only used in certified farms and requires involvement of TFTech.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;minimizing-disk-usage&quot;&gt;Minimizing disk usage&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The storage solution uses slow and big (the bigger the better) HDD disks which drive in rack density. As they spin slower they consume less power and need less cooling. But then, how can you deal with read&#x2F;write intensive workloads? The storage algorithm uses a SSD cache to acknowledge Inputs&#x2F;Outputs coming from the applications, fills the erasure coded data blocks in large (up to 64MB) storage containers and writes the big chunks of data on the big and slow HHDs. If you are familiar with HDD disks, you know they like to be streamed on instead of having a lot of small bits written in a scratchy way.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Continuous innovation in all of these areas are leading to an efficient technology stack.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Why We Do What We Do</title>
		<published>2020-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2020/04/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2020/04/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We are growing a green and responsible peer-to-peer Internet that is available everywhere and owned by everyone — across geographical and cultural borders, empowering people to be digitally independent and providing equal chances to learn, partake and succeed.
&lt;h2 id=&quot;values-first&quot;&gt;Values-First&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At ThreeFold, we are driven by three main values:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Equality is the foundation for a fair world where everyone is given the opportunity to be empowered and to achieve their full potential.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Freedom of thought, opinion, creativity and faith are fundamentals to achieve peace and fulfillment of humankind’s potential.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sustainability ensures the future of life on earth. It is about adopting the behavior and mindset to minimize our footprint.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Let’s take a deeper look.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;internet-access-a-human-right&quot;&gt;Internet Access | A Human Right&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2016, the United Nations officially declared Internet access to be a human right. The right to internet access aims to protect people’s freedom of expression and opinion, as well as other fundamentals such as access to knowledge and information.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Yet as of today, about 48% of humanity remains unconnected to the Internet, creating huge inequalities in the access to information and knowledge. It is important that the right steps are taken to improve the relationship between governments and citizens and to uphold all human rights.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
To make the new internet accessible and equal to all, ThreeFold built with ThreeFold Farmers an infrastructure that is affordable to all and collectively owned by the network peers. To ensure a fair and equal distribution of the internet to everyone, fully sponsored capacity will be deployed in remote regions of our world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;digital-freedom-for-everyone&quot;&gt;Digital Freedom | For Everyone&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet evolved to become the world’s largest database of information and knowledge, opening up exponential growth on personal, organizational and economic levels. Yet it is owned by large international companies that exploits users data.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The current approach of many governments and countries is to cut the Internet into pieces by limiting its accessibility and enforcing regulations. We need an internet that protects our digital freedom and fair access to global information for everyone, everywhere.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold is a peer-to-peer internet — owned by the users. All the technology of this new internet is open-source and the whole experience is built around the fundamentals of a peer-to-peer network. On this new internet, everyone owns their data and experiences — digital freedom.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-green-internet-for-our-planet&quot;&gt;A Green Internet | For Our Planet&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current internet consumes about 10% of global energy production. With the imminent boom of emerging technologies such as Blockchain, Internet of Things, Virtual Reality, Artificial Intelligence and 5G, the Internet’s energy consumption is expected to increase exponentially.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The current industry solutions focuses on increasing the use of renewable energies to power data centers. However this is not a viable solution as data centers consume enormous amounts of energy. Therefore, a new solution that can drastically reduce the global internet’s energy consumption is needed.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold is the first true peer-to-peer Internet. It uses pioneering technologies that remove the need for centralized and power-hungry data centers, consumes 90% less energy, and uses 90% less international fibre network capacity.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
If not now, when? If not us, who?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Photo by Yannis H on &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;unsplash.com&#x2F;photos&#x2F;uaPaEM7MiQQ&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Internet is growing wild</title>
		<published>2019-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2019/12/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2019/12/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;you-are-unique&quot;&gt;You are unique&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a gathering with some friends, I noticed something that made me think about how important it is what we’re doing at ThreeFold.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
One of my friends was complaining about how he couldn’t log in to one of his social media platforms, because all of his passwords are different and he forgot which one he used for this particular platform. Another friend was saying how she tagged her sister on a funny meme, but her sister couldn’t find it on Facebook. Turns out she tagged her on Instagram. And then one of them said something that I keep hearing more and more from people, “Why do we have so many apps, I can’t find anything anymore!”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We exist so many times online, but why? There is only one me in the real world. Why should there not be only one me online? Why should I have 25 different profiles on 25 different platforms, with 25 different logins, when I am unique?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
That is another dilemma that ThreeFold has a solution for, with its autonomous technology. 3Bot - a digital avatar like no other, that basically handles your entire online life. The focus lies on digital privacy, where only you can access your data, and no one else. The 3Bot has all the functionalities you need to interact and exchange information and value, there will be no need for that many applications on your device anymore. With 3Bot, everything changes.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The 3Bot is built on the ThreeFold Grid, and has the same values as ThreeFold. Freedom, Equality, and Sustainability. It is important that your data is safe, and what can be safer than you being the only one who not only has access to it, but also the only one who owns that data? Your online world should not be that different from your offline world. In your offline world, you are the center of your own life. That is what ThreeFold is doing with the 3Bot, putting you in the center of your online life, too.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
One decentralized application, one digital wallet, one login and one you. Because you’re unique.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Have questions? Feel free to ask us on our &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&quot;&gt;forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Photo by Jessica Ruscello on &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;unsplash.com&#x2F;photos&#x2F;DoSDQvzjeH0&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>An escape from the Great Hack</title>
		<published>2019-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2019/11/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2019/11/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-neutrality-of-the-current-internet-is-in-danger&quot;&gt;The neutrality of the current Internet is in danger.&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you seen ‘The Great Hack’ on Netflix? It’s a documentary about the Cambridge Analytica hacking scandal, where personal data of millions of peoples’ Facebook profiles were harvested without their consent and used for political advertising purposes. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
While watching it, I couldn’t help but think how unfair it is that in today’s digital society, people are being treated like products, because there is no such thing as a ‘free’ platform without YOU being the product. What did reassure me, is that people are sick of having their data used this way. But what they might not know, is that the internet problem is bigger than ‘just’ data protection.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The Internet is growing at an exponential rate. To service this demand, a few large companies (Google, Amazon, Alibaba, Facebook, etc.) have built and continue to build supersized, power-hungry and centralized data centers. These data centers make up the majority of all Internet capacity available today. However, the Internet is expanding much faster than datacenters and the planet can cope with. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In addition to that, the Internet is extremely centralized, with most of these data centers being located in the US. Think of it like electricity. If consumers in, for example, Turkey had to use electricity generated in the US, it would be too expensive and inefficient, because it is too far away. The transmission lines would be too strained and losses and repairs would make it unsustainable. Capacity is like electricity. When centralized, it becomes too expensive and wasteful for remote users.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-what-is-the-solution-to-these-problems&quot;&gt;So what is the solution to these problems?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet needs to be more distributed, cost-effective, neutral, and sustainable. ThreeFold has developed such a new technology, the ThreeFold Grid (Grid) and a token which enables all this to happen.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Combining the values of the ThreeFold Foundation (freedom, equality and fairness) with the technology developed by TFTech (Zero-OS, Zero-Chain, 3Bot) and a digital currency called the ThreeFold Token (a decentralized digital currency and means of payment to exchange autonomous and decentralized Internet services)  we believe that we have all the tools in order to actually make a difference in tomorrow’s digital world. Question is, are you ready to join us? 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Please visit &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&quot;&gt;our forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; if you have any questions or would like to continue the conversation!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Decentralizing the Internet</title>
		<published>2019-08-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-08-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2019/08/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2019/08/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;decentralization&quot;&gt;Decentralization&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1989, the Internet changed the world as we know it with the introduction of the World Wide Web. With time the Internet empowered people to share information in a decentralized way. Shortly after, big companies like Facebook, Google, and Apple emerged, providing many solutions that revolutionized the way we live. The “sharing economy” has grown exponentially over the last 5-10 years. This is thanks to a more simplified information flow and well-developed technology, which:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enables a much easier integration of independent players into the sharing economy.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eliminates the need for extensive management and structure of marketplace operators.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We are entering a flat-structure economy. An economy where fewer managerial levels are needed for the system to function. New technologies such as blockchain and the Internet of Things facilitate this ongoing trend. Participants can now interact on a peer-to-peer basis, forming marketplaces and organizations according to pre-agreed, programmed contracts.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-current-internet-is-centralized&quot;&gt;The current Internet is centralized&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the growth in popularity for decentralized systems, organizations, and currencies, the Internet remains centralized. The centralization within the Internet industry brought many barriers to entry. Indeed, to compete in the highly competitive market of Internet capacity dominated by big IT companies, massive investment, and IT development are needed.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
But what is really scary is that the current industry exploits the market tremendously. Data is officially the most valuable asset on earth for a few years, and about 20 companies rule over more than 80% of the cloud industry. In other words - these companies together have more than 80% of the world’s information. In recent years, we noticed the dangers that can arise with the wrong intentions within the data industry with the ‘Cambridge Analytica Scandal’, also highlighted in the movie &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=iX8GxLP1FHo&quot;&gt;‘The Great Hack’.&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold has been developing technology that allows the decentralization of the Internet infrastructure - removing the need for data centers, and allowing anyone to take part in the Internet capacity market. Adding capacity to the ThreeFold Grid (TF Grid) makes you a ThreeFold Farmer (TF Farmer). The more decentralized the Internet gets, the more secure and effective it will become. The already is the largest grid of compute and storage in the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-participate&quot;&gt;How To Participate&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process of becoming a ThreeFold Farmer is very straightforward. Anyone can join the ThreeFold Grid by downloading the ThreeFold Zero-OS onto their nodes and connecting them to the ThreeFold Grid.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
By doing this you will become an operator of a “micro data center” and with that earn ThreeFold Tokens. With or without experience in the field, anyone can become a ThreeFold Farmer. By becoming a ThreeFold Farmer, you empower a new neutral Internet that belongs to humanity - not corporations.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
You can build your server (3node) and configure it, but also options for people with less technical knowledge are available. Please see &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;pre-register.threefold.io&quot;&gt;pre-register.threefold.io&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to see how easy it is for anyone to become a ThreeFold Farmer.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Blog written in 2019, updated January 2021.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Co-create the new Internet. Participate with TFT!</title>
		<published>2019-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2019/06/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2019/06/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;do-you-believe-that-the-world-needs-change&quot;&gt;Do you believe that the world needs change?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you believe in decentralization? Equality? Sustainability?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Do you believe in circular economies, where everyone is invited to partake and succeed?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The ThreeFold Token is the currency of the new Internet and brings true solutions to all the above questions. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
It supports the ThreeFold Foundation - an open ecosystem that is shaping a better world by empowering game-changing technology. ThreeFold is growing a green and conscious peer-to-peer Internet that is available everywhere and owned by everyone – across geographical and cultural borders, empowering people to be autonomous, and providing equal chances to learn, partake and succeed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;ready-to-support-a-new-internet&quot;&gt;Ready to support a new Internet?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By buying and holding TFT, anyone can support the ThreeFold Foundation’s ability to achieve its next technological and growth milestones (see &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;tdeoverview&quot;&gt;Token Distribution Event&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for use-cases). From funding the next technological innovations to supporting the growth of ThreeFold use-cases built on top of the ThreeFold Grid, TFT powers the expansion of the new Internet. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The time has come for us to step up and shape the world we believe is possible. Join us and lets co-create our futures together.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Get TFT on &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;app.liquid.com&#x2F;exchange&#x2F;TFTBTC&quot;&gt;Liquid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; now.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Get TFT on &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;btc-alpha.com&#x2F;en&#x2F;exchange&#x2F;TFT_BTC&quot;&gt;BTC-Alpha&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; now.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
On behalf of our planet, humanity and the ThreeFold Community, we thank you for considering empowering a better world.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you need more guidance on buying TFT, please head &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;how_to_buy&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Datacenter Myths</title>
		<published>2017-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2017-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2017/10/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2017/10/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;hyperscale-realities-are-very-different-from-what-most-people-think&quot;&gt;Hyperscale realities are very different from what most people think&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;myth-1-bigger-data-centers-are-more-efficient&quot;&gt;Myth 1: Bigger data centers are more efficient&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are advantages in building larger-scale data centers, like economies of scale and sheer bulk buying power, but these are not as significant as what people think. The average cost per rack in a hyper-scale data center is $20-35K USD including all energy requirements and safety systems. The cost of hardware per rack is around the $200-300K USD mark.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
What is often forgotten is that anything that is of enormous scale and highly concentrated comes with complexity and specific problems to deal with. For example. resource requirements such as investment, operational costs, knowledge, and people increase significantly with size.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In reality, keeping things simple, small, and distributed is much more cost-effective than large complex environments.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;myth-2-big-data-centers-can-be-sustainable&quot;&gt;Myth 2: Big data centers can be sustainable&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The carbon footprint of a big data center is enormous. To improve the power usage effectiveness (PUE) of most data center farmers have adopted wind, hydro, and&#x2F;or solar power technologies, which indeed helps drop their PUE by an estimated 20%. But is this leading to more sustainability?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
This 20% looks great on paper and in the farmers’ corporate social responsibility reports. However, it just represents an improvement in the cooling technology and sourcing of energy. It doesn’t actually impact the energy consumed by the equipment that runs in their data centers (servers, storage chassis, physical disks, etc.) which is the equipment responsible for the carbon footprint. PUE only refers to overhead power consumption, i.e. cooling the facility, opening, and closing doors, maintaining power security systems, etc.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Real improvement lies in deploying technologies that actually consume less power to deliver the actual Internet capacity to run workloads, real CPU chassis, physical disks, and storage cabinets. Improving on how hardware is being more effectively used can have an impact of up to a thousand percent and lead to ten times more power-efficiency.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;myth-3-redundant-systems-have-better-uptime&quot;&gt;Myth 3: Redundant systems have better uptime&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of us believe that systems need redundancy mechanisms to improve their operational uptime and reliability. While it may make sense to IT experts, let’s translate this for the non-IT world?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
To make a car more reliable we add redundancy (as we do in IT). So for the risk of having a puncture, we add one extra tire for all the tires we use continuously. This adds 4 extra tires to the car. Then a decision needs to be made: Do we put those tires in a structure where they are always running along with the primary tires or do we choose not to have them “online” all the time, wearing and tearing in the same way as the primary tires?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Building such a system would take a large number of engineers to come up with a solution, and would change cars as we know them. Wouldn’t it make more sense to think outside the box and solve the root of the problem by making tires un-deflatable?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The IT industry has gone overboard with the concept of redundancy, having forgotten to look at the root cause issues. This has spawned a whole new industry of itself, which has a financial interest in creating complicated and expensive redundant systems.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;myth-4-big-companies-optimize-better&quot;&gt;Myth 4: Big companies optimize better&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big companies with a certain track record will know better how to optimize as they have more people and resources.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
At first glance, this sounds logical, but in reality, ninety percent of the innovation within the IT space comes from startups. The giant IT companies have a heritage they hardly can overcome. They are locked in old infrastructure designs, and building outside of that infrastructure would be costly, timely, and probably put the breaks on their businesses.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Real innovation gives way to fix the core symptoms rather than taking the problem pain-killer approach.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Creating solutions that respect humanity and the planet</title>
		<published>2017-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2017-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2017/06/post-2/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2017/06/post-2/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Organizations should always respect human rights, human effort and human experience. To enable a sustainable and prosperous civilization and world, we need a strong value system.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
*Ideas and texts were inspired from https:&#x2F;&#x2F;ind.ie&#x2F;ethical-design&#x2F;. We added our own twist to it.*
&lt;h2 id=&quot;respect-human-rights&quot;&gt;Respect Human Rights&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sustainability&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: It is important for a very simple reason: we cannot maintain our quality of life as human beings, the diversity of life on our planet, or Earth’s ecosystems unless we embrace and protect its balance.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Equality&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Everyone should have a right to learn, dream, partake and succeed. Equal access also means affordability, not ownership by big greedy companies.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decentralization&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: To better distribute power, value and opportunities, we need more decentralization. Technologies and solutions should be available everywhere to improve equality and sustainability. &lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Openness &amp;amp; Interoperability&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Allows technologies to work together in an open way, without limitation, and therefore expands the possibilities for innovation and sharing.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accessibility&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Whatever the location or situation, people should benefit from easy and fast access to information and solutions.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security &amp;amp; Privacy&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Protect people from being put in situations of danger or exploitation. People should be empowered to be independent and they should be the sole owners of their experiences.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;respect-human-effort&quot;&gt;Respect Human Effort&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reliability&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Make sure technologies are reliable and last longer.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simplicity&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: We need to keep things simple: no unnecessary complexity - less is more.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transparency&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Let people and companies work together in a 100% transparent way.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Collaboration&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: It’s all about the greater picture. We are stronger together and have to help each other in reaching our common visions.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;respect-human-experience&quot;&gt;Respect Human Experience&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ergonomy&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Products and solutions should empower productivity, safety and comfort, while reducing human error.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusiveness&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Design should always be global and inclusive. We are all equal.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Products should be visually appealing and should achieve it’s purpose.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transparency&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Organisational records and strategies should be accessible to everyone.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Photo by Renee Fisher on Unsplash.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
