<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>ThreeFold - technology</title>
	<subtitle>Our global digital backbone</subtitle>
	<link href="https://www3.threefold.io/categories/technology/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://www3.threefold.io"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2022-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://www3.threefold.io/categories/technology/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Stake TFT and Become a ThreeFold Validator</title>
		<published>2022-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/03/post-6/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/03/post-6/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold is an innovative Internet infrastructure. By applying peer-to-peer technology to the Internet, ThreeFold operates without centralized cloud providers or authorities the management of transactions and the offering of Internet capacity is carried out collectively by a people-powered network.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold is open-source – its code is public, nobody owns or controls ThreeFold and everyone can take part. Through many of its unique properties, ThreeFold represents the next-evolution of the Internet and is the low-level foundation to support any current or future digital workload including Edge Computing, Web2, Web3, Blockchain, IoT and the Metaverse.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold aims to ensure that no application, big or small, is subject to the limitations of Web3 or the pitfalls of Web2. Its peer-to-peer Internet Grid is infinitely more resilient, secure and scalable than centralized cloud providers like AWS or Microsoft Azure. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;participate-in-the-threefold-l2-validator-program&quot;&gt;Participate in the ThreeFold L2 Validator Program&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;tf_chain&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Blockchain&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; records transactions that happen on the ThreeFold Grid, including Internet capacity (farming), Internet capacity provisioning (smart contract for IT), identity, account metadata and more.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;decentralization&#x2F;validators&#x2F;threefold__validators&quot;&gt;Validator nodes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; support the network by remaining in sync with the ThreeFold Blockchain and recording the chain’s data while validating and&#x2F;or injecting transactions. Essentially, a validator stores and validates transactions aka, mining blocks.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With about a hundred L2 validator nodes to join the network, clients will be able to rely on a distributed, peer-to-peer network instead of relying on centralized services.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people and organizations rallied to run validator nodes using computing and bandwidth resources – but more are needed to allow ThreeFold to continue to grow. The rest of this post describes how you can help and what’s in it for you.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-run-a-threefold-l2-validator&quot;&gt;Why run a ThreeFold L2 Validator?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L2 Validators store the records of the ThreeFold Blockchain, the ThreeFold DAO and the development of side chains on the ThreeFold Grid. There are only 50 in the first batch and 37 have already been verified – meaning there are only 13 spots left! Running an L2 validator requires 2,000,000 TFT staked in order to begin validating. This 2,000,000 TFT is the minimum bond needed to begin validating blocks. A validator also earns voting rights in the ThreeFold DAO (Decentralized Autonomous Organization), which is responsible for the operations of the ThreeFold Blockchain and ThreeFold Grid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running a validator node on a computer isn’t a complicated task. For many of us who love ThreeFold, we want to support the decentralization of the peer-to-peer Internet, and running a validator node is a great way to do that. Also, it is a unique and revolutionary project to have in your room or office. Running a validator node requires little electricity, close to zero technical knowledge, and no real time commitments. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;validator-node-rewards&quot;&gt;Validator Node Rewards&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For their commitment, and as an incentive for their continued participation, validators are rewarded with a share of the ThreeFold Grid’s revenue. By helping the network reach consensus, validators also earn rewards for processing transactions into new blocks or checking the work of other validators because that’s what keeps the ThreeFold Blockchain secure. A minimum of 5% yield is foreseen in the next 2 years.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;join-the-peer-to-peer-revolution&quot;&gt;Join the Peer-to-Peer Revolution&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold is realizing the initial promise of an open-source, peer-to-peer Internet owned by the people. Anyone can become a validator and participate in the decentralization of the Internet economy. If you are interested in running one, just follow these simple steps:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 1&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Create an account (wallet) with the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tokens&#x2F;threefold__threefold_connect&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Connect&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; app.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 2&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Buy the required amount of TFT to reserve your validator. Find all TFT buying options &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tokens&#x2F;threefold__how_to_buy&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 3&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Log into the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; using ThreeFold Connect and go to the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;c&#x2F;dao&#x2F;validators-signup-l2&#x2F;83&quot;&gt;L2 Validator Signup&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; category.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 4&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Follow the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;procedure-to-register-your-l2-validator-node&#x2F;1864&quot;&gt;registration instructions&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to become a L2 Validator, and review the checklist of your application before submission.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someone from the ThreeFold community will get in touch with you within the next few days to welcome you to the ThreeFold universe. We’ll have a brief call to verify your identity and wallet treasury to confirm your application. The successful verification process secures your spot as a ThreeFold L2 Validator.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Bridges Connecting the ThreeFold Ecosystem to External Networks</title>
		<published>2022-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/01/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/01/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Wondering how to switch between blockchains? Cross-chain bridges allow you to easily transfer TFT from one blockchain to another. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the launch of &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;threefold__threefold_grid&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; 3.0, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tft&quot;&gt;TFT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; has been available on three blockchains – Stellar, Binance Smart Chain and the Substrate-based ThreeFold Blockchain (aka TF Chain).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are already active bridges that connect Stellar to Binance Smart Chain and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;tf_chain&#x2F;&quot;&gt;TF Chain&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, improving the accessibility and availability of TFT, while also connecting the ThreeFold ecosystem to external blockchain networks.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about TF Chain in our blog post &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;tf_chain&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-bridges-and-why-are-they-important&quot;&gt;What are bridges and why are they important?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept of bridges in crypto is similar to a bridge in the physical world. Bridges in the real world simply connect two different locations and communities so that the people can travel back and forth and resources can be exchanged freely.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, using bridges in blockchain allows users to easily transfer tokens and other crypto assets between two or more networks – regardless of the different protocols, tooling, and governance models these networks have. Simply put, a bridge ensures a secure interoperability between different blockchains.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold uses blockchain bridges to connect external blockchain networks to the ThreeFold ecosystem. The bridging mechanisms we’ve implemented allow TFT to be transferred securely between &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;threefold__money_blockchain_partity_link&quot;&gt;different blockchains&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Currently, we’ve established &lt;strong&gt;two 2-way bridges&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stellar &amp;lt;&amp;gt; Binance Smart Chain&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stellar &amp;lt;&amp;gt; TF Chain&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what is the difference between the 3 chains?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.stellar.org&#x2F;?locale=en&quot;&gt;Stellar&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; is an open-source network for storing and moving digital assets, and still remains the main blockchain for the minting of TFT and distribution of farming rewards. Until the launch of TF Chain with Grid 3.0, only TFT living on Stellar were accepted for the reservation of Internet capacity on the ThreeFold Grid. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.binance.org&#x2F;en&#x2F;smartChain&quot;&gt;Binance Smart Chain&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; (BSC) is a standalone, parallel Binance chain that is a leading DeFi ecosystem next to Ethereum. On BSC, TFT is implemented as a cross-chain asset, allowing anyone to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;bridge.bsc.threefold.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;connect&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to the bridge using &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tokens&#x2F;threefold__tft_bsc_metamask&quot;&gt;Metamask&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold&#x2F;#&#x2F;tokens&#x2F;threefold__threefold_wallets?id=the-threefold-connect-app&quot;&gt;Trust Wallet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; – the most popular Web 3 wallets in the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tech&#x2F;tf-chain&quot;&gt;TF Chain&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; was built on the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;substrate.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Substrate framework&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; with the purpose of decentralizing user-farmer relationships on the ThreeFold Grid. It has its own native form of &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tft&quot;&gt;TFT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, which can be bridged back and forth from Stellar-based TFT. This model will be implemented for other chains in the future, for interoperability and cross-chain features between blockchain and DeFi ecosystems and the ThreeFold Grid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-s-new-with-tf-chain&quot;&gt;What’s new with TF Chain?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TF Chain represents a leap forward for simplicity in payments for capacity reservations and a move towards greater decentralization of the systems that support the ThreeFold Grid. With the launch of &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;what-is-new-in-tfgrid-3-0&#x2F;1133&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid 3.0&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, TF Chain became the official record of ThreeFold farms and nodes, and brought peer-to-peer &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;introducing-tf-chain-an-updated-billing-model&#x2F;1277&quot;&gt;billing&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; based on smart contracts for workload deployments on the ThreeFold Grid. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, minting will remain on Stellar but reservations of nodes and capacity on ThreeFold Grid 3.0 are already executed via &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;threefold__tfchain&quot;&gt;TF Chain&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. In the future, minting will also also be handled over TF Chain, as the creation of a custom blockchain for our ThreeFold Grid gives us great flexibility and scalability moving forward.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bridges were established between Stellar and TF Chain to facilitate payments, e.g. if you pay for a workload deployment in Stellar TFT, this payment needs to be bridged to TF  Chain’s native TFT to fund the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;threefold__smartcontract_it&quot;&gt;smart contract&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-two-way-bridge-between-stellar-bsc&quot;&gt;The two-way &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;bridge.bsc.threefold.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;bridge&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; between Stellar &amp;amp; BSC &lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until recently, the bridge between Stellar and Binance Smart Chain (BSC) was one-way only: from BSC to Stellar. Even though it was possible to transfer TFT from Stellar to BSC via  &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;threefoldfoundation&#x2F;tft&#x2F;blob&#x2F;main&#x2F;bsc&#x2F;bridges&#x2F;stellar&#x2F;transfers.md&quot;&gt;command line&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, this was only an option for tech-savvy people. Now, you can also deposit TFT from Stellar to BSC using the bridge with a proper UI, as you can see in the image below.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;blog&#x2F;tft_bsc_bridge.png&quot; alt=&quot;tft_bsc_bridge&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When depositing from TFT Stellar, &lt;strong&gt;please be sure that both addresses and memo are as indicated&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; in the instructions or the TFT you transfer will be lost forever. To facilitate the process, a &lt;strong&gt;QR code&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; is generated and can be scanned using the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold&#x2F;#&#x2F;tokens&#x2F;threefold__threefold_connect&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Connect app&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, automatically filling in the right address and memo on your behalf.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;blog&#x2F;tft_bsc_transfer.png&quot; alt=&quot;tft_bsc_transfer&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Binance Smart Chain is a more expensive chain, &lt;strong&gt;a fee of 50 TFT&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; will be automatically charged for the bridge from Stellar to BSC. Find the full &lt;strong&gt;step-by-step guide&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; for the Stellar-BSC bridge &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tokens&#x2F;threefold__tft_bsc_bridge&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-s-next&quot;&gt;What’s next? &lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the ThreeFold ecosystem continues to grow, we’re looking into building more bridges (e.g. Cosmos, Ethereum), some of which are already under development, to improve the accessibility of TFT and simplify the onboarding of blockchain and DeFi projects on the ThreeFold Grid. TF Chain will play an important role in the further development of the People’s Internet as the main inter-chain for &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;threefold__threefold_token&quot;&gt;TFT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Try out the Stellar-BSC bridge &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;bridge.bsc.threefold.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and visit &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;our forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to share your experiences.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Also, check out our blog post on TF Chain &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;tf_chain&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold’s 2021 Review and 2022 Preview</title>
		<published>2022-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/01/post-2/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/01/post-2/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It was an important year for ThreeFold, with huge developments on the ThreeFold Grid, the continued expansion of the grid by farmers, key partnerships, and more – all setting up for a strong 2022.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a quick look back at the year that was.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-threefold-grid&quot;&gt;The ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In January we launched ThreeFold Grid 2.4 on Mainnet and evolved it through version 2.8. In September, we launched ThreeFold Grid 3.0 on testnet and just this week, we launched TF Grid 3.0 on mainnet, with limited capacity for now.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold Grid 3 brings a massive leap forward in the decentralization of the ThreeFold Grid and makes for a much simpler user experience for farmers and grid users.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The starting point ThreeFold Grid 3:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;what-is-new-in-tfgrid-3-0&#x2F;1133&quot;&gt;What’s New in TF Grid 3.0&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Manual&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;notable-tech-developments&quot;&gt;Notable Tech Developments&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other new developments on the tech side included &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;news&#x2F;post&#x2F;qsfs_intro&#x2F;&quot;&gt;QSFS&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (Quantum Safe Storage System), &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;tf_chain&#x2F;&quot;&gt;TF Chain&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, Smart Contracts and more (take a look at the new &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tech&quot;&gt;tech section&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; we launched with the new threefold.io this year and of course &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold&#x2F;#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;threefold__technology&quot;&gt;our knowledge base&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-threefold-token-tft&quot;&gt;The ThreeFold Token (TFT)&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2021 was all about bringing TFT to more chains and making TFT more accessible, with the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;news&#x2F;post&#x2F;bsc_update_news&#x2F;&quot;&gt;BSC integration&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, TF Chain, and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;news&#x2F;post&#x2F;tft_1inch&#x2F;&quot;&gt;1inch&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;tft-tfgrid-growth-simulation&#x2F;1633&quot;&gt;Read about our TFGrid &amp;amp; TFT Price Simulation.&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;threefold-farming&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Farming&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, the ThreeFold Grid is live in &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;explorer.threefold.io&quot;&gt;57 countries&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; with more than 1,450 Nodes online. Thanks to all the Farmers who both built or bought and connected 3Nodes!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2021, we introduced a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold&#x2F;#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;farming&#x2F;threefold__certified_farming&quot;&gt;certified farming program&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold&#x2F;#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;farming&#x2F;threefold__farming_reward&quot;&gt;farming rewards 3.0&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; which will apply from ThreeFold Grid 3.1 onwards (end Jan). We also established &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;c&#x2F;farming&#x2F;nodeshop-pre-order-faq&#x2F;59&quot;&gt;weekly 3Node updates&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to keep you in the loop at all times.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;partnerships&quot;&gt;Partnerships&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout 2021, we announced key partnerships with &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;news&#x2F;post&#x2F;owncloud_threefold&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ownCloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;news&#x2F;post&#x2F;digithree&#x2F;&quot;&gt;DigiThree Labs&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;news&#x2F;post&#x2F;threefold_casperlabs&#x2F;&quot;&gt;CasperLabs&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and many more. Most recently, two of these partnerships were featured in the news, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;martechseries.com&#x2F;technology&#x2F;threefold-and-take-action-global-partner-to-bring-internet-access-to-1-billion-people-across-the-globe&#x2F;&quot;&gt;TAG&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.bloomberg.com&#x2F;press-releases&#x2F;2021-12-21&#x2F;helping-africa-go-digital-a-metaverse-startup-is-working-with-an-ngo-to-expand-digital-infrastructure-in-africa&quot;&gt;Computecoin&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. All of these will be launched in 2022.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;2022-preview-q1&quot;&gt;2022 Preview (Q1)&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first part of 2022, we are launching our grid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read our launch plan and offer feedback!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;the-threefold-grid-3-x-launch-plan&#x2F;1634&quot;&gt;&amp;gt; OUR LAUNCHPLAN Q1 2022&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-threefold-token&quot;&gt;The ThreeFold Token&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now is the time to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tokens&#x2F;how_to_buy&quot;&gt;buy TFT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;! (Please take a look at the launch plan above.)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2022, our goal for the ThreeFold Token is to be available at as many entry points as possible. We’re planning integrations with many ecosystems like Cosmos to achieve great networking effects for the money networks. There will be discounts for Utilization based on pre-purchasing of TFT, and more.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;wrapping-things-up&quot;&gt;Wrapping Things Up&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s no other project out there like ThreeFold. TF Grid 3 is here, the grid is continuously growing across the world, and this collective effort is uniquely positioned to truly decentralize the Internet. Remember: ThreeFold is inevitable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, here we go! You can expect many more updates soon on what was covered above. And may the year 2022 be full of health, happiness and opportunities for all of us!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please be reminded we are a decentralized movement, we need your help to let us all “BE THE INTERNET.” Become a farmer, register for a validator, contribute to our movement, develop a solution on top of TF Grid … If you’re not sure how to help out but want to, please get in touch on &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;our two-way chat&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or here on the forum.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>The ThreeFold Blockchain</title>
		<published>2021-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/12/post-7/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/12/post-7/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;what-is-new-in-tfgrid-3-0&#x2F;1133&#x2F;1&quot;&gt;third release&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;threefold__threefold_grid&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; represents a major step in the decentralization of the People’s Internet with the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;threefold__smartcontract_tfgrid3&quot;&gt;Smart Contract for IT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; coming to life on the ThreeFold Blockchain (aka “TF Chain”). Built on the Substrate framework, TF Chain represents the layer-0 for all current and future technologies to provision decentralized Internet capacity. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what is Substrate to begin with? And what exactly does our TF Chain do?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-tf-chain-and-what-is-substrate&quot;&gt;What is TF Chain and what is Substrate?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;threefold__tfchain&quot;&gt;TF Chain&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is the universal smart contract layer on the ThreeFold Grid. It’s an application-specific blockchain customized for the operation of a single application – provisioning decentralized compute, storage and network capacity. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;substrate.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Substrate&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a blockchain-building framework from &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.parity.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Parity&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that allows developers to simply create future-proof solo blockchains or parachains for any use case. Parity was founded by Ethereum’s co-founder and first CTO Gavin Wood in 2015, and went on to develop Substrate to power a multichain, interoperable and decentralized Internet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-did-we-choose-substrate-for-our-tf-chain&quot;&gt;Why did we choose Substrate for our TF Chain?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Substrate brings clear benefits to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tech&#x2F;tf-chain&quot;&gt;TF Chain&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in relation to its frameworks for developers, its interoperability with other blockchain ecosystems and its huge community. More than 150 projects from NFTs to DeFi are already building on it.  &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By providing a solid, mature and secure layer for custom blockchains, Substrate is built for adoption. The blockchain framework was built with the programming language Rust and is modular by design. Choosing Substrate allowed our developer team to leverage great blockchain constructs and efficiently build TF Chain instead of re-inventing the wheel. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its flexible, modular and composable architecture enables our team to focus on what matters the most – the unique demands of &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;grid&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. For example, we’ve built  a Grid module with specific functionalities for farms and nodes. Just like a chef can invent a new recipe and add it to a menu, Substrate allows our developers to build and add as many custom functionalities to TF Chain as we’d like, in a fully decentralized way. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A major benefit that comes with TF Chain being built on Substrate is the native compatibility with the Polkadot ecosystem, opening up the opportunity for ThreeFold to become a parachain on the Polkadot network and seamlessly bridging to other Substrate-based chains in the future.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-s-the-purpose-of-tf-chain&quot;&gt;What’s the purpose of TF Chain?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For ThreeFold to be a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;quest_decentralize_internet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;truly decentralized&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; peer-to-peer Internet infrastructure, people should be able to use Internet infrastructures from anywhere without any intermediaries like &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;threefold_cloud_vs_centralized_providers_like_aws_azure&#x2F;&quot;&gt;AWS&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. TF Chain serves exactly that purpose. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It orchestrates the provisioning of compute, storage and network on the ThreeFold Grid via &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tech&#x2F;zero-os&quot;&gt;Zero-OS&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, removing all forms of intermediaries present in today’s centralized IT infrastructures. Put simply, TF Chain allows people to provide and use cloud resources in a 100% decentralized way. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-does-tf-chain-do&quot;&gt;What does TF Chain do?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;threefold__tfchain&quot;&gt;TF Chain&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is responsible for achieving consensus on all Internet capacity transactions on the ThreeFold Grid and to store them in a historical record. This prevents users from “double spending” their &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tft&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Tokens&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and ensures the correct execution of Internet capacity provisioning via smart contracts, while also protecting the network from potential attacks. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An exciting feature that comes with TF Chain 3.0 is a totally new peer-to-peer billing framework for Internet capacity provisioning and workload deployment. This module allows for all functionalities of the ThreeFold Grid to be provisioned peer-to-peer between users and farmers. Therefore, the ThreeFold Token now also lives on the Polkadot network, allowing it to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www2.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;bridges_connecting_threefold_ecosystem&#x2F;&quot;&gt;bridge back and forth&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; from the Stellar network and potentially from other chains in the future.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While TF Chain builds on the Substrate framework, most of its functionalities are custom-built to fit the specific needs of the ThreeFold Grid – from Internet capacity provisioning, workload deployments, and payment and billing processes, to digital twin creation and much more. By executing all these actions via &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tech&#x2F;smart-contract&quot;&gt;smart contracts&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in an automated and decentralized way, the activity on the ThreeFold Grid is always secured by blockchain technology and available to other users for open collaboration. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Farms can now be registered on our new &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;tech_update_admin_portal&#x2F;&quot;&gt;TF Chain Portal&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-future&quot;&gt;The Future&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Internet capacity provisioning and workload deployments are already executed via TF Chain, the minting of TFTs according to the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;farming&#x2F;threefold__proof_of_capacity&quot;&gt;Proof-of-Capacity algorithm&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; remains on the Stellar blockchain until Grid 3.1, when TF Chain will become the official chain of the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;threefold__threefold_token&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Token&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building our own application-specific blockchain represents a major step towards decentralizing the ThreeFold Grid and ecosystem, with the next milestone being the ThreeFold DAO planned for Grid 3.2. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;massive thank you&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; to our developer team for this great achievement! 🙏&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to dive deeper? We invite you to:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learn more about how smart contracts work on TF Chain 3.0 &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;threefold__smartcontract_tfgrid3&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;join the ThreeFold Grid 3.0 testnet conversations &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;joinchat&#x2F;BwOvOxxgK59GmRoZ2_sM0w&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;check our roadmap &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;cloud&#x2F;threefold__roadmap_grid&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>The ThreeFold Grid 3.x Explorer UI</title>
		<published>2021-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/11/post-2/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/11/post-2/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We are very excited to present to you the new Explorer UI for ThreeFold Grid 3.x! 🎉&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Explorer was designed to provide &lt;strong&gt;a simple way for anyone to find decentralized Internet capacity on the ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, and we’re thrilled to announce a new user interface for Grid 3.x on both &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;explorer.test.grid.tf&#x2F;&quot;&gt;testnet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;explorer.dev.grid.tf&#x2F;&quot;&gt;devnet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new explorer builds upon the recent migration to the Parity Substrate, &lt;strong&gt;bringing true decentralization&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; to the way compute, storage and network capacity information is sourced from 3Nodes. The previous &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;explorer.grid.tf&#x2F;&quot;&gt;explorer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (used for 2.x) has been sourcing its information from a centralized database as TF Chain was still under construction. Now, the new explorer receives its information via &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;manual__explorer_graphql_intro&quot;&gt;GraphQL&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;straight from the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;manual__grid3_tfchain_init&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Blockhain&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-graphql&quot;&gt;What is GraphQL?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;graphql.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;GraphQL&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is an open source data query language for APIs. The GraphQL interface queries our blockchain and displays the information registered on it in a command-line interface. We, in turn, created a graphical representation of that information in our explorer.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-to-expect-from-the-new-explorer-ui&quot;&gt;What to expect from the new Explorer UI&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;new &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;manual__explorer_home&quot;&gt;Explorer UI&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; allows you to &lt;strong&gt;explore the available Internet capacity&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; connected to ThreeFold Grid &lt;strong&gt;easier than ever before&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. As of now, the new Explorer displays data about the compute, storage, network and gateways connected to the Grid 3.x testnet and devnet by ThreeFold Farmers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The statistics section gives you &lt;strong&gt;an overview of &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;explorer.test.grid.tf&#x2F;&quot;&gt;key information&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; about our testnet (as of November 30th, 2021) as displayed below. Our farmer community has already connected &lt;strong&gt;more than 100 nodes (across 16 countries)&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, and we have seen &lt;strong&gt;more than 1,400 contracts deployed&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; on the ThreeFold Grid 3.0 testnet since its launch.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;blog&#x2F;tf_explorer_statistics.png&quot; alt=&quot;tf_explorer_statistics&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;All screenshots in this post are from the ThreeFold Grid 3.x testnet Explorer, and the numbers are growing continuously.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once a farm ID gets registered to &lt;strong&gt;the new &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;manual__tfchain_portal_home&quot;&gt;TF Chain Portal&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, all the relevant information (e.g. uptime, nodes specifications, location) of farms are automatically displayed on the Explorer for users to find their ideal decentralized Internet capacity. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users can now explore all farms and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;farm&#x2F;&quot;&gt;3Nodes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; using &lt;strong&gt;multiple filtering options&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; (e.g. farm name or farm ID), making it simpler than ever before to find the decentralized Internet capacity they are looking for. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not sure what the new Admin Portal is about? We’ve covered all the details in &lt;strong&gt;our &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;introducing-the-tf-chain-admin-portal-for-farmers-and-grid-users&#x2F;1526&quot;&gt;previous update&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, check it out!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;blog&#x2F;tf_explorer_farms.png&quot; alt=&quot;tf_explorer_farms&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;blog&#x2F;tf_explorer_nodes.png&quot; alt=&quot;tf_explorer_nodes&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also made the world map bigger to improve the display of the available decentralized Internet capacity.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;blog&#x2F;tf_explorer_worldmap.png&quot; alt=&quot;tf_explorer_worldmap&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dark mode is finally available for the ThreeFod Grid 3.x, bringing &lt;strong&gt;a more comfortable navigation&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; for some of us. Just click on the crescent&#x2F;sun icon in the upper-right corner of the screen, and you’re good to go.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;blog&#x2F;tf_explorer_darkmode.png&quot; alt=&quot;tf_explorer_darkmode&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We invite you to &lt;strong&gt;take a look at the ThreeFold Grid 3.x Explorer UI overview&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; with more details &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;manual__explorer_ui&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in mind, the overview of all 3Nodes worldwide across all nets can be found &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;explorer.grid.tf&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and this will phase out as we approach 3.x mainnet launch as shared on our previous &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;whats-new-in-tf-grid-3-0-1-and-the-path-to-mainnet&#x2F;1488&quot;&gt;update&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Visit our forum to share you experiences with the new explorer interface &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;the-threefold-grid-3-x-explorer-ui&#x2F;1536&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Introducing the TF (Chain) Admin Portal – for farmers and grid users!</title>
		<published>2021-11-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-11-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/11/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/11/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last week, we shared an update on &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;whats-new-in-tf-grid-3-0-1-and-the-path-to-mainnet&#x2F;1488&quot;&gt;what’s new in TF Grid 3.0.1 – and the path to mainnet!&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; There’s been a lot of exciting progress by the team, and we wanted to share with you some more specifics where we can – starting with the admin portal!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-the-admin-portal&quot;&gt;What is the admin portal?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the requests from farmers and grid users was a to have a simpler user experience. The admin portal (aka TF Chain UI) is a response to that feedback, a graphical user interface for farmers and grid users on top of &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;threefold__tfchain&quot;&gt;the TF Chain&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The admin portal is the starting point for anyone to start working with the TF Grid.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; For Farmers in particular they now have a much simpler way to create a farming identity and then connect their infrastructure to the ThreeFold Grid 3.0. It is a one stop shop to start a farm. Beyond that, it’s a way for any TF Grid user to create their account on the TF Chain, get a Twin, and get started (testing for now) on the TF Grid 3.0 devnet or testnet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Find links to get started at the bottom!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-does-the-admin-portal-do&quot;&gt;What does the admin portal do?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The admin portal is a place for TF Grid users to:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create an account on the TF Chain and a digital twin to start smart contracting on TF Chain (allowing you to also link to your IP address for added security).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;blog&#x2F;tf_chain_ui.png&quot; alt=&quot;tf_chain_ui&quot; &#x2F;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Operate a bridge between Stellar and TF Chain on Parity Substrate (deposit TFT from Stellar, or return unused TFT to the Stellar chain, the bridge is active in both directions)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;blog&#x2F;tf_chain_deposit.png&quot; alt=&quot;tf_chain_deposit&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;blog&#x2F;tf_chain_withdraw.png&quot; alt=&quot;tf_chain_withdraw&quot; &#x2F;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For farmers: create and manage your farm(s), provide IPv4 addresses available for your farm(s), attach a Stellar wallet for TFT payouts, and a link to download the bootloader for testnet and devnet (mainnet is on its way).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;blog&#x2F;tf_chain_your_farm.png&quot; alt=&quot;tf_chain_your_farm&quot; &#x2F;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The portal also links to the new capacity explorer, which we’ll share more about early next week.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;blog&#x2F;tf_chain_node_resources.png&quot; alt=&quot;tf_chain_node_resources&quot; &#x2F;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-is-this-an-improvement-over-the-old-process&quot;&gt;How is this an improvement over the old process?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously, all of these tools existed, but not always in the same place or with a clear and easy-to-use UX&#x2F;UI. We’ve tested this portal with people of all technical levels, and the response has been great! We believe the portal is a huge step forward for anyone using or managing the ThreeFold Grid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More improvements will come in the next versions. As an example, we’re planning for you to be able to see the connected nodes linked to your farm with their status, earned tokens, etc.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-started&quot;&gt;Get started&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The portal is currently available on &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;portal.dev.grid.tf&quot;&gt;devnet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;portal.test.grid.tf&#x2F;&quot;&gt;testnet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. You can also find information on the portal in our library &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;manual__tfgrid3_getstarted&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Please note, you’ll need to install the Polkadot{.js} extension and create or import an account in order to get started.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Visit our forum to discuss you experiences with the new admin portal &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;introducing-the-tf-chain-admin-portal-for-farmers-and-grid-users&#x2F;1526&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>A Journey through the Decentralization and Blockchain Space – Part Four: Storj</title>
		<published>2021-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/10/post-8/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/10/post-8/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the fourth part of our journey through the decentralization space. After exploring &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;project_comparison_1_dfinity&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Dfinity&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;project_comparison_2_akash&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Akash&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and most recently &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;project_comparison_3_filecoin&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Filecoin&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, we’ll now explore Storj to find out what we have in common and where ThreeFold stands out. Here we go!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;storj-how-the-project-compares-to-threefold&quot;&gt;Storj &amp;amp; how the project compares to ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.storj.io&quot;&gt;Storj&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a decentralized cloud storage (DCS) solution founded in 2014 by Shawn Wilkinson, offering cloud object storage on its network of nodes and ISPs spread across different countries.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold and Storj are both open source projects that view transparency as an integral part of their business philosophy. Actually, ThreeFold is the first full-stack blockchain-enabled &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cloud.threefold.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;cloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to be made open source – all of our code is open source and available for everyone to review or use. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another similarity is that security and privacy are crucial aspects of our projects. Both are private by design and believe it’s vital that every person has total &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;threefold_data_sovereignty&#x2F;&quot;&gt;control and ownership&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; over their data – not even Storj or ThreeFold can access the data of users within their respective ecosystems, creating trustless environments. Storj provides security and privacy by encrypting the data by an &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.storj.io&#x2F;dcs&#x2F;concepts&#x2F;overview&quot;&gt;Uplink client&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; before it is uploaded to its DCS. The data is then split into pieces which are distributed across different nodes and ISPs connected to Storj’s cloud network. At ThreeFold, we’re creating an &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;critical-security-updates-for-apple-and-google-underline-need-for-secure-it-ecosystem&#x2F;1271&quot;&gt;entirely secure&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, peer-to-peer IT ecosystem that empowers users and gives them back control and ownership of their own data. We’re &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;threefold__usp_secure?id=network-security&quot;&gt;secure&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; across all dimensions of our solutions – from our operating system Zero-OS to Quantum Safe File System (&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tech&#x2F;zdbfs&quot;&gt;QSFS&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;) and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tech&#x2F;planetary-network&quot;&gt;Planetary Network&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Storj does not have its own operating system, we’ve built our &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;tech&#x2F;zero-os&quot;&gt;Zero-OS&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; from scratch. It allows servers to run autonomously and workloads to be hosted securely, preventing them from administrative exploits and errors. The self-driving and self-healing &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;zero_os_blog&#x2F;&quot;&gt;features&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of Zero-OS eliminate backdoors, reduce the hacking surface and remove the need for human involvement.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both projects are compatible with certain IT tools and protocols. While Storj is  S3-compatible and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.storj.io&#x2F;integrations&quot;&gt;integrates&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; a couple of developer tools like FileZilla or Fastly, ThreeFold is highly compatible with leading industry standards and tools from S3 to Docker containers, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;grid-utilization-plan-part-one&#x2F;1157&quot;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and more. Moreover, ThreeFold can run anything that runs on Linux, allowing for a seamless migration of any digital workload, even from &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;threefold_cloud_vs_centralized_providers_like_aws_azure&#x2F;&quot;&gt;traditional cloud providers&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; like Microsoft Azure or AWS. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A difference between the projects is that Storj focuses on providing the storage layer for developers to build storage applications like Dropbox upon, rather than offering such services themselves, whereas our energy-efficient full stack &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cloud.threefold.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;cloud infrastructure&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; includes solutions like the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;marketplace&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Marketplace&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of ready-made peer-to-peer applications that runs on our Edge Virtual Data Center (&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;info&#x2F;cloud#&#x2F;cloud__evdc&quot;&gt;eVDC&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;). Moreover, we’re working with innovative teams and developers to develop self-sovereign &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;interview_with_jimber&#x2F;&quot;&gt;alternatives&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to commonly used applications (e.g. video conferencing, office tools).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;network-storage&quot;&gt;Network &amp;amp; Storage&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Storj’s decentralized network, uploaded data is automatically spread across nodes in different countries. The storage capacity on Storj’s network is increased whenever a new node is connected to it. There are roughly 9,6 Petabyte of data stored on Storj with nodes in more than 80 countries, whereas roughly 85 Petabyte of storage, compute, and network capacity are deployed on the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;grid&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Currently, the nodes connected to our Grid are spread over more than &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;explorer.grid.tf&quot;&gt;50 countries&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Storj only offers storage capacity, ThreeFold provides storage, compute, and network capacity. Moreover, our system is endlessly scaleable, whereas Storj’s scalability is limited as it does not empower people without technical skills to contribute and has more complex structures, such as its Satellite component which will be explained further down. We’re continuously extending our reach and our system is capable of seamlessly growing on demand, as it enables anyone to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;farm&quot;&gt;become a 3Node&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on our ThreeFold Grid. Moreover, our self-driving and self-healing &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tech&quot;&gt;technology&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is unique in the space and removes the need for monitoring and maintaining the nodes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Storage nodes on Storj are responsible for storing and returning data reliably. While Storj generally allows anyone with the excess capacity and bandwidth to run a node on its network, the project does not offer certified hardware. With Storj, anyone who wants to become a node operator has to build their own nodes which have to meet the specific hardware &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.storj.io&#x2F;node&#x2F;before-you-begin&#x2F;prerequisites&quot;&gt;requirements&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of Storj. At ThreeFold, our technology was designed to scale to anywhere electricity and bandwidth can be found to meet local digital infrastructure needs, to empower the unconnected and to drive our vision of an interconnected world. This is also why we’re working with certified hardware partners to provide &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;shop.threefold.tech&#x2F;index.php?route=common&#x2F;home&quot;&gt;plug-and-play&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; 3Nodes. These 3Nodes enable even people without technical skills to join and contribute to what we like to call the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;join_the_peoples_internet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;People’s Internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, as &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;mission&quot;&gt;we believe&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that everyone should be given equal chances and that Internet access is a human right.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next to the storage nodes, there are two other &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.storj.io&#x2F;dcs&#x2F;concepts&#x2F;overview&quot;&gt;main components&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of the Storj network: Uplink and Satellite. &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.storj.io&#x2F;dcs&#x2F;concepts&#x2F;definitions&quot;&gt;Uplink&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is Storj’s umbrella term for any application that stores or retrieves data and encrypts, encodes, and coordinates data with other services. Storj’s &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.storj.io&#x2F;dcs&#x2F;concepts&#x2F;satellite&quot;&gt;Satellite&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; consists of a set of storage node services like storage node reputation, data repair, billing and more. Storj users have to sign up for accounts on Satellites and pick a specific Satellite to trust. While any user could run their own Satellite in theory, Storj recommends users to create an account on a Satellite that is hosted by a third party like Storj Labs to reduce complexity. This approach, however, fosters centralization, whereas our peer-to-peer &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;smartereum.com&#x2F;189750&#x2F;threefold-is-audaciously-building-a-new-decentralized-internet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;infrastructure&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is an open system where anyone can provide and utilize cloud resources without any intermediaries. On top of that, we’ve implemented cryptographically-secured deployment specifications, called &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tech&#x2F;smart-contract&quot;&gt;Smart Contracts for IT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, to ensure that workloads run as intended in a tamper-proof way, and allow systems to scale and heal autonomously without intermediaries.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;tokenomics-payment-methods&quot;&gt;Tokenomics &amp;amp; Payment Methods&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both projects have native utility tokens. While the Storj token is an Ethereum-based token that represents a unit of storage capacity on the Storj network, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tft&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Tokens&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (TFT) can represent either a unit of compute, storage or network on the ThreeFold Grid. Some Storj community members &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.storj.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;the-elephant-in-the-room-where-is-the-storj-token-utility&#x2F;12452&quot;&gt;criticize&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; a lack of utility of the Storj token, as storage capacity on Storj can be purchased and paid for not only in Storj token but also using fiat payment options like credit card or invoice. However, Storj themselves don’t see this as an issue and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.storj.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;storj-token-balances-and-flows-report-q1-2021&quot;&gt;state&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that the intention behind their tokens is to facilitate the provision and receipt of data storage and not to create a digital currency or any other kind of financial instrument. In contrast, our ThreeFold Tokens are the fuel for IT capacity, as they allow people to hold current and future cloud capacity on the ThreeFold Grid. Moreover, a limited supply of four billion ThreeFold Token has been set to keep the currency scarce, while the burning mechanism simultaneously ensures continuous rewards for current and future nodes. Find out more about our two algorithms, Proof-of-Capacity (PoC) and Proof-of-Utilization (PoU), in our &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tokens&#x2F;threefold__tokenomics&quot;&gt;tokenomics&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By connecting storage nodes to Storj’s network and providing storage capacity to others, node operators get rewarded with Storj tokens which they receive &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.storj.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;storj-token-balances-and-flows-report-q2-2021&quot;&gt;from Storj Labs&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as a centralized payment operator, whereas ThreeFold Token are already rewarded upon the connection of capacity to our Grid. Moreover, storage capacity on Storj’s network can only be purchased with a subscription-based &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.storj.io&#x2F;pricing&quot;&gt;model&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. With ThreeFold, anyone can become a farmer and be &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;farming&#x2F;threefold__farming_reward&quot;&gt;rewarded income&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in the form of ThreeFold Tokens for &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;farming&#x2F;threefold__farming_intro&quot;&gt;expanding&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; the Internet by contributing cloud capacity. ThreeFold Tokens incentivize an open and autonomous &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tech&#x2F;peer-to-peer&quot;&gt;peer-to-peer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; system free from any type of intermediary. We’re enabling anyone to become an independent farmer, as we believe in empowering people and that no single entity should have the power to control systems. Based on our &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tech&#x2F;tf-chain&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Blockchain&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, which will be released on Testnet 3.0 soon, a new discount as well as &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;introducing-tf-chain-an-updated-billing-model&#x2F;1277&quot;&gt;billing model&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; will be introduced. The latter will allow users to authorize &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tech&#x2F;smart-contract&quot;&gt;smart contracts&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to automatically deduct their wallets according to the capacity they use.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, we both share the same vision of a decentralized Internet. The biggest difference between Storj and ThreeFold is that Storj is focused on providing storage, whereas &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;an_intro_to_the_threefold_grid&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; does not only provide storage but also compute and network capacity. While Storj seeks to be the storage layer for the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;quest_decentralize_internet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;decentralized Internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, ThreeFold provides the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;an_intro_to_the_threefold_grid&#x2F;&quot;&gt;low-level primitives&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for a &lt;em&gt;truly&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; decentralized Internet: compute, storage and network. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we’re the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.forbes.com&#x2F;sites&#x2F;johnkoetsier&#x2F;2020&#x2F;06&#x2F;20&#x2F;largest-distributed-peer-to-peer-grid-on-the-planet-laying-foundation-for-a-decentralized-internet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;largest&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, most advanced peer-to-peer cloud infrastructure in the world and are expanding fast, some aspects of Storj’s storage network still function in a rather centralized manner, such as their payment model and Satellites. In addition to that, we’re providing the ideal infrastructure for edge workloads. The project could therefore &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-is-the-substrate-for-decloud&#x2F;1295&quot;&gt;benefit&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; from moving on top of our fully decentralized, highly energy-efficient and autonomous &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;africa.businessinsider.com&#x2F;local&#x2F;markets&#x2F;ambitious-startup-to-disrupt-the-internet-and-cloud&#x2F;b38rwj4&quot;&gt;infrastructure&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Together, we could drive the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.econotimes.com&#x2F;ThreeFold-DFINITY-and-the-race-to-Decentralize-the-Internet-1618367&quot;&gt;decentralization&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of storage capacity all over the world. We believe in a world without boundaries, where people are able to share information, value and knowledge without limits nor intermediaries. To achieve this vision and to effect change at a large scale it takes collaboration. Thanks for coming along and stay tuned, as we’ll take a closer look at Holochain next!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
