<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>ThreeFold - farming</title>
	<subtitle>Our global digital backbone</subtitle>
	<link href="https://www3.threefold.io/tags/farming/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://www3.threefold.io"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2022-06-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://www3.threefold.io/tags/farming/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Weekly! June 15th, 2022 (Vol 21)</title>
		<published>2022-06-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-06-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/06/post-3/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/06/post-3/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;community-updates&quot;&gt;Community Updates:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The team spent a few eventful days in Austin, Texas, to celebrate the festival of the decentralized world: &lt;strong&gt;Consensus by CoinDesk&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. Over four days, we met hundreds of people, re-engaged with partners, took part in several interviews with the press, and co-hosted a gathering to lay the foundation for a &lt;strong&gt;sovereign Regional Internet in Austin&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; – by and for the people of the Austin community. Read the full recap &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;consensus-2022-and-laying-the-foundation-for-austins-sovereign-internet&#x2F;3018&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There’s a new episode available on our &lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold Podcast&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. Listen to Kyle and Weynand as they dive into everything from space to self-hosted data centers to the ownCloud partnership – you can listen to the episode &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;anchor.fm&#x2F;threefoldpodcast&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;technology-developments&quot;&gt;Technology Developments:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wondering what the team is working on in June? Well, it’s a lot – including many &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-product-updates-june-2022&#x2F;2937?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;updates and new functionalities&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for the Planetary Network, TF Wallet, the ownCloud freemium experience, and more.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also, check out this &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-product-updates-june-2022&#x2F;2937?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;sneak peak&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on &lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold Grid V3.0.0 Alpha-7&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;threefold-grid&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A new &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;gep-for-super-green-farming-with-100-renewable-energy&#x2F;2992&quot;&gt;Grid Enhancement Proposal&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for &lt;strong&gt;Green Farming with 100% Renewable Energy&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; was shared and is now open for voting. Make sure to participate – planet first, people first!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Global Titan shipping continues, so don’t forget to &lt;strong&gt;provide all &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;creating-your-v3-farm-required-for-open-unshipped-orders&#x2F;2144&quot;&gt;information&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; for your Titan order to ensure quick delivery.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sending you positive vibes from Austin, ThreeFolders! 🙌 &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you’re a community member interested in &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;looking-for-farmer-stories-to-share-with-the-world&#x2F;2398?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;sharing your story&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;looking-for-people-to-feature-in-threefold-content-its-super-simple&#x2F;2636&#x2F;3&quot;&gt;being featured&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in ThreeFold content, please reach out!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can find the previous editions on &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&quot;&gt;our blog&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. For older editions of ThreeFold Weekly (Vol 1-11), go to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;c&#x2F;ecosystem-developments&#x2F;41&quot;&gt;our forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Weekly! June 7th, 2022 (Vol 20)</title>
		<published>2022-06-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-06-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/06/post-2/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/06/post-2/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;major-threefold-news&quot;&gt;Major ThreeFold News:&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ThreeFold and &lt;strong&gt;the Institute of Emerging Technologies of South Africa &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;ietsa.org.za&#x2F;&quot;&gt;(IETSA)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; are partnering to &lt;strong&gt;expand the ThreeFold’s decentralized Internet infrastructure&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; across South Africa, and to &lt;strong&gt;provide education&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; in blockchain protocols and digital technologies. Learn more about this amazing collaboration &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.itweb.co.za&#x2F;content&#x2F;Pero3qZ3lkpvQb6m&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;community-updates&quot;&gt;Community updates:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ThreeFold team and community are &lt;strong&gt;heading to Austin&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; to celebrate the festival of the decentralized world: Consensus 2022 by CoinDesk. &lt;strong&gt;Meet the ThreeFold team at Booth 310&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; to connect, find resources that will empower you to get involved, and to learn about our gathering this Sunday!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have you read our &lt;strong&gt;updated ThreeFold Litepaper&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;? &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;litepaper-threefold-v17-important&#x2F;2927?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;Dive right in&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and let us know what you think – especially with regards to the structure of the &lt;strong&gt;Internet of Internets&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A community-initiated poll on &lt;strong&gt;locking farming rewards&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; is live. &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;polls-should-we-lock-farming-rewards&#x2F;2913?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;Leave your votes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on questions around locking and the different parameters that could be applied.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Registered to become a validator?&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; We’ll be sharing an update on next steps asap. If you have any specific questions please get in touch with @samtaggart on Telegram.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;technology-developments&quot;&gt;Technology Developments:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take a look at the &lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold Grid V3.0.0 Alpha-6 highlights&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; and learn more about what the team is working on in June &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-product-updates-june-2022&#x2F;2937?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;threefold-grid&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;specs-for-tfgrid-dao&#x2F;2926?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;this post&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; a read to learn more about the &lt;strong&gt;TF Grid DAO&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, who can vote and what areas can be voted on, as well as to find more about Grid Guardians, solutions rewards, and more!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;pricing-default-40-discount&#x2F;2924?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;Grid Enhancement Proposal&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on offering a &lt;strong&gt;40% discount by default&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; on Grid pricing is currently open for voting. Make sure to participate!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;gep-gold-certified-farming-specs&#x2F;2925&quot;&gt;Another Grid Enhancement Proposal&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; was started on &lt;strong&gt;Gold-Certified Farming Specs&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. Check out the suggested quality requirements and leave your vote!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please &lt;strong&gt;migrate your 3Nodes to V3 asap&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. Simply follow &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;farming-migration-grid-v2-v3&#x2F;2143?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;the migration process&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you ordered a Titan, please &lt;strong&gt;fill in your &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;creating-your-v3-farm-required-for-open-unshipped-orders&#x2F;2144&quot;&gt;information&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for your 3Node&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; to ensure quick delivery. Global Titan shipping continues.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you next week, ThreeFolders! 🙌 &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can find the previous editions on &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&quot;&gt;our blog&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. For older editions of ThreeFold Weekly (Vol 1-11), go to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;c&#x2F;ecosystem-developments&#x2F;41&quot;&gt;our forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Building the Future We Want to Live In – A Four Step Journey</title>
		<published>2022-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/06/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/06/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What started out as an idea for a better Internet about a decade ago has evolved into a global movement that’s building a decentralized, open and inclusive future through &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;internet_of_internets&#x2F;&quot;&gt;the Internet of Internets&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The journey towards our ultimate vision of a better future for all is a big one, but can be divided into four digestible phases: creation, expansion, Web 4 and velocity.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-the-phase-of-creation&quot;&gt;1 The Phase of Creation&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past six years, we’ve been building up an incredible full-stack, open-source, decentralized Internet infrastructure, all from the ground-up. From creating our own decentralized operating system, to building a Quantum Safe Storage System, a complete far edge cloud computing platform and planetary peer-to-peer network all accessible via a unique Smart Contract for IT on the ThreeFold Blockchain, we’re proud to have the most complete edge infrastructure to power the next-generation Internet era. A new world is coming, and our technology has the potential to revolutionize digitization on a global scale, across sectors. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creation phase was about developing the key tech components and an initial deployment of our infrastructure worldwide. The ThreeFold Grid is now live in its third generation and the stack is fully functional. As of today, people from all across the world have connected more than &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;threefold_io&#x2F;status&#x2F;1529903015938998272&quot;&gt;3,000 nodes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; across +78 countries to create the world’s largest decentralized Internet infrastructure, and new capacity is being connected every day.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to fully comprehensive decentralized edge cloud solutions, the ThreeFold ecosystem is also developing a range of applications and experiences across IoT, metaverse, blockchain, DeFi, banking, education and beyond.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The phase of creation is almost complete. The ThreeFold team is currently working on the Digital Twin solution that will allow the ecosystem to tap into Web 4 principles – a paradigm that overcomes the limitations of Web 2 and the inefficiencies of Web 3. By advancing our technology further, ThreeFold will be in a unique position to open new frontiers and support emerging global trends.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-the-phase-of-expansion&quot;&gt;2 The Phase of Expansion&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second phase is all about the growth of the ThreeFold Grid and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;connecting_the_dots&#x2F;&quot;&gt;connecting the dots&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. From individual farmers and farming cooperatives connecting Internet capacity independently to our global network, to building Community Clouds and Regional Internets for countries, various pathways to Grid growth have been established by the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;internet_of_internets&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Internet of Internets&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; concept.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet of Internets will interconnect us all, while providing us with digital sovereignty, privacy and meaningful experiences. It focuses on incentivizing local communities to build their own resilient Community Clouds to support their city, town or village with the foundation to build their decentralized future.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on their geographic proximity, Community Clouds will be able to form Regional Internets. Each Regional Internet will be equipped with their own blockchain, validators and liquidity providers as well as local digital experiences in order to remain independent from the rest of the world. In that sense, whatever would happen to the Internet infrastructure outside of the borders of that region would not affect local connectivity and digital economies. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, Regional Internets will be interconnected by the ThreeFold Hub on a global level to create the Internet of Internets. This model is infinitely scalable. Instead of relying on one global network and blockchain, ThreeFold will allow for many independent and interoperable Internet infrastructures that support local communities with a platform to build their own blockchain, DeFi, metaverse, IoT, eCommerce solutions, and much more. Each layer has its own distinct purpose and enables seamless ecosystem-wide interactions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;paradise_hills&#x2F;&quot;&gt;the Paradise Hills partnership&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as the first proof of concept for Community Clouds and our team working with governments in multiple countries, we’re following the glocal approach of applying the global Internet of Internets concept locally with regional context. With our growing community and ecosystem supporting us, and building new relationships, we’re well set to turn the Internet of Internets into reality in the upcoming years.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The phase of expansion will probably never end. ThreeFold is infinitely scalable, and there are many reasons to continue growing the ThreeFold Grid as it is best positioned to service the emerging demand for edge computing and sovereign Internet infrastructure for decades to come.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-the-phase-of-web-4&quot;&gt;3 The Phase of Web 4&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In parallel with the expansion phase, the rollout of the Web 4 phase is expected to kick off later this year to re-imagine business, governance, finance, education and more in order to provide better alternatives for people, enterprises and governments. Essentially, the Internet of Internets is laying the foundational infrastructure, and Web 4 technology will open a world of new possibilities around peer-to-peer and self-sovereign systems.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Web 4 phase will empower people to become 100% self-sovereign with a range of decentralized alternatives to Facebook, WhatsApp, YouTube, Chrome, Zoom and much more.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A multitude of valuable and meaningful experiences are being built by the ThreeFold ecosystem and partners to empower people with equal chances to learn, create, and thrive in a decentralized digital economy – what we like to call an abundance-based future for humanity.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key to all of this is ThreeFold’s open-source Digital Twin technology. It provides a unique digital identity that can serve as the key to an open, self-sovereign and complete digital future. The Digital Twin technology allows ThreeFold to flip the current centralized client-server model upside down, empowering people to become the masters of their own destiny. No more data being collected by servers and sold to third-parties – you become the center of your digital life. There will be more on Digital Twin and its potential to change everything coming very soon.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with strategic partnerships being formed across the four corners of the globe, the Web 4 phase will support the ThreeFold Foundation’s vision of providing access to a better Internet paradigm to a billion people by 2030.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-the-phase-of-velocity&quot;&gt;4 The Phase of Velocity&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rise of the Internet of Internets and the build-up of powerful experiences on Web 4 technology will bring the ecosystem to its fourth phase – Velocity. At that moment in time, it will be all about utilization, economic growth and the acceleration of our collective vision.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tokens&#x2F;threefold__tokenomics&quot;&gt;ThreeFold tokenomics&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; have been designed to support a decentralized Internet economy that incentivizes participants to host nodes, validate the blockchain and build applications on the ThreeFold Grid. The moment utilization kicks in at a large scale on Web 4, the ThreeFold Ecosystem will be ready to reach millions – and eventually, billions – of users through powerful digital experiences that provide a better alternative than today’s paradigm. As of today, 35% of ThreeFold Token transactions under Proof of Utilization are burned to create a deflationary economy. This will create additional &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tokens&#x2F;threefold__grid_valuation&quot;&gt;value&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for the token ecosystem as it will reduce the circulating supply in relation to the increasing demand for ThreeFold’s infrastructure. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put, the fourth phase will drive significant utilization of the ThreeFold Token and support in positioning it as the Bitcoin for Internet capacity. It will open up a decentralized Internet economy full of opportunities, empowerment and meaningful experiences for people all around the world. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;bringing-abundance-opportunity-to-the-world&quot;&gt;Bringing Abundance &amp;amp; Opportunity to the World&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“A dream you dream alone is only a dream. A dream you dream together is reality.” – John Lennon&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve reached a pivotal moment in the evolution of ThreeFold to support our world in solving some of its greatest challenges. A complete and resilient Internet infrastructure owned by local communities is an essential way to build a circular and participatory economy. Considering that the Internet is the second largest and fastest growing economy in the world, the Internet of Internets represents a foundation for a decentralized and abundant world. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;internet_of_internets&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Internet of Internets&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; model supports ThreeFold in achieving its vision of providing Internet access to more than a billion people worldwide. And we believe that if we work together, we can connect all of humanity responsibly. Driven by our planet-first, people-first philosophy, the ThreeFold movement is shaping the world we want to live in and laying the foundation for an open, inclusive and abundance-based future.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current phase of expansion is vital to turn our vision into reality and to fulfill our mission. Let’s build this world of opportunity and abundance together.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;Join&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; the ThreeFold movement now&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;what_is_farming&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Be&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; the Internet&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Help us &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;realizing_the_promise&#x2F;&quot;&gt;realize our vision&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for a better future&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Welcome to the Internet of Internets</title>
		<published>2022-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/05/post-7/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/05/post-7/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Internet of Internets is owned by the people.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; &lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;It interconnects us all, directly, without any intermediaries.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; &lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;We store our data in full sovereignty and privacy.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; &lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;On top of it, we build valuable experiences, useful experiences.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; &lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Not to control. Not to polarize. Not to addict. Not to manipulate.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; &lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Rather to connect. To exchange. To share. To provide value for each other.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; &lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A circular economy, to benefit the collective and, as a result, each of us individually.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; &lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;As believers in a better world who choose to act.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet is the backbone for the Web, a global infrastructure that makes our digital experiences possible. It represents a network of billions of interconnected computers and other electronic devices, communicating with each other and carrying all of the online information and services that we use on a daily basis.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hyperscale data centers owned and operated by big tech corporations make up the “housing” of the Internet today, where all of our digital information, services, and data reside. While these data centers are mainly located in North America, Europe, and parts of Asia, no matter where you live in the world, you rely on them to go about your daily digital life.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first glance, you might not see any glaring issues here. After all, the Internet is one of humanity’s greatest achievements, and these data centers have until today made the Internet accessible to billions of people around the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, this also means that for those of us who are connected, we depend on a few large tech corporations to act as the gatekeepers of the Internet. They own 80% of the infrastructure and most of the major online platforms, thus owning and capitalizing on our data and turning us all into products. And today, 3-4 billion people still remain unconnected, as these data centers are extremely expensive to build and difficult to maintain.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current Internet paradigm is also highly unsustainable, requiring enormous amounts of energy to connect the digital world. We have no choice but to find more regenerative solutions to provide humanity with the tools and infrastructures needed to solve the world’s greatest challenges.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, here we face a paradox. Today’s Internet would not exist in its current form if it were not for the centralized model. Yet, how can we continue down a path that has serious implications for humanity and our planet, while being incapable of scaling with emerging demand? Is there another viable solution?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It now exists. Welcome to the Internet of Internets.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;it-starts-locally-and-ends-globally&quot;&gt;It starts locally, and ends globally&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Internet of Internets is owned by the people.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; &lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;It interconnects us all, directly, without any intermediaries.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; &lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;We store our data in full sovereignty and privacy.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until today, people have been relegated to Internet “users,” or “clients” in a client-server model – either way, cogs in a big machine (the Internet) that ultimately benefits the few (big tech). But what if we reversed that model? We believe there should not be just one Internet, owned and operated by the few, rather a network of thousands of interconnected Internets, owned by and benefiting local communities.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basis of this new model, community or neighborhood clouds. Essentially acting as a community-owned, decentralized alternative to building data centers, neighborhood clouds provide high-bandwidth capabilities for regional Internets. With high-quality hardware installations and optimized networking infrastructure, neighborhood clouds provide more efficiency and interoperability than any traditional data center setup.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Local enterprises and developers can now customize and scale their solutions in ways never before possible. And people living in and around these community clouds can utilize the capacity as they wish, all while taking full control of their own data and interconnecting without intermediaries. This allows for a completely decentralized and localized Internet by the people, for the people. The foundation of the Internet of Internets.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Community clouds in proximity connect directly with each other to form a network, what we call a regional Internet. These regional Internets have their own blockchains and can operate 100% independent from other regional Internets. A regional Internet starts with 99 founding fathers and mothers who deploy blockchain nodes, with integrated support for DeFi. Each regional Internet has its own ThreeFold Token, and differences in farming and cultivation models are possible depending on the decisions of the regional Internet’s DAO. Further, each regional Internet has its own DeFi pool to allow frictionless exchange between TFT and the regional TFT.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ThreeFold Hub interconnects the Regional Internets to form  the Internet of Internets. Secured by 100 L2 Validators, this is the home of the TFT and the base governance layer for ThreeFold. Here you can see a model which starts locally and scales forever. Each layer has a distinct purpose and allows the ecosystem to interact. And while being hierarchical, it’s still 100% peer-to-peer and decentralized. An Internet of Internets, by the people, for the people – safe, sovereign, and sustainable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-world-of-endless-possibilities-lives-on-top&quot;&gt;A world of endless possibilities lives on top&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;On top of it, we build valuable experiences, useful experiences.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; &lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Not to control. Not to polarize. Not to addict. Not to manipulate.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; &lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Rather to connect. To exchange. To share. To provide value for each other.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet of Internets empowers people to build their own Internet infrastructure. Along with building community-owned Internets, our ecosystem is reimagining education, business, governance and finance for a fairer, more inclusive and regenerative future. The Internet of Internets is opening up a new world of possibilities, and we’re just getting started.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet of Internets provides a regenerative, safe and sovereign Internet infrastructure layer. It offers a secure, private, reliable and high-performing Internet experience. Moreover, it will include a set of experiences, solutions and knowledge that enable all people to equally learn, create, exchange, and thrive online.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the Internet of Internets, we’re laying the foundation for a world built on abundance, rather than scarcity.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-foundation-for-a-better-digital-world&quot;&gt;The foundation for a better (digital) world&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A circular economy, to benefit the collective and, as a result, each of us individually.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; &lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;As believers in a better world who choose to act.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We strongly believe in the ThreeFold Law which states that any good you do will return to you threefold in this lifetime. By making our technology actionable, we energize a collective approach towards a single mission – empowering humanity while regenerating our planet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet of Internets provides a much-needed alternative to big tech that can bring the Internet to even the most remote places in the world in an ethical, sustainable and secure way. It starts locally and ends globally.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet of Internets is based on an equality- and abundance-based paradigm to benefit and provide fair value exchange for the collective and each of us individually. We are driven by a planet-first, people-first philosophy that shapes the future we want to live in. Without our planet, we have nothing. And we believe people need a better system. One they can depend on. One that allows everyone to provide economic flow. One that gives them the opportunity to thrive. One that is able to empower local communities all over the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together, we’re building our own future through the Internet of Internets – decentralized, open, inclusive, regenerative, and resilient.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join the ThreeFold &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;movement&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; today and drive a new Internet era.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn how to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;what_is_farming&#x2F;&quot;&gt;be the Internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Help us &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;connecting_the_dots&#x2F;&quot;&gt;connect the dots&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In the coming weeks, we’ll be diving deeper into the Internet of Internets model, to share more about the different layers, how they come together, and how you can get involved.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Weekly! May 24th, 2022 (Vol 19)</title>
		<published>2022-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/05/post-8/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/05/post-8/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;community-updates&quot;&gt;Community Updates:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the UAE Tech Podcast, ThreeFold &lt;strong&gt;co-founder Weynand Kuijpers&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; explains how Threefold works in simple terms and why an Internet by the people for the people is so important. Tune in &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.albawaba.com&#x2F;business&#x2F;uae-tech-podcast-threefold-layer-zero-and-peoples-internet-1477554&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;medium.com&#x2F;coinmonks&#x2F;a-farmers-journey-through-yielding-defi-nodes-and-expanding-the-grid-with-threefold-a70a3e3b98ea&quot;&gt;this conversation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; between Kyle Ellicott and Scott Yeager a read. The two cover a lot of topics – from Scott’s &lt;strong&gt;experience as a DIY farmer&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; and his &lt;strong&gt;journey into ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; to advice for fellow farmers.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some of the team and members of the ThreeFold ecosystem finished two weeks of gatherings on the Nile to educate and evangelize. With &lt;strong&gt;new advocates for the ThreeFold movement&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; (e.g. farmers, investors) by our side, we’ll continue to &lt;strong&gt;build a better future&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; through the Internet of Internets.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We just launched our &lt;strong&gt;new ThreeFold Podcast&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. Listen to the first four episodes &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;anchor.fm&#x2F;threefoldpodcast&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you’re a community member interested in &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;looking-for-farmer-stories-to-share-with-the-world&#x2F;2398?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;sharing your story&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;looking-for-people-to-feature-in-threefold-content-its-super-simple&#x2F;2636&#x2F;3&quot;&gt;being featured&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in ThreeFold content, please reach out.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Registered to become a validator?&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; Follow the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;the-threefold-validators-verification-process&#x2F;2276&quot;&gt;verification process&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; asap to secure your spot.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;technology-developments&quot;&gt;Technology Developments:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Curious about what the team has been up to in May? Check out the highlights shared in &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-product-updates-tfgrid-v3-a-6-plan-may-2022&#x2F;2808?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;this update&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on &lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold Grid V3.0.0 Alpha-6&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;threefold-grid&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To learn how to verify your 3Nodes’ payouts on Stellar Blockchain, read &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;how-to-verify-your-3nodes-payments&#x2F;2864?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;this post&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you ordered a Titan but have not yet received it, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;creating-your-v3-farm-required-for-open-unshipped-orders&#x2F;2144&quot;&gt;please make sure you have created your V3 farm&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; to ensure quick delivery. Global Titan shipping is ongoing in all regions! &lt;em&gt;Our support team is available via threefold.io or on the ThreeFold Connect app with any questions.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And if you’re an existing farmer, we urge you to &lt;strong&gt;migrate 3Nodes to V3 asap&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. It just takes a few steps, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;farming-migration-grid-v2-v3&#x2F;2143?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;the migration process&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is quite simple and fast.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until next week, ThreeFolders!  🙌 &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can find the previous editions on &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&quot;&gt;our blog&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. For older editions of ThreeFold Weekly (Vol 1-11), go to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;c&#x2F;ecosystem-developments&#x2F;41&quot;&gt;our forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Weekly! May 17th, 2022 (Vol 18)</title>
		<published>2022-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/05/post-6/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/05/post-6/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;community-updates&quot;&gt;Community updates:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some of the team, investors, partners, and other contributors (new and old) are gathering on the Nile to help &lt;strong&gt;take ThreeFold to the next level&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. More precise developments and outcomes to be shared as soon as possible!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ThreeFold’s Sacha Obeegadoo appeared on &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;mainstaydigital.com&#x2F;verticals&#x2F;macro-visions&#x2F;macro-visions-doing-to-the-internet-what-bitcoin-did-to-money-with-sacha-obeegadoo&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Macro Visions&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; by &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.mainstaydigital.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Mainstay Digital&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for an insightful conversation on &lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold’s vision&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; and Internet infrastructure, the future of blockchain, digital sovereignty, and more.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check out the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-meme-gallery&#x2F;2811&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Meme Gallery&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, some community members are creating and sharing fun memes. Enjoy!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take a look at this cool &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;diy-3node-investment-ratio&#x2F;2834?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;investment ratio&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to compare different 3Node builds!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Registered to become a validator?&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; Don’t forget to follow the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;the-threefold-validators-verification-process&#x2F;2276&quot;&gt;verification process&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to secure your spot!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;technology-developments&quot;&gt;Technology Developments: &lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In May, the engineering team is working on upgrades, new features and functionalities for Zero-OS, TF Chain, ThreeFold Wallet, and more. Dive into the highlights of &lt;strong&gt;TF Grid V3.0.0 Alpha-6&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-product-updates-tfgrid-v3-a-6-plan-may-2022&#x2F;2808?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A small group of community members are working on a weblet to &lt;strong&gt;deploy a Hydra node&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; on the ThreeFold Grid. They’ve made incredible progress already and are proof of what a dedicated, talented community we have. Check out their work &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;grant-suggestion-deploy-a-hydra-node-on-tfgrid&#x2F;2493&#x2F;30&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;threefold-grid&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An initiative to power 3Nodes exclusively with &lt;strong&gt;renewable energy&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; is gaining momentum. Take a look at &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;distributed-farming-with-unsteady-renewable-energy&#x2F;2151?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;this post&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to learn more!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please &lt;strong&gt;migrate your 3Nodes to V3 asap&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. Simply follow the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;farming-migration-grid-v2-v3&#x2F;2143?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;migration process&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you ordered a Titan, please fill in your &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;creating-your-v3-farm-required-for-open-unshipped-orders&#x2F;2144&quot;&gt;information&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; for your 3Node to ensure quick delivery. Global Titan shipping continues, though Europe is still facing some delays.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;threefold-token&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Token:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After measuring the ThreeFold Token’s performance for five days, the &lt;strong&gt;InvestorsObserver&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; gave the TFT a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.investorsobserver.com&#x2F;news&#x2F;crypto-update&#x2F;threefold-tft-rises-0-28-wednesday-whats-next-for-this-bullish-rated-crypto&quot;&gt;“bullish” rating&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; for going up by 0.28% while the broader crypto market went down 9.83%. (ThreeFold believes in building strong technology that respects people and our planet and creates real value, and driving profit only as a result.)*&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you next week, ThreeFolders!  🙌 &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you’re a community member interested in &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;looking-for-farmer-stories-to-share-with-the-world&#x2F;2398?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;sharing your story&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;looking-for-people-to-feature-in-threefold-content-its-super-simple&#x2F;2636&#x2F;3&quot;&gt;being featured&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in ThreeFold content, please reach out!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can find the previous editions on &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&quot;&gt;our blog&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. For older editions of ThreeFold Weekly (Vol 1-11), go to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;c&#x2F;ecosystem-developments&#x2F;41&quot;&gt;our forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*(TFT &lt;em&gt;is not an investment instrument and this is not investment advice, everyone is free to make their own choices.)&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Weekly! May 10th, 2022 (Vol 17)</title>
		<published>2022-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/05/post-4/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/05/post-4/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;major-threefold-news&quot;&gt;Major ThreeFold News:&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The new &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;gep-grid-upgrade-to-version-alpha-5-a5&#x2F;2797?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;Grid Enhancement Proposal&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (GEP) has &lt;strong&gt;passed with 96%&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; of our community voting in favour, meaning we’ll be &lt;strong&gt;upgrading the ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; to V3 Alpha-5!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;community-updates&quot;&gt;Community updates:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We’ll be attending &lt;strong&gt;Consensus 2022 Presented by CoinDesk in June&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; as bronze sponsors to connect with attendees, share the ThreeFold story, and grow the community. Let us know if you or anyone you know will be in &lt;strong&gt;Austin&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; and take advantage of &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;events.coindesk.com&#x2F;consensus2022?promo=a7MsHxui&quot;&gt;our discount code&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some of the ThreeFold team and ecosystem are gathering on the Nile this week to discuss how to build a better future through the &lt;strong&gt;Internet of Internets and creating abundance&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We’ve seen questions and confusion in the community around &lt;strong&gt;Internet capacity and connectivity&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. Find the answers &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;internet-connectivity-capacity&#x2F;2802?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Registered to become a validator?&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; Follow the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;the-threefold-validators-verification-process&#x2F;2276&quot;&gt;verification process&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; asap to secure your spot, as we’ll share more information on activation soon!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Joined our community-led ThreeFold &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;discord.gg&#x2F;PaQtT7A72E&quot;&gt;Discord channel&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;technology-developments&quot;&gt;Technology Developments: &lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold Grid V3.0.0 Alpha-6&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; is on devnet! Check out the full update on what’s happening in May &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-product-updates-tfgrid-v3-a-6-plan-may-2022&#x2F;2808?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;threefold-grid&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;gep-for-tfgrid-pricing&#x2F;2772?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;Grid Enhancement Proposal&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on &lt;strong&gt;cloud unit pricing&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; has &lt;strong&gt;passed with 97%&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; of participants agreeing to the current pricing. Thank you all for voting!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Again, we urge you to &lt;strong&gt;migrate 3Nodes to V3 asap&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. It just takes a few steps, the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;farming-migration-grid-v2-v3&#x2F;2143?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;migration process&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is quite simple and fast.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The global shipping of Titan orders continues, though Europe is experiencing some provisioning delays. In case of any specific questions, please reach out to the support team.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until next time, ThreeFolders!  🙌 &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We’re looking for community stories and would love you to share &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;looking-for-farmer-stories-to-share-with-the-world&#x2F;2398?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;your story&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and&#x2F;or &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;looking-for-people-to-feature-in-threefold-content-its-super-simple&#x2F;2636&#x2F;3&quot;&gt;be featured&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in ThreeFold content. Thank you for reaching out!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can find the previous editions on &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&quot;&gt;our blog&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. For older editions of ThreeFold Weekly (Vol 1-11), go to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;c&#x2F;ecosystem-developments&#x2F;41&quot;&gt;our forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Vote on a New Grid Enhancement Proposal</title>
		<published>2022-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/05/post-02/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/05/post-02/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;🗳 &lt;strong&gt;Action Requested: Grid Enhancement Proposal&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi friends –&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Grid Enhancement Proposal is live on the forum as to whether we should upgrade TF Grid Mainnet to Version Alpha-5.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We look to the community to confirm this proposal. Please head to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;gep-grid-upgrade-to-version-alpha-5-a5&#x2F;2797&quot;&gt;the forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and make your vote. The poll ends in three days.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you have any questions or uncertainties, please ask away as a reply to the forum and someone from the team or community will respond.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; 🙏&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Weekly! May 5th, 2022 (Vol 16)</title>
		<published>2022-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/05/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/05/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;community-updates&quot;&gt;Community updates:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Earn a 500 TFT&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; ‘cash back’  for testing the latest version of the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;tft-fiat-gateway-beta-testing-program&#x2F;2746&quot;&gt;TFT Fiat Gateway&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; released as part of &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-product-updates-tfgrid-v3-a-5-april-2022&#x2F;2713?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid V3 A5&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Registered to become a validator?&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Follow the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;the-threefold-validators-verification-process&#x2F;2276&quot;&gt;verification process&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to secure your spot!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ThreeFold envisions a fully decentralized &lt;strong&gt;3Node marketplace&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; that connects buyers and sellers peer-to-peer. Join the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;3node-marketplace-how-do-we-further-decentralize&#x2F;2752?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;discussion&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on how to achieve that vision.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A community member will add ThreeFold branding to a coffee shop and is looking for feedback and ideas. Share your thoughts &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;if-bitcoin-is-resumed-in-one-word-as-hope-what-tft-would-be&#x2F;2725&#x2F;10&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ThreeFold Promotion Team is looking for community stories. We’d be grateful if you could share &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;looking-for-farmer-stories-to-share-with-the-world&#x2F;2398?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;your story&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and&#x2F;or &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;looking-for-people-to-feature-in-threefold-content-its-super-simple&#x2F;2636&#x2F;3&quot;&gt;be featured&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in ThreeFold content. Thank you for reaching out!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;technology-developments&quot;&gt;Technology Developments: &lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The team is currently testing the &lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold Hub&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; – the portal for validators and delegated stakers to take action and vote for the future developments of the ThreeFold ecosystem. More coming soon, so stay tuned! &lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;threefold-grid&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;gep-farming-v3-start-price-june-2022-and-v2-minting&#x2F;2745?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;Grid Enhancement Proposal&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to determine &lt;strong&gt;V3 Farming Price&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; for June 2022 and &lt;strong&gt;discontinuing V2 Minting&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; is currently open for voting. Make sure to participate!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We urge you to &lt;strong&gt;migrate 3Nodes to V3 asap&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; as described in the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;farming-migration-grid-v2-v3&#x2F;2143?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;migration process&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;gep-for-tfgrid-pricing&#x2F;2772?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;Grid Enhancement Proposal&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on &lt;strong&gt;cloud unit pricing&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; is currently open to determine utilization cost in the upcoming months.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Global Titan shipping continues while Europe is facing provisioning delays. If you ordered a Tian, please fill in your &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;creating-your-v3-farm-required-for-open-unshipped-orders&#x2F;2144&quot;&gt;information&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; for your 3Node to be set up accordingly. For specific questions about your order, please reach out to the support team.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On another note: Fake accounts are currently inviting people to participate in airdrop campaigns under the name of ThreeFold. Unfortunately, scams are very common in the crypto space. In order to protect yourself, please treat PMs with care and read this &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;medium.com&#x2F;the-capital&#x2F;cryptocurrency-airdrop-scams-how-to-spot-them-and-avoid-being-a-victim-38172ad91b2d&quot;&gt;article&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on &lt;strong&gt;how to spot scams&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you next week, ThreeFolders!  🙌 &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can find the previous editions on &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&quot;&gt;our blog&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. For older editions of ThreeFold Weekly (Vol 1-11), go to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;c&#x2F;ecosystem-developments&#x2F;41&quot;&gt;our forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Planting the Seeds: ThreeFold&#x27;s Plans to Regenerate the Planet</title>
		<published>2022-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/05/post-2/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/05/post-2/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘Being sustainable’ has become a buzzword – a claim to boost our image rather than an honest endeavour. It is hard to trust people and brands today when we fear to fall into the trap of greenwashing. However, we have no choice but to change our collective behaviour, consumption patterns and business practices if we want to combat climate change and the collapse of biodiversity.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last November, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.nature.com&#x2F;articles&#x2F;d41586-021-03431-4&quot;&gt;COP26&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; shed light on how indecisive our global institutions and governments are in the face of an unprecedented climate crisis. We now have to come to terms with the fact that carbon neutrality is no longer enough. Rising carbon emissions have been linked to an increasing amount of heat waves, droughts, floods and hurricanes globally. It is our collective responsibility to reverse the unintended consequences of our actions. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you know that warnings about the risks and harms of excessive carbon emissions date back as far as the 1960s to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.climatefiles.com&#x2F;climate-change-evidence&#x2F;presidents-report-atmospher-carbon-dioxide&#x2F;&quot;&gt;a report&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; by former US President Johnson’s Science Advisory Committee? We’ve clearly been inactive and ignorant for far too long. There’s always another crisis, another challenge to tackle. But we cannot afford to ignore climate change and biodiversity loss any longer.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;blog&#x2F;waves_of_crises.png&quot; alt=&quot;Waves of Crises&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need to tackle the climate crisis with the same urgency, force and determination we do with other crises. And we finally need to face the reality and severity of the climate crisis! After all, Greta Thunberg is right: “Nature does not bargain and you cannot compromise with the laws of physics.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The time has come for us to put our planet first. It is our duty to regenerate our planet and to support the right practices and organizations aligned with our vision of tomorrow. Now’s the time for regenerative action.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-save-our-planet&quot;&gt;How to save our planet&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The greatest threat to our planet is the belief that someone else will save it.” – Robert Swan&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By taking action and making the right choices for our planet and humanity, we can prevent the truly &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.technologyreview.com&#x2F;2021&#x2F;12&#x2F;23&#x2F;1042973&#x2F;climate-change-action-progress-clean-energy&#x2F;&quot;&gt;severe levels of global warming&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and restore the health of our planet. Once emitted, carbon dioxide can persist in the atmosphere for several hundreds, possibly thousands, of years. So, it all starts with reducing global emissions to the lowest level possible. In addition to that, we’ll need to compensate for those emissions that cannot be avoided as well as for all of the carbon and other greenhouse gases we’ve emitted in the past.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As most technological solutions for carbon removal remain expensive and early stage, nature-based solutions are the way forward. And trees, as the world’s largest plants, are an effective way to store carbon.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what are we doing at ThreeFold? How are we contributing to restoring the health of our planet? How are we taking climate action?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;our-commitment&quot;&gt;Our commitment&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe our planet needs regenerative solutions at a large scale. Our motto is: planet first, people second, profit as a result. Without a healthy planet, humanity can’t survive and no economy can exist.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;threefold__tfgrid_home&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is already much more &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;for_our_planet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;energy efficient&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; than the traditional Internet, there will always be energy consumption and emissions that cannot be avoided – and thus have to be compensated for. We’re not just going for the carbon neutrality of the ThreeFold Grid but for carbon negativity (or as we prefer to call it, planet positivity), i.e. offsetting its emissions three times through planting and protecting trees.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we decided to empower our community to take part in our regeneration efforts in a low-threshold way. ThreeFold Farmers will automatically compensate for their 3Nodes’ carbon footprint three times, and everybody will be able to use the ThreeFold Grid’s regenerative Internet capacity while simultaneously supporting impact initiatives.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we shared in our Planet-Positive Farming Series, we’re setting the plan for a planet-positive Internet by implementing a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-on-track-to-be-planet-positive&#x2F;2097?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;Voluntary Carbon Credits&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (VCC) system and supporting &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;supporting-initiatives-to-regenerate-the-planet&#x2F;2110?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;planet-positive initiatives&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; with our trusted partners from &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;driving-regeneration-with-tag&#x2F;2120?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;Take Action Global&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (TAG). &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;driving-regeneration-with-take-action-global&quot;&gt;Driving regeneration with Take Action Global&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re aiming to realize the initial promise of the Internet while also regenerating the planet. Our decentralized Internet infrastructure is already highly &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;internet_energy_consumption&#x2F;&quot;&gt;energy efficient&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; – we’re using about 10 times less energy than any comparable alternative. In December 2021, we &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.prnewswire.com&#x2F;news-releases&#x2F;threefold-and-take-action-global-partner-to-bring-internet-access-to-1-billion-people-across-the-globe-301446693.html&quot;&gt;announced&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; our commitment to achieve a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;c&#x2F;ecosystem-developments&#x2F;sustainability&#x2F;90&quot;&gt;carbon double win&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for the ThreeFold Grid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together with &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;partners&#x2F;take_action_global&#x2F;&quot;&gt;TAG&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; – experts on climate action and education who were &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;threefold_io&#x2F;status&#x2F;1493980240275812352?s=20&amp;amp;t=uW8aclYr82-xqQkEsCeGWw&quot;&gt;acknowledged&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for their incredible work by the Anthem Awards – we kicked off a pilot program for tree planting. After measuring the carbon footprint of the Grid and individual &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;farm&quot;&gt;3Nodes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, we knew what it would take to go beyond climate neutrality and fulfill our planet-positive commitment.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With our tree planting initiatives in Sierra Leone, Malawi and Cambodia, we’re planting enough trees in 2022 to lay the foundation for achieving and sustaining a carbon double win for our Internet infrastructure. Already, students and teachers in the three countries have planted more than 5,300 trees. Find out more about the pilot program &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;driving-regeneration-with-tag&#x2F;2120?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and head to the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;earthproject.org&#x2F;treeplanting&quot;&gt;EarthProject&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; page for the tree-planting details and how you yourself can get involved.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;blog&#x2F;tree_planting_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tree Planting 1&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;blog&#x2F;tree_planting_2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tree Planting 2&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we’ve laid the foundation for the ThreeFold Grid’s carbon double win, we will continue to produce Voluntary Carbon Credits to finance further impact initiatives, such as fostering climate education and renewable energy grid developments to enhance the life of communities.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-regenerative-internet-for-the-planet-and-the-people&quot;&gt;A regenerative Internet for the planet and the people&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all need to take responsibility and to pull our own weight. But we’re in this together. And together, this will happen. After kicking off our &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;driving-regeneration-with-tag&#x2F;2120?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;pilot program&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; a month ahead of schedule, we’re well set to achieve the carbon double win for the ThreeFold Grid – driving the regeneration of our planet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are pioneering the creation of an &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;internet_energy_consumption&#x2F;&quot;&gt;energy-efficient&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and regenerative Internet built and owned by the people. The ThreeFold ecosystem consists of like-minded individuals and partners that share our values and support us in our mission. United in our shared beliefs in open source, peer-to-peer, equality and inclusion, we come together to build a better Internet. And we’re being acknowledged for our work – we’re &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;evenements.optionfinance.fr&#x2F;les-debats-finance-impact-rse&#x2F;content&#x2F;candidats-sia&quot;&gt;nominated&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for the Sustainable Investment in Action &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;sustainableinvestmentinaction.com&#x2F;awards-conferences-2022&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Awards&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in the category “Basic Needs”.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re making it easy for everyone to join us – all you have to do is connect a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;farm&quot;&gt;3Node&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to the ThreeFold Grid and you’ll effortlessly regenerate the earth through providing Internet capacity – a process we call ‘farming’ because it’s a greener, purposeful &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;farming_a_greener_alternative_to_crypto_mining&#x2F;&quot;&gt;alternative&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to crypto mining.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you ready to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;join us&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in our mission?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And don’t forget:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“What we do today will determine what the world looks like tomorrow.” – Marie von Ebner-Eschenbach&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;P.S.: If you have ideas or suggestions for further planet-positive initiatives or potential partnerships, let us know on our &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;c&#x2F;ecosystem-developments&#x2F;sustainability&#x2F;90&quot;&gt;forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Weekly! April 26th, 2022 (Vol 15)</title>
		<published>2022-04-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-04-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/04/post-6/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/04/post-6/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;major-threefold-news&quot;&gt;Major ThreeFold News:&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We officially released &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-product-updates-tfgrid-v3-a-5-april-2022&#x2F;2713?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid V3.0.0 Alpha-5&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;! There are various upgrades, improvements and fixes to different ThreeFold Grid components like the &lt;strong&gt;TFT shop, Zero-OS, the Playground&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; and more.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;community-updates&quot;&gt;Community updates:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watch the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-april-19-2022-community-call-recording-presentation&#x2F;2714&#x2F;2?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;recording&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of the April 19th &lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold Community Call&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;! We covered topics including ThreeFold’s strategic goals, the Paradise Hills model, the latest ThreeFold Grid release, what’s coming soon, and token activities.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only &lt;strong&gt;7 &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;procedure-to-register-your-l2-validator-node&#x2F;1864&quot;&gt;L2&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; validator spots remain&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. As for L0 validator applicants, please follow the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;the-threefold-validators-verification-process&#x2F;2276&quot;&gt;verification process&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to secure your spot!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have you joined our community-led ThreeFold &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;discord.gg&#x2F;PaQtT7A72E&quot;&gt;Discord channel&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; yet?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We have a few new videos up on YouTube! Be sure to subscribe to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;c&#x2F;ThreeFoldFoundation&#x2F;videos&quot;&gt;our channel&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to stay in-the-know as new content is posted.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;technology-developments&quot;&gt;Technology Developments: &lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As of ThreeFold Grid V3.0.0 Alpha-5, we are supporting the deployment of &lt;strong&gt;dedicated nodes&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the &lt;strong&gt;new TFT Shop&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; release, we’re giving users the option to &lt;strong&gt;buy TFT with fiat currency&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; via the integration of a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.mercuryo.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;mercuryo.io&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (third-party) widget.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The new feature release of &lt;strong&gt;TF Connect App&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; includes new features such as enabling users to sign documents on the app directly, and many other backend improvements.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read the full &lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold Grid V3.0.0 Alpha-5&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; update &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-product-updates-tfgrid-v3-a-5-april-2022&#x2F;2713?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;threefold-grid&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The deadline for &lt;strong&gt;V3 migration is set for the 1st of May&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, so we urge you to migrate all 3Nodes asap. The &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;farming-migration-grid-v2-v3&#x2F;2143?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;migration process&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is quite simple and fast.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There has been a discussion about farming rewards V2 vs. V3. Take a look at &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;comparison-v2-vs-v3-minting&#x2F;2122&quot;&gt;this post&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for a comparison.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The new global 3Node marketplace was launched. Check it out &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;marketplace.3node.global&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The global shipping of Titan orders continues, although there is a pause in Europe due to provisioning delays. For specific questions about your order, please reach out to the support team.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until next time, ThreeFolders!  🙌 &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you’re a community member interested in &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;looking-for-farmer-stories-to-share-with-the-world&#x2F;2398?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;sharing your story&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;looking-for-people-to-feature-in-threefold-content-its-super-simple&#x2F;2636&#x2F;3&quot;&gt;being featured&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in ThreeFold content, please reach out!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can find the previous editions on &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&quot;&gt;our blog&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. For older editions of ThreeFold Weekly (Vol 1-11), go to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;c&#x2F;ecosystem-developments&#x2F;41&quot;&gt;our forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>How to stop the Internet from Gobbling the World’s Energy</title>
		<published>2022-04-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-04-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/04/post-7/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/04/post-7/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Global carbon emissions keep rising. Climate change and the collapse of biodiversity are accelerating faster than ever before. And yet, it’s important to believe in our ability to change our behaviour if we are to secure our children’s future. It’s not about being naive or optimistic, but rather a commitment to change and to do better. Across the globe, movements are sprouting to save our planet. How does ThreeFold take part in this? How are we contributing to making the world a better place?&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;  &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once emitted, carbon can remain in our atmosphere for hundreds of years. To survive climate change, massive amounts of carbon emissions have to be offset – and fast. According to a UN report, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.technologyreview.com&#x2F;2021&#x2F;07&#x2F;08&#x2F;1027908&#x2F;carbon-removal-hype-is-a-dangerous-distraction-climate-change&#x2F;&quot;&gt;10 billion tons&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of carbon emissions will have to be removed on a yearly basis by 2050 to prevent the planet from moving past the 2 degree Celsius threshold. Allowing the climate to heat by just one more degree would have unprecedented consequences – including the sinking of islands and coastal areas, an accelerated rate of extinction (right now, estimations suggest that about &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;e360.yale.edu&#x2F;features&#x2F;global_extinction_rates_why_do_estimates_vary_so_wildly&quot;&gt;24 to 150 species go extinct&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; every day) and much more. Our complacency towards climate change proves that we’re still in denial of the chain reaction and butterfly effects of our past and present actions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearly, we’ve already crossed the threshold in the climate crisis where we had enough time for long debates on potential measures and policies. The time for those debates was in the 1960s, when a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.climatefiles.com&#x2F;climate-change-evidence&#x2F;presidents-report-atmospher-carbon-dioxide&#x2F;&quot;&gt;report&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; by former US President Johnson’s Science Advisory Committee first warned about the risks and dangers of excessive carbon emissions. “Climate change is the result of more than a century of unsustainable energy and land use, lifestyles and patterns of consumption and production,” said Jim Skea, one of the IPCC Working Group III Co-Chairs in a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.enviro.or.id&#x2F;2022&#x2F;04&#x2F;ipcc-press-release&#x2F;&quot;&gt;press release&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; published earlier this month. According to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.ipcc.ch&#x2F;report&#x2F;sixth-assessment-report-working-group-3&#x2F;&quot;&gt;a report&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; published by the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC), we can still achieve our climate goals if we significantly reduce emissions across all economic sectors. However, we urgently need to take action to limit global warming to 1.5 degrees Celsius.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now is the time to act. Now is the time for bold moves. As Skea put it: “Without immediate and deep emissions reductions across all sectors, it will be impossible.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-astonishing-carbon-footprint-of-the-internet&quot;&gt;The astonishing carbon footprint of the Internet&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While people are legitimately obsessing about the emissions caused by air travel and whether to take that plane or not – bestowing us with concepts like ‘flight shaming’ – other industries’ significant impacts almost go unnoticed. One of them is the Internet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;carbonliteracy.com&#x2F;the-carbon-cost-of-an-email&#x2F;&quot;&gt;chat messages and emails&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; you send out every day. How many times do you &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.fastcompany.com&#x2F;90171268&#x2F;internet_impact_visualized&quot;&gt;‘google’&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; things? How much time do you spend &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.carbontrust.com&#x2F;resources&#x2F;carbon-impact-of-video-streaming&quot;&gt;streaming&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; music or videos? All of your online activities add to your carbon footprint. There are a couple grams of carbon emissions attached to the energy needed to power your devices and the wireless networks you connect to. On top of that comes the significant amount of energy required to support the infrastructure of today’s Internet, namely millions of data centers and the thousands of servers in each of them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though the emissions caused by streaming one song or sending one email may seem insignificant, the accumulated use of the Internet by billions of people all over the world adds up. It actually leads to a collective carbon footprint amounting to a share of roughly &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.bbc.com&#x2F;future&#x2F;article&#x2F;20200305-why-your-internet-habits-are-not-as-clean-as-you-think&quot;&gt;3.7% of global emissions&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; caused by the Internet and its infrastructure – and these carbon emissions are estimated&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.bbc.com&#x2F;future&#x2F;article&#x2F;20200305-why-your-internet-habits-are-not-as-clean-as-you-think&quot;&gt; to double&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; within the next three years. This 3.7% share of global emissions by the Internet almost makes the global aviation industry with its estimated &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.atag.org&#x2F;facts-figures.html&quot;&gt;2.1%&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; emissions look good.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The global pandemic – while decreasing emissions in aviation due to travel bans – has already accelerated Internet consumption and the resulting footprint due to increased streaming behaviour, remote work and more. With &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.cisco.com&#x2F;c&#x2F;en&#x2F;us&#x2F;solutions&#x2F;executive-perspectives&#x2F;annual-internet-report&#x2F;index.html&quot;&gt;1 billion people&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.statista.com&#x2F;statistics&#x2F;471264&#x2F;iot-number-of-connected-devices-worldwide&#x2F;#:%7E:text=Internet%20of%20Things%20%2D%20number%20of%20connected%20devices%20worldwide%202015%2D2025&amp;amp;text=By%202025%2C%20forecasts%20suggest%20that,IoT%20installed%20base%20in%202019.&quot;&gt;75 billion IoT devices&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; expected to join the Internet economy by 2025, a more sustainable infrastructure than power-hungry data centers is urgently needed to meet the future growth of the Internet in an ethical and sustainable way.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;data-centers-are-power-hungry&quot;&gt;Data Centers are power hungry&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big tech corporations like Amazon, for example, have massive carbon footprints with their corporate facilities, power-hungry data centers, complex operations and more. One larger data center alone consumes up to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.datacenterdynamics.com&#x2F;en&#x2F;opinions&#x2F;from-the-sensor-to-the-data-center&#x2F;&quot;&gt;120 MW&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; – and there are about 7.2 million data centers worldwide, according to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.statista.com&#x2F;statistics&#x2F;500458&#x2F;worldwide-datacenter-and-it-sites&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Statista&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Moreover, a data center’s energy consumption accounts for &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.datacenterdynamics.com&#x2F;en&#x2F;opinions&#x2F;from-the-sensor-to-the-data-center&#x2F;&quot;&gt;about 40%&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of its operating costs. In 2020, Amazon emitted more than &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;sustainability.aboutamazon.com&#x2F;environment&#x2F;sustainable-operations&#x2F;carbon-footprint&quot;&gt;60 million metric tons&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of carbon dioxide up from about 51 million in 2019. Others like Google try to downplay their energy consumption by switching to renewable energy. While renewable energy is an improvement for sure, it does not change the fact that Google’s energy consumption could &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.forbes.com&#x2F;sites&#x2F;robertbryce&#x2F;2020&#x2F;10&#x2F;21&#x2F;googles-dominance-is-fueled-by-zambia-size-amounts-of-electricity&#x2F;&quot;&gt;power entire countries&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is that really a desirable way for us to use the still scarce supply of renewable energy? Shouldn’t we rather focus on the root problem and on becoming more energy efficient in the first place?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step should be to reduce the Internet’s energy consumption and overall carbon footprint. But even then: reducing that energy consumption and transitioning to clean energy will only get us so far – particularly when considering that there simply is not enough clean energy to achieve a complete transition. Those emissions that cannot be cut have to be compensated for. A holistic solution to today’s Internet’s inefficiencies and emissions is needed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;an-energy-efficient-and-regenerative-internet&quot;&gt;An energy-efficient and regenerative Internet&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In December 2021, ThreeFold &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.prnewswire.com&#x2F;news-releases&#x2F;threefold-and-take-action-global-partner-to-bring-internet-access-to-1-billion-people-across-the-globe-301446693.html&quot;&gt;announced&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; its commitment to achieve a carbon double win for its open-source peer-to-peer Internet infrastructure, the ThreeFold Grid. The ThreeFold Grid is able to scale anywhere electricity and network exist, using about 10 times less energy than any comparable alternative while being more affordable as well. By starting from scratch at the operating system level, ThreeFold was able to build an Internet infrastructure that is highly &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;for_our_planet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;energy efficient&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. This infrastructure is already made up of thousands of 3Nodes that are spread across 75 countries and counting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together with &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;driving-regeneration-with-tag&#x2F;2120?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;Take Action Global&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (TAG), an expert on climate education and action, ThreeFold aims to make the ThreeFold Grid planet-positive by removing its carbon emissions from the atmosphere three times in the form of &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-on-track-to-be-planet-positive&#x2F;2097?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;Voluntary Carbon Credits&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. While the pilot for this initiative was announced to start in January 2022, ThreeFold and TAG were so eager to take action against climate change, they kicked-off the pilot one month early in December 2021. It is the first step in ThreeFold’s plan to support the use of ‘nature-based climate solutions’ like tree planting to absorb twice more carbon than the ThreeFold Grid emits by 2022. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-silver-lining-on-the-horizon&quot;&gt;A silver lining on the horizon&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every industry and organization has to pull their own weight. There is no way around it. Far-reaching actions and transformations are needed across industries to limit global warming to bearable levels. “The decisions we make now can secure a liveable future. We have the tools and know-how required to limit warming,” said Hoesung Lee, IPCC Chair, in an April 2022 &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.enviro.or.id&#x2F;2022&#x2F;04&#x2F;ipcc-press-release&#x2F;&quot;&gt;press release&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Together with TAG, ThreeFold leads the way by working on energy-efficient and sustainable solutions for the Internet. The new IPCC report gives us a reason to be optimistic about our future and have hope for the regeneration of our planet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really, all it takes right now is widespread support and adoption of more energy-efficient, sustainable alternatives across industries like ThreeFold for the Internet – something that is up to each and every one of us. Let us all take action for a fairer, more sustainable world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join the global ThreeFold &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;movement&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;farming&#x2F;threefold__farming_intro&quot;&gt;Start farming&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; today and support a greener Internet while regenerating the planet.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Farming – A Greener Alternative to Crypto Mining</title>
		<published>2022-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/04/post-5/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/04/post-5/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cointelegraph.com&#x2F;bitcoin-for-beginners&#x2F;the-history-of-bitcoin-when-did-bitcoin-start&quot;&gt;October 2008&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, when the financial crisis was in full swing, an anonymous individual or group under the pseudonym ‘Satoshi Nakamoto’ published a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;bitcoin.org&#x2F;bitcoin.pdf&quot;&gt;white paper&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on Bitcoin, a “peer-to-peer electronic cash system” that ended up disrupting the financial system and sparked the creation of an entirely new industry: crypto mining.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering that many people view Bitcoin as a commodity, similar to gold, it only makes sense that the process of generating new Bitcoins would become referred to as ‘mining’. In a way, mining is an incentive mechanism to reach consensus in the verification of transactions in a decentralized network. While crypto mining originated from Bitcoin, the system has spread quite widely across the blockchain space.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than a decade later, Bitcoin keeps intriguing individuals and organizations all around the world, and has become &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cointelegraph.com&#x2F;news&#x2F;is-bitcoin-a-waste-of-energy-pros-and-cons-about-bitcoin-mining&quot;&gt;one of the most popular&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; financial assets. Nevertheless, criticism and doubts around Bitcoin and crypto mining remain. The most popular cryptocurrency is also frequently brought to the spotlight around its potential affiliations to money laundering, financing of terrorism and cybercrime, as well as the energy the mining process of its cryptocurrency consumes. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cbeci.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Electricity Consumption Index&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of the University of Cambridge, the annual consumption of Bitcoin is currently estimated to amount to nearly 140 TWh. The United Arab Emirates (113 TWh) or the Netherlands (109 TWh) had a lower annual energy consumption than Bitcoin &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;blog.zorinaq.com&#x2F;bitcoin-electricity-consumption&#x2F;&quot;&gt;in 2020&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Moreover, news outlets like &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.theguardian.com&#x2F;technology&#x2F;2017&#x2F;nov&#x2F;27&#x2F;bitcoin-mining-consumes-electricity-ireland&quot;&gt;The Guardian&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.bbc.com&#x2F;news&#x2F;technology-56012952&quot;&gt;BBC News&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; reported on Bitcoin exceeding the energy consumption of further countries, including Ireland and Argentina. Within the last year, headlines like “&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.nytimes.com&#x2F;interactive&#x2F;2021&#x2F;09&#x2F;03&#x2F;climate&#x2F;bitcoin-carbon-footprint-electricity.html&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Uses More Electricity Than Many Countries&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;” in the New York Times or “&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.ft.com&#x2F;content&#x2F;1aecb2db-8f61-427c-a413-3b929291c8ac&quot;&gt;Bitcoin’s growing energy problem: ‘It’s a dirty currency’&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;” in the Financial Times were in no short supply.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the most popular quotes on the topic is Bill Gates’ statement in the New York Times in &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.nytimes.com&#x2F;2021&#x2F;03&#x2F;09&#x2F;business&#x2F;dealbook&#x2F;bill-gates-bitcoin.html&quot;&gt;March 2021&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;: “Bitcoin uses more electricity per transaction than any other method known to mankind, and so it’s not a great climate thing.” Not that this statement or the awareness of the issue would have prevented Microsoft from launching &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;identity.foundation&#x2F;ion&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ION&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, a decentralized digital identity system, to run on the Bitcoin network.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;but-why-is-bitcoin-mining-so-energy-intensive-anyways&quot;&gt;But why is Bitcoin mining so energy intensive anyways?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the heart of Bitcoin’s energy-intensive model is the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.coindesk.com&#x2F;learn&#x2F;2020&#x2F;12&#x2F;16&#x2F;what-is-proof-of-work&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Proof-of-Work (PoW)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; protocol. &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.investopedia.com&#x2F;tech&#x2F;how-does-bitcoin-mining-work&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Bitcoin mining&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, the process of creating new Bitcoins using PoW, requires solving complex cryptographic equations to receive the rewards associated with the creation of the next block in the blockchain. PoW is carried out by computers, known as ‘miners’. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the early days, a simple computer was enough to mine Bitcoin. However, the difficulty of the mining algorithm increased as the network grew larger and more people started competing to earn the next block’s rewards. On average, it takes &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;bitcoin.org&#x2F;bitcoin.pdf&quot;&gt;about 10 minutes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to solve such an equation and to mine a new block. Today, Bitcoin mining has become a costly and elaborate endeavour – accessible only to large investors that can support powerful supercomputers – at the cost of &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.technologyreview.com&#x2F;2022&#x2F;04&#x2F;18&#x2F;1049331&#x2F;bitcoin-cryptocurrency-cryptomining-new-york&#x2F;&quot;&gt;local communities&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s only sensible that miners are beefing up their machines to increase their chances. In fact, the sector became so competitive that &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.linkedin.com&#x2F;pulse&#x2F;sustainable-crypto-mining-becoming-reality-nameet-potnis&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Intel created&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; dedicated chips and specialized manufacturers for mining servers like &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.bitmain.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Bitmain&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; were established. With up to 32,500 Watts indicated by manufacturers, the power consumption of such devices averages 28,470 kWh per year if operated continuously. In comparison, the annual consumption of a freezer is estimated between 200 and 500 kWh per year. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, operating a single mining machine is hardly the way to succeed. The biggest Bitcoin miners have fleets of hundreds of machines in so-called ‘mining farms’, carefully maintained and constantly ventilated, to prevent them from overheating. Some of the largest, like &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.rockdalemdd.org&#x2F;news&#x2F;whinstone-us-breaks-ground-build-world%E2%80%99s-largest-bitcoin-mining-facility-rockdale-texas&quot;&gt;Northern Data&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in Texas, have an energy consumption of 1 GWh per year, the equivalent of the energy produced by about &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.energy.gov&#x2F;eere&#x2F;articles&#x2F;how-much-power-1-gigawatt&quot;&gt;3.1 million&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; photovoltaic (solar) panels. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In critical times where humanity is facing serious global challenges in relation to climate change and the collapse of biodiversity, we must rethink the basics of how to decentralize our world. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;are-there-more-energy-conscious-solutions&quot;&gt;Are there more energy-conscious solutions?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.coindesk.com&#x2F;learn&#x2F;2020&#x2F;12&#x2F;30&#x2F;what-is-proof-of-stake&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Proof-of-Stake (PoS)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; mechanisms have proven to be &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.investopedia.com&#x2F;tech&#x2F;how-does-bitcoin-mining-work&#x2F;#toc-downsides-of-mining&quot;&gt;less energy intensive&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; than PoW. With PoS, miners lock up (‘stake’) a blockchain’s cryptocurrency on escrow accounts to be granted mining rights. In exchange for this participation, miners receive an interest proportional to their stake as reward. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PoS-based blockchains are faster and much more energy efficient than PoW-based blockchains. However, the implementation of a PoS protocol poses its own challenges. For example, it is known for incentivizing hoarding, rather than utilization, and driving centralization. The mining industry is attempting to shift perceptions and move away from its climate-polluting, power-hungry image by powering large mining activities with renewable energies or by offsetting their emissions with carbon credits.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this might sound great at first, it does not resolve the underlying issue of incredibly high energy consumption. Should we really allocate relatively scarce renewable energy resources to such energy-intensive endeavours? Or should we rather look for more efficient alternatives – considering we have all the technology to create more energy-efficient models from scratch – and then support what energy consumption remains with renewable energy? &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;threefold-farming-offers-a-greener-paradigm&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Farming offers a greener paradigm&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;what_is_farming&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Farming&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a decentralized, energy-efficient and meaningful alternative to mining. &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;the-potential-of-the-threefold-token-tft&#x2F;1796&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Tokens&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (TFT) are minted whenever new Internet capacity in terms of compute, storage or network is added to the ThreeFold Grid by connecting computers, known as 3Nodes. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By contributing decentralized Internet capacity to the ThreeFold Grid, independent people and organizations called ‘farmers’ earn TFT in return – based on a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;farming&#x2F;threefold__proof_of_capacity?id=why-proof-of-capacity&quot;&gt;Proof-of-Capacity&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;  (PoC) algorithm. PoC is autonomously carried out by ThreeFold’s &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;for_our_planet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;extremely efficient&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; operating system. First, Zero-OS scans the computer’s resources. Then the operating system registers the computing power and Internet storage on the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;tf_chain&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Blockchain&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, making the resources available to the entire network – thereby creating a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;coincheckup.com&#x2F;blog&#x2F;threefold-is-the-decentralized-web-the-future-of-the-internet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;decentralized model&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for Internet capacity provisioning. The &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.docsend.com&#x2F;view&#x2F;wsru3f9tmeaq62wq&quot;&gt;energy consumption&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of a 3Node can vary, depending on the amount of Compute Units (CUs) and Storage Units (SUs) it holds. “The average consumption for a Titan 3Node is around 26.71 KwH per hour”, says ThreeFold’s &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;people&#x2F;alexandre_hannelas&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Alexandre Hannelas&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farming supports the realization of an open-source peer-to-peer Internet free from centralized servers and authorities. Similarly to Bitcoin, the management of transactions and the issuing of TFT is carried out collectively by the network to create a decentralized Internet economy. In a way, what &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;bitcoin_threefold&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Bitcoin did to money&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, ThreeFold does to the Internet – while using much &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;for_our_planet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;less energy&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“By using blockchain for what it’s good at and other pioneering technologies, such as peer-to-peer networking, to complement it, we built the most efficient Internet infrastructure in the world, and by far.” – Kristof de Spiegeleer.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developing sustainable solutions for our planet is essential to ThreeFold’s ethos which puts our planet and people first. A famous quote, we love and frequently refer to at ThreeFold, is Albert Einstein’s “We cannot solve our problems with the same thinking we used when we create them.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our planet needs regenerative solutions at a large scale, and ThreeFold aims to deliver on our promise providing better solutions for our planet and people through our technology. Based on the ThreeFold Grid’s average energy consumption, we’re planting trees with our partner &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;driving-regeneration-with-tag&#x2F;2120?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;Take Action Global&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to offset the Grid’s carbon emissions three times in the form of &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-on-track-to-be-planet-positive&#x2F;2097?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;Voluntary Carbon Credits&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (VCC). Our VCC system was implemented in the PoC algorithm, so every 3Node mints additional TFT to offset its own carbon emissions based on the power utilization of the individual 3Node per month. The &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-on-track-to-be-planet-positive&#x2F;2097&quot;&gt;process&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is fully automated and executed by the ThreeFold Blockchain.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold’s global community of farmers is on a mission to regenerate our planet through the planet-positive ThreeFold Farming which supports tree planting and other &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;supporting-initiatives-to-regenerate-the-planet&#x2F;2110?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;impact initiatives&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; by default. We’re on track to provide a planet-positive Internet and support our partners in their initiatives in fields like climate education, climate action and economic inclusion worldwide.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farming is about so much more than crypto mining. It’s about building a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;medium.com&#x2F;authority-magazine&#x2F;the-future-is-now-kristoff-de-spiegeleer-of-threefold-on-how-their-technological-innovation-will-7acc0e51c365&quot;&gt;better Internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and shaping the world we want to live in. Together with a community of like-minded people, we’re taking action for a better world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If not us, who? If not now, when?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join the global ThreeFold &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;movement&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;farming&#x2F;threefold__farming_intro&quot;&gt;Start farming&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; today and become a part of the new Internet while regenerating the planet.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Weekly! April 19th, 2022 (Vol 14)</title>
		<published>2022-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/04/post-4/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/04/post-4/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;major-threefold-news&quot;&gt;Major ThreeFold News:&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold was hand-picked as one of &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.startus-insights.com&#x2F;innovators-guide&#x2F;web3-startups&#x2F;&quot;&gt;5 top Web 3 startups&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; by StartUs Insights – standing out from about 300 startups analyzed for this report!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;community-updates&quot;&gt;Community updates:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are any of you in Amsterdam this week? &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;amsterdamblockchainweek.org&#x2F;events&#x2F;all-the-nachos-margaritas-threefold-decentralized-layer-0&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Join&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; the community-organized ThreeFold gathering during &lt;strong&gt;Amsterdam Blockchain Week&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Members of the ThreeFold community gathered in Miami during &lt;strong&gt;Bitcoin 2022&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; to evangelize the People’s Internet with the Blockchain space and the Americas.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weynand participated in the &lt;strong&gt;Fair Data Initiative&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; hosted by &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;partners&#x2F;solidaridad&quot;&gt;Solidaridad&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; along with about 25 agricultural innovators, NGOs, banks and large tech companies. Read the full update &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;solidaridad-revival&#x2F;2158&#x2F;6?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get to know &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;threefold_io&#x2F;status&#x2F;1512418985844916227?s=20&amp;amp;t=9jr1BAtpKT6zsWxW9euMGA&quot;&gt;Nelson&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;threefold_io&#x2F;status&#x2F;1513150808036061185?s=20&amp;amp;t=9jr1BAtpKT6zsWxW9euMGA&quot;&gt;Dan&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, both ThreeFold Farmers and soon-to-be Validators, a little better. Also check out &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.linkedin.com&#x2F;feed&#x2F;update&#x2F;urn:li:activity:6915127377786253312&#x2F;?actorCompanyId=13594159&quot;&gt;this unique node setup&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;Athus&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; in Brazil!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Another star Farmer &lt;strong&gt;Mik&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; (aka idrnd) and other ThreeFolders built a second part of FAQs &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;farming-faq-zero-os-v3-part-2&#x2F;2620&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We invite you to learn more about our &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;targeting-projects-communities-with-powerful-threefold-solutions&#x2F;2646&quot;&gt;outreach strategy&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and to share how you can support ThreeFold in reaching new frontiers in cyberspace.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only &lt;strong&gt;7 &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;procedure-to-register-your-l2-validator-node&#x2F;1864&quot;&gt;L2&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; validator spots remain&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. L0 validators are oversubscribed, so hurry up and follow the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;the-threefold-validators-verification-process&#x2F;2276&quot;&gt;verification process&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to secure your spot!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A community-led ThreeFold &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;discord.gg&#x2F;PaQtT7A72E&quot;&gt;Discord channel&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; was recently launched – join in!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;threefold-grid&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid: &lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A deadline has been set for the 1st of May for V3 migration&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, so make sure your 3Nodes are all migrated asap. Simply follow the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;farming-migration-grid-v2-v3&#x2F;2143?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;migration process&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Titan orders continue to be delivered, although there is a delay in Europe due to provisioning delays. In case of any specific questions, please reach out to the support team.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We shared new videos of our &lt;strong&gt;Knowledge Base series&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; explaining ThreeFold and the technology behind it. &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=AuegcGK1CSc&amp;amp;list=PLTGQlepPqwUXsvHsrm4pbQj0-DCa-Ud0c&quot;&gt;Watch&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; the latest additions on Zero-OS, TF Chain, the Planetary Network and more!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you next week, ThreeFolders!  🙌 &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you’re a community member interested in &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;looking-for-farmer-stories-to-share-with-the-world&#x2F;2398?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;sharing your story&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;looking-for-people-to-feature-in-threefold-content-its-super-simple&#x2F;2636&#x2F;3&quot;&gt;being featured&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in ThreeFold content, please reach out!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can find the previous editions on &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&quot;&gt;our blog&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. For older editions of ThreeFold Weekly (Vol 1-11), go to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;c&#x2F;ecosystem-developments&#x2F;41&quot;&gt;our forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Weekly! April 5th, 2022 (Vol 13)</title>
		<published>2022-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/04/post-2/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/04/post-2/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;major-threefold-news&quot;&gt;Major ThreeFold News:&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last week, Gulf Land Property hosted the  &lt;strong&gt;Paradise Hills Award Gala with over 160 people&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;  including home owners, contractors and supporting project developers. During the Gala, ThreeFold’s  &lt;strong&gt;Adnan Fatayerji and Weynand Kuijpers&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;  had the chance to present ThreeFold to the audience with an overwhelmingly positive response and support. Moreover, the two co-founders accepted  &lt;strong&gt;an award for ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;  as an  &lt;strong&gt;integral technology partner&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;  of Paradise Hills Development and establishing the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;news&#x2F;post&#x2F;paradise_hills&#x2F;&quot;&gt;world’s first community-driven cloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ThreeFold co-founder  &lt;strong&gt;Adnan Fatayerji&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;  joined the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;youtu.be&#x2F;wu-vf1H-zQ0&quot;&gt;BlockHash Podcast&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to share all about ThreeFold and to discuss decentralization. It’s a great interview,  &lt;strong&gt;covering all ThreeFold essentials&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; . Well done, Adnan!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;community-updates&quot;&gt;Community updates:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mik&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;  from Canada shared about his experiences as a DIY farmer and how he is  &lt;strong&gt;leading the way&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;  by providing  &lt;strong&gt;big-time support&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;  for the ThreeFold Farming community. Watch the inspiring conversation between Mik and Sam &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=IE5E1mCVdqk&amp;amp;t=2s&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;If you’re a community member interested in sharing your story in a similar format, let us know in the comments below &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;looking-for-farmer-stories-to-share-with-the-world&#x2F;2398?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;this post&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A big thank you to those who registered to become validators of the ThreeFold Grid for being vital members of our community and securing the Grid! There are only  &lt;strong&gt;8 &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;procedure-to-register-your-l2-validator-node&#x2F;1864&quot;&gt;L2&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and 1 &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;procedure-to-register-your-l0-validator-nodes&#x2F;1866&quot;&gt;L0&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; validator spots remaining&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. Take a look &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;stake_tft_become_validator&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; if you’d like to learn how to stake TFT and become a validator.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;technology-developments&quot;&gt;Technology Developments:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We’ve launched a new and improved  &lt;strong&gt;3.0 wallet in the TF Connect app&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; which includes a TF Chain wallet. Take a look at &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;tf-connect-wallet-v3&#x2F;2565&quot;&gt;this post&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to find all the details.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;threefold-grid&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid: &lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;gep-farming-start-price-april-2022&#x2F;2585?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;new Grid Enhancement Proposal&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, the Grid Council proposed the &lt;strong&gt;farming start price of 0.08 USD in April&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. Thank you all for voting, this GEP has &lt;strong&gt;passed with 89%&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; of our community voting in favour, meaning the farming start price for April will be 0.08 USD. Please remember that the minting payout for March 2022 will be executed on the 8th of April instead of the 5th of April.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have you migrated your 3Nodes from V2 to V3 yet?&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; If not, please do it asap as &lt;strong&gt;it’s our collective responsibility&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; to fully bring the ThreeFold Grid to its latest version. Also, it’s crucial for you to log in V3 farming rewards, so finish the migration process via ThreeFold Connect as explained &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;farming-migration-grid-v2-v3&#x2F;2143?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Titan 3Node orders continue to be shipped all over the world. If you have specific questions about your order, please get in touch with the support team!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until next time, ThreeFolders! 🙌 &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can find the latest edition &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;weekly_vol_12&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. For older editions of ThreeFold Weekly, go to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;c&#x2F;ecosystem-developments&#x2F;41&quot;&gt;our forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>The Internet that connects us also manipulates us. In search of a better future.</title>
		<published>2022-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/04/post-3/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/04/post-3/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Internet is one of humanity’s &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;coincodex.com&#x2F;article&#x2F;14083&#x2F;threefold-host-the-cloud-at-your-house&#x2F;&quot;&gt;greatest inventions&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. In its early days, it used to be &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;theconversation.com&#x2F;web-3-0-the-decentralised-web-promises-to-make-the-internet-free-again-113139&quot;&gt;free and decentralized&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; by nature. No single entity was able to control access to the web as it was built on the foundation of a peer-to-peer network of nodes owned by developers and researchers. Until the dot-com era. Throughout the early 2000s, large corporations took over the web. New platforms like YouTube and MySpace were launched and new infrastructure needed to be built at an extreme pace, starting the data revolution and changing the digital landscape forever. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twenty years down the line, the Internet’s architecture has become highly centralized – owned by a handful of large corporations that act as the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.newyorker.com&#x2F;magazine&#x2F;2017&#x2F;08&#x2F;28&#x2F;who-owns-the-internet&quot;&gt;gatekeepers&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of our digital world. What was once an open and free platform accessible to anyone has long since built up barriers and lost its neutrality. Users are trapped in a cyberspace that exploits their personal data and allows censorship, hate speech, disinformation and political targeting to thrive. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;going-down-the-rabbit-hole&quot;&gt;Going down the Rabbit Hole&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Wall Street Journal’s &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.wsj.com&#x2F;articles&#x2F;the-facebook-files-11631713039&quot;&gt;investigation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; “The Facebook Files” and The New York Times’ audio series “&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.nytimes.com&#x2F;2020&#x2F;04&#x2F;22&#x2F;podcasts&#x2F;rabbit-hole-prologue.html&quot;&gt;Rabbit Hole&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;” are only some of the latest examples that depict the shocking impacts of the manipulation, mental health problems, and extremism that social media algorithms are fuelling. Nevertheless, these incidents are only a glimpse into all the ways we’re being affected and influenced about the way we see the world – by the tech giants and their algorithms. Tech giants like Google and Facebook have been surrounded by a constant stream of data privacy &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.wired.com&#x2F;story&#x2F;should-big-tech-own-our-personal-data&#x2F;&quot;&gt;scandals&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as more and more whistleblowers expose their misconduct. However, there are plenty of other, hidden players using the tools and algorithms of social media platforms for their own agendas.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;filmthreat.com&#x2F;features&#x2F;4-thought-provoking-movies-on-digital-privacy-and-security&#x2F;&quot;&gt;The Great Hack and the Social Dilemma&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; are great documentaries that shed light on how the Internet as we know it became compromised. They depict how algorithms are used to mine user data, control information feeds and manipulate our digital experiences. The &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.politico.eu&#x2F;article&#x2F;cambridge-analytica-chris-wylie-brexit-trump-britain-data-protection-privacy-facebook&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Trump Election and the Brexit vote&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; were heavily influenced by private companies like &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.theguardian.com&#x2F;news&#x2F;series&#x2F;cambridge-analytica-files&quot;&gt;Cambridge Analytica&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that manipulated mass audiences through social media.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By purchasing thousands of personal data points collected by social media platforms and analyzing them, companies like Cambridge Analytica are able to not only predict but influence the behaviour of each and everyone of us. Data collection and analysis to such an extent allow these companies to craft and push perfectly targeted messages to users in a way that’s optimized to sway their opinions in favour of whatever agenda they have.  &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;can-a-neutral-and-free-internet-still-exist&quot;&gt;Can a neutral and free Internet still exist?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On 24th of March 2022, the European Parliament and Council negotiators agreed upon the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;variety.com&#x2F;2022&#x2F;digital&#x2F;global&#x2F;facebook-google-amazon-apple-digital-market-act-europe-regulation-1235214516&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Digital Markets Act&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (DMA). It seeks to give users more choice by demanding the most popular apps to open up and interoperate with smaller apps. Moreover, the act aims to ensure a fairer market competition by prohibiting certain gatekeeper practices like self-preferencing and targeted advertising. This set of new EU regulations is likely to impact the daily business of tech giants significantly once it becomes law. While the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.europarl.europa.eu&#x2F;news&#x2F;en&#x2F;press-room&#x2F;20220315IPR25504&#x2F;deal-on-digital-markets-act-ensuring-fair-competition-and-more-choice-for-users&quot;&gt;DMA&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; promises to mitigate some of the issues discussed, it is doubtful that the act will be enough to fundamentally change the current system. This is a step in the right direction, but much more needs to be done.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet has become our digital home. It’s impacting our lives in many ways by creating new opportunities, and changing how we communicate and connect. Therefore, it is crucial to restore the Internet’s neutrality to ensure a fair and equal environment. We need an Internet where we can rely on data security and privacy. An Internet where we’re empowered to truly and completely have ownership of and control of our own data. An Internet that empowers us with digital sovereignty.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet used to be a free movement of culture and the Web. It started with an open-source and peer-to-peer vision to connect people. And while Web 3.0 projects are looking to liberalize the Internet as we know it, most of them still rely on centralized Web 2.0 infrastructure to some degree. The world needs better, holistic solutions. ThreeFold is &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;realizing_the_promise&#x2F;&quot;&gt;realizing the initial vision and promise&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of the Internet as an open-source, peer-to-peer planetary mesh network of nodes owned by humanity. It’s a 100% open-source and community-driven project that builds the critical, neutral infrastructure for a decentralized world – one that is built and owned by the people. With ThreeFold, individuals and organizations are empowered to store their data and run their applications on a peer-to-peer network of nodes in a way that ensures their data will not be manipulated, hacked or lost. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Powered by a global community, ThreeFold is the world’s largest peer-to-peer Internet infrastructure with a few thousand 3Nodes connected from 74 countries and the neutral foundation for &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;medium.com&#x2F;authority-magazine&#x2F;the-future-is-now-kristoff-de-spiegeleer-of-threefold-on-how-their-technological-innovation-will-7acc0e51c365&quot;&gt;any current and future IT workload&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. ThreeFold is now on the verge of opening up a new Internet era free from censorship, user tracking and privacy breaches. And anyone can participate in ThreeFold’s model by building or buying a 3Node, and connecting Internet capacity from their home or office – creating a fully &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;coincheckup.com&#x2F;blog&#x2F;threefold-is-the-decentralized-web-the-future-of-the-internet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;decentralized Internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join the ThreeFold &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;movement&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; today and drive a new Internet era.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Break free from big tech and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;what_is_farming&#x2F;&quot;&gt;be the Internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; by setting up a 3Node at your home.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Help us &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;connecting_the_dots&#x2F;&quot;&gt;connect the dots&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Weekly! March 29th, 2022 (Vol 12)</title>
		<published>2022-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/03/post-7/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/03/post-7/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We have a new format for ThreeFold Weekly, now on our blog. If you’d like to review any of the first eleven editions, please find them on &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;c&#x2F;ecosystem-developments&#x2F;41&quot;&gt;our forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;major-threefold-news&quot;&gt;Major ThreeFold News:&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Members of the ThreeFold team attended the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;mobile.twitter.com&#x2F;threefold_io&#x2F;status&#x2F;1507009092165853185&quot;&gt;World Blockchain Summit&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; in Dubai. Over two days we exchanged with countless people and their reactions were unanimous – ThreeFold is undeniably one of the most exciting projects in the blockchain space. We’re excited to join many more events this year to drive the ThreeFold movement forward!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;world_blockchain_summit.png&quot; alt=&quot;World Blockchain Summit 2022 in Dubai&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yesterday, we participated in the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;gitlab.com&#x2F;gaia-x&#x2F;gaia-x-community&#x2F;gx-hackathon&#x2F;gx-hackathon-3&#x2F;-&#x2F;wikis&#x2F;GX-Hackathon-3#track-6-deployment-of-ecosystems-minimal-viable-gaia-x-track&quot;&gt;6th track&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of the &lt;strong&gt;Gaia-X Hackathon&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. Our tech gurus Geert and Weynand presented &lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; and guided participants through the deployment of workloads on ThreeFold Cloud in a &lt;strong&gt;hands-on session&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold was &lt;strong&gt;featured in the news twice&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; last week:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;medium.com&#x2F;authority-magazine&#x2F;the-future-is-now-kristoff-de-spiegeleer-of-threefold-on-how-their-technological-innovation-will-7acc0e51c365&quot;&gt;The Future Is Now: Kristof De Spiegeleer Of ThreeFold On How Their Technological Innovation Will Shake Up The Tech Scene&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (Interview with Authority Magazine)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;coincheckup.com&#x2F;blog&#x2F;threefold-is-the-decentralized-web-the-future-of-the-internet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ThreeFold: Is the Decentralized Web the Future of the Internet?&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (Coverage on CoinCheckup Blog)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;community-updates&quot;&gt;Community updates:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kyle Ellicott and Kristof de Spiegeleer discussed &lt;strong&gt;how ThreeFold is &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=5xzwg-CdJNk&quot;&gt;decentralizing the Internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; and how it is more relevant than ever before.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We’re collecting &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;looking-for-farmer-stories-to-share-with-the-world&#x2F;2398?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;farmer stories&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;share about the people behind ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; – a globally diverse community united around the mission of building an open-source, peer-to-peer Internet, owned by humanity.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only &lt;strong&gt;8 &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;procedure-to-register-your-l2-validator-node&#x2F;1864&quot;&gt;L2&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and 3 &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;procedure-to-register-your-l0-validator-nodes&#x2F;1866&quot;&gt;L0&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; validator spots remain&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. We are grateful to know that the people behind the validators believe in a decentralized future and want to take part in a meaningful way. Learn how to stake TFT and become a validator &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;stake_tft_become_validator&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;technology-developments&quot;&gt;Technology Developments:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;announcement-of-tfgrid-3-0-0-a5&#x2F;2522?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid version 3.0.0 A5&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; was released on Devnet. Testnet will follow soon.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TF Grid v3.0 A5 will support &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;dedicated-node-support&#x2F;2521&quot;&gt;dedicated nodes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;threefold-grid&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid: &lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hurry up and migrate your 3Nodes from V2 to V3&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. As a &lt;strong&gt;decentralized community, it’s our collective responsibility&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; to ensure we’re powering the latest version of our technology for feature and security reasons. Follow the migration process via ThreeFold Connect &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;farming-migration-grid-v2-v3&#x2F;2143?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please remember that the minting payout for March 2022 will be executed on the 8th of April instead of the 5th of April.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We created a &lt;strong&gt;new &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;new-pricing-calculator-and-suggested-price-change&#x2F;2520&quot;&gt;pricing calculator&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for TF Grid deployments&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; and are looking for &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;pricing-for-tfgrid&#x2F;2518&#x2F;3&quot;&gt;feedback&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3Node deliveries to all parts of the world continue. If you ordered a Titan recently, please fill in this  &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;farming-migration-grid-v2-v3-open-unshipped-orders&#x2F;2144&quot;&gt;specific migration process&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to ensure quick delivery.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you next week, everyone!  🙌 &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can find all earlier editions of ThreeFold Weekly along with the ThreeFold Product Updates &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;c&#x2F;ecosystem-developments&#x2F;41&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Connecting the Dots: ThreeFold plans to scale globally</title>
		<published>2022-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/03/post-9/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/03/post-9/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold started as an idea about ten years ago and is now manifesting itself into the most comprehensive peer-to-peer Internet and cloud infrastructure in the world. The potential of our technology to revolutionize digitization globally is endless and limited only to our collective imagination. In this blog, we share our ‘glocal’ strategy on how we will build our ecosystem, and the exciting opportunities opening up around the world for those interested to join us!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with some background. Today’s Internet is global*. However, it is incredibly centralized and vulnerable. ThreeFold aims to decentralize its infrastructure,  empower people to be sovereign, and accelerate the world’s transition towards open-source systems to build a more inclusive and fair future for all. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A peer-to-peer Internet has an undeniable potential in driving a distributed global economy. This is for a number of reasons – including, but not limited to the fact that instead of relying on centralized cloud providers and tech giants to expand the infrastructure that holds humanity’s data and applications, the peer-to-peer Internet allows any global citizen to participate in the Internet economy by connecting a computer from their house or office to build the decentralized future they want to live in.  Also, while half of the world takes Internet access for granted, it remains  unavailable to the other half.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*So then is the Internet really “global?”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;empowering-sovereignty-and-economic-freedom&quot;&gt;Empowering sovereignty and economic freedom&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Billions of people around the world still remain without access to the Internet or financial services today. Yet many of them have access to electricity and network, and some even already own a mobile phone that could help them access the Internet and financial services. But without fair and reliable connectivity, they remain in the dark. ThreeFold holds an answer here.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet is a human right but it is unequally distributed around the world. ThreeFold enables the realization of an open-source, peer-to-peer Internet that can scale to anywhere electricity and network exists. Everyone deserves access to the Internet, education and financial services to equally learn, partake and succeed, regardless of where they were born, their gender or their socioeconomic status.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-how-can-threefold-go-truly-global&quot;&gt;So how can ThreeFold go truly global?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going global is complicated and even more these days with the evolving regulatory and socio-economical landscapes. Thus, it’s important for us to be on the ground. So we will work with our community and ecosystem on one hand, and with governments and regulators on the other hand, for all of us to meet in the middle. We will always aim to be the most transparent, trusted, inclusive and decentralized Internet solution wherever we go. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A first step in our strategy is to support the growth of local communities across regions to build local presence on the ground. The only way for a truly decentralized Internet to emerge is to involve people in the building process of it, both on a hardware and software level. We are in the midst of kicking off an extensive global expansion strategy, with grants and hiring plans to grow the ThreeFold Grid across markets and ultimately build strong local communities that can serve potential customers locally. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together with these communities, we will develop and grow the ThreeFold Grid, establish our presence with local developers, grow our ecosystem, and collaborate closely with our network.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the last year we have made incredible connections across industries including Blockchain, Web 3.0, IoT, Real Estate and Supply Chains.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every region is unique and we cannot take the same approach wherever we go. This is where the idea of ‘glo-cality’ comes in – a global concept applied locally with regional context.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;global-concept-launch-of-educational-campaigns-around-the-importance-of-a-peer-to-peer-internet&quot;&gt;Global Concept: Launch of educational campaigns around the importance of a peer-to-peer Internet&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold’s mission is to realize the promise of an open-source, peer-to-peer Internet owned by humanity, and we take this commitment heartedly. The first objective of our global strategy is to allow anyone who wants to expand the peer-to-peer Internet to their neighborhood to be able to find compatible computers and how to get started. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a multi-region approach to scaling the ThreeFold Grid to arise, a decentralized 3Node marketplace will be launched in April 2022. This will allow communities to access a simple, decentralized and certified platform to buy and sell compatible computer hardware locally. As the ThreeFold Grid expands, we will look to go local, as shared below:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;applied-locally-grow-localized-ecosystems-of-developers-and-enterprises-to-productize-the-infrastructure&quot;&gt;Applied locally: Grow localized ecosystems of developers and enterprises  to productize the infrastructure&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most countries are looking for new Internet infrastructure alternatives to protect their sovereignty. ThreeFold’s peer-to-peer Internet supports any current and emerging technological trend in a way that is fully compliant with any local digital laws and regulations. For developers and  enterprises, this includes a peer-to-peer Infrastructure as a service which offers a distributed, quantum-safe storage and a decentralized edge computing platform to host any current or future technology. For institutions, we will offer a suite of advanced infrastructure set-ups for a sovereign and unbreakable Internet infrastructure. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decentralized financial and legal systems are being created along with industry experts from around the world to deliver on cross-border financial freedom, education and Internet access. Along with a strong ecosystem, we are planning to offer a full suite of advanced technological, financial and educational solutions to countries, especially in the global south to bring access to education, Internet and financial inclusion to more than a billion people by 2030.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At ThreeFold, we’re committed to building and expanding the open Internet that is owned by humanity. We are always looking at expanding our ecosystem with the world’s best thinkers and talent ready to be at service of a mission that unites us all. If you think this could be you, we’re waiting for you! &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you read our &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;realizing_the_promise&#x2F;&quot;&gt;manifesto&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; yet? Join the peer-to-peer &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;movement&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; today!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apply for an open position &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;careers&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and bring your proposals to the community-led &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;about-the-join-the-fold-category&#x2F;2570&quot;&gt;forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Co-Realizing the Promise</title>
		<published>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/03/post-8/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/03/post-8/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What was once a massive global movement sparked by the idealism of free culture and the net, is now hosting a wave of unintended consequences that may destroy sovereignty and freedom as we know it. The digital revolution and the “democratization” of the Internet promised to lead us to a prosperous and equitable world, one that brought us closer together, eliminating both physical and virtual boundaries.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“We are creating a world that all may enter without privilege or prejudice accorded by race, economic power, military force, or station of birth… a world where anyone, anywhere may express his or her beliefs, no matter how singular, without fear of being coerced into silence or conformity… Your legal concepts of property, expression, identity, movement, and context do not apply to us. They are all based on matter, and there is no matter here.” –  Declaration of independence of Cyberspace – John Perry Barlow – Davos, 1996.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this is not the world we live in today. Borders are hardening in our virtual world with the Great Firewall of China and the widespread emergence of Internet “clusters”. Many countries have attempted to turn off Internet services or to prevent free speech. Networks and algorithms turn us into data generators, influencing our daily habits and interests. It’s turning into a big AI-driven machine that commoditizes our lives, leaves the underserved behind and fails to provide sovereignty where we gather.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A centralized Internet which is controlled by a handful of companies is a serious existential threat. The technology that connects us is now used to distract, manipulate, polarize, divide and control the way we think, act and live our lives. If emerging technologies such as IoT, Blockchain and the Metaverse are not hosted on a self-sovereign, peer-to-peer infrastructure owned by all of us, we may be running head down into the matrix.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With billions of people and IoT devices expected to join this broken digital world this decade, we have no choice but to heal our broken information ecosystem if we want to address the challenges we face collectively. So as we move towards a world where tech and science are merging together, how do we ensure a neutral, inclusive and regenerative digital future – one that truly serves humanity and eliminates the barriers that divide us?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The peer-to-peer Internet incentivizes all citizens of our world to connect computers from their homes or offices to participate in a distributed data economy owned by the people. By allowing humans and machines to interweave without intermediaries, a decentralized and self-sovereign Internet can emerge.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite simply – there is no good reason that our data is being stored and controlled by others in the information age. Why are we paying centralized companies to handle our information on our  behalf, when it makes us vulnerable to be turned into products, and would take us the same time to do it ourselves?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peer-to-peer isn’t an alternative to the Internet, it’s an alternative to centralized cloud giants. The Internet doesn’t need replacing; it is one of the most beautiful inventions of our civilization, if not the greatest. Which is not to say that cloud providers are completely obsolete. They serve functions that decentralized systems cannot (e.g. big data); but peer-to-peer systems are just infinitely more resilient, secure, private and scalable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In times of exponential evolution and innovation, we have our fears around the Internet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don’t need to disconnect ourselves even further from our reality and it is our responsibility to ensure a safe and fair future for the generations to come. A centralized Internet which is controlled by a handful of companies is a serious existential threat. If emerging technologies such as IoT, Blockchain and the Metaverse are not hosted on a self-sovereign, peer-to-peer infrastructure owned by all of us, we may be running head down into the matrix. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The potential of technology to change the world remains endless and limited to our own imagination. We decide to switch from fear to love, and to move forward as one humanity. It is our responsibility as global citizens to pursue greater collective consciousness.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; movement, a community of like-minded people that build the world of tomorrow!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn how to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;farm&quot;&gt;host the Internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; at your home or office.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;gettft.com&#x2F;gettft&#x2F;&quot;&gt;TFT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, the currency of the peer-to-peer Internet.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Update on the 1st Grid Enhancement Proposal</title>
		<published>2022-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/03/post-09/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/03/post-09/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;🚨 &lt;strong&gt;Update &amp;amp; Next Steps: The First Grid Enhancement Proposal&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear all,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to thank the community for the support on last week’s &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;upgrade-proposal-for-minting-code-v3-2&#x2F;2447&quot;&gt;Grid Enhancement Proposal&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. We are happy to announce that with 97% positive votes, we are now moving forward with this proposal and implementing all of the mentioned points as soon as possible.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please keep in mind that this code adjustment on uptime requirements, as well as the rectification of last month’s payout (including the changed uptime requirements), will take some time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any missing payout for last months minting period - payout ASAP&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minting payout for March 2022 - payout 8th of April&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As stated on the Grid Enhancement Proposal post, payout will happen on the 8th of April instead of the 5th of April to give us some more time to verify the process.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kind regards,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ThreeFold Team&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Grid 3 Billing Update</title>
		<published>2022-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/03/post-08/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/03/post-08/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Since we are now moving more and more to Grid V3, we wanted to explain how &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;how-deployment-costs-get-calculated&#x2F;2486&quot;&gt;the billing process works&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for deployments. Some highlights:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grid V3 has implemented a post billing system, meaning you will get billed for the capacity you are using after you have deployed a workload. &lt;em&gt;No need to spend unnecessarily for capacity you won’t need.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also provide &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold&#x2F;#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;pricing&#x2F;threefold__pricing?id=discount-levels&quot;&gt;discounts&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for workloads if your account has a certain amount of balance. &lt;em&gt;This way you can enjoy cheaper deployments whilst you are holding TFT in your account.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some helpful links:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Get started on TF Grid 3&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;manual__weblets_home&quot;&gt;Take advantage of the Weblet Playground&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;from-zero-to-hero-deploy-discourse-and-wordpress-in-under-10-5-minutes&#x2F;2206&quot;&gt;Easily deploy Discourse&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;easily-deploy-wordpress-the-most-popular-website-builder-on-tf-grid&#x2F;2136&quot;&gt;WordPress on the TF Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldtesting&quot;&gt;Join our Grid Testers Chat&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>The 1st Grid Enhancement Proposal</title>
		<published>2022-03-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-03-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/03/post-06/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/03/post-06/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;🗳 &lt;strong&gt;Action Requested: Grid Enhancement Proposal&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi friends, particularly those in the farming community –&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you many of you know by now, we came across a bug in the minting code which had a negative effect on some nodes on the TF Grid during last month’s minting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, we want to thank the ThreeFold community for the way they reached out to us in regards to this. 🙏&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These events sparked a discussion on the current uptime requirements and as a result of that, &lt;strong&gt;we created &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;upgrade-proposal-for-minting-code-v3-2&#x2F;2447&quot;&gt;a forum post&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; with a poll where the community can vote&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; on the changes as suggested.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that the poll will be closed on Friday March 18th at 8AM CET. If a minimum of 60% positive votes are achieved, we will implement these changes as soon as we can.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the best,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold Team&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Peer-to-Peer Overcomes Web3 Challenges</title>
		<published>2022-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/03/post-4/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/03/post-4/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;First coined in 2014, Web3 is now one of the hottest and overused buzzwords in the digital space – the idea of a new iteration of the web, a decentralized environment based on blockchain technology that incorporates token-based economics. The promise of Web3 – decentralization of control and authority from big tech, data security, scalability, and privacy for users – is tremendous. But what is a promise without delivery? Is it possible that we will see major adoption soon?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar to the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;thenewstack.io&#x2F;as-blockchain-hype-fades-developers-give-ethereum-a-serious-look&#x2F;&quot;&gt;enterprise blockchain hype&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that happened a few years ago, Web3 seems to be repeating the same story, with lots of chatter but lagging adoption. Millions have rushed to trade crypto and NFTs attached to Web3 – with a lot of this activity based on speculation and hype – but that doesn’t mean they will replace legacy platforms anytime soon. New approaches such as DeFi (decentralized finance) don’t have the same problem of the legacy firms, but they face the challenge of scaling and mass adoption. However, many so-called ‘Web3’ solutions are not as decentralized as they seem, and still have to show they are scalable, secure and accessible enough for the mass market. This all may change, but there are clear limitations that will need to be overcome.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether Web3 is a marketing slogan or a true technological trend, there is a lot of money and technology behind it. Financial institutions are embracing blockchain technology and we are seeing a rising adoption of digital assets across industries. While the idea of utilizing digital currencies to exchange different forms of value in an increasingly digital world certainly makes sense, it’s a bigger leap to say that blockchain alone can support a broad set of use cases, including replacing the current Internet infrastructure.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet’s client-server infrastructure replicates data and workloads across many computers, and uses tons of computing resources and energy while limiting the scalability of our applications. However, the clear inefficiencies and gaps in security in today’s centralized infrastructures are being challenged by simpler means of building, storing and exchanging data.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blockchain is a clear evolution to the centralized client-server model, but there are  severe challenges sourced from the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;medium.com&#x2F;certik&#x2F;the-blockchain-trilemma-decentralized-scalable-and-secure-e9d8c41a87b3&quot;&gt;blockchain trilemma&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; between decentralization, scalability and security. Peer-to-peer systems transcend those challenges as they don’t require any valid2ation or verification from a third party, and enable end-to-end connections that can scale limitlessly without the potential of being altered or corrupted by intermediaries. In peer-to-peer systems, all participants are equally privileged, presenting a fairer model. Peer-to-peer represents an incredibly simple and efficient paradigm for organizing our digital world, and has already proven to be the most efficient alternative to centralized information systems.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put, there is no reason to replicate full sets of data and workloads across many computers, and use tons of computing resources and energy while limiting the scalability of our applications. While there is an increasing reliance on blockchain principles to organize our Internet systems, blockchain also makes things redundant, slow, complex and energy intensive. To be clear, blockchain isn’t the problem, as it is a great technology to store and exchange value in a decentralized way, but it is only one piece of the puzzle.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By inter-connecting the computing processing power and storage capacity of billions of computers worldwide in a peer-to-peer way, data transfers could happen end-to-end between people and machines without the need to be verified. Peer-to-peer is also the only way to achieve a truly self-sovereign Internet – creating a ‘trustful’ environment that allows users and developers to have real data ownership.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peer-to-peer systems aren’t meant to replace blockchains – they represent a way to decentralize models that blockchain cannot, such as Internet infrastructures. Peer-to-peer systems and blockchains, side by side. The best of both worlds. Peer-to-peer as the most efficient and decentralized alternative for us to exchange data and Internet resources. And blockchain for establishing trust through an irrefutable record of transactions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the rise of emerging technologies, a new technological foundation is needed to protect our sovereignty and freedom. The rise of blockchains, while well intended, ultimately has made the technological space more complex than ever before, and still benefits a plutocratic few (relative to its promise). More than just technology, peer-to-peer opens a world of new possibilities for humanity to co-initiate new paradigms and experiences.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By applying blockchain and peer-to-peer technology to the cloud, ThreeFold solves the security and autonomy issues of the Internet and realizes the initial promise of the Internet as an open-source, peer-to-peer, planetary mesh network of nodes owned by the people.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Support the realization of a peer-to-peer Internet owned by the people today:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tokens&#x2F;threefold__how_to_buy&quot;&gt;Get TFT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, the currency of the peer-to-peer Internet.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;farming&#x2F;threefold__farming_intro&quot;&gt;Connect a computer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to the peer-to-peer Internet and earn monthly rewards.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;&#x2F;manual__manual3_home_new&quot;&gt;Build applications&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on the peer-to-peer Internet.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>What is ThreeFold Farming?</title>
		<published>2022-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/03/post-2/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/03/post-2/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold farming refers to the act of connecting a 3Node to the ThreeFold Grid – providing Internet capacity to a globally distributed peer-to-peer Internet infrastructure. Farming is a decentralized and energy-efficient way for people to expand a new Internet infrastructure instead of corporations building hyper-scale data centers. It’s also a way to extend the Internet to underserved regions of our planet, which cannot afford data centers. Every ThreeFold Farmer around the world contributes to the growth of the foundation for a self-sovereign, private and secure digital world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;blog&#x2F;3node_example.png&quot; alt=&quot;3Node&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone can start farming by hosting a computer at their home or office and taking part in the decentralization of our global Internet and Cloud economy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-become-a-threefold-farmer&quot;&gt;Why become a ThreeFold Farmer?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today’s Internet model is highly centralized, owned and operated by the few. It has turned people into products, is too harmful for our planet, cannot scale to meet emerging demands and connect the billions who are being left behind. These alone are powerful reasons to participate in ThreeFold farming and participate in the growth of a new peer-to-peer Internet economy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further, the Internet is the second largest and fastest growing industry in the world after the financial markets. With the Internet expected to triple in size by 2025 to meet the data requirements of emerging technologies such as blockchain, Web3 and IoT, we need more capacity and especially in underserved regions of the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;basics-of-threefold-farming&quot;&gt;Basics of ThreeFold Farming&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold is a peer-to-peer network of computers (known as “3Nodes”), including servers, desktops and laptops, that creates an open-source, decentralized Internet. People who connect computers to the ThreeFold Grid (known as “farmers”) are rewarded with ThreeFold Tokens (TFT) on a monthly basis for meeting the required uptime necessary for users to access their workloads.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process of connecting decentralized Internet capacity and thereby creating new ThreeFold Tokens is described as farming because it resembles the process of farming in agriculture. With agricultural farming, farmers cultivate the land and earn revenue from their harvests. With ThreeFold, farmers connect decentralized Internet capacity and earn ThreeFold Tokens every month for achieving a certain uptime.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above model represents the building block for a distributed, edge infrastructure that can scale to anywhere electricity and network exists, to meet emerging data demands while also providing the self-sovereignty, privacy and security features to achieve true net-neutrality.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-fair-economic-model&quot;&gt;A Fair Economic Model&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold was created to realize the promise of an open-source, peer-to-peer Internet. As such, ThreeFold farming rewards all farmers equally according to the amount of Internet capacity they provide to the network.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold Tokens are rewarded for the amount of Internet capacity added and kept connected to the network. &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;farming&#x2F;threefold__farming_reward&quot;&gt;Farming rewards&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; are calculated according to the compute, storage and network capacity made available by the computers:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;30 TFT per Compute Unit (2 vCPU and 4 GB memory) per month&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;12.5 TFT per Storage Unit (1 TB of SSD and HDD) per month&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.38 TFT per Network Unit (1 GB of data transfer)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.06 TFT per public IP address per hour &lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above prices are based on the price of 1 TFT equalling $0.08. The farming rewards are pegged to the U.S Dollar and the price is locked from the time a farmer gets started to incentivize early contributors to the network. When the price of TFT rises, the farming rewards will decrease.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farming rewards are designed to be “reviewed” by &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;decentralization&#x2F;dao&#x2F;threefold__tfdao&quot;&gt;the ThreeFold DAO&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (a decentralized autonomous organization owned by the ThreeFold community) according to the growth of the ThreeFold Grid and the utilization of its decentralized cloud to ensure a fair distribution of the token economy while also ensuring that farmers will always be justly rewarded for their contribution.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;an-innovative-and-sustainable-solution&quot;&gt;An innovative and sustainable solution&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin mining and other blockchains became famous for requiring enormous amounts of computers and power to solve complex mathematical equations to win the chance of earning the famous cryptocurrency. Since then, many other projects have been born and carried on the mining concept.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold’s model is inclusive and planet-friendly. The decentralized operating system built and used by ThreeFold is extremely lightweight, allowing the peer-to-peer Internet infrastructure to be up-to 10x more energy efficient than the data center model and up-to 100x more energy efficient than Bitcoin mining.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The infrastructure was built in such a way that it removes the need for human intervention or maintenance to eliminate all unnecessary backdoors that open the possibility for ransomware and cyberattacks. Once booted, the decentralized operating system runs forever as the whole infrastructure was designed to be self-driving and self-healing. This 100% autonomous model allows for a completely decentralized system while also enhancing the security and privacy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While blockchain remains an incredible store of value, it is neither an efficient nor a scalable solution to store data and run applications. Only a peer–to-peer model can scale the Internet infinitely and efficiently.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;considerations-before-getting-started&quot;&gt;Considerations before getting started&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following are important factors to consider for ThreeFold farming profitability: &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;computer-hardware&quot;&gt;Computer Hardware&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farmers are encouraged to use the latest computers, including servers, desktops, and laptops that come with an AMD and Intel processor. The computer should have at least 1 Terabyte of SSD to optimize the performance of their farming activity. It is recommended to buy a ThreeFold 3Node server from certified partners around the globe that comes pre-configured and ready to run on the Grid. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Used or refurbished computers can be used but it is important to understand that older computers are less efficient and more power-hungry. Computers not older than 4 years are recommended. Please visit &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;c&#x2F;farming&#x2F;diy-farming&#x2F;43&quot;&gt;the DIY section of our forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for support and feedback on farming setups.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;power-costs&quot;&gt;Power Costs&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Electrical power is the  main operating expense. Electricity is charged per kilowatt-hour (kWh). The cost of farming can float from $0.10 to $0.35 per kWh. It is important for a farmer to verify the expected power usage of a computer before starting the operation to improve profitability.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note that the price of kWh varies depending on the country. Find a country power cost average comparison &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.electricrate.com&#x2F;data-center&#x2F;electricity-prices-by-country&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;threefold-token-price&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Token Price&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An incentive to farm ThreeFold Tokens is because of its future potential. What Bitcoin did to money, ThreeFold is doing to the Internet. While Bitcoin and Etheruem have already reached high market caps, ThreeFold is just getting started.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farmers are rewarded a given amount of TFT monthly based on the amount of Internet capacity they provide to the network.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the price of TFT is $0.1, the profitability of the farm will be average. If the price of TFT is $0.3  your farming operation may operate with healthy rewards. If the price of TFT is $1 your farming operation will be highly rewarding.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farming rewards are also locked until 30% utilization for a period of 2 years to incentivize early participants. The earlier you start your farming operation, the greater the rewards along with the growth in the value of TFT.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The right mix of the above elements make farming an attractive venture. If the variables are favorable, farmers can scale up operations and earn more rewards.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone can start farming by hosting a computer at their home or office and take part in the decentralization of our global Internet and Cloud economy. Considering ThreeFold’s market cap alongside the growing demand for a decentralized Internet, there’s no better time than now to get started farming!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;shop.threefold.tech&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Buy&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;farming&#x2F;threefold__diy_guide&quot;&gt;build&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; a 3Node and become a ThreeFold Farmer!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Grid V2 to V3 Migration Update</title>
		<published>2022-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/02/post-04/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/02/post-04/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;🧳 &lt;strong&gt;Grid V2 to Grid V3 Migration Update&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we are now live on TF Grid 3.0, it is important that all farmers who are still on Grid 2.x migrate their farms to the newest mainnet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;farming-migration-grid-v2-v3&#x2F;2143&quot;&gt;How to Migrate from V2 to V3&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;farming-migration-grid-v2-v3-open-unshipped-orders&#x2F;2144&quot;&gt;Migration for Unshipped Orders&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to all farmers who have already migrated, and for those who still need to migrate, please note the forum is open for questions if you have any!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Also important: V3 farming rewards have been sent, so please get in touch with the support team via threefold.io live chat if you are not seeing rewards in your wallet.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And here’s &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;comparison-v2-vs-v3-minting&#x2F;2122&quot;&gt;a comparison of V2 and V3 minting&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, for those who haven’t seen it.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Your January 11 3Node Team Update</title>
		<published>2022-01-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-01-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/01/post-05/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/01/post-05/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;*&lt;strong&gt;Your Weekly 3Node Update!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;january-11th-3node-team-update-v3-migration-shipping-updates&#x2F;1739&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have some important information on migration from Grid 2 to Grid 3 for Titan Farmers and DIY Farmers, as well as shipping updates for all parts of the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For questions or feedback please use our forum or &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldfarmers&quot;&gt;the farmers chat&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Support team is also available via live chat on threefold.io for support-specific questions!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; 🙏&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Your January 6 3Node Team Update</title>
		<published>2022-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/01/post-01/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/01/post-01/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your Weekly 3Node Update!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;january-6th-3node-team-update-new-year-shipping-farming-rewards&#x2F;1691&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week’s update is focused on shipping as well as farming rewards, and a reminder about our deep dive meetups!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>2021 Review, 2022 Preview</title>
		<published>2022-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/01/post-02/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/01/post-02/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;🎆 &lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold’s 2021 Review &amp;amp; 2022 Preview!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefolds-2021-review-and-2022-preview&#x2F;1641&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As 2022 kicks off, let’s take a look back at the year that was and what to expect throughout Q1 – TF Grid 3 Mainnet, validator nodes, the ThreeFold DAO, and more!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Your December 21 Titan Update</title>
		<published>2021-12-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-12-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/12/post-21/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/12/post-21/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your Weekly 3Node Update!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;december-21st-3node-team-update-shipping-updates-for-all&#x2F;1603&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good news for all those waiting for their Titan(s)! Pending hardware delivery, North America Titans continue to go out without holiday interruption, and all orders from the rest of the world (for which we have the required data) are expected be shipped before the new year!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For farming questions, please use the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldfarmers&quot;&gt;farmer chat&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or live chat on our website (blue chat icon) if specific to your order.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>The ThreeFold Blockchain</title>
		<published>2021-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/12/post-7/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/12/post-7/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;what-is-new-in-tfgrid-3-0&#x2F;1133&#x2F;1&quot;&gt;third release&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;threefold__threefold_grid&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; represents a major step in the decentralization of the People’s Internet with the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;threefold__smartcontract_tfgrid3&quot;&gt;Smart Contract for IT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; coming to life on the ThreeFold Blockchain (aka “TF Chain”). Built on the Substrate framework, TF Chain represents the layer-0 for all current and future technologies to provision decentralized Internet capacity. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what is Substrate to begin with? And what exactly does our TF Chain do?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-tf-chain-and-what-is-substrate&quot;&gt;What is TF Chain and what is Substrate?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;threefold__tfchain&quot;&gt;TF Chain&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is the universal smart contract layer on the ThreeFold Grid. It’s an application-specific blockchain customized for the operation of a single application – provisioning decentralized compute, storage and network capacity. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;substrate.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Substrate&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a blockchain-building framework from &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.parity.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Parity&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that allows developers to simply create future-proof solo blockchains or parachains for any use case. Parity was founded by Ethereum’s co-founder and first CTO Gavin Wood in 2015, and went on to develop Substrate to power a multichain, interoperable and decentralized Internet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-did-we-choose-substrate-for-our-tf-chain&quot;&gt;Why did we choose Substrate for our TF Chain?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Substrate brings clear benefits to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tech&#x2F;tf-chain&quot;&gt;TF Chain&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in relation to its frameworks for developers, its interoperability with other blockchain ecosystems and its huge community. More than 150 projects from NFTs to DeFi are already building on it.  &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By providing a solid, mature and secure layer for custom blockchains, Substrate is built for adoption. The blockchain framework was built with the programming language Rust and is modular by design. Choosing Substrate allowed our developer team to leverage great blockchain constructs and efficiently build TF Chain instead of re-inventing the wheel. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its flexible, modular and composable architecture enables our team to focus on what matters the most – the unique demands of &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;grid&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. For example, we’ve built  a Grid module with specific functionalities for farms and nodes. Just like a chef can invent a new recipe and add it to a menu, Substrate allows our developers to build and add as many custom functionalities to TF Chain as we’d like, in a fully decentralized way. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A major benefit that comes with TF Chain being built on Substrate is the native compatibility with the Polkadot ecosystem, opening up the opportunity for ThreeFold to become a parachain on the Polkadot network and seamlessly bridging to other Substrate-based chains in the future.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-s-the-purpose-of-tf-chain&quot;&gt;What’s the purpose of TF Chain?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For ThreeFold to be a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;quest_decentralize_internet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;truly decentralized&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; peer-to-peer Internet infrastructure, people should be able to use Internet infrastructures from anywhere without any intermediaries like &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;threefold_cloud_vs_centralized_providers_like_aws_azure&#x2F;&quot;&gt;AWS&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. TF Chain serves exactly that purpose. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It orchestrates the provisioning of compute, storage and network on the ThreeFold Grid via &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tech&#x2F;zero-os&quot;&gt;Zero-OS&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, removing all forms of intermediaries present in today’s centralized IT infrastructures. Put simply, TF Chain allows people to provide and use cloud resources in a 100% decentralized way. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-does-tf-chain-do&quot;&gt;What does TF Chain do?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;threefold__tfchain&quot;&gt;TF Chain&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is responsible for achieving consensus on all Internet capacity transactions on the ThreeFold Grid and to store them in a historical record. This prevents users from “double spending” their &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tft&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Tokens&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and ensures the correct execution of Internet capacity provisioning via smart contracts, while also protecting the network from potential attacks. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An exciting feature that comes with TF Chain 3.0 is a totally new peer-to-peer billing framework for Internet capacity provisioning and workload deployment. This module allows for all functionalities of the ThreeFold Grid to be provisioned peer-to-peer between users and farmers. Therefore, the ThreeFold Token now also lives on the Polkadot network, allowing it to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www2.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;bridges_connecting_threefold_ecosystem&#x2F;&quot;&gt;bridge back and forth&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; from the Stellar network and potentially from other chains in the future.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While TF Chain builds on the Substrate framework, most of its functionalities are custom-built to fit the specific needs of the ThreeFold Grid – from Internet capacity provisioning, workload deployments, and payment and billing processes, to digital twin creation and much more. By executing all these actions via &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tech&#x2F;smart-contract&quot;&gt;smart contracts&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in an automated and decentralized way, the activity on the ThreeFold Grid is always secured by blockchain technology and available to other users for open collaboration. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Farms can now be registered on our new &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;tech_update_admin_portal&#x2F;&quot;&gt;TF Chain Portal&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-future&quot;&gt;The Future&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Internet capacity provisioning and workload deployments are already executed via TF Chain, the minting of TFTs according to the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;farming&#x2F;threefold__proof_of_capacity&quot;&gt;Proof-of-Capacity algorithm&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; remains on the Stellar blockchain until Grid 3.1, when TF Chain will become the official chain of the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;threefold__threefold_token&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Token&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building our own application-specific blockchain represents a major step towards decentralizing the ThreeFold Grid and ecosystem, with the next milestone being the ThreeFold DAO planned for Grid 3.2. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;massive thank you&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; to our developer team for this great achievement! 🙏&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to dive deeper? We invite you to:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learn more about how smart contracts work on TF Chain 3.0 &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;threefold__smartcontract_tfgrid3&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;join the ThreeFold Grid 3.0 testnet conversations &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;joinchat&#x2F;BwOvOxxgK59GmRoZ2_sM0w&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;check our roadmap &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;cloud&#x2F;threefold__roadmap_grid&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Your December 14 Titan Update</title>
		<published>2021-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/12/post-14/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/12/post-14/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your Weekly 3Node Update!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;december-14th-3node-team-update-shipping-setting-up-your-titan-what-else-is-cooking&#x2F;1576&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s inside: Titans continue to go out in North America, clarifying Titan setup, and what else is cooking behind the scenes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As always, please join us on &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldfarmers&quot;&gt;the farmer chat&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for farming-related conversations &amp;amp; questions!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Your December 8 Titan Update</title>
		<published>2021-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/12/post-8/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/12/post-8/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your Weekly 3Node Update!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;december-8th-3node-team-update-shipping-status-expanding-our-partner-network&#x2F;1555&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re in the midst of shipping a large batch of Titans to North America, and we’re expanding our partner network. 🌍&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More info within!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Presenting the new Explorer UI for Grid 3.x</title>
		<published>2021-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/11/post-30/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/11/post-30/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;🚨 &lt;strong&gt;Presenting: the new Explorer UI for TF Grid 3.x!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The updated Explorer brings a simple interface and true decentralization to the way compute, storage, and network capacity information is sourced from 3Nodes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;the-threefold-grid-3-x-explorer-ui&#x2F;1536&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thanks to our farmer community for already connecting more than 100 nodes (across 16 countries) to testnet.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And to our testing community – more than 1,400 contracts have been deployed since testnet launch!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; 🚀&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Your November 29 Titan Update</title>
		<published>2021-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/11/post-29/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/11/post-29/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your Weekly 3Node Update!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;november-29th-3node-team-update-north-america-shipping-admin-portal-technical-support-more&#x2F;1533&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, the first batch of Titans begins shipping to North America! 🇨🇦🇺🇸🇲🇽 We’ve got some more updates inside. Take a look!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As always, you can find farming-related conversations in the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldfarmers&quot;&gt;farming chat&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Introducing the ThreeFold Admin Portal</title>
		<published>2021-11-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-11-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/11/post-26/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/11/post-26/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;🚨 &lt;strong&gt;Exciting news for farmers &amp;amp; grid users!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the requests we’ve had from farmers and grid users was to have a simpler user experience.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The admin portal (aka TF Chain UI) is a response to that feedback, a graphical user interface, and the starting point for anyone to begin working with the TF Grid!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;introducing-the-tf-chain-admin-portal-for-farmers-and-grid-users&#x2F;1526&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve tested this portal with people of all technical levels, and the response has been quite good! We believe the portal is a huge step forward for anyone using or managing the ThreeFold Grid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Your November 22 Titan Update</title>
		<published>2021-11-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-11-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/11/post-22/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/11/post-22/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your Weekly 3Node Team Update!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;november-22nd-3node-team-update-shipping-compensation-upgrading-the-process-more&#x2F;1509&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week, we’re covering shipping, compensation for the unexpected 3Node configuration issue, upgrades to our process, expanding support, &amp;amp; clarifying our communication channels.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please stay tuned on the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldfarming&quot;&gt;farming chat&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and we’ll share another update again here next week!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Your Mid November Titan Update</title>
		<published>2021-11-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-11-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/11/post-15/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/11/post-15/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your mid-November Titan 2.1 update!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;mid-november-titan-2-1-update-where-we-are-whats-coming&#x2F;1477&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve shipped 90% of all European orders that were placed up until early November, and later this month, we’ll begin shipping to the Americas.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inside please find more information and updates related to where we are and where we’re going when it comes to the Titan 2.1 orders.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you have any additional questions, you know how to find us!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Titan v2.1 Shipping Update</title>
		<published>2021-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/10/post-12/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/10/post-12/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hi all 👋&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re pleased to share that last week, we began shipping Titan v2.1s ordered by September 10 to the European Union*. Many new farmers have already received their 3Nodes! 👩‍🌾&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But many of you still haven’t filled out the information needed to set up your farm(s). Please note we won’t send your 3Node(s) out until we get this information.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you ordered a Titan v2.1 and haven’t done so, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forms.gle&#x2F;p8947F8kytTpcJKW6&quot;&gt;please fill out this short form&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; so we can get you your 3Node without unnecessary delays.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*&lt;em&gt;All other locations will begin shipping in November. Thank you for your patience during this global hardware shortage. 🙏&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>How ThreeFold Can Truly Decentralize Blockchain</title>
		<published>2021-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/10/post-5/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/10/post-5/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The topic of decentralization is commonly tied to blockchain and cryptocurrencies. Blockchain doesn’t store any of its information in a central location, rather it is copied and spread across a network of computers. And the most popular name in the blockchain space, Bitcoin, was intended as an alternative payment system free of central control.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But many blockchains are facing the same challenge: How can they escape the monopolies of centralized cloud providers for their own workloads, as well as for the dApps built on top of them? The key question is, is a blockchain truly decentralized if it is being hosted on a centralized solution? We say: no.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An example to illustrate this challenge is the fact that up to 60% of Ethereum (the world’s second most-popular blockchain) nodes run on centralized cloud providers and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;aws.amazon.com&#x2F;blockchain&#x2F;&quot;&gt;25% of them run on Amazon Web Services (AWS)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the topic is being addressed, it isn’t being solved at scale. The good news is that ThreeFold can play a large part in solving it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-should-blockchains-make-this-move&quot;&gt;Why should blockchains make this move?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The blockchain movement, as mentioned, is very heavily tied to the movement around decentralization. Cryptocurrencies represent the move away from centralized banks as the authorities and gatekeepers around money – just as ThreeFold and similar projects represent the move away from centralized clouds as the authorities and gatekeepers around data. The thing is, if blockchains are to rely on centralized cloud for hosting, they aren’t truly embodying decentralization.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understandably, many blockchains have chosen centralized cloud providers in the past because there wasn’t much of an alternative. But now, the Decentralized Cloud (DeCloud) movement has changed all of that.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how some specific audiences can benefit:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;for-node-operators&quot;&gt;For Node Operators&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any full node or validator node can run on ThreeFold’s &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cloud.threefold.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Peer-to-Peer (P2P) Cloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, making that particular Blockchain even more community-owned, and more decentralized from an IT&#x2F;cloud level. Any node operator can choose to run their nodes from any farmer location on the ThreeFold Grid, totally &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;what_is_peer_to_peer&#x2F;&quot;&gt;peer-to-peer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; between the chosen farmer and the node operator. The deployed workloads are computed in a P2P manner, no middle party involved.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;for-dapp-developers&quot;&gt;For dApp Developers&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Web3&#x2F;Blockchain developers can use ThreeFold’s P2P Cloud - offering both compute and storage - to build and power their applications in a truly decentralized cloud infrastructure, both blockchain-native and cloud-native. A strong advantage here is that developers have the ability to leverage Kubernetes, Docker, S3, and other cloud-native tools (all compatible &#x2F; integrated with the ThreeFold) to power and optimize their data processing capabilities, as well as the overall functionality of their dApps. But the sweet spot is that it is deployed on a decentralized IT infrastructure, close to where users would be located.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;but-why-choose-threefold-over-other-decloud-projects&quot;&gt;But why choose ThreeFold over other DeCloud projects?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There may be bigger names in the space, but ThreeFold’s technology and offerings are much more comprehensive than the rest. ThreeFold provides decentralized storage, compute, and network all under one roof (whereas most other projects offer only one of the three) and as mentioned, we have created an environment for developers which is highly-compatible to the developer tools and solutions they use today. Further, ThreeFold is building new infrastructure &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;an_intro_to_the_threefold_grid&#x2F;&quot;&gt;from the ground up&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (rather than relying on extra space in data centers) and the technology is truly peer-to-peer.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We already have &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;partners&#x2F;blockchain&quot;&gt;a number of partners in the space&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; who recognize these advantages.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any blockchain protocol or dApp, whether operating DeFi, NFTs, DEXs, etc, will at some point need to leverage the power of the decentralized cloud and escape from centralized cloud providers. We’re seeing some of that adoption from a decentralized storage side with IPFS, which has been adopted by many dApps, and others – but as a developer, you will have to think twice, not just about where your&#x2F;your users’ data is being stored, but also about how (and where) your app is computed and powered.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Participate now in our quest to fully decentralize the Internet by &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;farm&quot;&gt;becoming a node&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on our grid or &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tft&quot;&gt;buying TFT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Building a New Internet From the Ground Up – Part 3: Compute</title>
		<published>2021-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/10/post-2/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/10/post-2/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Welcome back for another installment of our accessible series on ThreeFold Grid technology. We are working through the three major categories that make up cloud infrastructure: storage, compute, and network. This time, we’ll be focusing on compute.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-compute&quot;&gt;What is compute?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;building_a_new_internet_from_the_ground_up_pt2&#x2F;&quot;&gt;storage&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and network are fairly intuitive concepts – where data lives and how it gets around – compute is about the more mysterious realm of data processing and ultimately computer programming. Don’t worry though, you don’t need any technical abilities to gain a deeper understanding of what’s happening behind the scenes when we use apps or interact with web sites.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;an_intro_to_the_threefold_grid&#x2F;&quot;&gt;first part&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of this series, compute is basically what happens with data once it reaches its destination. Compute gives data relevance, by processing it according to the instructions provided by developers in their source code. When talking about what the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;grid&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; offers in terms of compute, it’s mostly about how the code that developers produce gets executed in order to provide the services we enjoy. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With ThreeFold, this actually happens for the most part using the same tools and systems provided by traditional cloud services, meaning that it’s highly compatible with existing cloud applications. What really makes the Grid different is that it’s been designed to provide a level of efficiency and security that simply isn’t possible without starting “from the ground up”. Before we get into specifics of compute offerings built into ThreeFold’s &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;how-it-works&#x2F;zero-os&quot;&gt;Zero-OS&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, let’s briefly explore what computing is.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;playing-with-zeroes-and-ones&quot;&gt;Playing with zeroes and ones&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything a computer’s central processing unit does is based on a limited set of instructions that includes basic mathematical functions, logical operations, and ways to control the flow of a program. At their core, computers are really just automated adding machines that execute specified operations on whatever input they receive. It may be hard to believe that simple math creates all of the vibrant digital experience we enjoy, but at a certain low level, that’s the truth.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a messaging app as an example. Within a computer, all of the text, emojis, and images we see are represented by numbers. When we search for some text within a chat, matches are determined by checking if the numbers corresponding to the words we typed are equal to some numbers corresponding to words that appear in the chat history. This information is then converted into the list of results we see on screen.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this context, compute is mostly responsible for organizing all of our messages based on the individual or group we were talking with, the time that the message happened, and whether or not we’ve opened it yet. Typically, a messaging app stores data both on our local devices and on a back end in the cloud. Compute is also how the service decides to copy messages you sent on one device to other devices where you have the same app installed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is an important distinction about how the ThreeFold Grid operates. In a traditional cloud environment, it is impossible to know for sure what is happening on the backend, even if you are the one running the service. The administrative access retained by the cloud provider can be used for surveillance and tampering that can be very difficult or impossible to detect. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zero OS offers a unique assurance that no one can abuse the Grid in this way, because it operates autonomously with no facilities provided for human intervention. In order to utilize compute capacity on the Grid, individuals and organizations deploy their choice of several “primitives,” or basic components, that provide an environment for code to be executed and create the magic we experience as online applications.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;threefold-compute-primitives&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Compute Primitives&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we’re getting a bit into the technical weeds here, we’ll just take a brief look at each primitive and what makes it special.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;zmachine&quot;&gt;Zmachine&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zmachine is a lightweight virtual machine (VM) implementation that’s been developed in a uniquely efficient way by ThreeFold. VMs are essentially computers within computers, allowing multiple operating systems to run on a single physical system. A common example is running the Windows operating system on a Mac that’s already running MacOS. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the cloud world, virtual machines are a classic way to manage complex deployments with flexibility and resilience – by packaging different components into different VMs that can be run side by side and moved between different physical servers with ease. While VMs have been replaced in many cases with the new container paradigm, which we’ll cover next, they are still widely used and provide a simpler solution than containers that’s sufficient for many use cases.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;flist&quot;&gt;Flist&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;how-it-works&#x2F;zflist&quot;&gt;Flist&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;  is a next generation container format which extends the industry standard Docker container concept in an efficient and secure way. It is supported directly at the operating system level on Zero OS, and in its latest version on ThreeFold Grid 3.0, provides a unique advantage over traditional containers via the use of mini virtual machines.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Containers provide greater efficiency and flexibility than VMs, by sharing parts of the host operating system between containers rather than duplicating the full operating system for each component. This, however, means that containers typically come with less of an assurance that different workloads and their data remain isolated from each other. By employing mini VMs, the Flist concept provides better isolation than traditional container systems while retaining the advantages that containers offer over full VMs.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;kubernetes&quot;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Containers usually represent small parts of a full solution, which are created, interconnected, and destroyed on an ongoing basis. Kubernetes is the industry standard container orchestration system, and it’s used to manage many of the largest and most complex cloud deployments. Kubernetes solutions are defined through configuration files that specify the types of containers, how updates are handled, and the network architecture both between containers and with the outside world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multiple physical servers or VMs are typically used for a Kubernetes “cluster” which provides redundancy and scalability. The ThreeFold Grid provides a lightweight Kubernetes VM that can be used to create clusters according to specific needs. Kubernetes users can, for the most part, simply bring their existing configuration files and recreate their deployments on a Grid based cluster seamlessly.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;wrapping-up&quot;&gt;Wrapping up&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taken together, the compute primitives offer a comprehensive alternative to existing cloud compute providers. Users of Docker, Kubernetes, and virtual machines can bring their deployments to the Grid with a minimal amount of migration effort. This is distinct from other decentralized cloud projects, which either offer a single solution like Kubernetes or a completely new environment that developers must adapt their code to run within.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Better yet, each compute offering on the ThreeFold Grid benefits from the unique efficiency and security features of Zero OS, as well as the unique aspects of the primitives themselves. Thanks again for joining me on this journey into the wonderful world of ThreeFold technology. In the next episode, we’ll cover the last element of the cloud infrastructure triad: network.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Titan v2.1 Shipping Update</title>
		<published>2021-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-08/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-08/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;🚨 &lt;strong&gt;We have a Titan v2.1 shipping update (action required below)&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, in case you missed it in other channels:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
For all orders received before Friday the 10th of September, we plan to ship as follows:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🌍 Europe: Last week of September&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🌎 USA &amp;amp; Canada: Mid-October&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🌏 All Others: End of October
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📧 &lt;strong&gt;Please check your inbox&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; for an email from farming@threefold.tech (sent on September 7) in which we ask for details we need in order to set up your farm and node!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;You can follow &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;titan-v2-1-shipping-info&#x2F;1223&quot;&gt;this forum thread&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for continued shipping updates or to ask any questions you might have.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>September 1 Community Call Recording</title>
		<published>2021-09-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-09-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-02/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-02/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;📹 Here is &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=mc3-y-jT6r4&quot;&gt;the recording of yesterday’s community call&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, which focused on updates around farming and ThreeFold Grid 3.0!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The video is timestamped, so you can move around to the parts which are most relevant or interesting for you.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>September 1 Community Call Announcement</title>
		<published>2021-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/08/post-30/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/08/post-30/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We’ll host a &lt;strong&gt;community call this Wednesday&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; at 5pm CEST to share updates around &lt;strong&gt;farming&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; and to touch on a few important aspects of &lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold Grid 3.0&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
❗️Here’s &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;meet.jit.si&#x2F;moderated&#x2F;d211ee6bc96b7a4e6424955465c94be15837548e64703afc3c65bd92b61c849a&quot;&gt;the link&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to the call&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;We hope to see you there! If not, we’ll share the recording afterwards.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Introducing New Farming Rewards</title>
		<published>2021-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/07/post-07/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/07/post-07/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;With the forthcoming launch of ThreeFold Grid 3.0 later this year, the world is set to go peer-to-peer. With many use-cases being lined up, we updated the Farming Rewards to incentivize Farmers to expand the ThreeFold Grid further across the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;new-farming-logic-introducing-network-rewards&quot;&gt;New Farming Logic - Introducing Network Rewards&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new Farming Rewards logic can be found &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;threefold__farming_reward&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HERE&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
You will see that the farming rewards were simplified, and are now calculated according to the compute and storage units (CU &amp;amp; SU) provided to the ThreeFold Grid. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Also, as of this summer, Farmers will be able to earn more TFT for the Network traffic happening on their 3Nodes. The amount of data coming in and out of their CU and SU will determine extra rewards in the form of Network Units (NU).
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Certified NU: 0.3 TFT per GB per month&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DIY NU: 0.2 TFT per GB per month&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-do-i-get-certified&quot;&gt;How do I get Certified?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All 3Nodes bought from ThreeFold after June 5 2021 are eligible for certified farming. We will send instructions to everyone that purchased a Titan v2.1 on how to upgrade to a certified 3Node next week. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
For people that already bought an earlier batch of nodes, we are thinking of a solution for becoming certified, as our hardware partners need the physical 3Node to certify the hardware.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;important-notes&quot;&gt;Important notes&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All certified hardware is 100% dedicated to the ThreeFold Grid. While DIY nodes can be booted with a different Operating System, this is not possible with a Certified 3Node.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All certified hardware is automatically subject to the 3.0 Farming Logic. Read more &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;threefold__farming_reward&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HERE&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;P.s. If you’re already a farmer and would like to be featured on our websites please &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forms.gle&#x2F;cW6uFUhkohSw81KT6&quot;&gt;fill out this form.&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; Let’s introduce the world to the farming community behind this awesome project!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Introducing Certified Farming for a More Secure ThreeFold Grid</title>
		<published>2021-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/07/post-7/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/07/post-7/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last month, we went live with Titan V2.1, and we’re thrilled to count +1,000 orders already from all over the world.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
While orders keep on coming in, we are happy to launch the Certified Farming Program. Certification brings more security to 3Nodes and hence to the ThreeFold Grid, while also providing more rewards to Farmers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;more-security-for-everyone&quot;&gt;More Security For Everyone&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While anyone can connect hardware to the ThreeFold Grid, some workloads require the highest level of security standards. Certified hardware can only be booted by Zero-OS and allows for 100% tamper-proof capacity. With certification, ThreeFold is pushing the limits further and creating a new global standard for hardware security.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
There are key benefits for Farmers to certify their capacity: 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get a certified capacity label: Some developers and enterprises will seek for the highest levels of security. With the certified label, you will be able to provide capacity for their workloads at a higher price.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved hardware security: While DIY farming already provides incredible security, certified farming is 100% tamper-proof. Now you can bring more security to the ThreeFold Grid and to the people using it. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re building a more secure future for our digital lives. This will happen! 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;P.s. If you’re already a farmer and would like to be featured on our websites please &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forms.gle&#x2F;cW6uFUhkohSw81KT6&quot;&gt;fill out this form.&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; Let’s introduce the world to the farming community behind this awesome project!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>How ThreeFold Will Give Internet to 43% of the World’s Population</title>
		<published>2021-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/06/post-3/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/06/post-3/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The United Nations publicly ruled Internet access to be a human right in 2016. Proper access to the Internet helps to protect people’s freedom of speech and thought, as well as other fundamentals such as access to knowledge and information.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Nonetheless, as of 2019, about 43% of humanity remains unconnected to the Internet, creating huge inequalities in access to information and knowledge. It is essential to take the necessary steps to strengthen the relationship between governments and people while still upholding all human rights.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold created an infrastructure that is easily affordable and jointly operated by network peers to make the modern Internet open and fair to everyone. Anybody with a network connection and electricity can add capacity to the ThreeFold Grid. We’re looking for farmers around the globe and we’re also partnering with farming cooperatives to develop localized strategies and meet the specific needs of their region. Plus, the Foundation will incentivize and sponsor the extension and scope to areas that require Internet capacity the most, to ensure a fair and equitable delivery of the Internet to all.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Want to join the biggest internet revolution? &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;farming.threefold.io&quot;&gt;Be part&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of it, today.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Pre-Order Your Titan v2.1 Now!</title>
		<published>2021-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-011/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-011/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the last 24 hours, we’ve had Titan v2.1 3Node pre-orders from all corners of the globe – six of the seven continents. (Anybody know anyone in Antarctica?)
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;❗️ Pre-orders &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;pre-order.threefold.tech&#x2F;&quot;&gt;are now live&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for the general public!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, please visit &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;nodeshop-pre-order-faq&#x2F;853&quot;&gt;our FAQ&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; first to see if you can find the answer there. If you don’t find what you’re looking for, join our two-way farmer chat &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldfarmers&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>How You Can Join the People&#x27;s Internet</title>
		<published>2021-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/06/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/06/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yes, that’s right. With ThreeFold, you &lt;em&gt;can&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; become the Internet! Let me quickly explain. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Today’s Internet is powered by hyper-scale data centers which are owned by large corporations. With +80% of the global infrastructure and +60% of the global Internet networks owned by a bunch of companies, the Internet became a real business with us humans being the products of that business model.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold creates an entirely new Internet economy that is owned by all of us and makes the traditional cloud model of building data centers obsolete. With ThreeFold, independent people called “Farmers” plug in 3Nodes (hardware) from their homes or offices anywhere around the world. And they earn income for it. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Together, they power a new, data-sovereign, and planet-positive Internet owned and powered by the people. This is a game-changer.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-how-do-i-get-a-3node&quot;&gt;So, how do I get a 3Node?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can buy one of the ready-made nodes from cooperatives around the world. This is a good and very easy way to support the ThreeFold project and to “BE THE INTERNET.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Today you can buy a 3Node via our website. We are also working with our farming cooperatives to decentralize the provisioning and distribution of hardware to a glocal approach (a global network of local networks). 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
But what if 3Nodes are not immediately available? For example, last week we had a huge influx of orders for our Titan V2 3Nodes and sold out the entire batch with 3,000 extra orders. We’re now talking with many hardware distributors to make sure we can satsify all these orders, but this could take a while.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
So if you are a little bit more adventurous, and want to build your 3Node from the ground up, yourself, here’s how to do it:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
To “become the Internet” is fairly simple (but does take some technical knowledge and effort). Here’s what you’ll need:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A computer with an INTEL or AMD brain, some memory, and some storage cabilities.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A smartphone on which you can download and run the “ThreeFold Connect” app. This will provide you with a wallet (to receive your farmed TFT and to pay a very small amount of TFT to get started).&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A laptop &#x2F; desktop (and USB stick) to launch your online 3Bot, configure your farm, download your bootloader and burn the bootloader to a USB stick.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some technical knowledge, interest and 45 minutes of time.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are still here and reading, we’re good to go! I go through the whole process in a 3-minute video which will give you a quick overview of how to set up your farm. (Click through to the video on YouTube and find helpful links in the description.)
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;embed&#x2F;uxIZcsEsOUE&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;&#x2F;iframe&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prefer a different format? We also have forum topics live about &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;requirements-to-set-up-your-own-3node&#x2F;831&quot;&gt;the pre-requirements&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;how-to-set-up-your-own-3node&#x2F;833&quot;&gt;how to set up your 3Node&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (the steps I share in the video).
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you, thank you, thank you for reading this post and we hope to have you as part of our growing, global farming community. If you have any questions, please head to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;c&#x2F;farming&#x2F;diy-farming&#x2F;&quot;&gt;our forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or feel free to join us on &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldfarmers&quot;&gt;our ThreeFold Farmer chat&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on Telegram.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo by &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;unsplash.com&#x2F;@nickxshotz?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Nicholas Green&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on Unsplash&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>3,000+ 3Node Pre-Registrations for Batch 3</title>
		<published>2021-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-08/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-08/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Over the past days we have received &lt;strong&gt;more than 3,000 pre-registrations&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; for the Titan V2 3Node!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, pre-registration remains open &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;next3nodebatch.threefold.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For those who have already pre-registered, thank you! We’ll have actions for you to take in the coming days.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Tactical Investing Covers ThreeFold</title>
		<published>2021-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-05/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-05/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, YouTube influencer &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;channel&#x2F;UCPRC2wIfZtAlzCa_6iKE46w&quot;&gt;Tactical Investing&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; posted a video to his account “THIS IS HUGE…Better Than Akash Network? &lt;em&gt;Time Sensitive&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;” to share about the ThreeFold farming opportunity with his community.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
And today, he posted another video comparing ThreeFold with Akash Network and Holo. “With a P2P compute lending device, the titanv2 has the potential to make you quite a bit in passive income over the next few years.” The videos garnered more than 35,000 views (on the date of this post) and led to the Titan v2 3Node to sell out in a matter of hours.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch the videos &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=2ndSPsnRz3U&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=nLfwJNCwnE0&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Q2 3Node Batch is Sold Out! Q3 Pre-registration is Live!</title>
		<published>2021-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-04/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-04/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;😮 Wow!😮
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning our team woke up to 400+ emails to register for our Titan V2 3Node batch after &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;channel&#x2F;UCPRC2wIfZtAlzCa_6iKE46w&quot;&gt;Tactical Investing&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; covered our project.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;All of our Titan V2 3Nodes sold out!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Although our last batch sold out, we are taking new registrations for the next batch already. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pre-register &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;next3nodebatch.threefold.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>3Node Pre-Register Q2 Batch Closing Soon</title>
		<published>2021-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-03/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-03/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Our next batch of Titan V2 3Nodes will ship in a matter of weeks. 
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Cheers!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; 🥂 - to all that have pre-registered already and are making the internet a more sustainable and more private place!
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hurry up!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; 🏃🏽‍♀️ - to all of you still looking for an easy way to become a ThreeFold Farmer.
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
You can order your Titan v2 on our &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;shop.threefold.tech&#x2F;index.php?route=product&#x2F;product&amp;amp;path=59&amp;amp;product_id=53&quot;&gt;pre-register page&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;And yes, all Titan’s come with one of those rad stickers.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>How ThreeFold offers Data Sovereignty</title>
		<published>2021-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/05/post-3/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/05/post-3/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you’ve seen &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=uaaC57tcci0&quot;&gt;The Social Dilemma&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, you know all too well that today, people are being turned into products. Everything we do online – all of the data we upload and all of our digital activities – is tracked and oftentimes used against us. Targeted advertising is just the beginning.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Personal data is used by algorithms to make incredible important decisions, like whether someone should receive financial or health support or benefits. In China, people are now even receiving “scores” for their behaviors. It sounds like Black Mirror, but it’s real life.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
That’s the scary part. The good news is that things don’t have to be this way. ThreeFold is building the engine for an Internet where people can finally be data sovereign.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
With &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;threefold__why_intro?id=everyone-should-be-autonomous&quot;&gt;today’s Internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, infrastructure is centralized. Companies provide services in exchange for your personal data, which is stored on servers in hyper-scale data centers owned by private companies.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In ThreeFold’s model, those servers are called &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;threefold__3node&quot;&gt;3Nodes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and rather than sitting inside centralized data centers, they sit inside the homes or offices (or small data centers) owned by independent people and organizations called &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;threefold__farming_intro?id=what-is-3node&quot;&gt;Farmers&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. But the data inside is owned by the person or persons who put it there. They maintain access right as well. From a technical standpoint, data is dispersed across 3Nodes by &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold&#x2F;#&#x2F;threefold__part5_ultra_efficient_storage?id=the-space-algorithm-of-storage&quot;&gt;an algorithm&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that makes it such that nobody can access it. In addition, connections are peer-to-peer, meaning data goes directly between sender and recipient rather than passing through intermediaries as it does today – bringing further levels of security.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Thus, people can finally be data sovereign, knowing their data is safe, and truly theirs.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold’s Planet Positive Plan</title>
		<published>2021-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/05/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/05/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There’s no question that climate change is one of the biggest, if not the biggest threats facing humanity today. If we care at all about future generations and the health of our planet, we have no choice but to address these threats, and fast. That’s why one of our biggest aims is to lower the energy usage of our digital lives. But ThreeFold is taking not just a sustainable approach, we’re setting the plan for a planet positive Internet.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Recently, we released information on how our infrastructure saves up-to-90% on energy consumption compared to existing models. We achieve this mainly thanks to an extremely efficient storage system and the concept of a Digital Twin.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
From &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;threefold__energy_savings_storage&quot;&gt;a storage standpoint&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, we reduce energy by avoiding copies, implementing a multi-layer system, not using fast disks, through read&#x2F;write caching, and more. With &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;threefold__energy_savings_digital_twin&quot;&gt;Digital Twin&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, we have taken a very different approach to how we exist in today’s digital world. Rather than existing 100 times in a huge system of client-server architecture, now we exist only once. We believe that we can run 25 Digital Twins with &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;threefold__bulb_comparison_twin&quot;&gt;the same energy&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as used by one light bulb.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Saving energy is one thing, but there will still be remaining energy. This needs to be offset by carbon credits. Now, in order to regenerate our planet, we &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;threefold__carbon_negative&quot;&gt;work together with Take Action Global&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to let students farm carbon credits. This has the potential to offset energy usage 100% by the end of 2021, and we have, as an aim to take 2x more carbon out of the air than we put in.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Our planet needs better solutions across industries. No more talking. Now is the time to act.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Be the Internet – Become a Farmer!</title>
		<published>2021-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/04/post-18/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/04/post-18/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Now, you can &lt;strong&gt;BE THE INTERNET&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; by becoming a ThreeFold Farmer.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;Br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Electricity + Network + a 3Node&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; = All that you need in order to grow the grid from your home or office – and earn TFT. Provide new capacity on a secure, private, scalable, and sustainable peer-to-peer Internet!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;✅ &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;farm&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Pre-Register today for your 3Node&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📚 &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;threefold__farming_intro&quot;&gt;Learn more about ThreeFold Farming&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Q1 Highlights</title>
		<published>2021-04-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-04-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/04/post-02/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/04/post-02/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here’s a quick look at the first three months of 2021 for ThreeFold:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
🚀 The TF Grid technology made huge steps forward (v2.4, v2.5, eVDC, QSFS, Marketplace, &amp;amp; more)
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
👯‍♀️ Our digital avatar called Digital Twin nears testing phase
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
✅ 3Node Pre-Order Batch 1 of 2021 has closed (welcome, new farmers!)
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find the full update &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;threefold__q12021recap&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, with more details.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Seeking participation with the TFT plan</title>
		<published>2021-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/02/post-03/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/02/post-03/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We have a good plan in place to stimulate token growth but we have some key decisions to make &amp;amp; we are creating a group to help us finalize. We have already invited &#x2F; included a number of farmers, token holders, ambassadors, and outside industry experts – and now we want to open it up to the wider community.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
If you’re interested in being a part of this guidance committee, please get in touch with @samtaggart on Telegram and he will ask some questions to ensure we get a well-rounded group of people.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Please reply by the end of today 6pm CET, if you’d like to be a part. A call will be scheduled for Friday or Saturday.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Please take note of a few things:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The plan WILL be with the best interest for the long-term growth of the token&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The plan WILL be in the best interest of farmers and token holders&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The plan WILL be in line with our values&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
As a reminder, please know that neither Sam nor any member of the ThreeFold team will ever reach out to you requesting TFT or any other form of currency. 🙏
&lt;p&gt;If you are skeptical about any interaction or need support, please use the live chat function on our website.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>We Need a More Inclusive Internet</title>
		<published>2021-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/01/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/01/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Today, more than 40% of the world is without access to the internet, a tool which brings incredible access to knowledge (education) and important information, communication tools that keep loved ones connected and are crucial for emergencies, and economic opportunities. And over the last year, as the world is spending more time at home, digital economies are booming and education is going remote. With an uncertain future, we need to fix the digital divide or we risk leaving billions of people even further behind.
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-data-center-problem-cost-proximity&quot;&gt;The Data Center Problem: Cost &amp;amp; Proximity&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The centralized data centers that power today’s Internet are located “strategically” mainly in North America, Europe, and select parts of Asia. For populations living in these regions, Internet is accessible and generally relatively affordable. But the further you travel from these data centers, the less available and more expensive the internet becomes. Internet access is mostly an issue Sub-saharan Africa, throughout Asia, and some parts of South America.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Of course some data centers can be and are being built in and near developing and remote regions, but for reasons including cost and audience, this hasn’t been a huge priority to date. Beyond that, the data center model as a whole simply cannot scale to meet the future demands of the internet nor is it sustainable for our planet, so this is not the right option.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-internet-shutdown-problem-control-manipulation&quot;&gt;The Internet Shutdown Problem: Control &amp;amp; Manipulation&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lack of internet access isn’t always just an availability or affordability problem. Today’s internet can be limited or even shut down at any point, by the right people. Take a quick look at &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;netblocks.org&#x2F;reports&quot;&gt;NetBlocks.org&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, an organization that reports on global internet disruptions or outages. Typically governments are enacting these measures during times of unrest or protest or  important political moments. Even in the United States, the Executive Branch of the government has &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.klemchuk.com&#x2F;ip-law-trends&#x2F;government-power-to-shut-down-the-internet&quot;&gt;the power to shut down the internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in a case of a national emergency.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Cutting the internet or restricting certain services based on region (a common practice as well) is not only not right, it’s dangerous. People rely on the internet for information and communication and no government or entity should have the ability to shut the internet down at their discretion.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-threefold-solution-fair-neutral-internet-for-all&quot;&gt;The ThreeFold Solution: Fair &amp;amp; Neutral Internet for All&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2016, the United Nations declared internet access to be a human right, yet today if you are reading this post, you are privileged. All humans deserve access to the internet and ThreeFold has the solution.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
With the ThreeFold model, nodes can be set up anywhere in the world where an existing internet connection and electricity are present. By putting physical infrastructure at the edge (close to users), greater levels of access can be reached.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Further, the ThreeFold Grid cannot be shut down or manipulated. It is a neutral internet owned by the people, where autonomous technology heals and runs itself and requires minimal human intervention.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Today we are working with partners in the clean energy and network &#x2F; connectivity to build the solutions that are needed to provide fair and uninterrupted internet access with all corners of the world.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Of course we will need new safe, secure, and private solutions for people to collaborate online. Many of these are already live and deployable via ThreeFold Now Community Solutions. We are working with partners in the education space as well to build toolsets for students to enrich their lives.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We need a more inclusive internet, and that is what we are building.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>What Is Peer-to-Peer and Why Is It so Important?</title>
		<published>2020-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2020/12/post-2/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2020/12/post-2/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-peer-to-peer&quot;&gt;What is Peer-to-Peer?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peer-to-peer (P2P) is a term that originated from the distributed computer application architecture where tasks and workloads are shared between peers, popularized by &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Napster&quot;&gt;Napster&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, a revolutionary file storing system from the late 1990s.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The concept inspired new structures and philosophies in many areas of human interaction. P2P systems and groups are typically critical of authoritarian and centralized social structures and believe in equality, meritocracy, flat systems, participatory &amp;amp; circular economies, as the concept represents a concrete pathway to these outcomes or visions.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
P2P systems are network, not linear or ‘pyramidal’ hierarchies (though they may share some elements). They are ‘distributed’, though they may have elements of ‘centralization’ and ‘decentralization.’ And intelligence is not located at any center, but everywhere within the system.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-does-threefold-relate-to-peer-to-peer&quot;&gt;How does ThreeFold relate to peer-to-peer?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold’s Peer-to-Peer (P2P) computing network is a distributed architecture that splits tasks and workloads between its peers, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;what_is_farming&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Farmers&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Farmers are equal participants in the network and together they form a peer-to-peer network of nodes, the ThreeFold Grid.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Farmers make their resources, such as processing power, disk storage or network bandwidth, directly available to other network participants, without the need for central coordination by servers or stable hosts. Farmers are both suppliers and consumers of resources, in contrast to the traditional &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Client-server&quot;&gt;client-server&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; model in which the consumption and supply of resources is divided.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In the near future, ThreeFold will create Digital Twin, which will go beyond the era of peers doing similar things while sharing resources. It will actually enable much more than that. Digital Twin will create a complete new digital world with diverse peers that can bring in unique resources and capabilities to a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Virtual_community&quot;&gt;virtual community&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on the ThreeFold Grid. This will empower the network of peers to engage in greater tasks beyond those that can be accomplished by individual peers, and are beneficial to all the peers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-did-threefold-choose-peer-to-peer&quot;&gt;Why did ThreeFold choose peer-to-peer? &lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything starts (or should start) from the why, and the ThreeFold story started a long time ago. Before the inception of ThreeFold, many of the co-founders of the project used to work with the largest IT &amp;amp; Cloud actors. Throughout their experience working in the Industry, they realized that the complexity of the technology and the centralization of knowledge &amp;amp; power led to an inefficient, unsustainable, not scalable and unequally distributed infrastructure. So they decided to redesign the whole Internet and cloud infrastructure bottom-up with the vision of shaping a global internet economy that can scale anywhere efficiently, cost efficiently and sustainably. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-does-the-world-needs-peer-to-peer&quot;&gt;Why does the world needs peer-to-peer? &lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By developing the technology, the conviction that peer-to-peer was the best solution for humanity and the planet strengthened itself. Why? Well, put simply, a peer-to-peer system removes all forms of intermediaries, unnecessary steps and complexity from the picture. Therefore, it simplifies the architecture in an incredible way. The benefits are many but here are the most popular benefits:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Privacy&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;: Our peer-to-peer environment means no middlemen or intermediaries, meaning data travels directly between peers and stored on the nodes of their choice rather than being sent through and stored by a third party.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Security&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;: Data stored in data centers is susceptible to security breaches. In bypassing data centers and exchanging data directly between peers, we can achieve much greater security as it reduces code and back doors significantly. &lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Scalability&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;: In a many-to-many system, scale is essentially unlimited. There is simply no bottleneck. And hardware (nodes) can be added at ease compared to current data center model.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cost-efficiency &amp;amp; Sustainability&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;: End-to-end (direct) connection between peers means a more efficient path for data and less energy is needed. Less energy means less cost, and less harm to our planet.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;in-2021-the-world-is-going-peer-to-peer&quot;&gt;In 2021 the world is going peer-to-peer! &lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re now in 4 years into the project, and it is clear that ThreeFold holds the most advanced technology and is probably the only tech company in the world that can achieve a peer-to-peer network &amp;amp; digital world as envisioned by the concept authors. The ThreeFold Grid is running and already at it’s 2.4 version and 2021 will bring various commercial opportunities for the public to partake in the peer-to-peer network, from hosting IT workloads to experiencing P2P end-user solutions. In other words, in 2021, the world will be able to go peer-to-peer.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>You Are Unique</title>
		<published>2019-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2019/12/post-2/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2019/12/post-2/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;you-are-unique&quot;&gt;You are unique&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a gathering with some friends, I noticed something that made me think about how important it is what we’re doing at ThreeFold.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
One of my friends was complaining about how he couldn’t log in to one of his social media platforms, because all of his passwords are different and he forgot which one he used for this particular platform. Another friend was saying how she tagged her sister on a funny meme, but her sister couldn’t find it on Facebook. Turns out she tagged her on Instagram. And then one of them said something that I keep hearing more and more from people, “Why do we have so many apps, I can’t find anything anymore!”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We exist so many times online, but why? There is only one me in the real world. Why should there not be only one me online? Why should I have 25 different profiles on 25 different platforms, with 25 different logins, when I am unique?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
That is another dilemma that ThreeFold has a solution for, with its autonomous technology. 3Bot - a digital avatar like no other, that basically handles your entire online life. The focus lies on digital privacy, where only you can access your data, and no one else. The 3Bot has all the functionalities you need to interact and exchange information and value, there will be no need for that many applications on your device anymore. With 3Bot, everything changes.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The 3Bot is built on the ThreeFold Grid, and has the same values as ThreeFold. Freedom, Equality, and Sustainability. It is important that your data is safe, and what can be safer than you being the only one who not only has access to it, but also the only one who owns that data? Your online world should not be that different from your offline world. In your offline world, you are the center of your own life. That is what ThreeFold is doing with the 3Bot, putting you in the center of your online life, too.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
One decentralized application, one digital wallet, one login and one you. Because you’re unique.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Have questions? Feel free to ask us on our &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&quot;&gt;forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Photo by Jessica Ruscello on &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;unsplash.com&#x2F;photos&#x2F;DoSDQvzjeH0&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Decentralizing the Internet</title>
		<published>2019-08-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-08-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2019/08/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2019/08/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;decentralization&quot;&gt;Decentralization&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1989, the Internet changed the world as we know it with the introduction of the World Wide Web. With time the Internet empowered people to share information in a decentralized way. Shortly after, big companies like Facebook, Google, and Apple emerged, providing many solutions that revolutionized the way we live. The “sharing economy” has grown exponentially over the last 5-10 years. This is thanks to a more simplified information flow and well-developed technology, which:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enables a much easier integration of independent players into the sharing economy.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eliminates the need for extensive management and structure of marketplace operators.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We are entering a flat-structure economy. An economy where fewer managerial levels are needed for the system to function. New technologies such as blockchain and the Internet of Things facilitate this ongoing trend. Participants can now interact on a peer-to-peer basis, forming marketplaces and organizations according to pre-agreed, programmed contracts.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-current-internet-is-centralized&quot;&gt;The current Internet is centralized&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the growth in popularity for decentralized systems, organizations, and currencies, the Internet remains centralized. The centralization within the Internet industry brought many barriers to entry. Indeed, to compete in the highly competitive market of Internet capacity dominated by big IT companies, massive investment, and IT development are needed.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
But what is really scary is that the current industry exploits the market tremendously. Data is officially the most valuable asset on earth for a few years, and about 20 companies rule over more than 80% of the cloud industry. In other words - these companies together have more than 80% of the world’s information. In recent years, we noticed the dangers that can arise with the wrong intentions within the data industry with the ‘Cambridge Analytica Scandal’, also highlighted in the movie &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=iX8GxLP1FHo&quot;&gt;‘The Great Hack’.&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold has been developing technology that allows the decentralization of the Internet infrastructure - removing the need for data centers, and allowing anyone to take part in the Internet capacity market. Adding capacity to the ThreeFold Grid (TF Grid) makes you a ThreeFold Farmer (TF Farmer). The more decentralized the Internet gets, the more secure and effective it will become. The already is the largest grid of compute and storage in the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-participate&quot;&gt;How To Participate&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process of becoming a ThreeFold Farmer is very straightforward. Anyone can join the ThreeFold Grid by downloading the ThreeFold Zero-OS onto their nodes and connecting them to the ThreeFold Grid.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
By doing this you will become an operator of a “micro data center” and with that earn ThreeFold Tokens. With or without experience in the field, anyone can become a ThreeFold Farmer. By becoming a ThreeFold Farmer, you empower a new neutral Internet that belongs to humanity - not corporations.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
You can build your server (3node) and configure it, but also options for people with less technical knowledge are available. Please see &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;pre-register.threefold.io&quot;&gt;pre-register.threefold.io&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to see how easy it is for anyone to become a ThreeFold Farmer.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Blog written in 2019, updated January 2021.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>The need for ThreeFold&#x27;s neutral internet</title>
		<published>2017-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2017-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2017/06/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2017/06/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Internet is growing like crazy and is now a trillion dollar problem. Together we can build a new neutral Internet.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;an-introduction-to-the-problems&quot;&gt;An introduction to the problems&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Internet is no longer the neutral place it used to be. +80% of the Internet capacity is delivered by a handful of companies. This results in a loss of neutrality and openness and breeds inequalities.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To support the continuous growth of the Internet and connect billions to new Internet Of Things devices, 400 million new servers are needed by 2020. The world therefore needs another 4,000 large-scale data centers that each consume 200 MWe of electricity: &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;bit.ly&#x2F;1UPUZYG&quot;&gt;see source&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Today, about 4 billion people have no access to the Internet due to the high costs of connectivity and capacity. We believe these people have the fundamental right to have low-cost access to digital resources such as online identity solutions, education, health information and more. For this to happen, solutions that can lower the cost by a factor of 10 are required.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bandwidth does not follow Moore’s law. The growth of bandwidth required is much higher than the speed at which new capacity can be delivered. This is even more important in emerging markets.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Current blockchain technology is not scalable and not sustainable. Example: the Bitcoin blockchain alone uses more energy today than Croatia.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;current-internet-and-cloud-capacity&quot;&gt;Current Internet and Cloud capacity&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, the cloud computing industry represents a 100 billion dollar industry - mostly owned by about 20 global cooperations. Experts such as Bell Labs and Cisco believe the capacity requirements in the next decade will dramatically exceed existing infrastructure - requiring many more data centers and billions, if not trillions in investments.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The spectacular growth and advancements in cloud computing that occurred over the last decade resulted in large part from “hyper-scale” efficiencies - i.e. centralizing Internet infrastructure in very large billion dollar data centers.  However, demand for Internet capacity already surpassed the available infrastructure with emerging technologies such as Big Data, the Internet of Things (IoT) and Artificial Intelligence (AI) Technology. The existing hyperscale cloud architecture cannot cope with this growing demand as the requirements for land, power and funding are becoming outrageous.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The challenges facing the Internet includes the following:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trillions of Investment Required&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. In the next decade, the global Internet infrastructure requires another 4,000 data centers (250M - 1B dollar investment each) to meet demand which would cost trillions - this money could be better used in education, healthcare, or sustainable innovations. &lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impossible to scale the networks connecting users to the hyperscale data centers&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. Since hyperscale data centers are built in large “central” locations, the network leading to these data centers is congested. Even more, remote regions that are less connected to the Internet cannot benefit from these data centers’ IT services.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Non-local data and capacity&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. Governments around the world are becoming more and more concerned about data leaving their borders. To tackle this centralization issue, they would need local IT infrastructure. Also, IoT workloads need local capacity to deliver constant real-time computing and storage requirements - for certain applications and workloads (e.g. driverless cars), latency is not an option. Hyperscale data centers can simply not match these requirements.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not secure &#x2F; at risk of choke point failures&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. There are plenty of recent well-publicized problems around security, outages and loss of data. The reason for this is that centralized hyperscale architectures are inherently insecure - and failures at a single hyperscale location can cause widespread contagion and outages.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-threefold-solution&quot;&gt;The ThreeFold Solution&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our solution to these trillion dollar problems is to migrate Internet capacity to the Edge (closer to user location) - i.e. a “hyper-distributed” network architecture, located close to users (in cities, schools, offices, homes and even vehicles).
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Edge networks will not necessarily replace the existing hyperscale capacity powering today’s cloud - rather, they will scale to meet the increased capacity demands going forward. However, if the current hyperscale capacity can be decentralized to improve energy consumption and reduce costs, this would be a huge global success.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
By 2025, 60% of new Internet infrastructure will be decentralized and located at the edge of operator networks by using alternative locations which have stable (renewable) power and reliable connectivity.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;threefold-s-technology-main-benefits&quot;&gt;ThreeFold’s technology main benefits:&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: The ThreeFold Grid is distributed and benefits from our ItsYou.Online identity management platform - making it much more secure.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decentralized&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: The solution enables to bring capacity closer to where users are located, enabling a Cloud at the Edge.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sustainability&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: The technology removes the need to build huge power hungry datacenters and by decentralizing the architecture enables up-to 1000% energy savings.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Making IT a true utility&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;:  We always approached IT as Energy. Today we provide 3x more uptime and between 3-10x more cost effectiveness.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neutrality&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: The solution enables 100% neutral &amp;amp; private Internet IT capacity. Our blockchain technology provides security, neutrality &amp;amp; scale.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-threefold-zero-node&quot;&gt;The ThreeFold Zero-Node&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Zero-Node provides compute, network and storage capacity to the internet and ThreeFold’s blockchain. This capacity can be used for any possible workload. Here are some characteristics of ThreeFold’s Zero node:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Modularity&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Scaling from 8 vCPUs and 3.5 TB of storage (smallest) to clusters with 8000 vCPUs and 2 PB of storage (large), there is a range of possibilities at hand.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sustainability&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Storing the hardware uses about 10x less energy, and about 2-3x for other workloads.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decentralized&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: The Zero Operating System (“Zero OS”) is ideally suited for Edge networking - where automation, self-healing and hyper-distribution are must-haves.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Zero-Nodes are deployed as close as possible to the consumers of Internet IT capacity (IoT, residential, business, government, education, …).&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This results in massive bandwidth savings, we estimate to be able to keep 99% of the required bandwidth locally which has a huge impact on cost.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is the only viable solution to be able to provide internet to the 3.2 billion people waiting.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self healing&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: The architecture is designed to ensure that workloads and data can be accessed at all times. &lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neutral &amp;amp; private&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: A lot of work has done using blockchain (technology which powers crypto currency) to guarantee privacy and net neutrality.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed around simplicity to be used by everyone.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The technology provides anyone with the autonomy to deliver complex IT applications without the need for complex integration services.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Empowers equality&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Our technology should be usable by the “other billions” that remain unconnected. Due to the low cost-points, low energy requirements and reduced need of backbone network capacity.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
