<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>ThreeFold - peer-to-peer</title>
	<subtitle>Our global digital backbone</subtitle>
	<link href="https://www3.threefold.io/tags/peer-to-peer/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://www3.threefold.io"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2022-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://www3.threefold.io/tags/peer-to-peer/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Q&amp;A with Adnan Fatayerji and CyberNews</title>
		<published>2022-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/05/post-08/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/05/post-08/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This Q&amp;amp;A originally appeared &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cybernews.com&#x2F;security&#x2F;adnan-fatayerji-threefold-the-best-protection-is-ownership-and-sovereignty-over-your-own-online-data&#x2F;&quot;&gt;on CyberNews&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Every action done online leaves a trace of our personal data that can then be accessed by third parties. Unfortunately, this puts our privacy at risk and can lead to dangerous consequences.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If our sensitive information falls into the wrong hands, one can encounter identity theft and suffer enormous financial losses. Thus, it’s essential to explore how the Internet could become a safer place for everyone.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this reason, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cybernews.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;CyberNews&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; asked Adnan Fatayerji, the CEO of ThreeFold Foundation, to explain how blockchain technology can empower users and give them ownership over their own online data.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did ThreeFold originate? What has your journey been like?&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My journey with ThreeFold began in 2015. I was a serial entrepreneur up to this point, inspired by the energy and opportunity Dubai had to offer when I first arrived more than a decade prior. I had recently co-founded a company that worked with panoramic stitching and used an incredible piece of technology – we got a lot of interest and were quickly acquired.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At that point, a mutual friend and a business partner introduced me to Kristof de Spiegeleer. He shared his view of the problems with the Internet, with centralized data centers, the Internet’s stack, storage, and computation, and how they needed improvement in ways that serve the underserved around the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kristof expressed that he had been trying to resolve these problems for a long time and he thought he had the pieces to the puzzle, especially with the advent of blockchain which offered new and exciting possibilities. He thought we would hit it off, and we did.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve built ThreeFold and even created a new operating system – Zero OS. It is more energy-efficient and runs completely in an autonomous and decentralized way. It’s the first of its kind, built off of Linux.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ThreeFold journey has been a vast school of knowledge for me while working with incredible co-founders and mentors who have helped build pieces of the IT world as we know it. It has truly changed my life.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can you tell us a little bit about what you do? What are your main fields of focus at the moment?&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the last five years, I’ve been in charge of the ThreeFold Foundation which is building a global movement around the ThreeFold Grid – a peer-to-peer, open-source, and decentralized Internet. I’m also active in our fundraising, business, and ecosystem development efforts. It’s an honor every day to wake up and be a part of a global movement of people who are trying to build a better Internet for humanity that can uplift and empower.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, we are focused on building Neighborhood Clouds on ThreeFold that allow home and business owners to transform their own neighborhood into a decentralized, distributed data center by becoming a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;farm&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Farmer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Each home, office, or commercial property can host a 3Node – a dedicated server that provides the edge computing and Internet storage needed to run decentralized applications and Internet services.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3Nodes are interconnected using existing local Internet cable infrastructure. They offer a quantum-safe storage system with the capacity to host a metaverse, gaming, rendering cloud, compute cloud, and a platform for our digital applications that enable our daily digital life. Farmers, in turn, are rewarded every month in ThreeFold Tokens (TFT), a digital currency, for adding capacity to the ThreeFold Grid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We recently announced a historic partnership in Dubai with Paradise Hills Development to provide every homeowner in a 170-home gated community with a pre-installed 3Node. The initiative will provide residents, businesses, developers, and the government with a secure and highly accessible sovereign cloud infrastructure to run a vast array of applications and internet services, as well as store and process their data locally.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It is evident that open source is an important part of ThreeFold. Would you like to share more about your vision?&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just as Satoshi Nakamoto envisioned the democratization of the financial system through decentralization, ThreeFold is on a similar quest to democratize the Internet with open-source, autonomous, and blockchain technologies. ThreeFold has built the open-source technology behind the decentralized storage and compute capacity of the ThreeFold Grid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More Internet users can benefit from a neutral, peer-to-peer platform on which to store their data and run their applications privately and securely. Moreover, decentralization can help to remove the Internet’s singular potential points of failure which could seriously disrupt the global Internet and Cloud industry.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A decentralized Internet can also better serve underserved populations of the world, including indigenous populations across the globe. We believe in open-source and we are partnering with technology companies, governments, and indigenous communities to expand the Internet in underserved regions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you think the recent global events had an effect on the way people approach the blockchain landscape?&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent global events have definitely had an effect and spotlighted the fact that we need to consider new approaches to our IT systems with the blockchain landscape being one of them. A good example of the power of blockchain technology along with digital currency is Ukraine’s thriving fundraising. As the war began, a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.wired.com&#x2F;story&#x2F;i-created-a-dao-for-laughs-want-to-join&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Decentralized Autonomous Organization&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (DAO) was set up so that the government could accept cryptocurrency directly from donors.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DAOs have several advantages over traditional organizations. First is the lack of trust needed between the two parties. A traditional organization requires a lot of trust in the people behind it, especially on behalf of investors. With DAOs, only the code needs to be trusted.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ThreeFold DAO allows autonomous operation of the TFChain and ThreeFold Grid. At ThreeFold, we believe that decentralization is needed across a wide array of systems, including organizations, to build a better Internet. Decentralization typically brings more resilience, equality, and fairness. As such, we apply this in a variety of ways across our own structures and practices.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a similar note, the blockchain community needs to look at the vulnerability of the blockchain’s underlying infrastructure. Today, many are run on centralized cloud services and in a time of conflict can be vulnerable to hacks or attacks. I think this is where ThreeFold aligns so well with the blockchain industry since we provide the missing layer needed to be secure, scale, and remain decentralized.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Since blockchain is a relatively new technology, there are still some confusion and myths surrounding them. What misconceptions do you notice most often?&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the common misconceptions and misunderstandings about blockchain is that people often think cryptocurrency and blockchain are the same. Blockchain is a ledger and cryptocurrency is an alternative means of financial transaction. Cryptocurrency (or Digital Currency) is powered by blockchain, but blockchain does not need a cryptocurrency to function. 
Here’s how blockchain and digital currency work on ThreeFold:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Layer 2 (L2): the ecosystem security layer.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; The ThreeFold DAO and ThreeFold Token (TFT) live here. It’s our main chain with 100 validators and it secures the multiple Layer 1 (L1) networks. &lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Layer 1 (L1): the Internet of Blockchains layer.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; It’s ultimately scaleable because of thousands or millions of blockchains. It’s like a side chain for the ThreeFold Grid. &lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Layer Zero (L0): the IT capacity layer and the cloud computer layer.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; ThreeFold executors live on this layer, secured by L0 Validators. L0 provides compute, storage, and network resources to L1 and L2.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the ThreeFold Token (TFT) is the first token in the world that gives access to the most comprehensive, decentralized Internet capacity for computing, storage, networking, and soon GPUs. Look at it as &lt;em&gt;the Bitcoin for Internet Capacity&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users, developers, and enterprises can use TFT to store data, build applications, and create peer-to-peer ecosystems on the ThreeFold Grid. ThreeFold Farmers are rewarded in TFT for contributing capacity to the ThreeFold Grid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As more companies move their workload to the cloud, are there any details that might be overlooked when making the switch?&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A vastly overlooked detail about the current cloud landscape is that it is energy-hungry and unsustainable given the rate at which our digital demands are growing today. If your company is working to be more environmentally conscious and meet climate goals, cloud hosting might have been overlooked as a contributing factor.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet’s growth is exponential: 5.25 billion people have Internet access and are active users, so that’s about 66% of the world’s population. Since 2000, the number of Internet users has increased by 1,355%. The rate at which hyper-scale data centers need to be built to keep up with hosting these clouds is unrealistic, and their price tags are exorbitant considering there are more efficient ways to tackle this issue.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With ThreeFold, companies can now literally be their own data centers, without the data security risks, latency and downtime issues, or hosting expenses. We believe that the current centralized cloud infrastructure carries increasing risk and it delivers poorly for underserved populations of the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s crazy to think that more than 80% of today’s Internet infrastructure is owned by less than 20 organizations. The lack of ownership of our own data and the consequent commercialization of our data is a major concern for both individuals and governments alike. Neutrality and democratization of the Internet are an absolute necessity regarding the future of the Internet and cloud architecture.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What security measures do you think are crucial both for casual Internet users and large organizations?&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protecting our personal data is crucial for any individual or entity participating online. There are many precautions and measures that can be taken but the best protection is ownership and sovereignty over your own online data.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From data breaches to DoS attacks to hacked interfaces, cloud computing is under constant attack. ThreeFold’s decentralized cloud offers improved security through a new, secure operating system, Zero OS, that runs on ThreeFold 3Nodes. It has no shell so that farmers – the owners of the capacity that hosts the OS and the workloads – have no access to the data nor the applications running on their hardware.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This OS is booted over the network with cryptographic boot file verification to prevent physical disk access and man-in-the-middle attacks. All nodes have their own IPv6 address and are fully interconnected in the defined network. Additionally, all traffic on the network is encrypted and inaccessible by TF Farmers or hackers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold also offers a Quantum-Safe File System. This File System can be used inside VMs or Kubernetes. This is an amazing feature because it allows you to store endless amounts of data in a Virtual Machine.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s also added security. Deployment of IT workloads using a so-called “Smart Contract for IT” makes the deployment process resilient to human error and hacking. The system is self-driving and self-healing, therefore removing the human requirement for deploying and operating IT infrastructure or services. This represents a breakthrough in IT.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are your predictions for the future of blockchain technology?&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once mainstream organizations become more familiar with the technology and how to use it effectively, adoption will increase. It’s already happening and it’s being merged with other emerging technologies to create scale and efficiency across sectors. We will see a new and more refined era of blockchain technology where functional use cases drive the narrative.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Share with us, what does the future hold for ThreeFold?&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold is growing the ThreeFold Grid by enabling a community of thousands of farmers from around the world to participate and own a piece of the Internet. Check out our map to see if your region is lit up yet. We believe that the decentralized Internet is key to a sustainable future so that we can deliver on the true promise of the Internet and make it more widely available and affordable for all.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are continuously improving the ThreeFold Grid. We just announced the release of ThreeFold Grid V3.0.0 Alpha-5 with significant upgrades, improvements, and fixes. Users can now choose to deploy applications and services on dedicated 3Nodes or reserve an entire 3Node, then use it exclusively to deploy solutions for themselves or other customers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting with V3, the ThreeFold Grid is now operating as a DAO. We have also made it easier for users to buy ThreeFold Tokens by trading their BTC on our official &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;gettft.com&#x2F;gettft&#x2F;&quot;&gt;TFT Shop website&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are announcing several promising partnerships and use cases in 2022 and are working closely with several nations to help establish a decentralized and sovereign infrastructure that will improve Internet accessibility, security, and locally provisioned capacity. You can learn more about it at threeFold.io.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold at Consensus: A Decentralized World is in Our Hands</title>
		<published>2022-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/05/post-5/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/05/post-5/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s that time of the year when believers and builders of a decentralized tomorrow  gather to celebrate the festival for the decentralized world. About 15,000 people will attend Consensus 2022 by CoinDesk from June 9 through June 12. Throughout the festival, key topics around decentralization, blockchain, crypto, Web 3 and the metaverse will be explored and discussed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is ThreeFold attending Consensus? Excellent question. The ThreeFold community truly believes that collaboration, decentralization and peer-to-peer systems are the foundation for a better Internet, and subsequently, a better world. And together we are making that world a reality. But we need to grow and extend the community on the ground with the right people, dreamers who choose to act now.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As many consider Consensus the festival for the decentralized world, some questions linger: &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How committed are the projects and participants to decentralization, and for what reasons? How far are they willing to go to bring that world to life?&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s no secret that many projects in the space still rely on centralized infrastructure – at least to some degree. So, are they really delivering on their promise of decentralization? &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-decentralized-world-needs-a-decentralized-foundation&quot;&gt;A decentralized world needs a decentralized foundation&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think we’ve already come to Consensus that decentralization has to start at the foundational level. See what I did there? The ThreeFold co-founders have more than 20 years of experience in setting world records in Internet storage and cloud automation technologies. With ThreeFold, they started from scratch to build a fully decentralized Internet infrastructure that’s peer-to-peer and open source. We’re realizing the promise of an Internet built and owned by the people, back to the vision of Web 1 through the implementation of Web 4 technology. For us, it’s obvious that we simply cannot build a fair and equal digital world on top of today’s old-world infrastructure which is owned by the few. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With our fair, inclusive and decentralized Internet infrastructure, we’re laying the foundation for a better world. Following our ethos of &lt;em&gt;planet first – people second – profit (value) only as a result&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, we’re striving to regenerate our planet and to empower the collective – the many and not the few. By putting our planet and people first, we create real sustainable value. We believe that, together, we’re strong enough to build new regenerative systems powerful enough to enable anyone to have a sovereign, safer and more fulfilling life.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of today, people from 77 countries are connecting thousands of computers (3Nodes) to the ThreeFold Grid – all contributing to ThreeFold’s open-source peer-to-peer Internet infrastructure. And any node or dApp, actually anything that can run on Linux, can run on top of the ThreeFold Grid in a truly decentralized way. With ThreeFold’s infrastructure and thriving ecosystem, there’s an abundance of potential and opportunities – really anything is possible.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;threefold-consensus&quot;&gt;ThreeFold @Consensus&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ThreeFold team and community will soon gather at the Austin Convention Center, 500 E. Cesar Chavez Street, Austin. Meet the ThreeFold team at &lt;strong&gt;Exhibit Booth 310&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; not far from the Networking Lounge. We’ll be there throughout the entire exhibit to connect with participants, share the ThreeFold story and extend the community – Friday, June 10 through Saturday, June 11 from 9am until 6pm.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At our booth, you’ll be able to meet the team, see and hold a Titan 3Node, have the chance to win a free 3Node of your own, find resources that will empower you to get involved, and more.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold will also host a gathering outside of the Convention Center. We will share more via &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldnews&quot;&gt;our Telegram News Channel&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; when the details are finalized, so stay tuned.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold is more than an Internet. It is the foundation for a truly decentralized world. Are you ready to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;join&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; the global ThreeFold movement?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Check out the full &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;events.coindesk.com&#x2F;consensus2022&#x2F;agenda&quot;&gt;Consensus agenda&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and take advantage of &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;events.coindesk.com&#x2F;consensus2022?promo=a7MsHxui&quot;&gt;our 25% discount code&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to buy tickets.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And don’t forget to let us know if you’ll be joining ThreeFold at Consensus – we’d love to connect with you!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>The Internet is Moving to the Edge</title>
		<published>2022-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/05/post-3/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/05/post-3/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;With new devices being connected every day and emerging technologies like the Internet of Things (IoT), the metaverse and Web 3 gaining popularity, the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.cbre.com&#x2F;en&#x2F;insights&#x2F;reports&#x2F;north-america-data-center-trends-h2-2021&quot;&gt;demand&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for Internet capacity is booming. Already, these developments are shifting the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.securityinfowatch.com&#x2F;perimeter-security&#x2F;physical-hardening&#x2F;article&#x2F;21263002&#x2F;real-words-or-buzzwords-edge-cloud-and-the-evolving-internet&quot;&gt;Internet’s “center of gravity”&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; from its core to the edges in order to keep up with the growing demand. In an increasingly interconnected world, centralized cloud architectures are proving to be &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.forbes.com&#x2F;sites&#x2F;forbestechcouncil&#x2F;2022&#x2F;03&#x2F;25&#x2F;demystifying-edge-technology&#x2F;&quot;&gt;bottlenecks&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; hindering future growth.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some interesting numbers to emphasize the explosive growth of connected devices and the impending data explosion:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Back in 2018, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.securityinfowatch.com&#x2F;perimeter-security&#x2F;physical-hardening&#x2F;article&#x2F;21263002&#x2F;real-words-or-buzzwords-edge-cloud-and-the-evolving-internet&quot;&gt;90% of global data creation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; took place within the two previous years.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In 2022, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.securityinfowatch.com&#x2F;perimeter-security&#x2F;physical-hardening&#x2F;article&#x2F;21263002&#x2F;real-words-or-buzzwords-edge-cloud-and-the-evolving-internet&quot;&gt;4.95 billion people&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; are using the Internet and about &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.securityinfowatch.com&#x2F;perimeter-security&#x2F;physical-hardening&#x2F;article&#x2F;21263002&#x2F;real-words-or-buzzwords-edge-cloud-and-the-evolving-internet&quot;&gt;2.5 quintillion bytes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of data are created on a daily basis.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;About 2 billion computers, 15 billion mobile devices and more than 22 billion IoT devices are &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.securityinfowatch.com&#x2F;perimeter-security&#x2F;physical-hardening&#x2F;article&#x2F;21263002&#x2F;real-words-or-buzzwords-edge-cloud-and-the-evolving-internet&quot;&gt;active worldwide&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on a daily basis.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By 2025, more than &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.cisco.com&#x2F;c&#x2F;en&#x2F;us&#x2F;solutions&#x2F;executive-perspectives&#x2F;annual-internet-report&#x2F;index.html&quot;&gt;1 billion people&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.statista.com&#x2F;statistics&#x2F;471264&#x2F;iot-number-of-connected-devices-worldwide&#x2F;#:%7E:text=Internet%20of%20Things%20%2D%20number%20of%20connected%20devices%20worldwide%202015%2D2025&amp;amp;text=By%202025%2C%20forecasts%20suggest%20that,IoT%20installed%20base%20in%202019.&quot;&gt;75 billion IoT devices&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; are expected to join the Internet.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet, the expansion of Internet capacity still largely occurs in the same centralized and inefficient way. The client-server model of hyperscale data centers is unable to meet this rapidly growing demand due to high building and operational costs to fulfill bandwidth, performance and cybersecurity requirements. As data centers are primarily built in the US, China and Europe, emerging countries have to be connected via sea cables which makes the model’s limitations particularly severe for these countries. And even in countries where many data centers are located, they are built in regions where land and electricity are as cheap as possible. Consequently, the bulk of data centers is still &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.securityinfowatch.com&#x2F;perimeter-security&#x2F;physical-hardening&#x2F;article&#x2F;21263002&#x2F;real-words-or-buzzwords-edge-cloud-and-the-evolving-internet&quot;&gt;far away&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; from where the majority of users and connected devices reside, and where huge amounts of data are generated that require processing – resulting in a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;threefold__grid_valuation?id=what39s-the-potential-of-the-threefold-grid&quot;&gt;weak distribution&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of Internet capacity.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.seagate.com&#x2F;files&#x2F;www-content&#x2F;our-story&#x2F;rethink-data&#x2F;files&#x2F;Rethink_Data_Report_2020.pdf&quot;&gt;175 Zettabytes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of data will be created by 2025, as our economy becomes increasingly digital and data driven. And this amount of data needs to be captured, stored and activated in a secure, efficient and high-performing way. So, the aforementioned technological use cases will not only &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.cbre.com&#x2F;en&#x2F;insights&#x2F;reports&#x2F;north-america-data-center-trends-h2-2021&quot;&gt;accelerate the demand&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for Internet capacity but also require edge capabilities, such as low latencies, in order to run and scale successfully. In fact, the centralized data center model poses one of the biggest obstacles to the success and spread of the Internet of Things and related applications. This will have to change. Actually, industry experts &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.i-scoop.eu&#x2F;edge-computing-explained&#x2F;&quot;&gt;expect 75%&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of data to be processed outside of the traditional data center or cloud model by 2025.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-rise-of-edge-computing&quot;&gt;The rise of edge computing&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computing needs to be pushed from centralized data centers to the edge to support the massive data consumption coupled to the rise of connected devices and emerging technologies. For instance, as more and more home appliances and devices are getting interconnected through the IoT economy, the amount of real-time data generated within our homes on a daily basis is rapidly expanding. Edge computing &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.i-scoop.eu&#x2F;edge-computing-explained&#x2F;&quot;&gt;tackles the shortcomings&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of the centralized model in terms of bandwidth, latency and autonomy. It enables applications and solutions to be hosted closer to where their data is being produced and consumed, thereby allowing for low latencies, rapid data processing and real-time decisions. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The industry analyst company &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.idc.com&#x2F;getdoc.jsp?containerId=prUS48772522&quot;&gt;IDC estimates&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; the global spending on edge computing to increase by 14.8% compared to 2021 – amounting to roughly $176 billion in 2022. By 2025, this number is predicted to reach about $274 billion.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of edge computing’s ability to process data on-site is simple enough. Nevertheless, edge computing fails to deliver on its promise as it still remains somewhat centralized today. Granted, so-called edge data centers are &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;stlpartners.com&#x2F;articles&#x2F;edge-computing&#x2F;edge-data-centres&#x2F;&quot;&gt;closer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to where the data is being consumed than hyperscale data centers. But while they do provide an improvement from traditional data centers, they are not able to provide &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.thefastmode.com&#x2F;expert-opinion&#x2F;23002-what-are-various-types-of-edge-computing-that-exist-today&quot;&gt;far-edge&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; capabilities, i.e. moving as close to the user and point of data creation as possible. They are simply smaller types of data centers that are still operated in a centralized manner, require the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;connectorsupplier.com&#x2F;how-the-rise-of-edge-computing-will-reshape-the-data-center-landscape&#x2F;&quot;&gt;same infrastructure elements&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as centralized data centers, and usually &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.techtarget.com&#x2F;searchdatacenter&#x2F;definition&#x2F;edge-data-center&quot;&gt;rely&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on bigger, central data centers. Quite edgy isn’t it?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the need for Internet capacity – specifically at the edge – is rapidly intensifying, a new approach to Internet infrastructure is clearly needed. The Web 3 movement created a spur of interest across industries due to its promise to decentralize the Internet and cloud as we know it. Future data will be generated at the edge of the network and Internet which certainly requires an &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.forbes.com&#x2F;sites&#x2F;forbestechcouncil&#x2F;2022&#x2F;03&#x2F;25&#x2F;demystifying-edge-technology&#x2F;&quot;&gt;architectural shift&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; away from the current model.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;realizing-an-interconnected-future&quot;&gt;Realizing an interconnected future&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ironically, decades after the spark of the open-source peer-to-peer Internet movement was steamrolled by large tech companies and governments eager to centralize the global Internet, we seem to enter an era of decentralization again. There’s no doubt that large tech companies did bring a lot of innovation to our global Internet and cloud stack. Technically though, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;p2p_web3&#x2F;&quot;&gt;peer-to-peer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; systems have always been the most scalable option. Moreover, open-source architectures have built a strong reputation for providing high levels of security and flexibility. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a peer-to-peer model, people and devices are able to exchange directly, without intermediaries or servers in the middle – leading to a more energy-efficient, scalable and flexible paradigm that can expand on-demand. And undoubtedly, open-source will play a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;news.crunchbase.com&#x2F;news&#x2F;edge-computing-said-quissal-zededa&#x2F;&quot;&gt;key role&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in edge computing by simplifying and enhancing the building and deployment of software at the edge.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By leveraging open-source and peer-to-peer technologies, ThreeFold has come up with an Internet infrastructure that is capable of far-edge computing. ThreeFold offers a powerful set of &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;building_a_new_internet_from_the_ground_up_3&#x2F;&quot;&gt;compute primitives&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that provide the agility to create and deploy containers, Virtual Machines (VMs) and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;threefold__zkube?id=zkube&quot;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; environments at the edge. Having integrated all leading industry-standard tools, ThreeFold’s solution allows for a seamless migration of any digital workload, making ThreeFold the ideal infrastructure for edge workloads. And all data produced by these workloads can be stored in a way that is ultra safe, highly reliable and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;qsss&#x2F;threefold__qsss_home?id=quantum-safe-storage-system&quot;&gt;unbreakable&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Combined with end-to-end encrypted peer-to-peer &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;threefold__planetary_network?id=planetary-network&quot;&gt;networking&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, applications can be hosted closer to where the data is being consumed – representing the ideal underlying layer for IoT networks, blockchain-based workloads and more to run and scale at the edge seamlessly, efficiently and privately.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shift towards the edge is inevitable. ThreeFold is the first full-stack, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;coincheckup.com&#x2F;blog&#x2F;threefold-is-the-decentralized-web-the-future-of-the-internet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;decentralized&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, peer-to-peer Internet infrastructure in the world that combines compute in the form of highly-optimized containers, storage and network capacity in an all-in-one solution. With  more than &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;81 Petabytes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of capacity distributed across thousands of 3Nodes and 76 countries as well as &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;connecting_the_dots&#x2F;&quot;&gt;plans&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to sponsor the expansion of the Internet to developing regions, ThreeFold is the foundation for a thriving interconnected future that is secure, borderless and at the edge.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;what_is_farming&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Expand the new Internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; by setting up a 3Node at your home or office.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Help us &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;connecting_the_dots&#x2F;&quot;&gt;connect the dots&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and accelerate our far-edge capabilities.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join our global &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;movement&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; today.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Coverage in CryptoPotato</title>
		<published>2022-04-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-04-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/04/post-09/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/04/post-09/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Internet economy is largely managed by centralized companies that connect servers and storage space to run web content. These companies are responsible for critical decisions that affect the Internet at large. They decide how user data is collected, stored, analyzed, and used, leaving people with little to no privacy or control over their identity and information.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Giant corporations such as Amazon, Microsoft, Meta, and Google have been pioneering the Web 2.0 era, also known as the Cloud era. Over the past 25 years, they have built the most efficient data centers and networks to support the growth of the digital world. However, throughout the last decade, the inherent risks attached to the single points of failures and security issues related to centralized servers and APIs have raised major concerns for Internet users and countries.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the rising popularity of blockchain and peer-to-peer technologies, a gold rush around the decentralization of the Internet has already started. While many projects have attempted to decentralize the Internet and the Cloud with blockchain technology, a layer-0 is still missing for Web 3.0 and DeFi to scale to mass adoption.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, a project called ThreeFold has joined the race after recently &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;apnews.com&#x2F;press-release&#x2F;kisspr&#x2F;technology-middle-east-lifestyle-blockchain-dubai-079a0c910c55187206c58992347a8a1e&quot;&gt;announcing&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; the launch of the first neighborhood cloud in the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read the full article &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cryptopotato.com&#x2F;threefold-building-a-truly-decentralized-internet-infrastructure&#x2F;&quot;&gt;on CryptoPotato&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>April 19th Community Call Recording</title>
		<published>2022-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/04/post-06/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/04/post-06/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;🚨 &lt;strong&gt;This Week’s Community Call Recording!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;For anyone who missed the community call earlier this week, please find the recording and slides &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-april-19-2022-community-call-recording-presentation&#x2F;2714&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many thanks to those who were able to be there with us in-person!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please note the content of this call is for information purposes only and is subject to change as the project evolves.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>What Bitcoin did to money, ThreeFold is doing to the Internet</title>
		<published>2022-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/03/post-5/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/03/post-5/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The world’s most famous cryptocurrency Bitcoin, established in 2008 by a person or group of people under the pseudonym of Satoshi Nakamoto, is changing the world. With 106 million people owning Bitcoin after only twelve years, the growth momentum is undeniable. The popularity of Bitcoin is transforming monetary systems at large, and establishing trust through irrefutable records.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike traditional financial technologies, Bitcoin provides total control over one’s funds without the intervention of a central authority, such as a bank or government. Bitcoin is decentralized and spread across many computers worldwide. It’s not a company, it’s a protocol. No single person or entity can control, manipulate or influence the network’s operations. There has never been a hack at the network level since Bitcoin launched in 2009.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin sparked a revolution towards decentralized and peer-to-peer systems. The advantage of such systems is that they operate without central authority, can be audited by anyone, and push for collaboration as their designs are public, inviting everyone to take part.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New systems built from scratch, like DeFi (decentralized finance), don’t have the problem of legacy firms, but they face challenges in scaling towards mass adoption. Most of the so-called ‘Web3’ solutions provide the illusion of decentralization but are actually still quite centralized. Others still have to prove their scalability, security and accessibility to become real alternatives to the current tech giants. While that may change, it’s not a given considering the clear limitations they have to overcome.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet represents the second largest and fastest growing economy in the world. With plenty of technologies emerging such as Blockchain, Web3, IoT and the Metaverse to name just a few, the infrastructure that holds our digital world together is becoming more important than ever before. However, the Internet is struggling with many issues related to its incredibly centralized model, including a lack of resiliency and scalability, as well as the loss of its neutrality. And these issues keep intensifying.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon Web Services alone hosts more than a third of the Internet today. Adding in a few other tech giants, we essentially end up with only four or five companies controlling the majority of the Internet. While the US government has been debating potential regulations and even breakups of big tech corporations, other governments like China or Russia are already regulating certain aspects of the web. However, most regulations have failed to achieve the desired outcomes and are unable to keep up with the pace of innovations.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a saying that goes, “If it is free, you are the product.” Social media platforms like Facebook and Instagram are known for being completely free of charge. Their business models and profits are based on collecting, analyzing and selling their users’ data. &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.mcleanhospital.org&#x2F;essential&#x2F;it-or-not-social-medias-affecting-your-mental-health&quot;&gt;Studies&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; now show that high social media use correlates with self-reported declines in mental and physical health. The same platforms are being manipulated by private companies that spread political disinformation and polarity. According to internal Facebook &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.theverge.com&#x2F;2020&#x2F;5&#x2F;26&#x2F;21270659&#x2F;facebook-division-news-feed-algorithms&quot;&gt;reports&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, 64% of the people that joined extremist groups did so because algorithms steered them there. In an increasingly interconnected world where people are surrounded by smart devices that collect their data 24&#x2F;7, data ownership and control has never been more important than anything else.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the launch of Bitcoin, many cryptocurrencies have rallied the movement of decentralization, but only a handful hold technology that can bring true impact. What if there was one project out there that could apply the peer-to-peer and open-source fundamentals to the Internet? ThreeFold spent the last six years developing a new Internet infrastructure from the ground up consisting of a new decentralized operating system, a quantum safe storage system, a planetary mesh network and a distributed edge cloud solution.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold builds on 20+ years of technological innovations in the cloud automation, Internet storage and cybersecurity markets brought by its co-founders such as Kristof de Spiegeleer – a serial entrepreneur whose technologies have been acquired by Oracle, Verizon, Data Symantec and others. Together, the ThreeFold co-founders decided to start from scratch as they realized it was the only way to achieve a peer-to-peer and open-source digital backbone that secure, private and self-sovereign.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to de Spiegeleer, “ThreeFold holds more technology than all the Web3 space combined.” ThreeFold’s decentralized operating system can run on any computer, including servers, desktops and laptops, allowing anyone to connect hardware from their home or office to the peer-to-peer Internet.“&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what differentiates ThreeFold the most from the crowd is that it’s a project anchored in it’s values and vision. The project always remained far from fake hype, market making or FOMO games like the large majority of crypto projects. With a low market cap today, and its ability to transform the Internet at large, the time to buy &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tft&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Tokens (TFT)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is now. “We’re on the verge of signing our first countries and also have use cases across Real Estate, Education, Supply Chain, Metaverse and Blockchain coming up this year,” said de Spiegeleer, “So, we believe we are looking at tens of millions of users on ThreeFold in the upcoming years.“&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stake your claim in the decentralized Internet by &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;farming&#x2F;threefold__farming_intro&quot;&gt;hosting the Internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tokens&#x2F;threefold__how_to_buy&quot;&gt;getting TFT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; today.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Peer-to-Peer Overcomes Web3 Challenges</title>
		<published>2022-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/03/post-4/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/03/post-4/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;First coined in 2014, Web3 is now one of the hottest and overused buzzwords in the digital space – the idea of a new iteration of the web, a decentralized environment based on blockchain technology that incorporates token-based economics. The promise of Web3 – decentralization of control and authority from big tech, data security, scalability, and privacy for users – is tremendous. But what is a promise without delivery? Is it possible that we will see major adoption soon?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar to the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;thenewstack.io&#x2F;as-blockchain-hype-fades-developers-give-ethereum-a-serious-look&#x2F;&quot;&gt;enterprise blockchain hype&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that happened a few years ago, Web3 seems to be repeating the same story, with lots of chatter but lagging adoption. Millions have rushed to trade crypto and NFTs attached to Web3 – with a lot of this activity based on speculation and hype – but that doesn’t mean they will replace legacy platforms anytime soon. New approaches such as DeFi (decentralized finance) don’t have the same problem of the legacy firms, but they face the challenge of scaling and mass adoption. However, many so-called ‘Web3’ solutions are not as decentralized as they seem, and still have to show they are scalable, secure and accessible enough for the mass market. This all may change, but there are clear limitations that will need to be overcome.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether Web3 is a marketing slogan or a true technological trend, there is a lot of money and technology behind it. Financial institutions are embracing blockchain technology and we are seeing a rising adoption of digital assets across industries. While the idea of utilizing digital currencies to exchange different forms of value in an increasingly digital world certainly makes sense, it’s a bigger leap to say that blockchain alone can support a broad set of use cases, including replacing the current Internet infrastructure.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet’s client-server infrastructure replicates data and workloads across many computers, and uses tons of computing resources and energy while limiting the scalability of our applications. However, the clear inefficiencies and gaps in security in today’s centralized infrastructures are being challenged by simpler means of building, storing and exchanging data.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blockchain is a clear evolution to the centralized client-server model, but there are  severe challenges sourced from the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;medium.com&#x2F;certik&#x2F;the-blockchain-trilemma-decentralized-scalable-and-secure-e9d8c41a87b3&quot;&gt;blockchain trilemma&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; between decentralization, scalability and security. Peer-to-peer systems transcend those challenges as they don’t require any valid2ation or verification from a third party, and enable end-to-end connections that can scale limitlessly without the potential of being altered or corrupted by intermediaries. In peer-to-peer systems, all participants are equally privileged, presenting a fairer model. Peer-to-peer represents an incredibly simple and efficient paradigm for organizing our digital world, and has already proven to be the most efficient alternative to centralized information systems.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put, there is no reason to replicate full sets of data and workloads across many computers, and use tons of computing resources and energy while limiting the scalability of our applications. While there is an increasing reliance on blockchain principles to organize our Internet systems, blockchain also makes things redundant, slow, complex and energy intensive. To be clear, blockchain isn’t the problem, as it is a great technology to store and exchange value in a decentralized way, but it is only one piece of the puzzle.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By inter-connecting the computing processing power and storage capacity of billions of computers worldwide in a peer-to-peer way, data transfers could happen end-to-end between people and machines without the need to be verified. Peer-to-peer is also the only way to achieve a truly self-sovereign Internet – creating a ‘trustful’ environment that allows users and developers to have real data ownership.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peer-to-peer systems aren’t meant to replace blockchains – they represent a way to decentralize models that blockchain cannot, such as Internet infrastructures. Peer-to-peer systems and blockchains, side by side. The best of both worlds. Peer-to-peer as the most efficient and decentralized alternative for us to exchange data and Internet resources. And blockchain for establishing trust through an irrefutable record of transactions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the rise of emerging technologies, a new technological foundation is needed to protect our sovereignty and freedom. The rise of blockchains, while well intended, ultimately has made the technological space more complex than ever before, and still benefits a plutocratic few (relative to its promise). More than just technology, peer-to-peer opens a world of new possibilities for humanity to co-initiate new paradigms and experiences.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By applying blockchain and peer-to-peer technology to the cloud, ThreeFold solves the security and autonomy issues of the Internet and realizes the initial promise of the Internet as an open-source, peer-to-peer, planetary mesh network of nodes owned by the people.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Support the realization of a peer-to-peer Internet owned by the people today:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tokens&#x2F;threefold__how_to_buy&quot;&gt;Get TFT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, the currency of the peer-to-peer Internet.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;farming&#x2F;threefold__farming_intro&quot;&gt;Connect a computer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to the peer-to-peer Internet and earn monthly rewards.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;&#x2F;manual__manual3_home_new&quot;&gt;Build applications&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on the peer-to-peer Internet.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Can a &#x27;Democratized&#x27; Internet exist in times of a Cyber War?</title>
		<published>2022-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/03/post-3/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/03/post-3/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On February 24 2022, Russia launched a large-scale military invasion and attack on Ukraine. In the days since the invasion began, the war has been fought not only on the ground and in the air, but also in the digital realm.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyber warfare is nothing new, especially in Russia and Eastern Europe. “In the relatively short and rapidly evolving history of cyber conflict, perhaps nothing has been established with greater certainty and more widely accepted than the idea that Russia has significant cyber capabilities and isn’t afraid to use them,” &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;time.com&#x2F;6153902&#x2F;russia-major-cyber-attacks-invasion-ukraine&#x2F;&quot;&gt;writes Josephine Wolff&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, associate professor of cybersecurity policy at Tufts University. “Especially on Ukraine.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leading up to the invasion, Ukraine experienced a series of cyberattacks on its critical infrastructures, including banks and government agencies. On February 23 2022, just a day before the launch of Russia’s military attack, websites of the Ukrainian parliament and multiple government agencies were put out of work. Similar cyber attacks had also been seen in early February and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.economist.com&#x2F;europe&#x2F;2022&#x2F;02&#x2F;23&#x2F;will-war-in-ukraine-lead-to-a-wider-cyber-conflict?utm_campaign=a.io&amp;amp;utm_medium=audio.podcast.np&amp;amp;utm_source=babbage&amp;amp;utm_content=discovery.content.anonymous.tr_shownotes_na-na_article&amp;amp;utm_term=sa.listeners&quot;&gt;were attributed to GRU&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, Russia’s military-intelligence agency. And Ukrainian cities continue to suffer from &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.economist.com&#x2F;graphic-detail&#x2F;2022&#x2F;02&#x2F;26&#x2F;ukrainian-cities-are-suffering-internet-blackouts?utm_campaign=a.io&amp;amp;utm_medium=audio.podcast.np&amp;amp;utm_source=babbage&amp;amp;utm_content=discovery.content.anonymous.tr_shownotes_na-na_article&amp;amp;utm_term=sa.listeners&quot;&gt;internet blackouts&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. On Sunday, Ukraine’s vice president even called for tech specialists and hackers to join the “cyber front.” While the predictions of a Russian “cyber onslaught” have not necessarily come true yet, both sides have engaged in cyber attacks on visible and invisible levels.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-rise-in-state-sponsored-cyber-attacks-globally&quot;&gt;A Rise in State-Sponsored Cyber Attacks Globally&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digital or cyber warfare does not just apply to Russia and Ukraine. Broadly, cybersecurity experts have been raising concerns in recent years amid a sharp rise in ransomware and other types of digital attacks globally.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adam Meyers, Senior Vice President of Intelligence at the cybersecurity firm CrowdStrike &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.marketplace.org&#x2F;2022&#x2F;02&#x2F;24&#x2F;cybersecurity-to-take-center-stage-as-conflict-continues-in-ukraine&#x2F;&quot;&gt;said&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;: “Just in the last year, I think we’ve seen over 2,700 big-game hunting attacks [cyberattacks that target high-value data]. So they’re far and away that most prevalent actor. Nation-state actors are continuously operating as well, but they tend to operate a little bit more under the radar. They don’t conduct as many widespread and widely known attacks. They try to, obviously, steal information without it being identified that they’ve stolen it.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, these are just the most current examples – Russia is hardly the only country engaging in cyber warfare at a larger scale. In fact, it is becoming increasingly difficult for governments, corporations and organizations to protect themselves against cyber attacks, especially against &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.economist.com&#x2F;business&#x2F;2022&#x2F;02&#x2F;19&#x2F;companies-have-a-lot-to-fear-from-russias-digital-warmongering?utm_campaign=a.io&amp;amp;utm_medium=audio.podcast.np&amp;amp;utm_source=babbage&amp;amp;utm_content=discovery.content.anonymous.tr_shownotes_na-na_article&amp;amp;utm_term=sa.listeners&quot;&gt;state-sponsored attacks&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. And in the digital space, the best and most dangerous hacks are those that go unnoticed until it’s too late.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;some-governments-are-sectioning-off-the-internet-through-digital-borders&quot;&gt;Some Governments are Sectioning Off the Internet Through Digital Borders&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A set of countries like Russia, China, Saudi Arabia, and Iran have certain &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.codastory.com&#x2F;authoritarian-tech&#x2F;global-rise-internet-sovereignty&#x2F;&quot;&gt;aspirations for the internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Domestically, these countries want control and think governments should get to decide what information flows across their borders. Globally, they want governments, not companies and NGOs, to be in charge of the internet. While some may say that government-owned internet infrastructures would be the only way to protect a country’s sovereignty, it goes without saying that what once was a neutral space for humanity to connect and exchange information is turning into a political schema.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taken together, these goals are an attempt to align cyberspace with national borders, so they are sometimes dubbed the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.codastory.com&#x2F;authoritarian-tech&#x2F;global-rise-internet-sovereignty&#x2F;&quot;&gt;“cyber sovereignty” doctrine&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The term comes from China, whose internet censorship system, called the Great Firewall, is the vanguard of the global cyber-sovereignty push. China’s cyberspace agency released a much-ridiculed musical ode to cybersecurity under Lu Wei’s leadership, which included the line: “A cyberpower: Where the Internet is, so is the glorious dream.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vision of effective cyber-sovereignty is expanding to new horizons. A November &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.codastory.com&#x2F;authoritarian-tech&#x2F;global-rise-internet-sovereignty&#x2F;&quot;&gt;report&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; from Freedom House examined 65 countries and found since the previous year that internet freedom declined in 26 of them. Chinese-style “digital authoritarianism,” meanwhile, is growing in influence as China exports both its surveillance known-how and technology.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem here is that digital sovereignty is a major concept that not only addresses the issues of communication and connection but also the impact on societies and culture at large. With cyber sovereignty turning into a non-territorial challenge to sovereignty itself irrespective of the virtual realm of the internet, is there a way out for humanity?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-free-and-sovereign-cyber-space-is-needed&quot;&gt;A Free and Sovereign Cyber Space is Needed&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is evident that the current internet is facing some big challenges that have major implications for humanity. Data privacy and self-sovereignty is almost impossible today, raising serious questions towards those that control the Internet. But it also seems that these companies fell into the trap of their own business models and algorithms.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When taking a step back, the world seems just a few years away from the Matrix, as depicted by the Wachowskis.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet is playing an incredibly important role for the most powerful intelligence companies. As depicted by Meyers, we wouldn’t even notice that our information is being stolen all the time to benefit the greed of powerful geo-political actors. The internet is not a public good anymore, and unless humanity reacts fast, it may be that the world will lose all forms of freedom or sovereignty.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.eff.org&#x2F;cyberspace-independence&quot;&gt;“A declaration of the Independence of Cyberspace”&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; by John Perry Barlow once attempted to shed light on the applicability of government and institutions on the rapidly growing internet, already in 1996 trying to protect its neutrality. According to research, the world is experiencing innovation at an increasingly rapid pace. With the rise of blockchains and web3 technology, could the dream of John Perry Barlow turn into reality?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-what-is-the-solution&quot;&gt;So, What is the Solution?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a world aching for more decentralization and less dependence on governments and corporations, new decentralized and peer-to-peer models are already proving to be more resilient and secure. New Internet infrastructure companies such as ThreeFold have successfully built peer-to-peer internet infrastructures that are more resilient than the current centralized model. On such systems, people and enterprises can store their data and run their applications on a distributed network of computers in such a way that their data cannot be corrupted. ThreeFold even created a so-called “quantum safe” storage that guarantees that even the most powerful computers in the world wouldn’t be able to reconstruct user data.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The escalation of this cyber conflict can lead to unforeseen consequences and casualties. That is why it is especially important that our industry works together to protect customers, partner, employees and citizens. ThreeFold is on a mission to realize the promise of a fully-comprehensive, open-source and peer-to-peer internet infrastructure. ThreeFold is a platform for the creators of tomorrow to build that blueprint of responsibility and ensure that the outcome of future systems is neutrality.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;Br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join ThreeFold in building the new internet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>What is ThreeFold Farming?</title>
		<published>2022-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/03/post-2/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/03/post-2/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold farming refers to the act of connecting a 3Node to the ThreeFold Grid – providing Internet capacity to a globally distributed peer-to-peer Internet infrastructure. Farming is a decentralized and energy-efficient way for people to expand a new Internet infrastructure instead of corporations building hyper-scale data centers. It’s also a way to extend the Internet to underserved regions of our planet, which cannot afford data centers. Every ThreeFold Farmer around the world contributes to the growth of the foundation for a self-sovereign, private and secure digital world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;blog&#x2F;3node_example.png&quot; alt=&quot;3Node&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone can start farming by hosting a computer at their home or office and taking part in the decentralization of our global Internet and Cloud economy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-become-a-threefold-farmer&quot;&gt;Why become a ThreeFold Farmer?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today’s Internet model is highly centralized, owned and operated by the few. It has turned people into products, is too harmful for our planet, cannot scale to meet emerging demands and connect the billions who are being left behind. These alone are powerful reasons to participate in ThreeFold farming and participate in the growth of a new peer-to-peer Internet economy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further, the Internet is the second largest and fastest growing industry in the world after the financial markets. With the Internet expected to triple in size by 2025 to meet the data requirements of emerging technologies such as blockchain, Web3 and IoT, we need more capacity and especially in underserved regions of the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;basics-of-threefold-farming&quot;&gt;Basics of ThreeFold Farming&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold is a peer-to-peer network of computers (known as “3Nodes”), including servers, desktops and laptops, that creates an open-source, decentralized Internet. People who connect computers to the ThreeFold Grid (known as “farmers”) are rewarded with ThreeFold Tokens (TFT) on a monthly basis for meeting the required uptime necessary for users to access their workloads.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process of connecting decentralized Internet capacity and thereby creating new ThreeFold Tokens is described as farming because it resembles the process of farming in agriculture. With agricultural farming, farmers cultivate the land and earn revenue from their harvests. With ThreeFold, farmers connect decentralized Internet capacity and earn ThreeFold Tokens every month for achieving a certain uptime.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above model represents the building block for a distributed, edge infrastructure that can scale to anywhere electricity and network exists, to meet emerging data demands while also providing the self-sovereignty, privacy and security features to achieve true net-neutrality.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-fair-economic-model&quot;&gt;A Fair Economic Model&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold was created to realize the promise of an open-source, peer-to-peer Internet. As such, ThreeFold farming rewards all farmers equally according to the amount of Internet capacity they provide to the network.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold Tokens are rewarded for the amount of Internet capacity added and kept connected to the network. &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;farming&#x2F;threefold__farming_reward&quot;&gt;Farming rewards&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; are calculated according to the compute, storage and network capacity made available by the computers:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;30 TFT per Compute Unit (2 vCPU and 4 GB memory) per month&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;12.5 TFT per Storage Unit (1 TB of SSD and HDD) per month&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.38 TFT per Network Unit (1 GB of data transfer)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.06 TFT per public IP address per hour &lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above prices are based on the price of 1 TFT equalling $0.08. The farming rewards are pegged to the U.S Dollar and the price is locked from the time a farmer gets started to incentivize early contributors to the network. When the price of TFT rises, the farming rewards will decrease.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farming rewards are designed to be “reviewed” by &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;decentralization&#x2F;dao&#x2F;threefold__tfdao&quot;&gt;the ThreeFold DAO&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (a decentralized autonomous organization owned by the ThreeFold community) according to the growth of the ThreeFold Grid and the utilization of its decentralized cloud to ensure a fair distribution of the token economy while also ensuring that farmers will always be justly rewarded for their contribution.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;an-innovative-and-sustainable-solution&quot;&gt;An innovative and sustainable solution&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin mining and other blockchains became famous for requiring enormous amounts of computers and power to solve complex mathematical equations to win the chance of earning the famous cryptocurrency. Since then, many other projects have been born and carried on the mining concept.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold’s model is inclusive and planet-friendly. The decentralized operating system built and used by ThreeFold is extremely lightweight, allowing the peer-to-peer Internet infrastructure to be up-to 10x more energy efficient than the data center model and up-to 100x more energy efficient than Bitcoin mining.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The infrastructure was built in such a way that it removes the need for human intervention or maintenance to eliminate all unnecessary backdoors that open the possibility for ransomware and cyberattacks. Once booted, the decentralized operating system runs forever as the whole infrastructure was designed to be self-driving and self-healing. This 100% autonomous model allows for a completely decentralized system while also enhancing the security and privacy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While blockchain remains an incredible store of value, it is neither an efficient nor a scalable solution to store data and run applications. Only a peer–to-peer model can scale the Internet infinitely and efficiently.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;considerations-before-getting-started&quot;&gt;Considerations before getting started&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following are important factors to consider for ThreeFold farming profitability: &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;computer-hardware&quot;&gt;Computer Hardware&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farmers are encouraged to use the latest computers, including servers, desktops, and laptops that come with an AMD and Intel processor. The computer should have at least 1 Terabyte of SSD to optimize the performance of their farming activity. It is recommended to buy a ThreeFold 3Node server from certified partners around the globe that comes pre-configured and ready to run on the Grid. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Used or refurbished computers can be used but it is important to understand that older computers are less efficient and more power-hungry. Computers not older than 4 years are recommended. Please visit &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;c&#x2F;farming&#x2F;diy-farming&#x2F;43&quot;&gt;the DIY section of our forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for support and feedback on farming setups.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;power-costs&quot;&gt;Power Costs&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Electrical power is the  main operating expense. Electricity is charged per kilowatt-hour (kWh). The cost of farming can float from $0.10 to $0.35 per kWh. It is important for a farmer to verify the expected power usage of a computer before starting the operation to improve profitability.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note that the price of kWh varies depending on the country. Find a country power cost average comparison &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.electricrate.com&#x2F;data-center&#x2F;electricity-prices-by-country&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;threefold-token-price&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Token Price&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An incentive to farm ThreeFold Tokens is because of its future potential. What Bitcoin did to money, ThreeFold is doing to the Internet. While Bitcoin and Etheruem have already reached high market caps, ThreeFold is just getting started.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farmers are rewarded a given amount of TFT monthly based on the amount of Internet capacity they provide to the network.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the price of TFT is $0.1, the profitability of the farm will be average. If the price of TFT is $0.3  your farming operation may operate with healthy rewards. If the price of TFT is $1 your farming operation will be highly rewarding.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farming rewards are also locked until 30% utilization for a period of 2 years to incentivize early participants. The earlier you start your farming operation, the greater the rewards along with the growth in the value of TFT.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The right mix of the above elements make farming an attractive venture. If the variables are favorable, farmers can scale up operations and earn more rewards.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone can start farming by hosting a computer at their home or office and take part in the decentralization of our global Internet and Cloud economy. Considering ThreeFold’s market cap alongside the growing demand for a decentralized Internet, there’s no better time than now to get started farming!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;shop.threefold.tech&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Buy&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;farming&#x2F;threefold__diy_guide&quot;&gt;build&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; a 3Node and become a ThreeFold Farmer!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>The Validator Verification Process is Underway</title>
		<published>2022-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/02/post-09/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/02/post-09/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;🚨 &lt;strong&gt;The ThreeFold Validator Verification Process&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’ve submitted your interest for either an &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;c&#x2F;dao&#x2F;validators-signup-l0&#x2F;84&quot;&gt;L0&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;c&#x2F;dao&#x2F;validators-signup-l2&#x2F;83&quot;&gt;L2&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; Validator, we are now pleased to share the verification process with you.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;the-threefold-validators-verification-process&#x2F;2276&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Limited spots remain&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; for both L0 and L2 Validators, &lt;strong&gt;so be sure to submit your interest asap&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; via the links above!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And if you have any questions about validators still, please refer to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;decentralization&#x2F;validators&#x2F;threefold__validators&quot;&gt;the Validators section&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of the Library or in particular &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;decentralization&#x2F;validators&#x2F;threefold__validators_faq&quot;&gt;our FAQs&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;*&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Validator Frequently Asked Questions</title>
		<published>2022-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/02/post-06/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/02/post-06/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;🚨 &lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold Validator Nodes Update!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve received many questions on our programs for the &lt;strong&gt;L2 and L0 validators&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; since we opened registrations, so we compiled this &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;all-you-need-to-know-about-our-validator-programs&#x2F;2208?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;Validator FAQ&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for you. In &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;all-you-need-to-know-about-our-validator-programs&#x2F;2208?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;this post&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, you will also find more information on the next steps like verifying applications and deploying the validators.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;all-you-need-to-know-about-our-validator-programs&#x2F;2208?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;Validator FAQ &amp;amp; Next Steps&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We’re looking forward to driving the decentralization of the ThreeFold Grid with all of you. If you have further questions, please let us know in the comments.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;about-the-validators-signup-l2-category&#x2F;1862&quot;&gt;More about L2 Validators&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;about-the-validators-signup-l0-category&#x2F;1863&quot;&gt;More about L0 Validators&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Validator Reservations Progress</title>
		<published>2022-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/02/post-01/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/02/post-01/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Since opening ThreeFold Validator Node reservations earlier in the week, there has been strong interest from the community – applications are coming in, TFT are being accumulated – and limited spots remain!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;L2 Validators (20 left)&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;procedure-to-register-your-validator-node&#x2F;1864&quot;&gt;Reserve a L2 Validator&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;about-the-validators-signup-l2-category&#x2F;1862&quot;&gt;More about L2 Validators&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;L0 Validators (25 left)&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;procedure-to-register-your-l0-validator-nodes&#x2F;1866&quot;&gt;Reserve a L0 Validator&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;about-the-validators-signup-l0-category&#x2F;1863&quot;&gt;More about L0 Validators&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be amongst the first ThreeFold Validators contributing to the decentralization and expansion of the Internet – and get rewarded for it! Join in now.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Validator Node Update</title>
		<published>2022-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/01/post-17/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/01/post-17/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;⚡ &lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold Validator Node Update&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; ⚡&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In support of the establishment of ThreeFold’s DAO we have officially opened registrations for the first L2 and L0 validators.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L2 Validator Node registration forum post: &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;procedure-to-register-your-l2-validator-node&#x2F;1864&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L0 Validator Node registration forum post: &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;procedure-to-register-your-l0-validator-nodes&#x2F;1866&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This marks an important step towards realizing the promise of a decentralized Internet owned by the people.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>GetTFT.com is Live</title>
		<published>2022-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/01/post-15/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/01/post-15/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;🚨 &lt;strong&gt;Get TFT Directly with BTC!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our ongoing efforts to make TFT more accessible to the world, we’re happy to share that anyone can now buy TFT directly with the world’s most popular cryptocurrency, BTC (Bitcoin).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;get-tft-directly-with-btc&#x2F;1825&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;There’s been lots of positive attention around TFT over the last weeks despite the downward market. People are waking up to ThreeFold and showing their belief in the People’s Internet!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>New Year Deep Dive Session 6</title>
		<published>2022-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/01/post-09/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/01/post-09/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Today, we hosted our final deep dive meeup for now. We’ll pick up community sessions in a few weeks. In the meantime, we’ll catch you on the chats and in the forum!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tuesday January 18 2022&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Session 6: ThreeFold DAO, Validator Nodes, &amp;amp; COSMOS&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recording &amp;amp; Presentation Link: &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;tf-deep-dive-session-6-threefold-dao-validator-nodes-cosmos&#x2F;1784&quot;&gt;Here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>New Year Deep Dive Sessions 4 &amp; 5</title>
		<published>2022-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/01/post-06/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/01/post-06/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This week we continued with two more deep dive meetups. Don’t miss our final deep dive next week, covering the ThreeFold DAO, Validator Nodes, &amp;amp; the COSMOS integration!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wednesday January 12 2022&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Session 4: Deplpying Decentralized Solutions on TF Grid 3&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recording &amp;amp; Presentation Link: &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;tf-deep-dive-session-4-deploying-decentralized-solutions-on-tf-grid-3&#x2F;1751&quot;&gt;Here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thursday January 13 2022&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Session 5: ThreeFold Grid Architecture&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recording &amp;amp; Presentation Link: &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;tf-deep-dive-session-5-threefold-grid-architecture&#x2F;1756&quot;&gt;Here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>New Year Deep Dive Sessions 1, 2, &amp; 3</title>
		<published>2022-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/01/post-03/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/01/post-03/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A lot happened in 2021 and many things are changing! To kick the year off, we’re hosting six community meetups to deep dive into key topics related to ThreeFold. Here are the first three sessions from this week.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tuesday January 4 2022&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Session 1: TF Grid 3.0, Weblets, And Demos&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recording &amp;amp; Presentation Link: &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;tf-deep-dive-session-1-tf-grid-3-weblets-demos&#x2F;1673&#x2F;3&quot;&gt;Here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wednesday January 5 2022&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Session 2: TF Grid &amp;amp; TFT Growth Simulator + Tokenomics&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recording &amp;amp; Presentation Link: &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;tf-deep-dive-session-2-tf-grid-tft-growth-simulator-tokenomics&#x2F;1682&#x2F;2&quot;&gt;Here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thursday January 6 2022&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Session 3: TF Grid 3.x Launch Plan&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recording &amp;amp; Presentation Link: &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;tf-deep-dive-session-3-tf-grid-3-x-launch-plan&#x2F;1694&quot;&gt;Here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>All About ThreeFold Grid 3</title>
		<published>2021-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/12/post-13/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/12/post-13/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;✍️ As the team is working hard on &lt;strong&gt;bringing ThreeFold Grid 3 to mainnet&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, we thought it would be a good time to remind of &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;what-is-new-in-tfgrid-3-0&#x2F;1133&quot;&gt;What’s New in TF Grid 3.0&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More About TF Grid 3:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🗞 &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;whats-new-in-tf-grid-3-0-1-and-the-path-to-mainnet&#x2F;1488&quot;&gt;Release 3.0.1&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🌀 &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;introducing-the-tf-chain-admin-portal-for-farmers-and-grid-users&#x2F;1526&quot;&gt;The TF Admin Portal&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🔍 &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;the-threefold-grid-3-x-explorer-ui&#x2F;1536&quot;&gt;Grid 3 Explorer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the farmers acrossed 18 countries 🌎 who have connected capacity to TF Grid 3 Testnet and to the testers who have deployed more than 1,800 contracts to date.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For those who are interested in testing, please join &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldtesting&quot;&gt;our testing community&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Join us at the virtual Horizon Cloud Summit</title>
		<published>2021-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/12/post-2/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/12/post-2/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We’d like to invite you to &lt;strong&gt;join us at the virtual Horizon Cloud Summit next week&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, on December 8 and 9!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Geert Machtelinckx will be presenting &amp;amp; sharing in two different sessions. Find the full details &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;join-threefold-horizon-cloud-summit-2021&#x2F;1539&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Horizon Cloud is a European Commission initiative. They recently recognized ThreeFold’s peer-to-peer cloud infrastructure as leading in the fields of edge, federation, and green technology.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>What&#x27;s New in Grid 3.0.1!</title>
		<published>2021-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/11/post-18-grid/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/11/post-18-grid/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We have been, for some months, in testing mode on our ThreeFold Grid 3.X and today we are sharing &lt;strong&gt;what’s new in TF Grid 3.0.1 – and the path to mainnet!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; 🚨&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Including: improvements suggested for 3.x farming model, a web-based widget to simplify calculations, validator nodes, a DAO, and what we still need to for mainnet!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Find the full update &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;whats-new-in-tf-grid-3-0-1-and-the-path-to-mainnet&#x2F;1488&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And a big thank you to the testers &amp;amp; farmers who have offered your time &amp;amp; feedback in helping us get to where we are today!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>DigiThree Labs is live!</title>
		<published>2021-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/11/post-18/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/11/post-18/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DigiThree Labs is live!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; 🚀&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DigiThree combines ThreeFold’s peer-to-peer technology and the vast benefits of the DigiByte blockchain to protect and elevate enterprises into the metaverse, our digital future.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🌐 https:&#x2F;&#x2F;digithreelabs.com&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Announcing DigiThree Labs</title>
		<published>2021-10-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-10-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/10/post-28/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/10/post-28/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;🚨 &lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;digicorplabs.com&quot;&gt;DigiCorp Labs&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; have joined forces to form DigiThree Labs&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, bringing together ThreeFold and DigiByte technologies and strong shared beliefs around decentralization, security, and privacy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DigiThree will deliver secure and private next-level solutions for people and enterprises, for a better tomorrow. Built on the DigiMetaverse, a decentralized foundational layer for the Metaverse.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More to come. 👀&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Find the news &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;threefold_io&#x2F;status&#x2F;1453759609911619591&quot;&gt;on Twitter&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as well! We’d love your support in getting the word out.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Europe&#x27;s Next-Gen Edge Computing Platform</title>
		<published>2021-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/10/post-26/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/10/post-26/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We’ve &lt;strong&gt;joined forces&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; with some incredible European open source projects with the collective ambition &lt;strong&gt;to build Europe’s next-generation edge computing platform&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🌐 &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;sovereignedge.eu&#x2F;MetaOS&#x2F;&quot;&gt;SovereignEdge.EU&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please find &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;threefold_io&#x2F;status&#x2F;1452941932129312774&quot;&gt;the announcement on Twitter&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and show your support. The more noise we make with this application, the more chances for our ecosystem to develop Europe’s edge cloud.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; 🙏&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>A Journey through the Decentralization and Blockchain Space – Part Four: Storj</title>
		<published>2021-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/10/post-8/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/10/post-8/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the fourth part of our journey through the decentralization space. After exploring &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;project_comparison_1_dfinity&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Dfinity&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;project_comparison_2_akash&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Akash&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and most recently &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;project_comparison_3_filecoin&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Filecoin&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, we’ll now explore Storj to find out what we have in common and where ThreeFold stands out. Here we go!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;storj-how-the-project-compares-to-threefold&quot;&gt;Storj &amp;amp; how the project compares to ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.storj.io&quot;&gt;Storj&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a decentralized cloud storage (DCS) solution founded in 2014 by Shawn Wilkinson, offering cloud object storage on its network of nodes and ISPs spread across different countries.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold and Storj are both open source projects that view transparency as an integral part of their business philosophy. Actually, ThreeFold is the first full-stack blockchain-enabled &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cloud.threefold.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;cloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to be made open source – all of our code is open source and available for everyone to review or use. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another similarity is that security and privacy are crucial aspects of our projects. Both are private by design and believe it’s vital that every person has total &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;threefold_data_sovereignty&#x2F;&quot;&gt;control and ownership&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; over their data – not even Storj or ThreeFold can access the data of users within their respective ecosystems, creating trustless environments. Storj provides security and privacy by encrypting the data by an &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.storj.io&#x2F;dcs&#x2F;concepts&#x2F;overview&quot;&gt;Uplink client&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; before it is uploaded to its DCS. The data is then split into pieces which are distributed across different nodes and ISPs connected to Storj’s cloud network. At ThreeFold, we’re creating an &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;critical-security-updates-for-apple-and-google-underline-need-for-secure-it-ecosystem&#x2F;1271&quot;&gt;entirely secure&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, peer-to-peer IT ecosystem that empowers users and gives them back control and ownership of their own data. We’re &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;threefold__usp_secure?id=network-security&quot;&gt;secure&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; across all dimensions of our solutions – from our operating system Zero-OS to Quantum Safe File System (&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tech&#x2F;zdbfs&quot;&gt;QSFS&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;) and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tech&#x2F;planetary-network&quot;&gt;Planetary Network&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Storj does not have its own operating system, we’ve built our &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;tech&#x2F;zero-os&quot;&gt;Zero-OS&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; from scratch. It allows servers to run autonomously and workloads to be hosted securely, preventing them from administrative exploits and errors. The self-driving and self-healing &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;zero_os_blog&#x2F;&quot;&gt;features&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of Zero-OS eliminate backdoors, reduce the hacking surface and remove the need for human involvement.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both projects are compatible with certain IT tools and protocols. While Storj is  S3-compatible and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.storj.io&#x2F;integrations&quot;&gt;integrates&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; a couple of developer tools like FileZilla or Fastly, ThreeFold is highly compatible with leading industry standards and tools from S3 to Docker containers, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;grid-utilization-plan-part-one&#x2F;1157&quot;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and more. Moreover, ThreeFold can run anything that runs on Linux, allowing for a seamless migration of any digital workload, even from &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;threefold_cloud_vs_centralized_providers_like_aws_azure&#x2F;&quot;&gt;traditional cloud providers&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; like Microsoft Azure or AWS. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A difference between the projects is that Storj focuses on providing the storage layer for developers to build storage applications like Dropbox upon, rather than offering such services themselves, whereas our energy-efficient full stack &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cloud.threefold.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;cloud infrastructure&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; includes solutions like the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;marketplace&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Marketplace&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of ready-made peer-to-peer applications that runs on our Edge Virtual Data Center (&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;info&#x2F;cloud#&#x2F;cloud__evdc&quot;&gt;eVDC&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;). Moreover, we’re working with innovative teams and developers to develop self-sovereign &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;interview_with_jimber&#x2F;&quot;&gt;alternatives&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to commonly used applications (e.g. video conferencing, office tools).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;network-storage&quot;&gt;Network &amp;amp; Storage&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Storj’s decentralized network, uploaded data is automatically spread across nodes in different countries. The storage capacity on Storj’s network is increased whenever a new node is connected to it. There are roughly 9,6 Petabyte of data stored on Storj with nodes in more than 80 countries, whereas roughly 85 Petabyte of storage, compute, and network capacity are deployed on the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;grid&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Currently, the nodes connected to our Grid are spread over more than &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;explorer.grid.tf&quot;&gt;50 countries&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Storj only offers storage capacity, ThreeFold provides storage, compute, and network capacity. Moreover, our system is endlessly scaleable, whereas Storj’s scalability is limited as it does not empower people without technical skills to contribute and has more complex structures, such as its Satellite component which will be explained further down. We’re continuously extending our reach and our system is capable of seamlessly growing on demand, as it enables anyone to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;farm&quot;&gt;become a 3Node&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on our ThreeFold Grid. Moreover, our self-driving and self-healing &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tech&quot;&gt;technology&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is unique in the space and removes the need for monitoring and maintaining the nodes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Storage nodes on Storj are responsible for storing and returning data reliably. While Storj generally allows anyone with the excess capacity and bandwidth to run a node on its network, the project does not offer certified hardware. With Storj, anyone who wants to become a node operator has to build their own nodes which have to meet the specific hardware &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.storj.io&#x2F;node&#x2F;before-you-begin&#x2F;prerequisites&quot;&gt;requirements&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of Storj. At ThreeFold, our technology was designed to scale to anywhere electricity and bandwidth can be found to meet local digital infrastructure needs, to empower the unconnected and to drive our vision of an interconnected world. This is also why we’re working with certified hardware partners to provide &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;shop.threefold.tech&#x2F;index.php?route=common&#x2F;home&quot;&gt;plug-and-play&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; 3Nodes. These 3Nodes enable even people without technical skills to join and contribute to what we like to call the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;join_the_peoples_internet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;People’s Internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, as &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;mission&quot;&gt;we believe&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that everyone should be given equal chances and that Internet access is a human right.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next to the storage nodes, there are two other &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.storj.io&#x2F;dcs&#x2F;concepts&#x2F;overview&quot;&gt;main components&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of the Storj network: Uplink and Satellite. &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.storj.io&#x2F;dcs&#x2F;concepts&#x2F;definitions&quot;&gt;Uplink&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is Storj’s umbrella term for any application that stores or retrieves data and encrypts, encodes, and coordinates data with other services. Storj’s &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.storj.io&#x2F;dcs&#x2F;concepts&#x2F;satellite&quot;&gt;Satellite&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; consists of a set of storage node services like storage node reputation, data repair, billing and more. Storj users have to sign up for accounts on Satellites and pick a specific Satellite to trust. While any user could run their own Satellite in theory, Storj recommends users to create an account on a Satellite that is hosted by a third party like Storj Labs to reduce complexity. This approach, however, fosters centralization, whereas our peer-to-peer &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;smartereum.com&#x2F;189750&#x2F;threefold-is-audaciously-building-a-new-decentralized-internet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;infrastructure&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is an open system where anyone can provide and utilize cloud resources without any intermediaries. On top of that, we’ve implemented cryptographically-secured deployment specifications, called &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tech&#x2F;smart-contract&quot;&gt;Smart Contracts for IT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, to ensure that workloads run as intended in a tamper-proof way, and allow systems to scale and heal autonomously without intermediaries.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;tokenomics-payment-methods&quot;&gt;Tokenomics &amp;amp; Payment Methods&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both projects have native utility tokens. While the Storj token is an Ethereum-based token that represents a unit of storage capacity on the Storj network, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tft&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Tokens&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (TFT) can represent either a unit of compute, storage or network on the ThreeFold Grid. Some Storj community members &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.storj.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;the-elephant-in-the-room-where-is-the-storj-token-utility&#x2F;12452&quot;&gt;criticize&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; a lack of utility of the Storj token, as storage capacity on Storj can be purchased and paid for not only in Storj token but also using fiat payment options like credit card or invoice. However, Storj themselves don’t see this as an issue and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.storj.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;storj-token-balances-and-flows-report-q1-2021&quot;&gt;state&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that the intention behind their tokens is to facilitate the provision and receipt of data storage and not to create a digital currency or any other kind of financial instrument. In contrast, our ThreeFold Tokens are the fuel for IT capacity, as they allow people to hold current and future cloud capacity on the ThreeFold Grid. Moreover, a limited supply of four billion ThreeFold Token has been set to keep the currency scarce, while the burning mechanism simultaneously ensures continuous rewards for current and future nodes. Find out more about our two algorithms, Proof-of-Capacity (PoC) and Proof-of-Utilization (PoU), in our &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tokens&#x2F;threefold__tokenomics&quot;&gt;tokenomics&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By connecting storage nodes to Storj’s network and providing storage capacity to others, node operators get rewarded with Storj tokens which they receive &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.storj.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;storj-token-balances-and-flows-report-q2-2021&quot;&gt;from Storj Labs&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as a centralized payment operator, whereas ThreeFold Token are already rewarded upon the connection of capacity to our Grid. Moreover, storage capacity on Storj’s network can only be purchased with a subscription-based &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.storj.io&#x2F;pricing&quot;&gt;model&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. With ThreeFold, anyone can become a farmer and be &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;farming&#x2F;threefold__farming_reward&quot;&gt;rewarded income&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in the form of ThreeFold Tokens for &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;farming&#x2F;threefold__farming_intro&quot;&gt;expanding&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; the Internet by contributing cloud capacity. ThreeFold Tokens incentivize an open and autonomous &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tech&#x2F;peer-to-peer&quot;&gt;peer-to-peer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; system free from any type of intermediary. We’re enabling anyone to become an independent farmer, as we believe in empowering people and that no single entity should have the power to control systems. Based on our &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tech&#x2F;tf-chain&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Blockchain&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, which will be released on Testnet 3.0 soon, a new discount as well as &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;introducing-tf-chain-an-updated-billing-model&#x2F;1277&quot;&gt;billing model&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; will be introduced. The latter will allow users to authorize &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tech&#x2F;smart-contract&quot;&gt;smart contracts&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to automatically deduct their wallets according to the capacity they use.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, we both share the same vision of a decentralized Internet. The biggest difference between Storj and ThreeFold is that Storj is focused on providing storage, whereas &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;an_intro_to_the_threefold_grid&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; does not only provide storage but also compute and network capacity. While Storj seeks to be the storage layer for the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;quest_decentralize_internet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;decentralized Internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, ThreeFold provides the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;an_intro_to_the_threefold_grid&#x2F;&quot;&gt;low-level primitives&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for a &lt;em&gt;truly&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; decentralized Internet: compute, storage and network. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we’re the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.forbes.com&#x2F;sites&#x2F;johnkoetsier&#x2F;2020&#x2F;06&#x2F;20&#x2F;largest-distributed-peer-to-peer-grid-on-the-planet-laying-foundation-for-a-decentralized-internet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;largest&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, most advanced peer-to-peer cloud infrastructure in the world and are expanding fast, some aspects of Storj’s storage network still function in a rather centralized manner, such as their payment model and Satellites. In addition to that, we’re providing the ideal infrastructure for edge workloads. The project could therefore &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-is-the-substrate-for-decloud&#x2F;1295&quot;&gt;benefit&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; from moving on top of our fully decentralized, highly energy-efficient and autonomous &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;africa.businessinsider.com&#x2F;local&#x2F;markets&#x2F;ambitious-startup-to-disrupt-the-internet-and-cloud&#x2F;b38rwj4&quot;&gt;infrastructure&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Together, we could drive the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.econotimes.com&#x2F;ThreeFold-DFINITY-and-the-race-to-Decentralize-the-Internet-1618367&quot;&gt;decentralization&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of storage capacity all over the world. We believe in a world without boundaries, where people are able to share information, value and knowledge without limits nor intermediaries. To achieve this vision and to effect change at a large scale it takes collaboration. Thanks for coming along and stay tuned, as we’ll take a closer look at Holochain next!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Our Quest to Fully Decentralize the Internet</title>
		<published>2021-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/10/post-7/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/10/post-7/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tim Berners-Lee created the web server and browser in 1990. Back then, the web was of a free, rather decentralized nature in which no single entity was to control the access to it. With the client-server architecture of the web, however, centralization came about. &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;threefold__why_intro?id=everyone-should-be-autonomous&quot;&gt;Nowadays&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, the web as well as the Internet in general are highly centralized. There are only a few companies acting as gatekeepers to large parts of today’s Internet. The Internet as we know it is continuously &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;theconversation.com&#x2F;web-3-0-the-decentralised-web-promises-to-make-the-internet-free-again-113139&quot;&gt;struggling with issues&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; related to its centralized nature – from censorship and attacks on net neutrality to manipulation attempts from companies with &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.newyorker.com&#x2F;magazine&#x2F;2017&#x2F;08&#x2F;28&#x2F;who-owns-the-internet&quot;&gt;monopolistic power&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. These issues are systematic and major players like Amazon or Facebook are &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;techmonitor.ai&#x2F;boardroom&#x2F;power-of-tech-companies&quot;&gt;benefitting&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; from the situation as it is. This business model is also highly reliant on centralized hyperscale &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;data_leaks&#x2F;&quot;&gt;data centers&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that also come with a whole set of issues, from their vulnerability and limited scalability to their extremely high energy consumption &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;threefold_cloud_vs_centralized_providers_like_aws_azure&#x2F;&quot;&gt;and more&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People have become the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;threefold_data_sovereignty&#x2F;&quot;&gt;product&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of a business model where companies offer their services in exchange for personal data – in order to capitalize on and exploit the data, basically squeezing people out for their data like oranges for juice. In times where &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.techradar.com&#x2F;news&#x2F;why-personal-data-exploitation-has-become-the-norm&quot;&gt;data exploitation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is the norm, it makes sense that data is often referred to as digital oil or gold. Moreover, algorithms of social media platforms increasingly lead to content provoking controversy and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;thereboot.com&#x2F;creating-decentralized-social-media-alternatives-to-facebook-and-twitter&#x2F;&quot;&gt;addictive&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; engagement as this type of content tends to increase the time people spend on the platforms – with shocking impacts like The Wall Street Journals’ &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.wsj.com&#x2F;articles&#x2F;the-facebook-files-11631713039&quot;&gt;investigation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; “The Facebook Files” and The New York Times’ audio series &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.nytimes.com&#x2F;2020&#x2F;04&#x2F;22&#x2F;podcasts&#x2F;rabbit-hole-prologue.html&quot;&gt;Rabbit Hole&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; show.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of these issues have strengthened the push towards decentralization, mainly associated with the blockchain technology and cryptocurrencies like Bitcoin. However, many of the projects in the decentralized space still rely on centralized providers or structures to some degree. The second most-popular blockchain in the world, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;decentralize_blockchain&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Ethereum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, for example, has 60% of its nodes run on &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;threefold_cloud_vs_centralized_providers_like_aws_azure&#x2F;&quot;&gt;centralized cloud providers&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; with 25% of them running on Amazon Web Services (AWS). &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;project_comparison_2_akash&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Akash&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, a blockchain-based cloud computing platform, prevents unutilized capacity from centralized cloud computing services from going to waste. Leveraging this underutilized cloud capacity, however, also causes Akash to be highly dependent on &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;blog.orchid.com&#x2F;akash-networks-greg-osuri-on-decentralizing-cloud-computing&#x2F;&quot;&gt;centralized capacity&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;project_comparison_1_dfinity&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Dfinity’s&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; platform for decentralized apps (dApps) is based on an ecosystem of independent data centers, which makes it rather centralized on an infrastructural level. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the previously mentioned projects are all seeking to push decentralization, they all have one thing in common: they rely on centralized structures or providers at least to some degree and therefore, are not fully decentralized yet. So, what does &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;decentralize_blockchain&#x2F;&quot;&gt;true decentralization&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; look like?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-threefold-is-changing-the-game&quot;&gt;How ThreeFold is Changing the Game&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is our &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;mission&quot;&gt;mission&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to transform the Internet and Cloud and to create borderless opportunities for humanity. Therefore, we‘re truly committed to decentralizing the infrastructure behind the Internet to scale current and future digital workloads. At Threefold, we’re building an entirely &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;an_intro_to_the_threefold_grid&#x2F;&quot;&gt;new infrastructure&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; from the ground up, starting with a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;grid&quot;&gt;Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of new, neutral capacity and our operating system &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;zero_os_blog&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Zero-OS&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Our ThreeFold Grid, based on open-source &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tech&quot;&gt;technology&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, enables an autonomous, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;threefold__usp_secure?id=network-security&quot;&gt;secure&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and energy-efficient infrastructure that allows for unlimited scalability while remaining affordable. Our Grid is the largest and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.forbes.com&#x2F;sites&#x2F;johnkoetsier&#x2F;2020&#x2F;06&#x2F;20&#x2F;largest-distributed-peer-to-peer-grid-on-the-planet-laying-foundation-for-a-decentralized-internet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;most advanced&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; peer-to-peer infrastructure in the world, already available in more than &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;explorer.grid.tf&#x2F;&quot;&gt;50 countries&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and keeps expanding fast. With our energy-efficient full stack &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cloud.threefold.io&quot;&gt;cloud infrastructure&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, uniting compute, storage, and network, we are much more comprehensive than other projects. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At ThreeFold, we believe in giving power to the people by developing technologies that empower individuals, enable social participation, and foster collaboration. We’re enabling even people without technical skills to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;farm&quot;&gt;join the network&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; with plug-and-play &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;shop.threefold.tech&#x2F;index.php?route=common&#x2F;home&quot;&gt;3Nodes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; offered through our certified hardware partners. The ThreeFold Grid is therefore &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;tf_grid_peoples_internet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;more inclusive&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and allows any individual to participate. Our peer-to-peer nature removes the need of centralized servers and any type of intermediary, allowing applications and data to live closer to where they’re being utilized. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to that, we believe that no one but you should own your data. Our technology empowers every user to be &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;threefold_data_sovereignty&#x2F;&quot;&gt;data sovereign&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, giving them full control over their own data by using a variety of innovative technologies, such as autonomous IT, blockchain, and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tech&#x2F;peer-to-peer&quot;&gt;peer-to-peer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; networking. This way, our technology is turning traditional IT upside down, enabling a data-sovereign Internet that gives users &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;join_the_peoples_internet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;control&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and ownership of their data in an &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;critical-security-updates-for-apple-and-google-underline-need-for-secure-it-ecosystem&#x2F;1271&quot;&gt;entirely secure&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, peer-to-peer IT ecosystem.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, we provide the low-level primitives for a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-is-the-substrate-for-decloud&#x2F;1295&quot;&gt;decentralized world&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, enabling any project to run on a fully decentralized, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;new.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;for_our_planet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;energy-efficient&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and self-healing infrastructure. As we truly believe in collaboration to effect change at a large scale to fully decentralize the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;africa.businessinsider.com&#x2F;local&#x2F;markets&#x2F;ambitious-startup-to-disrupt-the-internet-and-cloud&#x2F;b38rwj4&quot;&gt;Internet and Cloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, our &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;partners&quot;&gt;partnership&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; ecosystem keeps growing. Most recently, we announced a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;partners&#x2F;owncloud&quot;&gt;strategic partnership&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; with ownCloud, an alternative to public clouds with more than 200 million users worldwide, that aims to advance the decentralization of the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;news&#x2F;post&#x2F;owncloud_threefold&#x2F;&quot;&gt;consumer cloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, we’d like to invite you to join forces with us to further push the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.econotimes.com&#x2F;ThreeFold-DFINITY-and-the-race-to-Decentralize-the-Internet-1618367&quot;&gt;decentralization&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of the Internet together – whether by becoming a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;farm&quot;&gt;3Node&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or building on our ThreeFold Grid, by buying our ThreeFold Token (&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tft&quot;&gt;TFT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;), our currency for a decentralized world, or by &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;info&#x2F;cloud#&#x2F;cloud__evdc_getting_started&quot;&gt;testing&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; our P2P Cloud. Let’s &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;tgdaily.com&#x2F;web&#x2F;6-dfinity-threefold-are-leading-an-internet-decentralization-revolution&#x2F;&quot;&gt;revolutionize&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; the Internet together!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Business Insider Africa Covers ThreeFold</title>
		<published>2021-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/10/post-13/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/10/post-13/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🗞 ThreeFold in the News 🗞&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“ThreeFold, a disruptive tech project, has recognized an underlying issue and is determined to solve it by providing a decentralized internet infrastructure and peer-to-peer cloud solution…&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any digital workload can be hosted natively on the ThreeFold Grid with minimum migration, including cloud alternatives, blockchains, IoT networks, decentralized organizations and applications.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ambitious startup to disrupt the Internet and Cloud, via Business Insider Africa.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full article &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;africa.businessinsider.com&#x2F;local&#x2F;markets&#x2F;ambitious-startup-to-disrupt-the-internet-and-cloud&#x2F;b38rwj4&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Why is ThreeFold P2P Cloud the better solution for customers than Amazon Web Services or Microsoft Azure?</title>
		<published>2021-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/10/post-6/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/10/post-6/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As we’ve recently been exploring decentralized &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;project_comparison_1_dfinity&#x2F;&quot;&gt;projects&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to see where ThreeFold is in the space and where we stand out, we thought it’s a good time to also look into how we compare to traditional, centralized cloud providers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cloud market is a highly complex and competitive one, currently &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.srgresearch.com&#x2F;articles&#x2F;amazon-and-microsoft-maintain-their-grip-market-others-are-also-growing-rapidly&quot;&gt;dominated&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; by the market leaders Amazon Web Services (AWS) and Microsoft Azure who account for more than half of the worldwide cloud revenues. This centralized nature of today’s cloud as well as its hyper-scale data center model are the cause for various issues, ranging from the monopolistic power of the few big market players and vendor lock-in effects to the incredibly high energy consumption of data centers and the limited scalability of the current model. Moreover, traditional data centers are more prone to outages and cyber attacks. We believe the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;grid&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; built by independent farmers around the globe and our &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cloud.threefold.io&quot;&gt;ThreeFold P2P Cloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; provide a solution to all of these issues.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While centralized cloud providers do offer some benefits, such as robust feature sets and huge customer service teams, there are a few key and important differences we think any customer would care about:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;decentralization&quot;&gt;Decentralization&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the biggest and most obvious difference. Today, big tech holds a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.srgresearch.com&#x2F;articles&#x2F;amazon-and-microsoft-maintain-their-grip-market-others-are-also-growing-rapidly&quot;&gt;monopoly&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on the Internet and Cloud markets, meaning they somehow became the gatekeepers of what was originally intended to be a distributed, neutral Internet. When using AWS or Google Cloud, the data is stored in centralized data centers owned by private corporations. These data centers are susceptible to hacking and outages that can take down massive chunks of the Internet. In this system, people have become products, as they exchange their &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;data_leaks&#x2F;&quot;&gt;data&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for “free” online experiences. With &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;mission&quot;&gt;ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, data is stored fully decentralized on the peer-to-peer ThreeFold Grid, where the physical hardware is owned by independent ThreeFold &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;farm&quot;&gt;Farmers&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and the data is owned by as well as only accessible to the person(s) who put it there. So, hackers can’t get in and due to the decentralized nature of the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;grid&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, large-scale outages would be much less likely as well. Further, no organization or entity needs to be trusted and people are not treated as products – with ThreeFold’s infrastructure, the Internet is owned &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;tf_grid_peoples_internet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;by the people&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;limitless-scalability-at-the-edge&quot;&gt;Limitless Scalability at the Edge&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our lightweight operating system &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tech&#x2F;zero-os&quot;&gt;Zero-OS&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; makes it possible and even easy to install a node close to where the data is being consumed. There is no need for large servers, nor for heavy power supply installations. Together with our hardware partner, we’re offering &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;farm&quot;&gt;3Nodes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; with plug-and-play functionalities, allowing &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;join_the_peoples_internet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;anyone to participate&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. This makes our model infinitely scalable at the edge. Hyper-scale data centers are not able to provide these levels of scalability and edge benefits. In order to scale their operations, centralized cloud providers need to build more data centers and take care of the related maintenance which takes time and costs billions. The traditional data center model also isn’t well suited for the edge, as this requires flexibility and close proximity to the respective data.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;security&quot;&gt;Security&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Centralized clouds are secure, but vulnerable. At ThreeFold, we pride ourselves on the levels of security we’re providing. The &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tech&#x2F;peer-to-peer&quot;&gt;peer-to-peer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; nature of our technology means end-to-end transmission of data between parties (with no middlemen). This is a big one: Nothing is being stored or copied in central servers. Moreover, ThreeFold’s self-driving and self-healing IT removes the need for human intervention and eliminates the many back doors present in current architecture. So, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;critical-security-updates-for-apple-and-google-underline-need-for-secure-it-ecosystem&#x2F;1271&quot;&gt;security issues&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; caused by human error and hacking possibilities both diminish greatly. In addition to that, there is the distributed storage algorithm which makes it nearly impossible for data to be lost. And much more. You can find more info on our &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;threefold__usp_secure?id=network-security&quot;&gt;wiki&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or in this &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;security-privacy-on-the-threefold-grid-and-second-best-alternatives-out-there-today&#x2F;1290&quot;&gt;forum post&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;privacy&quot;&gt;Privacy&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact that you &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;threefold_data_sovereignty&#x2F;&quot;&gt;own your data&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and nobody – not even us – can get access to it is key to making ThreeFold much more private than centralized cloud providers. On top of that, connections within our global overlay network, the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;how-our-planetary-network-works&#x2F;1210&quot;&gt;Planetary Network&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, are peer-to-peer and end-to-end encrypted.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;affordability&quot;&gt;Affordability&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, the centralized cloud is quite expensive, whereas our ThreeFold P2P Cloud is much more cost-effective. Learn more about this in our cloud pricing comparison &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;pricing&#x2F;threefold__cloud_pricing_compare&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;energy-efficiency&quot;&gt;Energy Efficiency&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While electricity for storing and transporting data, administration, human resources, and even gas (to transport physical data-holding devices) lead to a very high energy consumption, our dispersed storage model and peer-to-peer infrastructure allow for &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;sustainability&#x2F;threefold__energy_savings_storage&quot;&gt;significant energy savings&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. So, another big difference between ThreeFold and centralized cloud providers is that we’re up to 100x more &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;new.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;for_our_planet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;energy-efficient&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, the combination of our &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;grid&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cloud.threefold.io&quot;&gt;ThreeFold P2P Cloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; provide significant advantages over centralized cloud providers with their hyper-scale data centers. From decentralization and infinite scalability at the edge to considerable energy savings and cost effectiveness as well as data privacy and security, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;africa.businessinsider.com&#x2F;local&#x2F;markets&#x2F;ambitious-startup-to-disrupt-the-internet-and-cloud&#x2F;b38rwj4&quot;&gt;our solution&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; has much more value to offer, while solving critical issues related to centralized clouds. If you’d like to test our cloud solution yourself, take a look &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;info&#x2F;cloud#&#x2F;cloud__evdc_getting_started&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. You can also start participating in our decentralized ecosystem by becoming a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;shop.threefold.tech&#x2F;index.php?route=common&#x2F;home&quot;&gt;3Node&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on our ThreeFold Grid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>How ThreeFold Can Truly Decentralize Blockchain</title>
		<published>2021-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/10/post-5/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/10/post-5/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The topic of decentralization is commonly tied to blockchain and cryptocurrencies. Blockchain doesn’t store any of its information in a central location, rather it is copied and spread across a network of computers. And the most popular name in the blockchain space, Bitcoin, was intended as an alternative payment system free of central control.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But many blockchains are facing the same challenge: How can they escape the monopolies of centralized cloud providers for their own workloads, as well as for the dApps built on top of them? The key question is, is a blockchain truly decentralized if it is being hosted on a centralized solution? We say: no.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An example to illustrate this challenge is the fact that up to 60% of Ethereum (the world’s second most-popular blockchain) nodes run on centralized cloud providers and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;aws.amazon.com&#x2F;blockchain&#x2F;&quot;&gt;25% of them run on Amazon Web Services (AWS)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the topic is being addressed, it isn’t being solved at scale. The good news is that ThreeFold can play a large part in solving it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-should-blockchains-make-this-move&quot;&gt;Why should blockchains make this move?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The blockchain movement, as mentioned, is very heavily tied to the movement around decentralization. Cryptocurrencies represent the move away from centralized banks as the authorities and gatekeepers around money – just as ThreeFold and similar projects represent the move away from centralized clouds as the authorities and gatekeepers around data. The thing is, if blockchains are to rely on centralized cloud for hosting, they aren’t truly embodying decentralization.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understandably, many blockchains have chosen centralized cloud providers in the past because there wasn’t much of an alternative. But now, the Decentralized Cloud (DeCloud) movement has changed all of that.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how some specific audiences can benefit:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;for-node-operators&quot;&gt;For Node Operators&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any full node or validator node can run on ThreeFold’s &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cloud.threefold.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Peer-to-Peer (P2P) Cloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, making that particular Blockchain even more community-owned, and more decentralized from an IT&#x2F;cloud level. Any node operator can choose to run their nodes from any farmer location on the ThreeFold Grid, totally &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;what_is_peer_to_peer&#x2F;&quot;&gt;peer-to-peer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; between the chosen farmer and the node operator. The deployed workloads are computed in a P2P manner, no middle party involved.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;for-dapp-developers&quot;&gt;For dApp Developers&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Web3&#x2F;Blockchain developers can use ThreeFold’s P2P Cloud - offering both compute and storage - to build and power their applications in a truly decentralized cloud infrastructure, both blockchain-native and cloud-native. A strong advantage here is that developers have the ability to leverage Kubernetes, Docker, S3, and other cloud-native tools (all compatible &#x2F; integrated with the ThreeFold) to power and optimize their data processing capabilities, as well as the overall functionality of their dApps. But the sweet spot is that it is deployed on a decentralized IT infrastructure, close to where users would be located.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;but-why-choose-threefold-over-other-decloud-projects&quot;&gt;But why choose ThreeFold over other DeCloud projects?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There may be bigger names in the space, but ThreeFold’s technology and offerings are much more comprehensive than the rest. ThreeFold provides decentralized storage, compute, and network all under one roof (whereas most other projects offer only one of the three) and as mentioned, we have created an environment for developers which is highly-compatible to the developer tools and solutions they use today. Further, ThreeFold is building new infrastructure &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;an_intro_to_the_threefold_grid&#x2F;&quot;&gt;from the ground up&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (rather than relying on extra space in data centers) and the technology is truly peer-to-peer.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We already have &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;partners&#x2F;blockchain&quot;&gt;a number of partners in the space&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; who recognize these advantages.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any blockchain protocol or dApp, whether operating DeFi, NFTs, DEXs, etc, will at some point need to leverage the power of the decentralized cloud and escape from centralized cloud providers. We’re seeing some of that adoption from a decentralized storage side with IPFS, which has been adopted by many dApps, and others – but as a developer, you will have to think twice, not just about where your&#x2F;your users’ data is being stored, but also about how (and where) your app is computed and powered.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Participate now in our quest to fully decentralize the Internet by &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;farm&quot;&gt;becoming a node&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on our grid or &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tft&quot;&gt;buying TFT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>EconoTimes Covers ThreeFold and DFINITY</title>
		<published>2021-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/10/post-7/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/10/post-7/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🗞 ThreeFold in the News 🗞&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“DFINITY and ThreeFold may have the same goal in sight, but their route to achieving the goal differs.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ThreeFold, DFINITY and the race to Decentralize the Internet, via EconoTimes.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full article &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;econotimes.com&#x2F;ThreeFold-DFINITY-and-the-race-to-Decentralize-the-Internet-1618367&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>How to Deploy ownCloud on the ThreeFold Grid</title>
		<published>2021-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-30/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-30/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Following up on recent news:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We wanted to share &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=2ZkpsG6dQvw&quot;&gt;the demo&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of how to deploy ownCloud on top of the ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; – which was first showcased to the ownCloud ecosystem this Monday at ownCloud Conference 2021.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The demo itself starts at 13:30, and takes under ten minutes.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>TechTimes Covers Zero OS</title>
		<published>2021-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-028/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-028/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🗞 ThreeFold in the News 🗞&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The world’s economy is increasingly being plagued by constant cyberattacks” and “the centralized model sets the whole system up for a possible collapse”. Learn how ThreeFold’s infrastructure offers a solution to this alarming global issue.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full article &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.techtimes.com&#x2F;articles&#x2F;265905&#x2F;20210927&#x2F;threefolds-zero-os-promises-unparalleled-levels-of-internet-security-and-efficiency.htm&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>How ThreeFold Provides a Secure IT Ecosystem</title>
		<published>2021-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-17/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-17/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week, &lt;strong&gt;Apple and Google issued critical security updates&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; due to multiple “zero-day” (read: extremely urgent) vulnerabilities which most likely have already been exploited. And these most recent examples are just the tip of the iceberg.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📚 Learn about the prevalent &amp;amp; growing threat of cyberattacks and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;critical-security-updates-for-apple-and-google-underline-need-for-secure-it-ecosystem&#x2F;1271&quot;&gt;how ThreeFold provides a secure IT ecosystem&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; the world so badly needs.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>What&#x27;s Possible on Grid 2</title>
		<published>2021-09-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-09-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-9/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-9/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;While we &lt;strong&gt;work to open testing of Grid 3.0&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; to our community, questions are coming in around how to get started testing the Grid today.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;what-you-can-do-on-the-threefold-grid-today&#x2F;1220&quot;&gt;this post&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, Scott outlines &lt;strong&gt;what’s currently available to test on Grid 2&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;If you’re interested in testing on the ThreeFold Grid, please join &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldtesting&quot;&gt;our testing community&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Interview – Designing Solutions for a P2P Future</title>
		<published>2021-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/08/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/08/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month, I met with Jonas Delrue from Jimber, the team developing P2P solutions like video chat, office workspace, isolated web browser, and messaging, using the Digital Twin platform. Digital Twin is a use case on top of the ThreeFold Grid. We talked about the technical hurdles and motivations for developing private, decentralized, and open source alternatives to popular products from major corporations.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The following has been edited lightly for clarity and flow.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
I’m wondering about this video chat solution that we’re using for the interview right now. Building reliable video conferencing took a long time for the industry to get right, as far as I understand, and this seems very comparable in performance to Zoom. What did it take to produce this, what challenges came up, and what open source components are you using?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Yes, the solution is fully open source, using Janus as a back end which is a signaling and MTU server that handles all the traffic. But the main reason why we created our own solution is because we want to deploy the solution on the ThreeFold Grid and make a really decentralized video application. So everyone can start their own video room and the data will only be shared between the members of the room, instead of going through Zoom.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The reasons for this have become very clear in the latest developments at Zoom where they had the lawsuits for end-to-end encryption. So something that our solution will offer is not only end-to-end encryption but also the traffic won’t go through central points – so there’s no way for us to eavesdrop on any of the conversations as a company since we’re not included in the process. So that’s the main reason that we created this one.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Very cool. I know for Zoom free accounts, all traffic is routed through servers in the United States which also has performance implications for anyone in other parts of the world. You have this big transatlantic hop back and forth for people talking to each other in different parts of Europe, for example, which could create lag or dropouts. And of course, the privacy feature is super important, because if we’re using Zoom or any other centralized service it’s a black box. They say your connections are end-to-end encrypted, but there’s no way to verify that without open source code and self hosting.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Yep, so what we offer is fully open source, and using the Digital Twin platform you’ll be able to start your own solutions, so it’s fully in your own hands.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Do you know what kind of resources are required to run the video chat server?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The CPU and memory usage on the server is very low, but bit rate depends on how good your connection is and how high quality you want to use. Right now we have some default quality but we will be able to make that configurable, so you’ll be able to choose how much data that you want to consume during your conversation, which will of course imply a better or a worse resolution and experience.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Totally. I’ve heard that we should be able to host many Digital Twins on a single node. I’m curious of your thoughts on that. How many Digital Twins do you think we could run on a single Titan node or server in a rack?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;That’s a hard one. I’d have to check for real numbers on the current implementation, but the thing is that there’s not really a hard limit, as long as you keep improving your software and making it more efficient, making it more suitable to the scaling case. Right now in centralized systems this mostly is not a concern, but if you make it more suitable to self hosting and the digital twin scenario, then we should be able to get really far on that.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;It’s going to take some effort and time to improve it and to make it better so the usage goes down, while the hardware also gets better so it’s two ways. I think in the long run we should be able to host really lots and lots of Digital Twins on one single node. It also depends on what you’re doing on the Digital Twins, if everyone is doing video conversations it will of course have more consumption than if everyone is just chatting in text.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
There’s a good number of features here in video chat already like the background replace and some others I was impressed to see already during my testing. Of course Zoom has many more features like hosting these large conferences, breakout groups, allowing people to raise their hand digitally. I’m wondering what features are on the road map for this solution and what should we expect to see coming next?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Raising hands is one of the things that we’re developing now, but we’re mostly doing improvements at the back end so we can get a more efficient solution and a solution that is better suited to the decentralized way of working. Now, we don’t have the size of team that Zoom has of course at this point, so we’re a bit slower in releasing new features. We do have a list of things that we want to implement in the near future. Things like waiting rooms and all the stuff that you came up with, they’re on the road map but not for the very short term since right now we’re really focusing on getting this thing working in a decentralized way on the Grid.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
That makes sense. And what is the status of that? Are we using the Grid right now, or is this a staging server?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;This is a production server of Jimber. We use this one to talk to our employees, so for internal calls, and we’re also using it to talk to clients. We’ve been using it for over six months without any problems so it’s really production ready, but this version is not running on the Grid right now. We do have deployments on the Grid that work perfectly.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Good to know. Is that something that someone with the proper amount of knowledge and motivation could test for themselves already, running the solution on the Grid?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Yeah, they should be able to. It might be that they still need a little bit of help from the technical team, but it should be doable, yes.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Cool, I’ll put that on my list of things to try out. So that’s video chat. Do you see any challenges arising from quirks of the Grid in implementing any features or scaling things up to a certain level. Is there anything that’s tricky about moving something like this onto the Grid?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;It’s more about the Digital Twin than the meeting solution itself. Right now we’re really working on getting the Digital Twin able to launch for a single person, so we’re checking out how we’ll do the deployments, the payment flow, things like that.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;So for us, that’s the challenge right now, but in the long run it’s probably going to be scaling, being sure that the Digital Twin runs close enough to the person actually using it, being sure that the interaction between Digital Twins is really fast and with low latency. Things like that will of course be a huge challenge, and also keeping everything private, making sure that everything is secure is also a bit challenging.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Another big challenge is that users are not used to a decentralized environment. So if you lose your seed phrase or in some way destroy your own Digital Twin, it’s decentralized so we can’t access it. There isn’t a company that can just look into the big system and fix it for you. You are a bit responsible for your own system so that’s also a bit of a challenge. So to get users informed and make software that’s really easy for them, where they can’t mess things up, and where users can give us enough logs when something goes wrong to help them in a decentralized way.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
For sure, I know that’s a big concern around our VDC solution as well. You onboard someone into the system and they need to take responsibility for their own data and deployments. I think that’s a huge issue across this space right, you want to give people the power but they also need to be able to take the responsibility. We’ll see how that goes, as users start to come onboard and what kinds of challenges they run into.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Yeah, that’s going to be the fun part, once users really start onboarding and start using everything. It’s mostly a stressful situation at first if you launch a new product, but we’re going to be starting off with a beta version so we don’t get too much ahead of ourselves. Using the beta period to really get the software to be at the point where we need it for production will probably be the best step, to take the stress a bit off the team, and in the next version we can go full fledged production with a really nice product.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
How soon do you think we’ll be ready to invite some members of the community to start testing?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;We want to have a version ready for September, so that’s what we’re looking at.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Great. Let’s shift gears and talk about the file browser and office solution, which I’ve also tested. It’s very cool. You’re able to preview images and videos, edit documents, and more. I understand it’s at least two open source components, you have the file browser and OnlyOffice working together.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;So the file browser is totally made by us, it’s fully new. We use OnlyOffice as a document service to edit the documents, and right now you can already share documents with other people and collaborate on documents. We’re building a kind of online office alternative that is owned by you and where your files are safe from companies trying to get data from it to give you specific advertisements and that sort of thing.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Okay, I didn’t realize that the file browser piece had been built in house.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;It’s still very basic. It doesn’t have all the features of the big ones yet. It has the basic functionality—you can upload files, make folders, put the files in the folders, open files, collaborate, save them, share with people, all of those things are available, so it’s pretty usable. This has been launched in a staging version right now, so it’s not available to the full public yet but it should be available in September when we launch the first Digital Twin version.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
I’ve tested it, and it works really well. I’m curious again—obviously building something like this isn’t a small task. Building an alternative to products from massive corporations with huge budgets and teams. So for your team, what are the challenges and how did you make this work?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Of course using open source components like OnlyOffice is a big difference. It’d be hard to make all of the documents services ourselves—that would be really insane. So using open source components is a big key factor in this, but a second thing is that our team has been building and trying out stuff like this for a few years so we do have some experience in building these kinds of tools.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
So in Digital Twin we also have the chat solution. Is there anything about chat that’s cool or unique?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;We’re looking at the big modern chat applications for our ideas there, as well as adding some new stuff in it. For the most part you have all the features that you need. You can send text messages and audio streams. You can send GIFs, which is of course the most important feature in any chat application. Then there’s, block users, delete users, add users to make group conversations, share files with the whole group, all the things like that.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Does that mean that we should be able to switch from Telegram sometime in the near future?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;I hope so yeah, it would be really cool when we can do that. The biggest difference of course is the underlying decentralized architecture.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
So finally, to wrap up, maybe you could talk a bit about how privacy and security is handled? We have end-to-end encryption, we have self hosting of data. What does that look like and how is it built?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;In terms of the platform itself, that’s something that the ThreeFold core team is more working on, so I know the principles and know how it works but I can’t give you real technical details. As for what we build, the biggest tool that we use right now for end-to-end encryption is Yggdrasil or the Planetary Network, as we refer to it in ThreeFold. So that’s a technology where multiple computers form one grid and they can exchange messages with each other which are fully end-to-end encrypted, using the standard TCP stack of those nodes. In that way we can communicate between Digital Twins in a very easy way, using standard technology, but just changing the underlying network architecture.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Totally, I know a bit about Yggdrasil. I haven’t had a chance to test it myself, but it’s super exciting technology, right? It allows anyone behind a firewall to still have a public address where they can still be reachable on IPv6 and everything is encrypted.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;And as soon as you’re connected to one node, you’re connected to every one of them, because they all forward the packets, all end to end encrypted. So it’s a really cool technology.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Absolutely, and it’s great to be able to build on this kind of stuff. Like you’re saying, the open source components give us a big head start in trying to build these alternatives.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Indeed.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Is there anything else you’d like to say about what you all have been building over there?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The whole ride has been really cool, we’re kind of working on a few things at once, and ThreeFold is one of the components of it. For us it’s a very exciting project, it’s very technical and building something entirely new that doesn’t exist yet using all these open source components. So for the team it’s a very cool challenge, we really like to work on it, and it drives the team to create something really cool. It’s a great opportunity.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
I love that, and it’s a big reason I’m excited to be involved with ThreeFold as well: building something that’s totally new, going from 0 to 1, and then inviting the world to come check it out and enjoy all the benefits.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Oh yeah, I forgot to ask about the web browser. I understand that Jimber has been building this for a while and I’ve seen some things about this on your website. So the web browser solution essentially renders the webpage on the back end and just shows the user an image of it?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Yeah, it caches the page on the back end and forwards the data to the client where it’s rendered. So the code of the website itself doesn’t reach you, and that’s a solution that we use for multiple things. One is to protect APIs from getting attacked by users, what we call web application isolation. The second use case is where we have an office environment where people browse the internet and they use our solution to kind of make a gap between the computer in the company and the internet itself. But they can still browse the web and use all their favorite tools without having the risk of getting viruses and things like that.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
I didn’t realize that there’s benefit on the server end as well. So by requiring users to interact with a web service through the browser solution, that provides isolation for the app as well?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;If users are going to the service they are going through our browser, which will fetch the service for you and just give you a state of how it looks so that way we can really protect the back end of the applications from multiple attacks.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
And does this effectively provide a VPN for users as well?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;It’s kind of the same thing, yes.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
That’s super exciting. Something that folks ask me about when they learn about ThreeFold is hosting VPNs on the Grid as a way to get the benefits of VPN in a decentralized way.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Yggdrasil is a bit closer to a VPN than our browser itself, but they pretty much help each other out. The browser in the ThreeFold network is used to protect the Digital Twin itself, to make it very secure and private for you, but the browser can also be used to browse websites from any country in the world without restrictions. So it can be used in that way too, which is kind of similar to how people at home use VPNs.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
That’s good to know. Well, I really like the bigger picture here of an internet experience that’s end-to-end encrypted, where all of your data is under your control, and you have the anonymity and privacy that a VPN would provide. It’s very exciting stuff, and I’m looking forward to sharing about it with our larger community.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Art &amp; Culture in VR: Coming to the ThreeFold Grid</title>
		<published>2021-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/08/post-2/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/08/post-2/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last year at a ThreeFold gathering, a few of us on the team had the pleasure to meet a man named Vasily, a creative mind with a big heart and proud founder of Artheon. Artheon, in its essence, was a virtual reality museum experience focused on bringing fine art and culture from around the world directly to people. The concept was immediately captivating, and the demo brought it to life for us. The graphics were already solid, and being able to walk around a museum and interact with the artwork was a unique experience to say the least. We talked about the implications and his greater vision around access and education, and it was very clear we needed to partner up. Not long after, Artheon and ThreeFold joined forces.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-what-is-the-partnership-all-about&quot;&gt;So what is the partnership all about?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together with ThreeFold, Artheon aims to create the world’s largest open art database – made for everyone, and owned by everyone. We will provide access to art and cultural heritage to people around the world, without borders. Not just access, but a high-quality and high-resolution virtual reality experience where people can really immerse themselves in their surrounding environment. With Artheon, people can now even touch and hold paintings or artifacts, something that would clearly not be possible in real life. And while today, only a select few (relative to the total global population) have the opportunity to travel and to experience museums and cultural &amp;amp; sacred sites, Artheon will change that!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
It’s not only about experience, though, it’s also about community and education and providing a more equal access to art and cultural objects. We’ll bring together a global community of museums, artists, and art seekers who can not only enjoy, but also teach and learn about the art and cultural objects housed within the Artheon universe. For Artheon, it’s imperative
that people are able to access information about the artists and the art itself, and then make and share their own perceptions as well. No need or pressure to follow the direction of the current system’s ideology. This is a different angle from how we traditionally learn at school, where narrow or accepted views and concepts are imposed upon us. A key aim of Artheon is to bring different perspectives through collective, participatory, and experiental teaching and learning.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Looking ahead, the vision is that people will be able to create their own virtual spaces and expose them on Artheon. They can create something from scratch or even re-imagine a historical site as it was long ago and share it with the community.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-does-threefold-benefit-artheon&quot;&gt;How does ThreeFold benefit Artheon?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the start, there was a clear connection between Artheon and ThreeFold from a vision, values, and ethos perspective. But there are also some more specific reasons why Artheon chose and benefits from ThreeFold, which mainly revolve around the decentralized nature of the ThreeFold Grid.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Virtual and augmented reality (VR and AR) provide significant benefits to our new digital reality. These technologies open new ways of sharing information in areas such as the arts in the case of Artheon, allowing for upgraded and immersive experiences for users.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Decentralized clouds have been associated with the promise of new digital applications and services that come with a hyper-connected life. Because the graphics of VR&#x2F;AR experiences require heavy rendering, on-device processes are augmented by splitting workloads between the VR&#x2F;AR device and a decentralized cloud. So, graphics rendering on a decentralized cloud like what the ThreeFold Grid provides would be significantly improved by achieving a much lower latency. Another advantage of the ThreeFold Grid is that it provides an extremely high level of security and privacy, empowering Artheon and its users with real data sovereignty.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
And finally, Artheon experienced an unfortunate event earlier this summer where their servers suffered from an intense heat wave and essentially burned up. There was no backup, and this would have been catastrophic in the scenario of them having millions of users. Good thing they aren’t live yet, but this is a great example of how centralized models fail. With a decentralized infrastructure like ThreeFold, this type of situation would not have occured, as data would be hosted on many locations.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
So, by distributing the computing power closer to their users, a VR experience such as Artheon would not only improve their latency speed, security, and privacy, but also the resilience of their business model. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-the-status-of-artheon-and-its-partnership-with-threefold&quot;&gt;What is the status of Artheon (and its partnership with ThreeFold)?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past year, Artheon has been making incredible improvements to the graphics and experience, and adding as many new pieces of art as possible into the universe. As you can imagine, the possibilities really are endless, but here are some of the milestones planned for the rest of this year:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Planning to add partial DLC (downloadable content) support and photogrammetry-scanned locations for users to experience&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New UI for desktop (Windows, MacOS, Linux)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implementation of desired social features such as follower and friend system&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People will be able to see who of their friends or people they follow are online – from that, they can connect to a server and join them to share experiences together&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People will also be able to see how many people are online at the moment and where they are located on the globe (if permissions are allowed)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow the possibility for museums to host free or closed paid exhibitions&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Artheon will be hosted on the ThreeFold Grid!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-can-you-do-now-to-get-involved&quot;&gt;What can you do now to get involved?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re reading this section, we’re thrilled you are interested in what is happening with Artheon! We are, too! As Artheon is not yet live, the best option for you is to join &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;artheon&quot;&gt;the Artheon Early Access chat on Telegram&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; where you can stay tuned there for updates and ask questions directly to Artheon’s creators and contributors.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Watch the P2P File Browser Demo!</title>
		<published>2021-07-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-07-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/07/post-29/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/07/post-29/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, we’re excited to share with you &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=oT_dKuvF6Ng&quot;&gt;a demo of the ultra-secure peer-to-peer file browser (storage) solution&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; that’s being built on top of the ThreeFold Grid!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
This is part of a series of demos showcasing a little piece of what we’re building at the ThreeFold – private, secure, peer-to-peer alternatives to many of the tools and experiences we all use today.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Last week, we shared a demo of the self-hosted video solution, which you can find &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;news&#x2F;post&#x2F;video_chat_demo&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
See you next time! 👋&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Building a New Internet From the Ground Up – Part 2: Storage</title>
		<published>2021-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/07/post-6/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/07/post-6/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome back for the second part of this introductory series on ThreeFold Grid technology. &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;an_intro_to_the_threefold_grid&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Last time&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; we took a high level view of all that the Grid offers. This time, we’ll be zooming in on storage, covering the low level components and how they can provide a familiar experience like the cloud “drives” and “boxes” we use today.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The ThreeFold Grid offers several different storage primitives that can be combined in various ways to meet the needs of developers and end users of Grid capacity. Ultimately, all storage services are a way of presenting the underlying hardware to software workloads in various ways, according to the desired features. ThreeFold has created a few unique storage offerings, providing distinct benefits over legacy cloud infrastructure. From the start, every component has been designed for optimal efficiency and they work together to offer an unprecedented level of security.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Our most basic storage primitive is a “volume”, which simply offers some disk space to an application in a generic way. We’ll focus more on the innovative solutions that are built on the Zero Database, or Zdb. These are compatible with existing use cases but also represent a quantum leap forward for privacy and security. They are called Zdbfs, Zstor, and QSFS. Let’s take a look at each component and how they work together to provide a complete set of tools for developers building on the Grid. We’ll also see why this matters to end users of services that are hosted on the Grid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;zdb&quot;&gt;Zdb&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zdb is a low level offering that implements with a subset of features from the popular Redis protocol. It is a key-value store, which means that information is indexed like a dictionary. Each “word” in the database is associated with a “definition” or piece of data. Zdb is super fast and efficient, along with operating in an “append only” manner. This means that all new data is added to empty space following the end of existing data, never overwritten. It’s like writing in pen on paper without leaving any white space.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Append only has many advantages, including extending the life of certain hardware and offering archiving features out of the box. The disadvantage, of course, is that old data is retained even when no longer needed. However, this can be addressed by periodically “compacting” the data, to remove what’s no longer needed and restructure what remains with the same level of efficiency. We use Zdb as a base layer for more complex storage implementations that benefit from these features.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;zdbfs&quot;&gt;Zdbfs&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Zdb has all of those neat properties, it requires that applications utilize a specific database interface. To expand its capabilities, we have the Zdb Filesystem. With Zdbfs, the back end Zdb is exposed through the most common interface used for storing and retrieving data: a filesystem. This is the same format we’re all familiar with from the file explorers on our computers. When running Zdbfs, a new “folder” appears on the system, allowing reading and writing to the connected Zdb without any concern for the underlying database. With Zdbfs, nearly all existing tools for working with data can be plugged in to and benefit from the advantages of Zdb.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;zstor&quot;&gt;Zstor&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, we’ve been discussing solutions that utilize storage space on a single node only. While this offers flexibility for developers with a variety of needs, it is also limited in the sense that the failure of a single node would result in the loss of all data. With that in mind, we offer the Zstor solution for spreading data across multiple nodes in a way that provides both resilience against failures and unprecedented security.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Zstor takes a single file as input, to be stored among a number of nodes as specified in its configuration. The system is flexible and able to cater to different needs for performance, redundancy, and geographical distribution. Understanding what happens behind the scenes requires a little math, but I’ll provide as simple an explanation as I can. Zstor has a very unique property: it does not actually upload any of the user’s data to the back end nodes, but it is able to reconstruct the data later based on the descriptive information that is stored.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-magic-of-erasure-encoding&quot;&gt;The magic of erasure encoding&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sounds like magic? Well, let’s explore briefly how this is possible. Zstor relies on a technology known as erasure encoding, which was originally designed to protect data against errors that sometimes occur in the normal operation of computer hardware. Rather than simply making copies of the data as backups, a clever scheme is used to efficiently offer the same benefit. With basic redundancy, four extra copies would be needed to accommodate four failures without a loss of data. Erasure encoding can accomplish the same failure tolerance using less than half the space needed for the original data.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
While erasure encoding can be implemented by storing the data itself along with some extra data known as “parity”, it can also be implemented without storing the original data at all. As a simplified example, let’s say that we want to store the number 13. First, we take each digit individually, 1 and 3. Next, we calculate 1 + 3 = 4 and 3 - 1 = 2. By storing 4 and 2, along with the instructions to reverse these calculations, we have everything needed to get back to 13. If we add one more equation, say 1 - 3 = -2, we can restore the original data using any two of the numbers we’ve computed.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Each of our values would be stored on separate nodes, while the instructions to recombine them would be stored in yet another location. If an attacker were to compromise one of these nodes, they would only have a number that’s meaningless without the other elements. If a single node fails, the original data can be restored using the remaining nodes, and we can add a new node to bring us back to our desired state. By tuning these values, additional security or redundancy can be achieved. We might decide that we want 9 of 10 values to be present for reconstruction, representing a high level of security. Alternatively, a 2 of 10 arrangement would provide high redundancy, tolerating the failure of 8 nodes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;quantum-safe-filesystem&quot;&gt;Quantum Safe Filesystem&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all of these components working together, we have ThreeFold’s flagship storage solution, the Quantum Safe Filesystem or QSFS. It uses Zstor to backup data written to a Zdbfs. This provides the convenient and highly compatible filesystem interface along with the exceptional security and redundancy benefits of Zstor. We call it quantum safe, because even an attacker with a quantum computer would not be able to decode users’ data, if they managed to hack into one of the back end nodes—already an extraordinary feat given the exceptional security of Zero OS.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;bringing-it-home&quot;&gt;Bringing it home&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, we’ve toured a good bit of technology which might be feeling a bit abstract at this point. Bringing this home, our front end experience with these technologies can feel no different than any of the “drives” and “boxes” we use to store our files in the cloud. In fact, ThreeFold has already developed a prototype file browser based on QSFS which has many cool features like editing documents and viewing media directly in the web interface. It’s one piece of a full suite of solutions we’re excited to showcase and invite the community to test soon.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
I hope you found this piece informative and approachable. Thanks for joining me to learn and explore the wonderful world of ThreeFold technology. We’ll cover more aspects of what makes it all tick in future parts of this series. Do you have questions or feel like chatting about what’s possible with ThreeFold’s technology? We’d love to hear from you on &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&quot;&gt;our forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or in &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;our Telegram group&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>This ThreeFold Farm Keeps Veggies Warm</title>
		<published>2021-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/07/post-5/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/07/post-5/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Somewhere in the Netherlands, a ThreeFold Farm is supporting the growth of vegetable crops such as tomatoes, peppers and cucumbers. By directing the excess heat generated from the hardware operations to the greenhouse next door, they are able to achieve an incredible model that benefits both hardware and vegetables. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Jeroen Burks, CEO of Blockheating, tells us everything we need to know about their sustainable farming operations. As far as he can remember, Jeroen has always been a protagonist of the “no waste” approach. He started by recycling material previously used by the tech industry, mainly in the cloud market. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
“By default, most data center operations replace their power supplies every 3 years, no matter the state they are in. They are being replaced to counter any possible downtime.” 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
By refurbishing and repurposing “old” power units from data centers, he gives them a second life as electric tractor chargers, lithium ION pack chargers, and more. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
“You just need to trick the unit into thinking it is still powering servers, add some cables here and there, and it is ready for duty.” 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
His quest towards sustainability started when he was challenged on a pilot project. His friend had bought a new building and was looking for the most sustainable approach to heating it. Jeroen came up with the idea of putting two server racks in the basement and using the heat from that operation, to heat the offices and spaces above. While this project was a success, Jeroen realised that it could be way more efficient, if done with other structures. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
He quickly engaged with a second pilot project where he used two server racks to heat a small greenhouse. This model turned out to be a great combination, which benefited both hardware, as well as farming operations. And so sprouted ‘Blockheating’ – a data center that provides heat for tomatoes, peppers and cucumbers. Why specifically these vegetables? Well, the Netherlands has a fair amount of greenhouses cultivating them, and these ‘veggies’ need that heat during summer nights. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Right now Blockheating has around 400 compute nodes with direct cooling that stores all the heat in a buffer throughout the day, which is then released into the greenhouses during the night hours.
“By doing it the way we do, we grow the internet grid, help grow vegetables and curb fossil fuel usage – in carbon negative compute power!” 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Right now, Blockheating has a portion of their data center dedicated to ThreeFold Farming for a few reasons:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The alignment of values is huge&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ThreeFold Farming is easy to manage&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ThreeFold Farming counters wasteful behavior of internet resources, so it’s a triple win&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Blockheating envisions to scale up-to three data centers of this kind, in an interconnected way, with a fiber ring between them. By doing so, they will be able to increase their offering and have a larger impact on countering the wasteful patterns of the cloud industry. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold is proud to have Blockheating as a ‘State-of-the-Art’ Farmer and Partner, and hopes to see many more people and companies inspired by Blockheating around the world, to expand the ‘People’s Internet’ in a regenerative way. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find out more about Blockheating here: &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;blockheating.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;blockheating.com&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find out more about our partners here: &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;partners&quot;&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;partners&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Grid v2.8.0 Highlights and Release Notes</title>
		<published>2021-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/07/post-22/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/07/post-22/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;📚 &lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold Update&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; 📚
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Recently, &lt;strong&gt;we released ThreeFold Grid 2.8.0&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, which features:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
🤝 Generic VMs Support
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
🔎 ThreeFold Explorer v0.5.1
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
👨‍🌾 Farming &amp;amp; Minting Operational Improvements
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Not sure what this means? 🤔 Scott (who’s on a roll this week) took the time to explain &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;discussing-threefold-grid-2-8-release-highlights&#x2F;1040&quot;&gt;the highlights here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. Feel free to ask questions!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
And you can find &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;threefold__release_notes_grid_2_8_0&quot;&gt;the full release notes here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Into the Fold – The ThreeFold Movement</title>
		<published>2021-07-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-07-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/07/post-4/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/07/post-4/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s not by mistake that you’re here, reading this post. You, like I, understand that today’s systems need to change. You know that decentralization is needed for better wealth distribution and equal opportunities. And that we need better solutions for our planet. You can feel that a global shift is happening. And you want to do something about it. You want to be a part of it.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
You’ve dreamt of a different world. A world where people trust and treat each other with respect – and where everyone has equal chances to learn and to thrive. A world where we’re not just cogs in a machine that serves only the few, rather we work and co-create as part of systems that benefit all. A world where solutions are sustainable for our planet, or even better, regenerative. This world is not just a dream, though – and you’re not alone. Each day, more and more like-minded people are coming together. Welcome into the fold.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;meet-the-movement&quot;&gt;Meet the Movement&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To understand ThreeFold, you should first understand where we came from. Since the late 90’s, some of the ThreeFold co-founders have worked on Internet storage and cloud technology. And after years of building, and many successful launches, they came to understand that they were part of a broken system that was productizing people and damaging the planet. Despite this, they knew that the Internet held and holds the key to a better world, and that the only way to have a truly sovereign, secure, and energy-efficient Internet was to start from scratch. So we did.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
This is how our story began – and over the past four years we have grown and expanded a team of like-minded and passionate people from around the world to bring ThreeFold to life. But for us, we are still in the beginning of something much bigger to come.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We don’t consider ourselves a company, rather a group of humans helping other humans – and our planet. We believe the world needs to change, and we choose to not just talk, but act, to make that change happen. We cannot and would not want to do this alone. There is a strong, passionate, and growing community around us – partners, farmers, ambassadors, technology testers, other contributors, and supporters just like you.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;our-mission-vision-and-values-drive-us-forward&quot;&gt;Our Mission, Vision, and Values Drive us Forward&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our mission is to build and expand a data-sovereign and planet-positive Internet owned by the people, for the people. This will enable equal chances for people around the world to learn, partake and succeed, and will help to heal our planet.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Engrained into the work that we do are three key values or principles:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We believe in &lt;strong&gt;sovereignty&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, and in protecting people. Everyone should own their data, and no one else, not even ThreeFold. Our peer-to-peer technology allows every user to be data sovereign – giving them 100% control over their data.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We believe that everyone should be given &lt;strong&gt;equal chances&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; to learn, partake and succeed. Internet access is a human right, and at ThreeFold we commit to scale our technology to new regions to empower the unconnected.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
And we unify our practices, partnerships, and products around a single mission – to &lt;strong&gt;heal our planet&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. By making our technology actionable, we enable a collective approach to have an impact together.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;together-we-invite-the-world-into-the-fold&quot;&gt;Together, We Invite the World Into the Fold&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s important for others to understand who we are. Thus, we identify with and embody three key attributes as a collective, to show the world what the movement is all about:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold is purposeful.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; We exist to help humanity thrive. Our mission is bold and motivates every step we take. We adapt to our evolving environment and passionately strive for excellence.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold is empowering.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; We help people find themselves and do what they love. We provide support to people and projects that help build a better world, whether they have moonshot visions or down-to-earth ambitions. We aren’t the hero of our story – they are.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold is approachable.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; ThreeFold keeps it real. We’re open and honest, avoiding upstage corporate language and phony marketing spins. We don’t see ourselves as a company, but more like humans helping other humans. So being genuine, friendly, and loving comes naturally.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In its essence, the movement is open and inviting. We’ve created &lt;strong&gt;a participatory Internet economy&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, where anybody around the world can plug in a 3Node and add capacity to the ThreeFold Grid. Together, we’re expanding a data sovereign and planet positive Internet infrastructure, owned by the people, across geographical and cultural borders.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We believe in &lt;strong&gt;collaboration, not competition&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. Our technology serves as a responsible underlying layer on top of which anybody can build and create. We have &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;partners&quot;&gt;beautiful partners&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; already on board – and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;aci&quot;&gt;an alliance&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of conscious people and organizations who share our vision – and we are constantly expanding our ecosystem across industries.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
And while the ThreeFold Foundation is currently the driving force behind the ThreeFold Movement, we believe in &lt;strong&gt;decentralization&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. We have open channels like &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&quot;&gt;a forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;a two-way Telegram chat&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, Github (&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;threefoldfoundation&quot;&gt;Foundation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;threefoldtech&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Tech&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;), and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;threefold_io&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, where people can and do contribute, ask questions and provide feedback that goes into our everyday decision-making and actions.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
As I said at the start, you’ve dreamt of a different world. And so have I. John Lennon once said, “A dream you dream alone is only a dream. A dream you dream together is reality.” Thank you for dreaming with us. Together, this will happen!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Photo by Ahmad Odeh on Unsplash.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Watch the Self-Hosted Video Chat Demo!</title>
		<published>2021-07-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-07-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/07/post-20/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/07/post-20/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;👀 &lt;strong&gt;Check out a little piece of what we’re building at ThreeFold!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
This &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;youtu.be&#x2F;VlxLHxEL1WI&quot;&gt;self-hosted video chat solution&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; is just one component of a full suite of tools you’ll be able to deploy for yourself soon on the ThreeFold Grid!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Building a New Internet From the Ground Up – Part 1: Introduction</title>
		<published>2021-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/07/post-3/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/07/post-3/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;an-intro-to-the-threefold-grid&quot;&gt;An Intro to the ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a farmer or member of the ThreeFold community, you may be wondering about the capacity provided by the ThreeFold Grid and how it’s relevant to individuals and businesses who currently rely on centralized corporate clouds. This can be hard to imagine, because the back end infrastructure that makes all of our apps and services tick is generally invisible to us. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This piece will be the first in a series where I’ll be working to understand what the technical components are and how ThreeFold provides an alternative with distinct benefits for individuals, businesses, and for the planet as a whole. But don’t worry, we’ll start from the ground level and build up understanding in a way that’s accessible to everyone.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;infrastructure-for-a-new-internet&quot;&gt;Infrastructure for a New Internet&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what is the internet? In short, it is a network of interconnected devices that facilitates communication and commerce. These devices include our mobile phones and personal computers, but also the servers that store and process data to provide the end experiences we enjoy. Currently the vast majority of these servers live in massive data centers controlled by a handful of corporations. ThreeFold is changing this, by allowing anyone to connect computational and storage capacity to an open network that is available for all to use, known as the ThreeFold Grid. Our farmers do include some data centers operating on a smaller scale than major cloud providers, and also many individuals connecting nodes at their home or office all over the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the ThreeFold Grid, servers are known as 3Nodes. A 3Node can be pretty much any modern computer system, offering capacity by running the Zero OS operating system. This is a major distinguishing factor, both from the traditional cloud computing world and also from other projects working to create decentralized networks in this space. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-os-for-a-next-generation-cloud&quot;&gt;The OS for a Next Generation Cloud&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By starting from the operating system level, ThreeFold is able to provide a network with much stronger security and greater efficiency than anything that came before. Zero OS includes a collection of components, known as “primitives”, which provide developers with everything they need. These primitives can be used to migrate existing applications from the legacy cloud and also to create new solutions that leverage the Grid’s capacity in unique ways.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re all familiar with operating systems like Windows and MacOS that provide an interface to applications on our personal computers. The OS interacts with the underlying hardware to expose its capabilities in a way that’s useful for both the software it hosts and also the humans who utilize it. For example, when you launch an app on your phone, it is the OS that’s responsible for connecting it to data networks and providing access to peripherals like cameras or microphones. Things are a little different in the world of servers, where rather than through direct interactions, users benefit through the services provided to the applications we use.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To extend the example, when you open a messaging app it will connect to a server somewhere to check for new messages and relay any messages you are sending to the recipient. Here we can see a central issue that has inspired the design of ThreeFold’s technology: when our messages pass through servers controlled by others, it creates an open door for surveillance of all kinds.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold farmers, on the other hand, have no administrative access to their nodes. Furthermore, each component offered by the ThreeFold Grid is built with the intention of allowing for secure and private storage, processing, and transmission of information. Of course, sharing is absolutely possible, but only when the creator of data or content chooses for it to happen.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;three-essential-resources&quot;&gt;Three Essential Resources&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the world of cloud computing, we speak of three basic resources provided by servers: compute, storage, and network. The ThreeFold Grid provides various primitives in each of these categories, to fulfill all the same needs served by centralized cloud providers. While our offerings have the special properties discussed above, they are also highly compatible with the most popular tools and protocols currently used in the industry. This makes it relatively simple to migrate the back end applications, also known as “workloads”, that provide a kind of connective tissue for all of the digital experiences we enjoy on a daily basis.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Workloads are pieces of software that provide services. If you upload a file to some cloud storage service, there could be a number of individual workloads orchestrated together in order to ensure the data you want to save is successfully transmitted to and stored in the back end system. We can understand the need for each kind of capacity by looking at the journey that your file might take in such a scenario. Starting on your device, a network connection, some processing, and finally storage capacity are all involved in providing the conditions that allow you to retrieve that file later.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;network&quot;&gt;Network&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Networking takes place over cellular connections, wifi, and wired internet lines to move data from one place to another. For our purposes here, those details aren’t so important—we’ll focus on what happens once communication is completed by whatever means. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you connect to the cloud storage service, there are network workloads that transmit your data to the appropriate services that process and store it. This might consist of some routing and also authentication that ensures that you and only you access the files that are associated with your account. On the Grid, we provide primitives for secure peer to peer communication and also for allowing public access to back end services.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;compute&quot;&gt;Compute&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compute is what happens with data once it reaches its destination. Computers are mostly just fancy adding machines that take numbers and turn them into other numbers according to a set of specifications, which we call software. In our example, the compute step might involve compressing the information so it takes up less space and also deriving some useful statistics like the file’s original size. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are many details we’re glossing over here, and the compute resources are ultimately responsible for providing much of our end user experience and the interactivity of the apps we utilize. 3Nodes offer a compute environment that natively runs the vast majority of workloads in use today. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;storage&quot;&gt;Storage&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Storage, of course, is the disk space where data resides. It can be a little strange to think about, actually, that all of the information you’ve stored online actually has at least one physical location where it exists as many small electrical charges. On the Grid, application developers can access the disks of nodes directly, in a way that’s optimized for energy efficiency. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also have more advanced storage solutions that offer unparalleled security and low overhead redundancy, giving users the best possible guarantee that only they have access to their data and that it will actually be there when they go to retrieve it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;looking-forward&quot;&gt;Looking Forward&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taken together, network, storage, and compute are the raw elements that give life to the internet we know and love. On the ThreeFold Grid, these elements are expressed in a way that’s both familiar for developers but also pushes the limits of what is possible in terms of technical evolution. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks so much for joining me on this introductory overview of what the Grid provides. Please join me next time for a deeper dive on some of what we’ve covered and more specifics about how ThreeFold technology represents a quantum leap for cloud computing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>The ThreeFold Grid is by the People, For the People</title>
		<published>2021-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/07/post-2/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/07/post-2/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What do you think of when you hear the word Internet? For many, it’s the websites and applications we consume online as end users. But the Internet is much more than this. And ultimately, every action we take online goes through a complex set of automated processes and protocols to store, run, and transmit data (e.g. photos, videos, messages, other files) across the global Internet infrastructure.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Today, this infrastructure consists of massive, power-hungry data centers, and is largely privatized and owned by tech giants such as Facebook, Google and Amazon – who also happen to own the biggest online “free” platforms. But there’s a catch. By owning both the infrastructure and the digital experiences we consume for free, we were actually turned into products of their business models. Our data is being collected and isn’t owned by us anymore. While data has become the most valuable commodity on earth, don’t you think it’s wrong that we don’t own the value of our data today? 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Today, every individual is worth between US $1,000 and $20,000 online, per year. The Internet and Cloud Industry is worth trillions, yet all this value is centralized to a handful of companies. This has to change.”&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold’s open source technology powers the peer-to-peer Internet revolution that holds the premise to disrupt the global Internet in many ways.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;an-internet-by-the-people&quot;&gt;An Internet By the People&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ThreeFold Grid is formed by people from all around the world that connect Internet capacity to a peer-to-peer Infrastructure owned by humanity. Together, we expand a data-sovereign and planet-positive Internet infrastructure that puts people back in control of their data, and their digital lives. ThreeFold’s infrastructure can store all of humanity’s data – from personal data to public datasets and security archives – and can run all emerging technologies such as blockchain, IoT, and Big Data – with more efficiency and security.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold flips the current data center model upside-down, and allows people around the globe to connect Internet capacity in the form of hardware, and earn income for it. This decentralized approach means that anyone can take part in the world’s largest and fastest growing economy – the Internet and Cloud. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
You can see now how this new Internet is by the people, but how about the latter? What does the ThreeFold Grid enable?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;an-internet-for-the-people&quot;&gt;An Internet For the People&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now anyone, anywhere can connect to the ThreeFold Grid and use capacity with some key advantages:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-world-where-we-own-the-value-of-our-data&quot;&gt;A World Where we Own the Value of Our Data&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, all of the data we create online sits inside of centralized data centers and we do not own it. ThreeFold turns terms &amp;amp; conditions on their head and gives us, the people, full control of our data rather than third parties. We can keep our data private, decide with whom to share it, and even decide on where it’s stored and located. And considering that our personal data is worth between US $1,000 and $20,000 per year, ThreeFold offers a direct way for us to own our digital life and the value attached to it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;we-exchange-value-without-intermediaries&quot;&gt;We Exchange Value Without Intermediaries&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The “People’s Internet” is peer-to-peer. This means connections between senders and recipients are completely end-to-end, eliminating the need for any form of intermediaries from the model. Can you imagine what the world would look like without intermediaries? Let’s take an example like Airbnb.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Today, if you are looking for a place to stay on vacation, you will probably end up using the services of Airbnb. But did you know that Airbnb charges both consumers and property owners for using their service? In a peer-to-peer world, this wouldn’t be necessary. You’d simply access a database of property owners (possibly through a peer-to-peer marketplace) and be able to complete the transaction yourselves. No hidden fees, just a direct exchange of value!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;applications-run-on-the-edge&quot;&gt;Applications Run on the Edge&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In its essence, edge computing brings compute and storage closer to people (and the devices where it’s being gathered) rather than relying on a centralized data centers located on the other side of the planet. This is the essence of the ThreeFold Grid. So, data doesn’t suffer any latency issues (performance) and it’s far more efficient &#x2F; money-saving. Further, the distributed nature of the Grid allows for true privacy and security. Edge computing is not just a growing trend but, because of the growing number of connected devices and global Internet usage, it’s becoming a real necessity.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;but-what-about-the-planet&quot;&gt;But what about the planet?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been following us, you must already know that the Internet is responsible for 10% or more of the world’s energy consumption. And with decades of experience in the Internet and Cloud industry, ThreeFold co-founders knew how to turn this around. We developed a lightweight operating system and infrastructure, removing unnecessary layers of complexity from the traditional and Web3 models (actually, blockchains are making it even more complex). The ThreeFold technology is always geared towards maximum efficiency while maintaing performance. And with these advancements, we can already save up-to 90% energy on storage workloads.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Additionally, the distributed nature of the Grid uses less bandwidth (see above re: edge computing). It’s been reported that Netflix alone takes up 15% of the Internet’s bandwidth. What if Netflix were to leverage the ThreeFold Grid? If stored closer to watchers, we could reduce network usage considerably.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Our commitment to the planet goes beyond the technology. Through a partnership with Take Action Global (TAG), we aim to take three times more CO2 out of the air compared to what we put in. Imagine regenerating the earth while using the Internet?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
At ThreeFold, we believe that it’s time for us to take back control. As the world turns more and more digital due to the pandemic and even just the natural progression of technology, it’s time that we not just realize the problems of today’s Internet, but that we do something about it.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
This will happen! So join in, and spread the word! &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Response - The Internet is Destroying Our Brains, but We Can&#x27;t Quit</title>
		<published>2021-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/07/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/07/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The other day, I came across &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;africa.businessinsider.com&#x2F;strategy&#x2F;the-internet-is-destroying-our-brains-but-we-cant-quit-its-a-factory-were-forced-to&#x2F;z4drxf5&quot;&gt;a poignant article&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; written by &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;_pem_pem&quot;&gt;P.E. Moskowitz&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; entitled “The internet is destroying our brains, but we can’t quit. It’s a factory we’re forced to work in without any pay.” As someone who started out in social media advertising (read: trying to capture peoples’ attention to get them to buy or do something often by using their data against them), worked in influencer marketing in its early days, and has now gone 180º to help to build a decentralized Internet by people and for people (where people are digitally sovereign), it really resonated with me.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
It’s commonly-discussed (see: The Social Dilemma) and quite obvious if you use or have used the Internet and specifically social media, that we are addicted to being online. In fact, we’re actually even chemically triggered by social media and other online experiences. Said Jeff Orlowski, director of The Social Dilemma, “Social media powerhouses like Facebook, Twitter and Instagram are “designed” to exploit users’ brain chemistry in order to keep them glued to their phones… They were designed to get us to come back. It’s to figure out how to reverse-engineer what we’re most vulnerable to, most susceptible to, to come back. And what we are seeing is a dopamine response in the brain.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In their article, Moskowitz points out how the Internet is not just like a toxic relationship or junk food, where you can leave or stop yourself from eating, rather it’s “an all-encompassing technology, our main economic engine, the tool we are forced to use to meet others and mediate our entire lives.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The truth is that the Internet &lt;em&gt;has&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; become more than an addiction, it’s become a necessity to keep up in today’s increasingly-digital world. Yet the Internet is not even accessible to about 40% of the global population – and for those who &lt;em&gt;do&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; have access, it does not serve us. It’s actually the other way around. We are the product.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
“We produce the memes, tweets, posts, and pictures that keep us tethered to the internet, and then that content is monetized in the form of advertisements - revenue users help produce, but do not usually see a penny of,” says Moskowitz. We have become cogs in a machine that uses us for its own benefit. Or as they call it, “a factory we’re forced to work in without any pay.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
“Our entire society has been reformulated around the internet, much like it was centered around the factory during the Industrial Revolution. If there’s an Amazon Web Services outage, much of our society stops functioning. Without the internet, we couldn’t find jobs, or, at this point, even friends.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-what-do-we-do&quot;&gt;So, what do we do?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moskowitz is correct in their thinking when they say the following, “A solution to our current internet-use crisis cannot come at an individual level anymore than one person quitting their job would solve capitalism’s poor working conditions. If we want any hope of making the internet less stressful, less back-breaking, and more fulfilling, content creators, gig economy workers, and even casual internet users need to push for a systemic solution.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Simply pending less time on the Internet or using certain apps instead of others is not going to make much of a difference in the end. There are billions of people on the Internet today to make up for the loss. And the underlying system is still massively flawed and can be manipulated. Bold, widespread, systemic change is indeed what we need. A revolution, perhaps.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As pointed out recently &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;tgdaily.com&#x2F;web&#x2F;6-dfinity-threefold-are-leading-an-internet-decentralization-revolution&#x2F;&quot;&gt;in TGDaily&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, ThreeFold is that revolution.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold is the engine for a &lt;em&gt;new&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; Internet, driven by a movement of people who care about a better future. With more than two decades of direct knowledge of the Internet and Cloud industries, we flipped today’s Internet on its head. We rebuilt the architecture from the ground up, with people and our planet at the center of our focus. Instead of relying on centralized hyper-scale data centers owned by a few private corporations, we provide the opportunity for people across the world with access to a network connection and electricity to plug in hardware and provide local capacity, and earn income while they are at it.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In our model, we prioritize simplicity, security, efficiency, and privacy. The technology runs autonomously, removing human error and malicious intent from the equation. Connections are peer-to-peer, meaning no middlemen get in the way of our content, our transactions, or other data. And importantly, people own their data. What we produce is ours. We decide where it gets stored and we decide who can access it (and for what value). In fact, it’s basically impossible from a technical standpoint for anybody to access someone’s data without their consent – including us.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
On top of the technology, we provide experiences. People will have one single log-in and verifiable identity, and gain access to the tools (experiences) they need for communication and for work. As we are a decentralized movement, soon, anybody will be able to build anything they like on top of ThreeFold – but it is our vision and belief that the Internet should not be addictive. Rather a tool for all of humanity to connect, learn, and prosper – with people at the center, not treated as products.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
To the author’s concern, content creators and gig economy workers would clearly benefit from such a digital world as well. Of course services like Airbnb or Uber or Etsy or even YouTube provide value as they are crowded marketplaces both for providers and customers. That said, they profit from people, typically on both sides of the transaction. In a peer-to-peer world, we can create fair and equal marketplaces where the content or product is owned completely by the person listing it there and the value goes 100% directly from person to person. This means no hidden fees, no uncertainty over ownership, no censorship or control from a third party. Of course it’s not all predetermined at this moment, but what I can say is that our biggest concerns in what we create are and will always be fairness and equality (and sustainability &#x2F; regeneration). So, together, we will bring all of this tolife in the best interest of people.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;join-the-movement&quot;&gt;Join the Movement&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In their article, Moskowitz concluded that “perhaps it is only a matter of time before enough of us say ‘enough,’ and protest the internet’s totalizing grasp on our labor and our lives.” But where does protest lead without a viable solution? Maybe this is the type of systemic change Moskowitz could imagine and could stand behind. It’s not a band-aid approach, rather a total re-imagination and re-execution of today’s flawed and manipulative Internet. It’s an Internet by people, for people. Instead of working in the factory, we become the factory co-owners – and the Internet works for us.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
If you believe in what we are building, we invite you to join the movement:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;farming&quot;&gt;Become a farmer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldnews&quot;&gt;Stay updated on ThreeFold News&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;Join the conversation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldtesting&quot;&gt;Test the technology&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;threefold_io&quot;&gt;Follow us on Twitter&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;threefold__how_to_buy_and_sell&quot;&gt;Buy the ThreeFold Token&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are a growing group of people from around the world who not only believe what many of you believe, but we are doing something about it. Let’s grow the People’s Internet, together.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Coverage in Yahoo! News</title>
		<published>2021-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-26/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-26/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;🗞 &lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold Set To Disrupt Status Quo With a P2P Internet Powered by the People&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; (via Yahoo! News)
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
“Overall, Threefold aims to help humanity thrive, save the planet, and make the internet accessible to everyone, including people living in remote locations.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Now when you factor in their partnerships with other decentralized corporations, this goal seems achievable in no distant time. One can only imagine what they accomplish in the near future given the uniqueness of their project and the quality of the team behind it.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full article &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;news.yahoo.com&#x2F;news&#x2F;threefold-set-disrupt-status-quo-051457787.html?guccounter=1&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>It&#x27;s Time We Stand Up For Our Data</title>
		<published>2021-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/06/post-2/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/06/post-2/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Do a quick search for “data leak” on your search engine of choice, and you’ll likely see headlines like this:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personal Details of Over 3.3M Volkswagen Customers Exposed in Data Leak&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Billions of emails and passwords appear in largest data leak ever&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Here’s How the IRS Could Have Prevented the Tax Data Leak&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time to Change Your Password: Tips on Protecting Yourself from Online Scams
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Week after week, month after month, year after year, companies are being hacked, private consumer data is being compromised and released, and we somehow begin to think that this is the reality of our world, something we just have to deal with.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Internet security, cyber attacks, and data leaks are a global threat – and increasingly so as the world moves more digital, and smart people with malicious intent try to take advantage. But this is not normal, nor should it be. As consumers, we should be able to trust that our data is truly safe and secure. And today, we cannot. It’s time we stand up for what is ours.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
That’s where ThreeFold comes in.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Many of today’s issues around cyber security and data privacy come from the lack of innovation in the IT industry over the last decades and the reliance on centralized hyper-scale data centers. ThreeFold has disrupted this model in a few ways:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
First, we started from the ground up. Some ThreeFold co-founders have been working in the cloud &amp;amp; storage space for over two decades, having built components of the cloud and Internet still used today. They knew that the only way to have a truly secure and data sovereign Internet was to rebuild the architecture and the technology components from scratch. So they did. A few years down the line, we’ve created a new operating system, a smart contract for IT, and a peer-to-peer network that can be scaled to anywhere by anyone.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Second, we removed people from the equation. IT has become so overly-complex that people are required in order to maintain it. Because of this, “backdoors” are needed to allow these gateholders to enter the systems and make necessary fixes. But this can lead to human error, and also allows people with malicious intent to make their way in as well. With Autonomous IT powering the ThreeFold Grid, the technology runs and heals itself, and drastically reduces the opportunity for humans to interfere.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
And lastly, your data is owned by you. Rather than relying on centralized data centers, the ThreeFold Grid is an Internet grid made up by independent ThreeFold “Farmers” from around the world who plug in capacity from their home or office. While they own the hardware, they do not own the data inside. User data is stored across multiple devices, and proprietary data storage algorithms ensure that the data cannot be retrieved by anyone besides the user – not the farmer, and not even us.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
As Einstein said, “We can’t solve our problems with the same level of thinking that created them.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a lot more information in &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;&quot;&gt;our wikis&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; about the technology, but what we want to emphasize here with you is that we don’t have to accept data leaks and hacking. There is an answer to the cybersecurity issues the world is facing. And that answer is ThreeFold.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Coverage in CoinTelegraph!</title>
		<published>2021-06-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-06-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-10/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-10/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, ThreeFold received some nice coverage in CoinTelegraph:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
“The ThreeFold Grid … can add tangible value to Dfinity or Solid and other similar projects if they want to benefit from a truly decentralized and sovereign infrastructure instead of relying on current data center models.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🗞 Full Article: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cointelegraph-com.cdn.ampproject.org&#x2F;c&#x2F;s&#x2F;cointelegraph.com&#x2F;news&#x2F;is-a-new-decentralized-internet-or-web-3-0-possible&#x2F;amp&quot;&gt;Is a new decentralized internet, or Web 3.0, possible?&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; via CoinTelegraph.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>What Is Peer-to-Peer and Why Is It so Important?</title>
		<published>2020-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2020/12/post-2/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2020/12/post-2/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-peer-to-peer&quot;&gt;What is Peer-to-Peer?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peer-to-peer (P2P) is a term that originated from the distributed computer application architecture where tasks and workloads are shared between peers, popularized by &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Napster&quot;&gt;Napster&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, a revolutionary file storing system from the late 1990s.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The concept inspired new structures and philosophies in many areas of human interaction. P2P systems and groups are typically critical of authoritarian and centralized social structures and believe in equality, meritocracy, flat systems, participatory &amp;amp; circular economies, as the concept represents a concrete pathway to these outcomes or visions.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
P2P systems are network, not linear or ‘pyramidal’ hierarchies (though they may share some elements). They are ‘distributed’, though they may have elements of ‘centralization’ and ‘decentralization.’ And intelligence is not located at any center, but everywhere within the system.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-does-threefold-relate-to-peer-to-peer&quot;&gt;How does ThreeFold relate to peer-to-peer?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold’s Peer-to-Peer (P2P) computing network is a distributed architecture that splits tasks and workloads between its peers, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;what_is_farming&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Farmers&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Farmers are equal participants in the network and together they form a peer-to-peer network of nodes, the ThreeFold Grid.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Farmers make their resources, such as processing power, disk storage or network bandwidth, directly available to other network participants, without the need for central coordination by servers or stable hosts. Farmers are both suppliers and consumers of resources, in contrast to the traditional &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Client-server&quot;&gt;client-server&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; model in which the consumption and supply of resources is divided.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In the near future, ThreeFold will create Digital Twin, which will go beyond the era of peers doing similar things while sharing resources. It will actually enable much more than that. Digital Twin will create a complete new digital world with diverse peers that can bring in unique resources and capabilities to a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Virtual_community&quot;&gt;virtual community&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on the ThreeFold Grid. This will empower the network of peers to engage in greater tasks beyond those that can be accomplished by individual peers, and are beneficial to all the peers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-did-threefold-choose-peer-to-peer&quot;&gt;Why did ThreeFold choose peer-to-peer? &lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything starts (or should start) from the why, and the ThreeFold story started a long time ago. Before the inception of ThreeFold, many of the co-founders of the project used to work with the largest IT &amp;amp; Cloud actors. Throughout their experience working in the Industry, they realized that the complexity of the technology and the centralization of knowledge &amp;amp; power led to an inefficient, unsustainable, not scalable and unequally distributed infrastructure. So they decided to redesign the whole Internet and cloud infrastructure bottom-up with the vision of shaping a global internet economy that can scale anywhere efficiently, cost efficiently and sustainably. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-does-the-world-needs-peer-to-peer&quot;&gt;Why does the world needs peer-to-peer? &lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By developing the technology, the conviction that peer-to-peer was the best solution for humanity and the planet strengthened itself. Why? Well, put simply, a peer-to-peer system removes all forms of intermediaries, unnecessary steps and complexity from the picture. Therefore, it simplifies the architecture in an incredible way. The benefits are many but here are the most popular benefits:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Privacy&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;: Our peer-to-peer environment means no middlemen or intermediaries, meaning data travels directly between peers and stored on the nodes of their choice rather than being sent through and stored by a third party.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Security&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;: Data stored in data centers is susceptible to security breaches. In bypassing data centers and exchanging data directly between peers, we can achieve much greater security as it reduces code and back doors significantly. &lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Scalability&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;: In a many-to-many system, scale is essentially unlimited. There is simply no bottleneck. And hardware (nodes) can be added at ease compared to current data center model.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cost-efficiency &amp;amp; Sustainability&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;: End-to-end (direct) connection between peers means a more efficient path for data and less energy is needed. Less energy means less cost, and less harm to our planet.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;in-2021-the-world-is-going-peer-to-peer&quot;&gt;In 2021 the world is going peer-to-peer! &lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re now in 4 years into the project, and it is clear that ThreeFold holds the most advanced technology and is probably the only tech company in the world that can achieve a peer-to-peer network &amp;amp; digital world as envisioned by the concept authors. The ThreeFold Grid is running and already at it’s 2.4 version and 2021 will bring various commercial opportunities for the public to partake in the peer-to-peer network, from hosting IT workloads to experiencing P2P end-user solutions. In other words, in 2021, the world will be able to go peer-to-peer.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Decentralizing the Internet</title>
		<published>2019-08-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-08-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2019/08/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2019/08/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;decentralization&quot;&gt;Decentralization&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1989, the Internet changed the world as we know it with the introduction of the World Wide Web. With time the Internet empowered people to share information in a decentralized way. Shortly after, big companies like Facebook, Google, and Apple emerged, providing many solutions that revolutionized the way we live. The “sharing economy” has grown exponentially over the last 5-10 years. This is thanks to a more simplified information flow and well-developed technology, which:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enables a much easier integration of independent players into the sharing economy.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eliminates the need for extensive management and structure of marketplace operators.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We are entering a flat-structure economy. An economy where fewer managerial levels are needed for the system to function. New technologies such as blockchain and the Internet of Things facilitate this ongoing trend. Participants can now interact on a peer-to-peer basis, forming marketplaces and organizations according to pre-agreed, programmed contracts.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-current-internet-is-centralized&quot;&gt;The current Internet is centralized&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the growth in popularity for decentralized systems, organizations, and currencies, the Internet remains centralized. The centralization within the Internet industry brought many barriers to entry. Indeed, to compete in the highly competitive market of Internet capacity dominated by big IT companies, massive investment, and IT development are needed.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
But what is really scary is that the current industry exploits the market tremendously. Data is officially the most valuable asset on earth for a few years, and about 20 companies rule over more than 80% of the cloud industry. In other words - these companies together have more than 80% of the world’s information. In recent years, we noticed the dangers that can arise with the wrong intentions within the data industry with the ‘Cambridge Analytica Scandal’, also highlighted in the movie &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=iX8GxLP1FHo&quot;&gt;‘The Great Hack’.&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold has been developing technology that allows the decentralization of the Internet infrastructure - removing the need for data centers, and allowing anyone to take part in the Internet capacity market. Adding capacity to the ThreeFold Grid (TF Grid) makes you a ThreeFold Farmer (TF Farmer). The more decentralized the Internet gets, the more secure and effective it will become. The already is the largest grid of compute and storage in the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-participate&quot;&gt;How To Participate&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process of becoming a ThreeFold Farmer is very straightforward. Anyone can join the ThreeFold Grid by downloading the ThreeFold Zero-OS onto their nodes and connecting them to the ThreeFold Grid.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
By doing this you will become an operator of a “micro data center” and with that earn ThreeFold Tokens. With or without experience in the field, anyone can become a ThreeFold Farmer. By becoming a ThreeFold Farmer, you empower a new neutral Internet that belongs to humanity - not corporations.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
You can build your server (3node) and configure it, but also options for people with less technical knowledge are available. Please see &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;pre-register.threefold.io&quot;&gt;pre-register.threefold.io&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to see how easy it is for anyone to become a ThreeFold Farmer.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Blog written in 2019, updated January 2021.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
