<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>ThreeFold - why</title>
	<subtitle>Our global digital backbone</subtitle>
	<link href="https://www3.threefold.io/tags/why/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://www3.threefold.io"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2022-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://www3.threefold.io/tags/why/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Building the Future We Want to Live In – A Four Step Journey</title>
		<published>2022-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/06/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/06/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What started out as an idea for a better Internet about a decade ago has evolved into a global movement that’s building a decentralized, open and inclusive future through &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;internet_of_internets&#x2F;&quot;&gt;the Internet of Internets&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The journey towards our ultimate vision of a better future for all is a big one, but can be divided into four digestible phases: creation, expansion, Web 4 and velocity.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-the-phase-of-creation&quot;&gt;1 The Phase of Creation&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past six years, we’ve been building up an incredible full-stack, open-source, decentralized Internet infrastructure, all from the ground-up. From creating our own decentralized operating system, to building a Quantum Safe Storage System, a complete far edge cloud computing platform and planetary peer-to-peer network all accessible via a unique Smart Contract for IT on the ThreeFold Blockchain, we’re proud to have the most complete edge infrastructure to power the next-generation Internet era. A new world is coming, and our technology has the potential to revolutionize digitization on a global scale, across sectors. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creation phase was about developing the key tech components and an initial deployment of our infrastructure worldwide. The ThreeFold Grid is now live in its third generation and the stack is fully functional. As of today, people from all across the world have connected more than &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;threefold_io&#x2F;status&#x2F;1529903015938998272&quot;&gt;3,000 nodes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; across +78 countries to create the world’s largest decentralized Internet infrastructure, and new capacity is being connected every day.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to fully comprehensive decentralized edge cloud solutions, the ThreeFold ecosystem is also developing a range of applications and experiences across IoT, metaverse, blockchain, DeFi, banking, education and beyond.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The phase of creation is almost complete. The ThreeFold team is currently working on the Digital Twin solution that will allow the ecosystem to tap into Web 4 principles – a paradigm that overcomes the limitations of Web 2 and the inefficiencies of Web 3. By advancing our technology further, ThreeFold will be in a unique position to open new frontiers and support emerging global trends.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-the-phase-of-expansion&quot;&gt;2 The Phase of Expansion&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second phase is all about the growth of the ThreeFold Grid and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;connecting_the_dots&#x2F;&quot;&gt;connecting the dots&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. From individual farmers and farming cooperatives connecting Internet capacity independently to our global network, to building Community Clouds and Regional Internets for countries, various pathways to Grid growth have been established by the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;internet_of_internets&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Internet of Internets&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; concept.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet of Internets will interconnect us all, while providing us with digital sovereignty, privacy and meaningful experiences. It focuses on incentivizing local communities to build their own resilient Community Clouds to support their city, town or village with the foundation to build their decentralized future.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on their geographic proximity, Community Clouds will be able to form Regional Internets. Each Regional Internet will be equipped with their own blockchain, validators and liquidity providers as well as local digital experiences in order to remain independent from the rest of the world. In that sense, whatever would happen to the Internet infrastructure outside of the borders of that region would not affect local connectivity and digital economies. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, Regional Internets will be interconnected by the ThreeFold Hub on a global level to create the Internet of Internets. This model is infinitely scalable. Instead of relying on one global network and blockchain, ThreeFold will allow for many independent and interoperable Internet infrastructures that support local communities with a platform to build their own blockchain, DeFi, metaverse, IoT, eCommerce solutions, and much more. Each layer has its own distinct purpose and enables seamless ecosystem-wide interactions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;paradise_hills&#x2F;&quot;&gt;the Paradise Hills partnership&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as the first proof of concept for Community Clouds and our team working with governments in multiple countries, we’re following the glocal approach of applying the global Internet of Internets concept locally with regional context. With our growing community and ecosystem supporting us, and building new relationships, we’re well set to turn the Internet of Internets into reality in the upcoming years.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The phase of expansion will probably never end. ThreeFold is infinitely scalable, and there are many reasons to continue growing the ThreeFold Grid as it is best positioned to service the emerging demand for edge computing and sovereign Internet infrastructure for decades to come.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-the-phase-of-web-4&quot;&gt;3 The Phase of Web 4&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In parallel with the expansion phase, the rollout of the Web 4 phase is expected to kick off later this year to re-imagine business, governance, finance, education and more in order to provide better alternatives for people, enterprises and governments. Essentially, the Internet of Internets is laying the foundational infrastructure, and Web 4 technology will open a world of new possibilities around peer-to-peer and self-sovereign systems.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Web 4 phase will empower people to become 100% self-sovereign with a range of decentralized alternatives to Facebook, WhatsApp, YouTube, Chrome, Zoom and much more.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A multitude of valuable and meaningful experiences are being built by the ThreeFold ecosystem and partners to empower people with equal chances to learn, create, and thrive in a decentralized digital economy – what we like to call an abundance-based future for humanity.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key to all of this is ThreeFold’s open-source Digital Twin technology. It provides a unique digital identity that can serve as the key to an open, self-sovereign and complete digital future. The Digital Twin technology allows ThreeFold to flip the current centralized client-server model upside down, empowering people to become the masters of their own destiny. No more data being collected by servers and sold to third-parties – you become the center of your digital life. There will be more on Digital Twin and its potential to change everything coming very soon.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with strategic partnerships being formed across the four corners of the globe, the Web 4 phase will support the ThreeFold Foundation’s vision of providing access to a better Internet paradigm to a billion people by 2030.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-the-phase-of-velocity&quot;&gt;4 The Phase of Velocity&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rise of the Internet of Internets and the build-up of powerful experiences on Web 4 technology will bring the ecosystem to its fourth phase – Velocity. At that moment in time, it will be all about utilization, economic growth and the acceleration of our collective vision.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tokens&#x2F;threefold__tokenomics&quot;&gt;ThreeFold tokenomics&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; have been designed to support a decentralized Internet economy that incentivizes participants to host nodes, validate the blockchain and build applications on the ThreeFold Grid. The moment utilization kicks in at a large scale on Web 4, the ThreeFold Ecosystem will be ready to reach millions – and eventually, billions – of users through powerful digital experiences that provide a better alternative than today’s paradigm. As of today, 35% of ThreeFold Token transactions under Proof of Utilization are burned to create a deflationary economy. This will create additional &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tokens&#x2F;threefold__grid_valuation&quot;&gt;value&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for the token ecosystem as it will reduce the circulating supply in relation to the increasing demand for ThreeFold’s infrastructure. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put, the fourth phase will drive significant utilization of the ThreeFold Token and support in positioning it as the Bitcoin for Internet capacity. It will open up a decentralized Internet economy full of opportunities, empowerment and meaningful experiences for people all around the world. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;bringing-abundance-opportunity-to-the-world&quot;&gt;Bringing Abundance &amp;amp; Opportunity to the World&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“A dream you dream alone is only a dream. A dream you dream together is reality.” – John Lennon&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve reached a pivotal moment in the evolution of ThreeFold to support our world in solving some of its greatest challenges. A complete and resilient Internet infrastructure owned by local communities is an essential way to build a circular and participatory economy. Considering that the Internet is the second largest and fastest growing economy in the world, the Internet of Internets represents a foundation for a decentralized and abundant world. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;internet_of_internets&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Internet of Internets&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; model supports ThreeFold in achieving its vision of providing Internet access to more than a billion people worldwide. And we believe that if we work together, we can connect all of humanity responsibly. Driven by our planet-first, people-first philosophy, the ThreeFold movement is shaping the world we want to live in and laying the foundation for an open, inclusive and abundance-based future.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current phase of expansion is vital to turn our vision into reality and to fulfill our mission. Let’s build this world of opportunity and abundance together.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;Join&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; the ThreeFold movement now&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;what_is_farming&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Be&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; the Internet&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Help us &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;realizing_the_promise&#x2F;&quot;&gt;realize our vision&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for a better future&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Welcome to the Internet of Internets</title>
		<published>2022-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/05/post-7/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/05/post-7/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Internet of Internets is owned by the people.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; &lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;It interconnects us all, directly, without any intermediaries.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; &lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;We store our data in full sovereignty and privacy.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; &lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;On top of it, we build valuable experiences, useful experiences.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; &lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Not to control. Not to polarize. Not to addict. Not to manipulate.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; &lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Rather to connect. To exchange. To share. To provide value for each other.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; &lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A circular economy, to benefit the collective and, as a result, each of us individually.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; &lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;As believers in a better world who choose to act.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet is the backbone for the Web, a global infrastructure that makes our digital experiences possible. It represents a network of billions of interconnected computers and other electronic devices, communicating with each other and carrying all of the online information and services that we use on a daily basis.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hyperscale data centers owned and operated by big tech corporations make up the “housing” of the Internet today, where all of our digital information, services, and data reside. While these data centers are mainly located in North America, Europe, and parts of Asia, no matter where you live in the world, you rely on them to go about your daily digital life.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first glance, you might not see any glaring issues here. After all, the Internet is one of humanity’s greatest achievements, and these data centers have until today made the Internet accessible to billions of people around the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, this also means that for those of us who are connected, we depend on a few large tech corporations to act as the gatekeepers of the Internet. They own 80% of the infrastructure and most of the major online platforms, thus owning and capitalizing on our data and turning us all into products. And today, 3-4 billion people still remain unconnected, as these data centers are extremely expensive to build and difficult to maintain.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current Internet paradigm is also highly unsustainable, requiring enormous amounts of energy to connect the digital world. We have no choice but to find more regenerative solutions to provide humanity with the tools and infrastructures needed to solve the world’s greatest challenges.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, here we face a paradox. Today’s Internet would not exist in its current form if it were not for the centralized model. Yet, how can we continue down a path that has serious implications for humanity and our planet, while being incapable of scaling with emerging demand? Is there another viable solution?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It now exists. Welcome to the Internet of Internets.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;it-starts-locally-and-ends-globally&quot;&gt;It starts locally, and ends globally&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Internet of Internets is owned by the people.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; &lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;It interconnects us all, directly, without any intermediaries.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; &lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;We store our data in full sovereignty and privacy.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until today, people have been relegated to Internet “users,” or “clients” in a client-server model – either way, cogs in a big machine (the Internet) that ultimately benefits the few (big tech). But what if we reversed that model? We believe there should not be just one Internet, owned and operated by the few, rather a network of thousands of interconnected Internets, owned by and benefiting local communities.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basis of this new model, community or neighborhood clouds. Essentially acting as a community-owned, decentralized alternative to building data centers, neighborhood clouds provide high-bandwidth capabilities for regional Internets. With high-quality hardware installations and optimized networking infrastructure, neighborhood clouds provide more efficiency and interoperability than any traditional data center setup.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Local enterprises and developers can now customize and scale their solutions in ways never before possible. And people living in and around these community clouds can utilize the capacity as they wish, all while taking full control of their own data and interconnecting without intermediaries. This allows for a completely decentralized and localized Internet by the people, for the people. The foundation of the Internet of Internets.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Community clouds in proximity connect directly with each other to form a network, what we call a regional Internet. These regional Internets have their own blockchains and can operate 100% independent from other regional Internets. A regional Internet starts with 99 founding fathers and mothers who deploy blockchain nodes, with integrated support for DeFi. Each regional Internet has its own ThreeFold Token, and differences in farming and cultivation models are possible depending on the decisions of the regional Internet’s DAO. Further, each regional Internet has its own DeFi pool to allow frictionless exchange between TFT and the regional TFT.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ThreeFold Hub interconnects the Regional Internets to form  the Internet of Internets. Secured by 100 L2 Validators, this is the home of the TFT and the base governance layer for ThreeFold. Here you can see a model which starts locally and scales forever. Each layer has a distinct purpose and allows the ecosystem to interact. And while being hierarchical, it’s still 100% peer-to-peer and decentralized. An Internet of Internets, by the people, for the people – safe, sovereign, and sustainable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-world-of-endless-possibilities-lives-on-top&quot;&gt;A world of endless possibilities lives on top&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;On top of it, we build valuable experiences, useful experiences.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; &lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Not to control. Not to polarize. Not to addict. Not to manipulate.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; &lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Rather to connect. To exchange. To share. To provide value for each other.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet of Internets empowers people to build their own Internet infrastructure. Along with building community-owned Internets, our ecosystem is reimagining education, business, governance and finance for a fairer, more inclusive and regenerative future. The Internet of Internets is opening up a new world of possibilities, and we’re just getting started.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet of Internets provides a regenerative, safe and sovereign Internet infrastructure layer. It offers a secure, private, reliable and high-performing Internet experience. Moreover, it will include a set of experiences, solutions and knowledge that enable all people to equally learn, create, exchange, and thrive online.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the Internet of Internets, we’re laying the foundation for a world built on abundance, rather than scarcity.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-foundation-for-a-better-digital-world&quot;&gt;The foundation for a better (digital) world&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A circular economy, to benefit the collective and, as a result, each of us individually.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; &lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;As believers in a better world who choose to act.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We strongly believe in the ThreeFold Law which states that any good you do will return to you threefold in this lifetime. By making our technology actionable, we energize a collective approach towards a single mission – empowering humanity while regenerating our planet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet of Internets provides a much-needed alternative to big tech that can bring the Internet to even the most remote places in the world in an ethical, sustainable and secure way. It starts locally and ends globally.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet of Internets is based on an equality- and abundance-based paradigm to benefit and provide fair value exchange for the collective and each of us individually. We are driven by a planet-first, people-first philosophy that shapes the future we want to live in. Without our planet, we have nothing. And we believe people need a better system. One they can depend on. One that allows everyone to provide economic flow. One that gives them the opportunity to thrive. One that is able to empower local communities all over the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together, we’re building our own future through the Internet of Internets – decentralized, open, inclusive, regenerative, and resilient.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join the ThreeFold &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;movement&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; today and drive a new Internet era.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn how to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;what_is_farming&#x2F;&quot;&gt;be the Internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Help us &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;connecting_the_dots&#x2F;&quot;&gt;connect the dots&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In the coming weeks, we’ll be diving deeper into the Internet of Internets model, to share more about the different layers, how they come together, and how you can get involved.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold at Consensus: A Decentralized World is in Our Hands</title>
		<published>2022-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/05/post-5/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/05/post-5/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s that time of the year when believers and builders of a decentralized tomorrow  gather to celebrate the festival for the decentralized world. About 15,000 people will attend Consensus 2022 by CoinDesk from June 9 through June 12. Throughout the festival, key topics around decentralization, blockchain, crypto, Web 3 and the metaverse will be explored and discussed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is ThreeFold attending Consensus? Excellent question. The ThreeFold community truly believes that collaboration, decentralization and peer-to-peer systems are the foundation for a better Internet, and subsequently, a better world. And together we are making that world a reality. But we need to grow and extend the community on the ground with the right people, dreamers who choose to act now.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As many consider Consensus the festival for the decentralized world, some questions linger: &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How committed are the projects and participants to decentralization, and for what reasons? How far are they willing to go to bring that world to life?&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s no secret that many projects in the space still rely on centralized infrastructure – at least to some degree. So, are they really delivering on their promise of decentralization? &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-decentralized-world-needs-a-decentralized-foundation&quot;&gt;A decentralized world needs a decentralized foundation&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think we’ve already come to Consensus that decentralization has to start at the foundational level. See what I did there? The ThreeFold co-founders have more than 20 years of experience in setting world records in Internet storage and cloud automation technologies. With ThreeFold, they started from scratch to build a fully decentralized Internet infrastructure that’s peer-to-peer and open source. We’re realizing the promise of an Internet built and owned by the people, back to the vision of Web 1 through the implementation of Web 4 technology. For us, it’s obvious that we simply cannot build a fair and equal digital world on top of today’s old-world infrastructure which is owned by the few. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With our fair, inclusive and decentralized Internet infrastructure, we’re laying the foundation for a better world. Following our ethos of &lt;em&gt;planet first – people second – profit (value) only as a result&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, we’re striving to regenerate our planet and to empower the collective – the many and not the few. By putting our planet and people first, we create real sustainable value. We believe that, together, we’re strong enough to build new regenerative systems powerful enough to enable anyone to have a sovereign, safer and more fulfilling life.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of today, people from 77 countries are connecting thousands of computers (3Nodes) to the ThreeFold Grid – all contributing to ThreeFold’s open-source peer-to-peer Internet infrastructure. And any node or dApp, actually anything that can run on Linux, can run on top of the ThreeFold Grid in a truly decentralized way. With ThreeFold’s infrastructure and thriving ecosystem, there’s an abundance of potential and opportunities – really anything is possible.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;threefold-consensus&quot;&gt;ThreeFold @Consensus&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ThreeFold team and community will soon gather at the Austin Convention Center, 500 E. Cesar Chavez Street, Austin. Meet the ThreeFold team at &lt;strong&gt;Exhibit Booth 310&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; not far from the Networking Lounge. We’ll be there throughout the entire exhibit to connect with participants, share the ThreeFold story and extend the community – Friday, June 10 through Saturday, June 11 from 9am until 6pm.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At our booth, you’ll be able to meet the team, see and hold a Titan 3Node, have the chance to win a free 3Node of your own, find resources that will empower you to get involved, and more.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold will also host a gathering outside of the Convention Center. We will share more via &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldnews&quot;&gt;our Telegram News Channel&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; when the details are finalized, so stay tuned.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold is more than an Internet. It is the foundation for a truly decentralized world. Are you ready to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;join&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; the global ThreeFold movement?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Check out the full &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;events.coindesk.com&#x2F;consensus2022&#x2F;agenda&quot;&gt;Consensus agenda&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and take advantage of &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;events.coindesk.com&#x2F;consensus2022?promo=a7MsHxui&quot;&gt;our 25% discount code&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to buy tickets.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And don’t forget to let us know if you’ll be joining ThreeFold at Consensus – we’d love to connect with you!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Planting the Seeds: ThreeFold&#x27;s Plans to Regenerate the Planet</title>
		<published>2022-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/05/post-2/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/05/post-2/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘Being sustainable’ has become a buzzword – a claim to boost our image rather than an honest endeavour. It is hard to trust people and brands today when we fear to fall into the trap of greenwashing. However, we have no choice but to change our collective behaviour, consumption patterns and business practices if we want to combat climate change and the collapse of biodiversity.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last November, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.nature.com&#x2F;articles&#x2F;d41586-021-03431-4&quot;&gt;COP26&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; shed light on how indecisive our global institutions and governments are in the face of an unprecedented climate crisis. We now have to come to terms with the fact that carbon neutrality is no longer enough. Rising carbon emissions have been linked to an increasing amount of heat waves, droughts, floods and hurricanes globally. It is our collective responsibility to reverse the unintended consequences of our actions. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you know that warnings about the risks and harms of excessive carbon emissions date back as far as the 1960s to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.climatefiles.com&#x2F;climate-change-evidence&#x2F;presidents-report-atmospher-carbon-dioxide&#x2F;&quot;&gt;a report&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; by former US President Johnson’s Science Advisory Committee? We’ve clearly been inactive and ignorant for far too long. There’s always another crisis, another challenge to tackle. But we cannot afford to ignore climate change and biodiversity loss any longer.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;blog&#x2F;waves_of_crises.png&quot; alt=&quot;Waves of Crises&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need to tackle the climate crisis with the same urgency, force and determination we do with other crises. And we finally need to face the reality and severity of the climate crisis! After all, Greta Thunberg is right: “Nature does not bargain and you cannot compromise with the laws of physics.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The time has come for us to put our planet first. It is our duty to regenerate our planet and to support the right practices and organizations aligned with our vision of tomorrow. Now’s the time for regenerative action.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-save-our-planet&quot;&gt;How to save our planet&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The greatest threat to our planet is the belief that someone else will save it.” – Robert Swan&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By taking action and making the right choices for our planet and humanity, we can prevent the truly &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.technologyreview.com&#x2F;2021&#x2F;12&#x2F;23&#x2F;1042973&#x2F;climate-change-action-progress-clean-energy&#x2F;&quot;&gt;severe levels of global warming&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and restore the health of our planet. Once emitted, carbon dioxide can persist in the atmosphere for several hundreds, possibly thousands, of years. So, it all starts with reducing global emissions to the lowest level possible. In addition to that, we’ll need to compensate for those emissions that cannot be avoided as well as for all of the carbon and other greenhouse gases we’ve emitted in the past.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As most technological solutions for carbon removal remain expensive and early stage, nature-based solutions are the way forward. And trees, as the world’s largest plants, are an effective way to store carbon.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what are we doing at ThreeFold? How are we contributing to restoring the health of our planet? How are we taking climate action?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;our-commitment&quot;&gt;Our commitment&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe our planet needs regenerative solutions at a large scale. Our motto is: planet first, people second, profit as a result. Without a healthy planet, humanity can’t survive and no economy can exist.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;threefold__tfgrid_home&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is already much more &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;for_our_planet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;energy efficient&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; than the traditional Internet, there will always be energy consumption and emissions that cannot be avoided – and thus have to be compensated for. We’re not just going for the carbon neutrality of the ThreeFold Grid but for carbon negativity (or as we prefer to call it, planet positivity), i.e. offsetting its emissions three times through planting and protecting trees.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we decided to empower our community to take part in our regeneration efforts in a low-threshold way. ThreeFold Farmers will automatically compensate for their 3Nodes’ carbon footprint three times, and everybody will be able to use the ThreeFold Grid’s regenerative Internet capacity while simultaneously supporting impact initiatives.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we shared in our Planet-Positive Farming Series, we’re setting the plan for a planet-positive Internet by implementing a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-on-track-to-be-planet-positive&#x2F;2097?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;Voluntary Carbon Credits&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (VCC) system and supporting &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;supporting-initiatives-to-regenerate-the-planet&#x2F;2110?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;planet-positive initiatives&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; with our trusted partners from &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;driving-regeneration-with-tag&#x2F;2120?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;Take Action Global&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (TAG). &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;driving-regeneration-with-take-action-global&quot;&gt;Driving regeneration with Take Action Global&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re aiming to realize the initial promise of the Internet while also regenerating the planet. Our decentralized Internet infrastructure is already highly &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;internet_energy_consumption&#x2F;&quot;&gt;energy efficient&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; – we’re using about 10 times less energy than any comparable alternative. In December 2021, we &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.prnewswire.com&#x2F;news-releases&#x2F;threefold-and-take-action-global-partner-to-bring-internet-access-to-1-billion-people-across-the-globe-301446693.html&quot;&gt;announced&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; our commitment to achieve a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;c&#x2F;ecosystem-developments&#x2F;sustainability&#x2F;90&quot;&gt;carbon double win&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for the ThreeFold Grid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together with &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;partners&#x2F;take_action_global&#x2F;&quot;&gt;TAG&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; – experts on climate action and education who were &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;threefold_io&#x2F;status&#x2F;1493980240275812352?s=20&amp;amp;t=uW8aclYr82-xqQkEsCeGWw&quot;&gt;acknowledged&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for their incredible work by the Anthem Awards – we kicked off a pilot program for tree planting. After measuring the carbon footprint of the Grid and individual &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;farm&quot;&gt;3Nodes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, we knew what it would take to go beyond climate neutrality and fulfill our planet-positive commitment.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With our tree planting initiatives in Sierra Leone, Malawi and Cambodia, we’re planting enough trees in 2022 to lay the foundation for achieving and sustaining a carbon double win for our Internet infrastructure. Already, students and teachers in the three countries have planted more than 5,300 trees. Find out more about the pilot program &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;driving-regeneration-with-tag&#x2F;2120?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and head to the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;earthproject.org&#x2F;treeplanting&quot;&gt;EarthProject&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; page for the tree-planting details and how you yourself can get involved.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;blog&#x2F;tree_planting_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tree Planting 1&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;blog&#x2F;tree_planting_2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tree Planting 2&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we’ve laid the foundation for the ThreeFold Grid’s carbon double win, we will continue to produce Voluntary Carbon Credits to finance further impact initiatives, such as fostering climate education and renewable energy grid developments to enhance the life of communities.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-regenerative-internet-for-the-planet-and-the-people&quot;&gt;A regenerative Internet for the planet and the people&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all need to take responsibility and to pull our own weight. But we’re in this together. And together, this will happen. After kicking off our &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;driving-regeneration-with-tag&#x2F;2120?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;pilot program&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; a month ahead of schedule, we’re well set to achieve the carbon double win for the ThreeFold Grid – driving the regeneration of our planet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are pioneering the creation of an &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;internet_energy_consumption&#x2F;&quot;&gt;energy-efficient&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and regenerative Internet built and owned by the people. The ThreeFold ecosystem consists of like-minded individuals and partners that share our values and support us in our mission. United in our shared beliefs in open source, peer-to-peer, equality and inclusion, we come together to build a better Internet. And we’re being acknowledged for our work – we’re &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;evenements.optionfinance.fr&#x2F;les-debats-finance-impact-rse&#x2F;content&#x2F;candidats-sia&quot;&gt;nominated&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for the Sustainable Investment in Action &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;sustainableinvestmentinaction.com&#x2F;awards-conferences-2022&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Awards&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in the category “Basic Needs”.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re making it easy for everyone to join us – all you have to do is connect a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;farm&quot;&gt;3Node&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to the ThreeFold Grid and you’ll effortlessly regenerate the earth through providing Internet capacity – a process we call ‘farming’ because it’s a greener, purposeful &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;farming_a_greener_alternative_to_crypto_mining&#x2F;&quot;&gt;alternative&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to crypto mining.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you ready to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;join us&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in our mission?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And don’t forget:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“What we do today will determine what the world looks like tomorrow.” – Marie von Ebner-Eschenbach&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;P.S.: If you have ideas or suggestions for further planet-positive initiatives or potential partnerships, let us know on our &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;c&#x2F;ecosystem-developments&#x2F;sustainability&#x2F;90&quot;&gt;forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>How to stop the Internet from Gobbling the World’s Energy</title>
		<published>2022-04-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-04-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/04/post-7/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/04/post-7/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Global carbon emissions keep rising. Climate change and the collapse of biodiversity are accelerating faster than ever before. And yet, it’s important to believe in our ability to change our behaviour if we are to secure our children’s future. It’s not about being naive or optimistic, but rather a commitment to change and to do better. Across the globe, movements are sprouting to save our planet. How does ThreeFold take part in this? How are we contributing to making the world a better place?&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;  &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once emitted, carbon can remain in our atmosphere for hundreds of years. To survive climate change, massive amounts of carbon emissions have to be offset – and fast. According to a UN report, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.technologyreview.com&#x2F;2021&#x2F;07&#x2F;08&#x2F;1027908&#x2F;carbon-removal-hype-is-a-dangerous-distraction-climate-change&#x2F;&quot;&gt;10 billion tons&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of carbon emissions will have to be removed on a yearly basis by 2050 to prevent the planet from moving past the 2 degree Celsius threshold. Allowing the climate to heat by just one more degree would have unprecedented consequences – including the sinking of islands and coastal areas, an accelerated rate of extinction (right now, estimations suggest that about &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;e360.yale.edu&#x2F;features&#x2F;global_extinction_rates_why_do_estimates_vary_so_wildly&quot;&gt;24 to 150 species go extinct&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; every day) and much more. Our complacency towards climate change proves that we’re still in denial of the chain reaction and butterfly effects of our past and present actions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearly, we’ve already crossed the threshold in the climate crisis where we had enough time for long debates on potential measures and policies. The time for those debates was in the 1960s, when a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.climatefiles.com&#x2F;climate-change-evidence&#x2F;presidents-report-atmospher-carbon-dioxide&#x2F;&quot;&gt;report&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; by former US President Johnson’s Science Advisory Committee first warned about the risks and dangers of excessive carbon emissions. “Climate change is the result of more than a century of unsustainable energy and land use, lifestyles and patterns of consumption and production,” said Jim Skea, one of the IPCC Working Group III Co-Chairs in a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.enviro.or.id&#x2F;2022&#x2F;04&#x2F;ipcc-press-release&#x2F;&quot;&gt;press release&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; published earlier this month. According to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.ipcc.ch&#x2F;report&#x2F;sixth-assessment-report-working-group-3&#x2F;&quot;&gt;a report&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; published by the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC), we can still achieve our climate goals if we significantly reduce emissions across all economic sectors. However, we urgently need to take action to limit global warming to 1.5 degrees Celsius.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now is the time to act. Now is the time for bold moves. As Skea put it: “Without immediate and deep emissions reductions across all sectors, it will be impossible.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-astonishing-carbon-footprint-of-the-internet&quot;&gt;The astonishing carbon footprint of the Internet&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While people are legitimately obsessing about the emissions caused by air travel and whether to take that plane or not – bestowing us with concepts like ‘flight shaming’ – other industries’ significant impacts almost go unnoticed. One of them is the Internet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;carbonliteracy.com&#x2F;the-carbon-cost-of-an-email&#x2F;&quot;&gt;chat messages and emails&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; you send out every day. How many times do you &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.fastcompany.com&#x2F;90171268&#x2F;internet_impact_visualized&quot;&gt;‘google’&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; things? How much time do you spend &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.carbontrust.com&#x2F;resources&#x2F;carbon-impact-of-video-streaming&quot;&gt;streaming&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; music or videos? All of your online activities add to your carbon footprint. There are a couple grams of carbon emissions attached to the energy needed to power your devices and the wireless networks you connect to. On top of that comes the significant amount of energy required to support the infrastructure of today’s Internet, namely millions of data centers and the thousands of servers in each of them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though the emissions caused by streaming one song or sending one email may seem insignificant, the accumulated use of the Internet by billions of people all over the world adds up. It actually leads to a collective carbon footprint amounting to a share of roughly &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.bbc.com&#x2F;future&#x2F;article&#x2F;20200305-why-your-internet-habits-are-not-as-clean-as-you-think&quot;&gt;3.7% of global emissions&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; caused by the Internet and its infrastructure – and these carbon emissions are estimated&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.bbc.com&#x2F;future&#x2F;article&#x2F;20200305-why-your-internet-habits-are-not-as-clean-as-you-think&quot;&gt; to double&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; within the next three years. This 3.7% share of global emissions by the Internet almost makes the global aviation industry with its estimated &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.atag.org&#x2F;facts-figures.html&quot;&gt;2.1%&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; emissions look good.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The global pandemic – while decreasing emissions in aviation due to travel bans – has already accelerated Internet consumption and the resulting footprint due to increased streaming behaviour, remote work and more. With &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.cisco.com&#x2F;c&#x2F;en&#x2F;us&#x2F;solutions&#x2F;executive-perspectives&#x2F;annual-internet-report&#x2F;index.html&quot;&gt;1 billion people&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.statista.com&#x2F;statistics&#x2F;471264&#x2F;iot-number-of-connected-devices-worldwide&#x2F;#:%7E:text=Internet%20of%20Things%20%2D%20number%20of%20connected%20devices%20worldwide%202015%2D2025&amp;amp;text=By%202025%2C%20forecasts%20suggest%20that,IoT%20installed%20base%20in%202019.&quot;&gt;75 billion IoT devices&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; expected to join the Internet economy by 2025, a more sustainable infrastructure than power-hungry data centers is urgently needed to meet the future growth of the Internet in an ethical and sustainable way.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;data-centers-are-power-hungry&quot;&gt;Data Centers are power hungry&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big tech corporations like Amazon, for example, have massive carbon footprints with their corporate facilities, power-hungry data centers, complex operations and more. One larger data center alone consumes up to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.datacenterdynamics.com&#x2F;en&#x2F;opinions&#x2F;from-the-sensor-to-the-data-center&#x2F;&quot;&gt;120 MW&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; – and there are about 7.2 million data centers worldwide, according to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.statista.com&#x2F;statistics&#x2F;500458&#x2F;worldwide-datacenter-and-it-sites&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Statista&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Moreover, a data center’s energy consumption accounts for &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.datacenterdynamics.com&#x2F;en&#x2F;opinions&#x2F;from-the-sensor-to-the-data-center&#x2F;&quot;&gt;about 40%&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of its operating costs. In 2020, Amazon emitted more than &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;sustainability.aboutamazon.com&#x2F;environment&#x2F;sustainable-operations&#x2F;carbon-footprint&quot;&gt;60 million metric tons&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of carbon dioxide up from about 51 million in 2019. Others like Google try to downplay their energy consumption by switching to renewable energy. While renewable energy is an improvement for sure, it does not change the fact that Google’s energy consumption could &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.forbes.com&#x2F;sites&#x2F;robertbryce&#x2F;2020&#x2F;10&#x2F;21&#x2F;googles-dominance-is-fueled-by-zambia-size-amounts-of-electricity&#x2F;&quot;&gt;power entire countries&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is that really a desirable way for us to use the still scarce supply of renewable energy? Shouldn’t we rather focus on the root problem and on becoming more energy efficient in the first place?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step should be to reduce the Internet’s energy consumption and overall carbon footprint. But even then: reducing that energy consumption and transitioning to clean energy will only get us so far – particularly when considering that there simply is not enough clean energy to achieve a complete transition. Those emissions that cannot be cut have to be compensated for. A holistic solution to today’s Internet’s inefficiencies and emissions is needed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;an-energy-efficient-and-regenerative-internet&quot;&gt;An energy-efficient and regenerative Internet&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In December 2021, ThreeFold &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.prnewswire.com&#x2F;news-releases&#x2F;threefold-and-take-action-global-partner-to-bring-internet-access-to-1-billion-people-across-the-globe-301446693.html&quot;&gt;announced&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; its commitment to achieve a carbon double win for its open-source peer-to-peer Internet infrastructure, the ThreeFold Grid. The ThreeFold Grid is able to scale anywhere electricity and network exist, using about 10 times less energy than any comparable alternative while being more affordable as well. By starting from scratch at the operating system level, ThreeFold was able to build an Internet infrastructure that is highly &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;for_our_planet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;energy efficient&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. This infrastructure is already made up of thousands of 3Nodes that are spread across 75 countries and counting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together with &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;driving-regeneration-with-tag&#x2F;2120?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;Take Action Global&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (TAG), an expert on climate education and action, ThreeFold aims to make the ThreeFold Grid planet-positive by removing its carbon emissions from the atmosphere three times in the form of &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-on-track-to-be-planet-positive&#x2F;2097?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;Voluntary Carbon Credits&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. While the pilot for this initiative was announced to start in January 2022, ThreeFold and TAG were so eager to take action against climate change, they kicked-off the pilot one month early in December 2021. It is the first step in ThreeFold’s plan to support the use of ‘nature-based climate solutions’ like tree planting to absorb twice more carbon than the ThreeFold Grid emits by 2022. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-silver-lining-on-the-horizon&quot;&gt;A silver lining on the horizon&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every industry and organization has to pull their own weight. There is no way around it. Far-reaching actions and transformations are needed across industries to limit global warming to bearable levels. “The decisions we make now can secure a liveable future. We have the tools and know-how required to limit warming,” said Hoesung Lee, IPCC Chair, in an April 2022 &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.enviro.or.id&#x2F;2022&#x2F;04&#x2F;ipcc-press-release&#x2F;&quot;&gt;press release&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Together with TAG, ThreeFold leads the way by working on energy-efficient and sustainable solutions for the Internet. The new IPCC report gives us a reason to be optimistic about our future and have hope for the regeneration of our planet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really, all it takes right now is widespread support and adoption of more energy-efficient, sustainable alternatives across industries like ThreeFold for the Internet – something that is up to each and every one of us. Let us all take action for a fairer, more sustainable world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join the global ThreeFold &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;movement&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;farming&#x2F;threefold__farming_intro&quot;&gt;Start farming&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; today and support a greener Internet while regenerating the planet.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Today is Earth Day!</title>
		<published>2022-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/04/post-08/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/04/post-08/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;🌍 &lt;strong&gt;Today is Earth Day&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;A good reminder that we all must do our part to combat climate change. At ThreeFold we believe in “Planet First.” This is why we are working towards a regenerative Internet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some ThreeFold Earth Day content for you:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;youtu.be&#x2F;r0r7GrgoLcI&quot;&gt;ThreeFold is a Sustainable Alternative&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (Video)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;farming_a_greener_alternative_to_crypto_mining&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Farming – A Greener Alternative to Mining&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-on-track-to-be-planet-positive&#x2F;2097&quot;&gt;ThreeFold on track to be Planet-Positive&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;blockheating_intro&#x2F;&quot;&gt;This ThreeFold Farm Keeps Veggies Warm&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;for_our_planet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;A Better Solution For Our Planet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And take a look at a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;looking-for-investments-in-truly-green-farming&#x2F;2260&quot;&gt;couple&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;distributed-farming-with-unsteady-renewable-energy&#x2F;2151&quot;&gt;conversations&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; happening in the forum around green farming!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Farming – A Greener Alternative to Crypto Mining</title>
		<published>2022-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/04/post-5/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/04/post-5/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cointelegraph.com&#x2F;bitcoin-for-beginners&#x2F;the-history-of-bitcoin-when-did-bitcoin-start&quot;&gt;October 2008&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, when the financial crisis was in full swing, an anonymous individual or group under the pseudonym ‘Satoshi Nakamoto’ published a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;bitcoin.org&#x2F;bitcoin.pdf&quot;&gt;white paper&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on Bitcoin, a “peer-to-peer electronic cash system” that ended up disrupting the financial system and sparked the creation of an entirely new industry: crypto mining.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering that many people view Bitcoin as a commodity, similar to gold, it only makes sense that the process of generating new Bitcoins would become referred to as ‘mining’. In a way, mining is an incentive mechanism to reach consensus in the verification of transactions in a decentralized network. While crypto mining originated from Bitcoin, the system has spread quite widely across the blockchain space.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than a decade later, Bitcoin keeps intriguing individuals and organizations all around the world, and has become &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cointelegraph.com&#x2F;news&#x2F;is-bitcoin-a-waste-of-energy-pros-and-cons-about-bitcoin-mining&quot;&gt;one of the most popular&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; financial assets. Nevertheless, criticism and doubts around Bitcoin and crypto mining remain. The most popular cryptocurrency is also frequently brought to the spotlight around its potential affiliations to money laundering, financing of terrorism and cybercrime, as well as the energy the mining process of its cryptocurrency consumes. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cbeci.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Electricity Consumption Index&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of the University of Cambridge, the annual consumption of Bitcoin is currently estimated to amount to nearly 140 TWh. The United Arab Emirates (113 TWh) or the Netherlands (109 TWh) had a lower annual energy consumption than Bitcoin &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;blog.zorinaq.com&#x2F;bitcoin-electricity-consumption&#x2F;&quot;&gt;in 2020&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Moreover, news outlets like &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.theguardian.com&#x2F;technology&#x2F;2017&#x2F;nov&#x2F;27&#x2F;bitcoin-mining-consumes-electricity-ireland&quot;&gt;The Guardian&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.bbc.com&#x2F;news&#x2F;technology-56012952&quot;&gt;BBC News&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; reported on Bitcoin exceeding the energy consumption of further countries, including Ireland and Argentina. Within the last year, headlines like “&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.nytimes.com&#x2F;interactive&#x2F;2021&#x2F;09&#x2F;03&#x2F;climate&#x2F;bitcoin-carbon-footprint-electricity.html&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Uses More Electricity Than Many Countries&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;” in the New York Times or “&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.ft.com&#x2F;content&#x2F;1aecb2db-8f61-427c-a413-3b929291c8ac&quot;&gt;Bitcoin’s growing energy problem: ‘It’s a dirty currency’&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;” in the Financial Times were in no short supply.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the most popular quotes on the topic is Bill Gates’ statement in the New York Times in &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.nytimes.com&#x2F;2021&#x2F;03&#x2F;09&#x2F;business&#x2F;dealbook&#x2F;bill-gates-bitcoin.html&quot;&gt;March 2021&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;: “Bitcoin uses more electricity per transaction than any other method known to mankind, and so it’s not a great climate thing.” Not that this statement or the awareness of the issue would have prevented Microsoft from launching &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;identity.foundation&#x2F;ion&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ION&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, a decentralized digital identity system, to run on the Bitcoin network.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;but-why-is-bitcoin-mining-so-energy-intensive-anyways&quot;&gt;But why is Bitcoin mining so energy intensive anyways?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the heart of Bitcoin’s energy-intensive model is the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.coindesk.com&#x2F;learn&#x2F;2020&#x2F;12&#x2F;16&#x2F;what-is-proof-of-work&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Proof-of-Work (PoW)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; protocol. &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.investopedia.com&#x2F;tech&#x2F;how-does-bitcoin-mining-work&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Bitcoin mining&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, the process of creating new Bitcoins using PoW, requires solving complex cryptographic equations to receive the rewards associated with the creation of the next block in the blockchain. PoW is carried out by computers, known as ‘miners’. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the early days, a simple computer was enough to mine Bitcoin. However, the difficulty of the mining algorithm increased as the network grew larger and more people started competing to earn the next block’s rewards. On average, it takes &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;bitcoin.org&#x2F;bitcoin.pdf&quot;&gt;about 10 minutes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to solve such an equation and to mine a new block. Today, Bitcoin mining has become a costly and elaborate endeavour – accessible only to large investors that can support powerful supercomputers – at the cost of &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.technologyreview.com&#x2F;2022&#x2F;04&#x2F;18&#x2F;1049331&#x2F;bitcoin-cryptocurrency-cryptomining-new-york&#x2F;&quot;&gt;local communities&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s only sensible that miners are beefing up their machines to increase their chances. In fact, the sector became so competitive that &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.linkedin.com&#x2F;pulse&#x2F;sustainable-crypto-mining-becoming-reality-nameet-potnis&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Intel created&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; dedicated chips and specialized manufacturers for mining servers like &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.bitmain.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Bitmain&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; were established. With up to 32,500 Watts indicated by manufacturers, the power consumption of such devices averages 28,470 kWh per year if operated continuously. In comparison, the annual consumption of a freezer is estimated between 200 and 500 kWh per year. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, operating a single mining machine is hardly the way to succeed. The biggest Bitcoin miners have fleets of hundreds of machines in so-called ‘mining farms’, carefully maintained and constantly ventilated, to prevent them from overheating. Some of the largest, like &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.rockdalemdd.org&#x2F;news&#x2F;whinstone-us-breaks-ground-build-world%E2%80%99s-largest-bitcoin-mining-facility-rockdale-texas&quot;&gt;Northern Data&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in Texas, have an energy consumption of 1 GWh per year, the equivalent of the energy produced by about &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.energy.gov&#x2F;eere&#x2F;articles&#x2F;how-much-power-1-gigawatt&quot;&gt;3.1 million&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; photovoltaic (solar) panels. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In critical times where humanity is facing serious global challenges in relation to climate change and the collapse of biodiversity, we must rethink the basics of how to decentralize our world. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;are-there-more-energy-conscious-solutions&quot;&gt;Are there more energy-conscious solutions?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.coindesk.com&#x2F;learn&#x2F;2020&#x2F;12&#x2F;30&#x2F;what-is-proof-of-stake&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Proof-of-Stake (PoS)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; mechanisms have proven to be &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.investopedia.com&#x2F;tech&#x2F;how-does-bitcoin-mining-work&#x2F;#toc-downsides-of-mining&quot;&gt;less energy intensive&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; than PoW. With PoS, miners lock up (‘stake’) a blockchain’s cryptocurrency on escrow accounts to be granted mining rights. In exchange for this participation, miners receive an interest proportional to their stake as reward. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PoS-based blockchains are faster and much more energy efficient than PoW-based blockchains. However, the implementation of a PoS protocol poses its own challenges. For example, it is known for incentivizing hoarding, rather than utilization, and driving centralization. The mining industry is attempting to shift perceptions and move away from its climate-polluting, power-hungry image by powering large mining activities with renewable energies or by offsetting their emissions with carbon credits.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this might sound great at first, it does not resolve the underlying issue of incredibly high energy consumption. Should we really allocate relatively scarce renewable energy resources to such energy-intensive endeavours? Or should we rather look for more efficient alternatives – considering we have all the technology to create more energy-efficient models from scratch – and then support what energy consumption remains with renewable energy? &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;threefold-farming-offers-a-greener-paradigm&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Farming offers a greener paradigm&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;what_is_farming&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Farming&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a decentralized, energy-efficient and meaningful alternative to mining. &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;the-potential-of-the-threefold-token-tft&#x2F;1796&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Tokens&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (TFT) are minted whenever new Internet capacity in terms of compute, storage or network is added to the ThreeFold Grid by connecting computers, known as 3Nodes. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By contributing decentralized Internet capacity to the ThreeFold Grid, independent people and organizations called ‘farmers’ earn TFT in return – based on a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;farming&#x2F;threefold__proof_of_capacity?id=why-proof-of-capacity&quot;&gt;Proof-of-Capacity&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;  (PoC) algorithm. PoC is autonomously carried out by ThreeFold’s &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;for_our_planet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;extremely efficient&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; operating system. First, Zero-OS scans the computer’s resources. Then the operating system registers the computing power and Internet storage on the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;tf_chain&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Blockchain&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, making the resources available to the entire network – thereby creating a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;coincheckup.com&#x2F;blog&#x2F;threefold-is-the-decentralized-web-the-future-of-the-internet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;decentralized model&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for Internet capacity provisioning. The &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.docsend.com&#x2F;view&#x2F;wsru3f9tmeaq62wq&quot;&gt;energy consumption&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of a 3Node can vary, depending on the amount of Compute Units (CUs) and Storage Units (SUs) it holds. “The average consumption for a Titan 3Node is around 26.71 KwH per hour”, says ThreeFold’s &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;people&#x2F;alexandre_hannelas&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Alexandre Hannelas&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farming supports the realization of an open-source peer-to-peer Internet free from centralized servers and authorities. Similarly to Bitcoin, the management of transactions and the issuing of TFT is carried out collectively by the network to create a decentralized Internet economy. In a way, what &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;bitcoin_threefold&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Bitcoin did to money&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, ThreeFold does to the Internet – while using much &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;for_our_planet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;less energy&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“By using blockchain for what it’s good at and other pioneering technologies, such as peer-to-peer networking, to complement it, we built the most efficient Internet infrastructure in the world, and by far.” – Kristof de Spiegeleer.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developing sustainable solutions for our planet is essential to ThreeFold’s ethos which puts our planet and people first. A famous quote, we love and frequently refer to at ThreeFold, is Albert Einstein’s “We cannot solve our problems with the same thinking we used when we create them.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our planet needs regenerative solutions at a large scale, and ThreeFold aims to deliver on our promise providing better solutions for our planet and people through our technology. Based on the ThreeFold Grid’s average energy consumption, we’re planting trees with our partner &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;driving-regeneration-with-tag&#x2F;2120?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;Take Action Global&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to offset the Grid’s carbon emissions three times in the form of &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-on-track-to-be-planet-positive&#x2F;2097?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;Voluntary Carbon Credits&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (VCC). Our VCC system was implemented in the PoC algorithm, so every 3Node mints additional TFT to offset its own carbon emissions based on the power utilization of the individual 3Node per month. The &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-on-track-to-be-planet-positive&#x2F;2097&quot;&gt;process&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is fully automated and executed by the ThreeFold Blockchain.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold’s global community of farmers is on a mission to regenerate our planet through the planet-positive ThreeFold Farming which supports tree planting and other &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;supporting-initiatives-to-regenerate-the-planet&#x2F;2110?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;impact initiatives&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; by default. We’re on track to provide a planet-positive Internet and support our partners in their initiatives in fields like climate education, climate action and economic inclusion worldwide.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farming is about so much more than crypto mining. It’s about building a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;medium.com&#x2F;authority-magazine&#x2F;the-future-is-now-kristoff-de-spiegeleer-of-threefold-on-how-their-technological-innovation-will-7acc0e51c365&quot;&gt;better Internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and shaping the world we want to live in. Together with a community of like-minded people, we’re taking action for a better world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If not us, who? If not now, when?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join the global ThreeFold &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;movement&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;farming&#x2F;threefold__farming_intro&quot;&gt;Start farming&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; today and become a part of the new Internet while regenerating the planet.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold in Paradise</title>
		<published>2022-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/04/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/04/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s January 2022. ThreeFold co-founder Adnan Fatayerji sits in the office of Shaher Mousli, CEO of Paradise Hills Development, along with Suhaib Sheikh, COO of the project. Shaher and Adnan are long-time friends and in fact Shaher gave Adnan his first internship in Dubai about two decades ago, while Adnan was in his final year at university.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shaher is well-known in the Dubai real-estate market,  for his open-heartedness and transparency, and has a history of always looking for ways to stand out and differentiate himself and his projects. Paradise Hills in itself came from the idea of creating a “paradise” themed model for residents that could even serve as a tropical resting place for birds in Dubai.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-aha-moment&quot;&gt;The “aha” moment&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past twenty years, Adnan and Shaher have maintained a strong relationship, and on this day, they are gathering to find a way to work together – to bring things full circle. They discuss how the real estate market is making a strong comeback, and various types of value propositions for future Paradise Hills residents, when the incredible “aha” moment drops. Instead of a standard one-time gift or fee write-off, why don’t we add a 3Node to each residence? A gift that keeps on giving! The room is filled with excitement. They realize that a new dawn in the property and homeownership market is born, combining the unified empowerment of digital and physical assets.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;blog&#x2F;paradise_hills_3node.png&quot; alt=&quot;Paradise Hills 3Node&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together, ThreeFold and Paradise Hills will collaborate on a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;news&#x2F;post&#x2F;paradise_hills&#x2F;&quot;&gt;historic partnership&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to create the world’s first neighborhood cloud network, living on top of the ThreeFold Grid. Dedicated servers called 3Nodes will be installed into 170 homes, providing the edge computing and Internet storage needed to run decentralized applications and Internet services. This will give residents, businesses, developers, and the government a secure and highly-available sovereign cloud infrastructure to store and process their data locally. And homeowners will be rewarded in the form of ThreeFold Tokens (TFT) simply by having these 3Nodes connected.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;no-time-to-waste&quot;&gt;No time to waste&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quickly the team puts the idea to paper, and by February the deal is done. In March, the collaboration is announced and makes the rounds in publications like &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;finance.yahoo.com&#x2F;news&#x2F;paradise-hills-property-development-threefold-090000146.html&quot;&gt;Yahoo! Finance&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and on plenty of regional properties. Adnan even begins training the Paradise Hills sales team on how to present the opportunity to potential residents. The speed of the collaboration is proof of a collective commitment to take this leap of faith, and a high-level of trust in each other and the possibilities. Another big reason for confidence: once the modeling was done, it was clear that this could be a massive financial opportunity for residents, one which could even pay off the cost of the house in a relatively short number of years.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;blog&#x2F;paradise_hills_connected.png&quot; alt=&quot;Paradise Hills Connected&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ThreeFold &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;farm&quot;&gt;3Node&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; will be a standard “appliance” in each Paradise Hills residence, much like a refrigerator or an oven. But this appliance is anything but “standard” – it provides and connects decentralized Internet capacity owned by the Paradise Hills community, and comes with an onboarding guide to welcome each resident into the much larger ThreeFold community.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further, Paradise Hills is adamant about building tools on top of the ThreeFold Grid – digital storefronts for local businesses, peer-to-peer marketplaces and forums or chats for the residents, and whatever else is deemed to be needed. The collaboration with ThreeFold essentially turns Paradise Hills into a sovereign “smart” community, where even the footage from the security cameras on premise can be stored locally and privately.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-community-comes-together&quot;&gt;The community comes together&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flash forward to a few weeks ago, the early Paradise Hills community gathers together for a gala. ThreeFold co-founder and tech guru Weynand Kuijpers has the chance to speak in front of the group. He speaks about the early days of the Internet, how it was hijacked by Big Tech turning people into products, and how now there is a new model for the Internet by people, for people. “You are some of the first to do this,” he says to the crowd.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;blog&#x2F;paradise_hills_partners.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Partners of Paradise Hills&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afterwards, residents come up and express their excitement, even if they don’t quite understand all the details. One woman in particular asks, “Can you please explain to me how having this device in my home won’t impact my privacy or security?” Adnan goes on to describe how the 3Node is actually there to preserve privacy and security. “A 3Node is just like a solar panel, only instead of electricity, it provides Internet capacity for local usage. In fact, any data that’s in your home is just a fragment of a piece of a puzzle, so it’s inaccessible to you or anyone else for that matter.” Overall, there is a clear feeling that contributing to this new Internet Grid will bring a unifying force to the community, and a deeper sense of meaning for what it means to be a resident of Paradise Hills.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;bringing-paradise-to-the-world&quot;&gt;Bringing Paradise to the world&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paradise Hills is a first of its kind partnership, but it is only the first. We at ThreeFold see incredible opportunities to scale this model across the world, and not only in real estate developments. Imagine if we apply this to lower-income and affordable housing communities, or colleges and universities. Hardware gifted to residents that connect together to form a localized part of a truly sovereign Internet Grid, on top of which useful community tools can be built – all while generating passive token rewards for the residents. A ground-up model. A global concept, applied locally.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the Paradise Hills story inspires you, and you have an idea for how to bring this model elsewhere, we invite you to take action. Head to the ThreeFold Forum, create a topic under the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;about-the-paradise-hills-model-category&#x2F;2632&quot;&gt;Paradise Hills Model&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; category, and let’s spread this to the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Coverage in CoinCodex</title>
		<published>2022-04-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-04-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/04/post-01/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/04/post-01/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;🗞 &lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold in the News&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; 🗞&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coverage in CoinCodex today! Taking a look at some of the challenges of today’s Internet (centralization, data privacy, unequal access), how ThreeFold presents the solution, and how anybody can get involved.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The sole requirements to run a 3Node are access to electricity and network. As such, virtually anyone can join the Grid and aid in the creation of a truly decentralized Internet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ThreeFold: Host the Cloud At Your House, via CoinCodex&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full article &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;coincodex.com&#x2F;article&#x2F;14083&#x2F;threefold-host-the-cloud-at-your-house&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Interview on the BlockHash Podcast</title>
		<published>2022-03-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-03-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/03/post-15/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/03/post-15/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;🎙 &lt;strong&gt;Podcast Alert&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case you missed it, ThreeFold co-founder Adnan Fatayerji just finished up an interview on the BlockHash Podcast.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;youtu.be&#x2F;wu-vf1H-zQ0&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a great share for audiences outside of the ThreeFold community as the interview covered the full scope of the project. Well done, Adnan!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Interviewed by Authority Magazine</title>
		<published>2022-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/03/post-12/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/03/post-12/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;🗞 &lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold in the News&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; 🗞&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about ThreeFold through the Lens of Co-Founder and Tech visionary Kristof de Spiegeleer. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Today it’s like a war on data as it became more valuable than oil and that’s what needs to go back to the people. Our data should be ours and on an Infrastructure we co-own.” 🌎&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Future Is Now: Kristof De Spiegeleer Of ThreeFold On How Their Technological Innovation Will Shake Up The Tech Scene, via Authority Magazine.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full interview &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;medium.com&#x2F;authority-magazine&#x2F;the-future-is-now-kristoff-de-spiegeleer-of-threefold-on-how-their-technological-innovation-will-7acc0e51c365&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Coverage in CoinCheckup</title>
		<published>2022-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/03/post-13/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/03/post-13/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;🗞 &lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold in the News&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; 🗞&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The Internet is one of the greatest inventions of our time. ThreeFold is making it even better with a decentralized Internet powered by Blockchain and owned by the people.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ThreeFold: Is the Decentralized Web the Future of the Internet?, via CoinCheckup.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full article &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;coincheckup.com&#x2F;blog&#x2F;threefold-is-the-decentralized-web-the-future-of-the-internet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Peer-to-Peer Overcomes Web3 Challenges</title>
		<published>2022-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/03/post-4/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/03/post-4/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;First coined in 2014, Web3 is now one of the hottest and overused buzzwords in the digital space – the idea of a new iteration of the web, a decentralized environment based on blockchain technology that incorporates token-based economics. The promise of Web3 – decentralization of control and authority from big tech, data security, scalability, and privacy for users – is tremendous. But what is a promise without delivery? Is it possible that we will see major adoption soon?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar to the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;thenewstack.io&#x2F;as-blockchain-hype-fades-developers-give-ethereum-a-serious-look&#x2F;&quot;&gt;enterprise blockchain hype&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that happened a few years ago, Web3 seems to be repeating the same story, with lots of chatter but lagging adoption. Millions have rushed to trade crypto and NFTs attached to Web3 – with a lot of this activity based on speculation and hype – but that doesn’t mean they will replace legacy platforms anytime soon. New approaches such as DeFi (decentralized finance) don’t have the same problem of the legacy firms, but they face the challenge of scaling and mass adoption. However, many so-called ‘Web3’ solutions are not as decentralized as they seem, and still have to show they are scalable, secure and accessible enough for the mass market. This all may change, but there are clear limitations that will need to be overcome.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether Web3 is a marketing slogan or a true technological trend, there is a lot of money and technology behind it. Financial institutions are embracing blockchain technology and we are seeing a rising adoption of digital assets across industries. While the idea of utilizing digital currencies to exchange different forms of value in an increasingly digital world certainly makes sense, it’s a bigger leap to say that blockchain alone can support a broad set of use cases, including replacing the current Internet infrastructure.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet’s client-server infrastructure replicates data and workloads across many computers, and uses tons of computing resources and energy while limiting the scalability of our applications. However, the clear inefficiencies and gaps in security in today’s centralized infrastructures are being challenged by simpler means of building, storing and exchanging data.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blockchain is a clear evolution to the centralized client-server model, but there are  severe challenges sourced from the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;medium.com&#x2F;certik&#x2F;the-blockchain-trilemma-decentralized-scalable-and-secure-e9d8c41a87b3&quot;&gt;blockchain trilemma&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; between decentralization, scalability and security. Peer-to-peer systems transcend those challenges as they don’t require any valid2ation or verification from a third party, and enable end-to-end connections that can scale limitlessly without the potential of being altered or corrupted by intermediaries. In peer-to-peer systems, all participants are equally privileged, presenting a fairer model. Peer-to-peer represents an incredibly simple and efficient paradigm for organizing our digital world, and has already proven to be the most efficient alternative to centralized information systems.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put, there is no reason to replicate full sets of data and workloads across many computers, and use tons of computing resources and energy while limiting the scalability of our applications. While there is an increasing reliance on blockchain principles to organize our Internet systems, blockchain also makes things redundant, slow, complex and energy intensive. To be clear, blockchain isn’t the problem, as it is a great technology to store and exchange value in a decentralized way, but it is only one piece of the puzzle.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By inter-connecting the computing processing power and storage capacity of billions of computers worldwide in a peer-to-peer way, data transfers could happen end-to-end between people and machines without the need to be verified. Peer-to-peer is also the only way to achieve a truly self-sovereign Internet – creating a ‘trustful’ environment that allows users and developers to have real data ownership.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peer-to-peer systems aren’t meant to replace blockchains – they represent a way to decentralize models that blockchain cannot, such as Internet infrastructures. Peer-to-peer systems and blockchains, side by side. The best of both worlds. Peer-to-peer as the most efficient and decentralized alternative for us to exchange data and Internet resources. And blockchain for establishing trust through an irrefutable record of transactions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the rise of emerging technologies, a new technological foundation is needed to protect our sovereignty and freedom. The rise of blockchains, while well intended, ultimately has made the technological space more complex than ever before, and still benefits a plutocratic few (relative to its promise). More than just technology, peer-to-peer opens a world of new possibilities for humanity to co-initiate new paradigms and experiences.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By applying blockchain and peer-to-peer technology to the cloud, ThreeFold solves the security and autonomy issues of the Internet and realizes the initial promise of the Internet as an open-source, peer-to-peer, planetary mesh network of nodes owned by the people.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Support the realization of a peer-to-peer Internet owned by the people today:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tokens&#x2F;threefold__how_to_buy&quot;&gt;Get TFT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, the currency of the peer-to-peer Internet.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;farming&#x2F;threefold__farming_intro&quot;&gt;Connect a computer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to the peer-to-peer Internet and earn monthly rewards.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;&#x2F;manual__manual3_home_new&quot;&gt;Build applications&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on the peer-to-peer Internet.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Tree-Planting is Underway for a Planet-Positive Internet</title>
		<published>2022-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/03/post-03/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/03/post-03/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;🌳 &lt;strong&gt;Tree-Planting is underway to enable a planet-positive Internet&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three big Take Action Global and ThreeFold sponsored tree-planting initiatives have gotten started in Malawi 🇲🇼, Cambodia 🇰🇭, and Sierra Leone 🇸🇱 – and soon in the Philippines 🇵🇭 – with &lt;strong&gt;more than 5,000 trees planted so far&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;newsroom&#x2F;students_trees.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Students&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These actions will help to enable ThreeFold as &lt;strong&gt;the first planet-positive peer-to-peer Internet&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; infrastructure on earth. Sending so much love to the children and teachers involved in this project. 💚&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For project details and to get involved, visit https:&#x2F;&#x2F;earthproject.org&#x2F;treeplanting&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More updates to come.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In case you missed it, check out &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-on-track-to-be-planet-positive&#x2F;2097&quot;&gt;our previously-shared plans&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to enable a regenerative Internet for all! You can find plenty of details in our three-part series.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Can a &#x27;Democratized&#x27; Internet exist in times of a Cyber War?</title>
		<published>2022-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/03/post-3/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/03/post-3/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On February 24 2022, Russia launched a large-scale military invasion and attack on Ukraine. In the days since the invasion began, the war has been fought not only on the ground and in the air, but also in the digital realm.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyber warfare is nothing new, especially in Russia and Eastern Europe. “In the relatively short and rapidly evolving history of cyber conflict, perhaps nothing has been established with greater certainty and more widely accepted than the idea that Russia has significant cyber capabilities and isn’t afraid to use them,” &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;time.com&#x2F;6153902&#x2F;russia-major-cyber-attacks-invasion-ukraine&#x2F;&quot;&gt;writes Josephine Wolff&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, associate professor of cybersecurity policy at Tufts University. “Especially on Ukraine.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leading up to the invasion, Ukraine experienced a series of cyberattacks on its critical infrastructures, including banks and government agencies. On February 23 2022, just a day before the launch of Russia’s military attack, websites of the Ukrainian parliament and multiple government agencies were put out of work. Similar cyber attacks had also been seen in early February and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.economist.com&#x2F;europe&#x2F;2022&#x2F;02&#x2F;23&#x2F;will-war-in-ukraine-lead-to-a-wider-cyber-conflict?utm_campaign=a.io&amp;amp;utm_medium=audio.podcast.np&amp;amp;utm_source=babbage&amp;amp;utm_content=discovery.content.anonymous.tr_shownotes_na-na_article&amp;amp;utm_term=sa.listeners&quot;&gt;were attributed to GRU&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, Russia’s military-intelligence agency. And Ukrainian cities continue to suffer from &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.economist.com&#x2F;graphic-detail&#x2F;2022&#x2F;02&#x2F;26&#x2F;ukrainian-cities-are-suffering-internet-blackouts?utm_campaign=a.io&amp;amp;utm_medium=audio.podcast.np&amp;amp;utm_source=babbage&amp;amp;utm_content=discovery.content.anonymous.tr_shownotes_na-na_article&amp;amp;utm_term=sa.listeners&quot;&gt;internet blackouts&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. On Sunday, Ukraine’s vice president even called for tech specialists and hackers to join the “cyber front.” While the predictions of a Russian “cyber onslaught” have not necessarily come true yet, both sides have engaged in cyber attacks on visible and invisible levels.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-rise-in-state-sponsored-cyber-attacks-globally&quot;&gt;A Rise in State-Sponsored Cyber Attacks Globally&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digital or cyber warfare does not just apply to Russia and Ukraine. Broadly, cybersecurity experts have been raising concerns in recent years amid a sharp rise in ransomware and other types of digital attacks globally.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adam Meyers, Senior Vice President of Intelligence at the cybersecurity firm CrowdStrike &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.marketplace.org&#x2F;2022&#x2F;02&#x2F;24&#x2F;cybersecurity-to-take-center-stage-as-conflict-continues-in-ukraine&#x2F;&quot;&gt;said&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;: “Just in the last year, I think we’ve seen over 2,700 big-game hunting attacks [cyberattacks that target high-value data]. So they’re far and away that most prevalent actor. Nation-state actors are continuously operating as well, but they tend to operate a little bit more under the radar. They don’t conduct as many widespread and widely known attacks. They try to, obviously, steal information without it being identified that they’ve stolen it.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, these are just the most current examples – Russia is hardly the only country engaging in cyber warfare at a larger scale. In fact, it is becoming increasingly difficult for governments, corporations and organizations to protect themselves against cyber attacks, especially against &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.economist.com&#x2F;business&#x2F;2022&#x2F;02&#x2F;19&#x2F;companies-have-a-lot-to-fear-from-russias-digital-warmongering?utm_campaign=a.io&amp;amp;utm_medium=audio.podcast.np&amp;amp;utm_source=babbage&amp;amp;utm_content=discovery.content.anonymous.tr_shownotes_na-na_article&amp;amp;utm_term=sa.listeners&quot;&gt;state-sponsored attacks&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. And in the digital space, the best and most dangerous hacks are those that go unnoticed until it’s too late.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;some-governments-are-sectioning-off-the-internet-through-digital-borders&quot;&gt;Some Governments are Sectioning Off the Internet Through Digital Borders&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A set of countries like Russia, China, Saudi Arabia, and Iran have certain &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.codastory.com&#x2F;authoritarian-tech&#x2F;global-rise-internet-sovereignty&#x2F;&quot;&gt;aspirations for the internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Domestically, these countries want control and think governments should get to decide what information flows across their borders. Globally, they want governments, not companies and NGOs, to be in charge of the internet. While some may say that government-owned internet infrastructures would be the only way to protect a country’s sovereignty, it goes without saying that what once was a neutral space for humanity to connect and exchange information is turning into a political schema.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taken together, these goals are an attempt to align cyberspace with national borders, so they are sometimes dubbed the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.codastory.com&#x2F;authoritarian-tech&#x2F;global-rise-internet-sovereignty&#x2F;&quot;&gt;“cyber sovereignty” doctrine&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The term comes from China, whose internet censorship system, called the Great Firewall, is the vanguard of the global cyber-sovereignty push. China’s cyberspace agency released a much-ridiculed musical ode to cybersecurity under Lu Wei’s leadership, which included the line: “A cyberpower: Where the Internet is, so is the glorious dream.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vision of effective cyber-sovereignty is expanding to new horizons. A November &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.codastory.com&#x2F;authoritarian-tech&#x2F;global-rise-internet-sovereignty&#x2F;&quot;&gt;report&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; from Freedom House examined 65 countries and found since the previous year that internet freedom declined in 26 of them. Chinese-style “digital authoritarianism,” meanwhile, is growing in influence as China exports both its surveillance known-how and technology.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem here is that digital sovereignty is a major concept that not only addresses the issues of communication and connection but also the impact on societies and culture at large. With cyber sovereignty turning into a non-territorial challenge to sovereignty itself irrespective of the virtual realm of the internet, is there a way out for humanity?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-free-and-sovereign-cyber-space-is-needed&quot;&gt;A Free and Sovereign Cyber Space is Needed&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is evident that the current internet is facing some big challenges that have major implications for humanity. Data privacy and self-sovereignty is almost impossible today, raising serious questions towards those that control the Internet. But it also seems that these companies fell into the trap of their own business models and algorithms.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When taking a step back, the world seems just a few years away from the Matrix, as depicted by the Wachowskis.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet is playing an incredibly important role for the most powerful intelligence companies. As depicted by Meyers, we wouldn’t even notice that our information is being stolen all the time to benefit the greed of powerful geo-political actors. The internet is not a public good anymore, and unless humanity reacts fast, it may be that the world will lose all forms of freedom or sovereignty.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.eff.org&#x2F;cyberspace-independence&quot;&gt;“A declaration of the Independence of Cyberspace”&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; by John Perry Barlow once attempted to shed light on the applicability of government and institutions on the rapidly growing internet, already in 1996 trying to protect its neutrality. According to research, the world is experiencing innovation at an increasingly rapid pace. With the rise of blockchains and web3 technology, could the dream of John Perry Barlow turn into reality?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-what-is-the-solution&quot;&gt;So, What is the Solution?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a world aching for more decentralization and less dependence on governments and corporations, new decentralized and peer-to-peer models are already proving to be more resilient and secure. New Internet infrastructure companies such as ThreeFold have successfully built peer-to-peer internet infrastructures that are more resilient than the current centralized model. On such systems, people and enterprises can store their data and run their applications on a distributed network of computers in such a way that their data cannot be corrupted. ThreeFold even created a so-called “quantum safe” storage that guarantees that even the most powerful computers in the world wouldn’t be able to reconstruct user data.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The escalation of this cyber conflict can lead to unforeseen consequences and casualties. That is why it is especially important that our industry works together to protect customers, partner, employees and citizens. ThreeFold is on a mission to realize the promise of a fully-comprehensive, open-source and peer-to-peer internet infrastructure. ThreeFold is a platform for the creators of tomorrow to build that blueprint of responsibility and ensure that the outcome of future systems is neutrality.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;Br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join ThreeFold in building the new internet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>What is ThreeFold Farming?</title>
		<published>2022-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/03/post-2/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/03/post-2/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold farming refers to the act of connecting a 3Node to the ThreeFold Grid – providing Internet capacity to a globally distributed peer-to-peer Internet infrastructure. Farming is a decentralized and energy-efficient way for people to expand a new Internet infrastructure instead of corporations building hyper-scale data centers. It’s also a way to extend the Internet to underserved regions of our planet, which cannot afford data centers. Every ThreeFold Farmer around the world contributes to the growth of the foundation for a self-sovereign, private and secure digital world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;blog&#x2F;3node_example.png&quot; alt=&quot;3Node&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone can start farming by hosting a computer at their home or office and taking part in the decentralization of our global Internet and Cloud economy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-become-a-threefold-farmer&quot;&gt;Why become a ThreeFold Farmer?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today’s Internet model is highly centralized, owned and operated by the few. It has turned people into products, is too harmful for our planet, cannot scale to meet emerging demands and connect the billions who are being left behind. These alone are powerful reasons to participate in ThreeFold farming and participate in the growth of a new peer-to-peer Internet economy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further, the Internet is the second largest and fastest growing industry in the world after the financial markets. With the Internet expected to triple in size by 2025 to meet the data requirements of emerging technologies such as blockchain, Web3 and IoT, we need more capacity and especially in underserved regions of the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;basics-of-threefold-farming&quot;&gt;Basics of ThreeFold Farming&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold is a peer-to-peer network of computers (known as “3Nodes”), including servers, desktops and laptops, that creates an open-source, decentralized Internet. People who connect computers to the ThreeFold Grid (known as “farmers”) are rewarded with ThreeFold Tokens (TFT) on a monthly basis for meeting the required uptime necessary for users to access their workloads.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process of connecting decentralized Internet capacity and thereby creating new ThreeFold Tokens is described as farming because it resembles the process of farming in agriculture. With agricultural farming, farmers cultivate the land and earn revenue from their harvests. With ThreeFold, farmers connect decentralized Internet capacity and earn ThreeFold Tokens every month for achieving a certain uptime.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above model represents the building block for a distributed, edge infrastructure that can scale to anywhere electricity and network exists, to meet emerging data demands while also providing the self-sovereignty, privacy and security features to achieve true net-neutrality.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-fair-economic-model&quot;&gt;A Fair Economic Model&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold was created to realize the promise of an open-source, peer-to-peer Internet. As such, ThreeFold farming rewards all farmers equally according to the amount of Internet capacity they provide to the network.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold Tokens are rewarded for the amount of Internet capacity added and kept connected to the network. &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;farming&#x2F;threefold__farming_reward&quot;&gt;Farming rewards&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; are calculated according to the compute, storage and network capacity made available by the computers:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;30 TFT per Compute Unit (2 vCPU and 4 GB memory) per month&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;12.5 TFT per Storage Unit (1 TB of SSD and HDD) per month&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.38 TFT per Network Unit (1 GB of data transfer)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.06 TFT per public IP address per hour &lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above prices are based on the price of 1 TFT equalling $0.08. The farming rewards are pegged to the U.S Dollar and the price is locked from the time a farmer gets started to incentivize early contributors to the network. When the price of TFT rises, the farming rewards will decrease.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farming rewards are designed to be “reviewed” by &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;decentralization&#x2F;dao&#x2F;threefold__tfdao&quot;&gt;the ThreeFold DAO&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (a decentralized autonomous organization owned by the ThreeFold community) according to the growth of the ThreeFold Grid and the utilization of its decentralized cloud to ensure a fair distribution of the token economy while also ensuring that farmers will always be justly rewarded for their contribution.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;an-innovative-and-sustainable-solution&quot;&gt;An innovative and sustainable solution&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin mining and other blockchains became famous for requiring enormous amounts of computers and power to solve complex mathematical equations to win the chance of earning the famous cryptocurrency. Since then, many other projects have been born and carried on the mining concept.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold’s model is inclusive and planet-friendly. The decentralized operating system built and used by ThreeFold is extremely lightweight, allowing the peer-to-peer Internet infrastructure to be up-to 10x more energy efficient than the data center model and up-to 100x more energy efficient than Bitcoin mining.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The infrastructure was built in such a way that it removes the need for human intervention or maintenance to eliminate all unnecessary backdoors that open the possibility for ransomware and cyberattacks. Once booted, the decentralized operating system runs forever as the whole infrastructure was designed to be self-driving and self-healing. This 100% autonomous model allows for a completely decentralized system while also enhancing the security and privacy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While blockchain remains an incredible store of value, it is neither an efficient nor a scalable solution to store data and run applications. Only a peer–to-peer model can scale the Internet infinitely and efficiently.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;considerations-before-getting-started&quot;&gt;Considerations before getting started&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following are important factors to consider for ThreeFold farming profitability: &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;computer-hardware&quot;&gt;Computer Hardware&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farmers are encouraged to use the latest computers, including servers, desktops, and laptops that come with an AMD and Intel processor. The computer should have at least 1 Terabyte of SSD to optimize the performance of their farming activity. It is recommended to buy a ThreeFold 3Node server from certified partners around the globe that comes pre-configured and ready to run on the Grid. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Used or refurbished computers can be used but it is important to understand that older computers are less efficient and more power-hungry. Computers not older than 4 years are recommended. Please visit &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;c&#x2F;farming&#x2F;diy-farming&#x2F;43&quot;&gt;the DIY section of our forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for support and feedback on farming setups.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;power-costs&quot;&gt;Power Costs&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Electrical power is the  main operating expense. Electricity is charged per kilowatt-hour (kWh). The cost of farming can float from $0.10 to $0.35 per kWh. It is important for a farmer to verify the expected power usage of a computer before starting the operation to improve profitability.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note that the price of kWh varies depending on the country. Find a country power cost average comparison &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.electricrate.com&#x2F;data-center&#x2F;electricity-prices-by-country&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;threefold-token-price&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Token Price&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An incentive to farm ThreeFold Tokens is because of its future potential. What Bitcoin did to money, ThreeFold is doing to the Internet. While Bitcoin and Etheruem have already reached high market caps, ThreeFold is just getting started.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farmers are rewarded a given amount of TFT monthly based on the amount of Internet capacity they provide to the network.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the price of TFT is $0.1, the profitability of the farm will be average. If the price of TFT is $0.3  your farming operation may operate with healthy rewards. If the price of TFT is $1 your farming operation will be highly rewarding.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farming rewards are also locked until 30% utilization for a period of 2 years to incentivize early participants. The earlier you start your farming operation, the greater the rewards along with the growth in the value of TFT.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The right mix of the above elements make farming an attractive venture. If the variables are favorable, farmers can scale up operations and earn more rewards.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone can start farming by hosting a computer at their home or office and take part in the decentralization of our global Internet and Cloud economy. Considering ThreeFold’s market cap alongside the growing demand for a decentralized Internet, there’s no better time than now to get started farming!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;shop.threefold.tech&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Buy&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;farming&#x2F;threefold__diy_guide&quot;&gt;build&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; a 3Node and become a ThreeFold Farmer!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Realizing a Planet-Positive Internet</title>
		<published>2022-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/02/post-03/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/02/post-03/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;🧳 &lt;strong&gt;Grid V2 to Grid V3 Migration Update&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Together with Take Action Global 🤝 we are taking real action to make the ThreeFold Grid the first planet-positive 🌍 Internet infrastructure in the world.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a look at our three-part series to explore these efforts:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-on-track-to-be-planet-positive&#x2F;2097&#x2F;3&quot;&gt;Pt I: ThreeFold on track to be planet-positive&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;supporting-initiatives-to-regenerate-the-planet&#x2F;2110&quot;&gt;Pt II: Supporting initiatives to regenerate the planet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;driving-regeneration-with-tag&#x2F;2120&quot;&gt;Pt III: Driving regeneration with Take Action Global&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can support a planet-positive Internet by becoming a farmer! All you have to do is connect capacity to the grid and you’re effortlessly contributing to the regeneration of our planet, as this model will allow all farms to become planet positive by default.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;shop.threefold.tech&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Buy a Certified 3Node&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;farming&#x2F;threefold__diy_guide&quot;&gt;Build a DIY 3Node&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>A Special Visit for the Team in Dubai</title>
		<published>2022-01-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-01-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/01/post-14/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/01/post-14/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last week we received a visit from Tina Taylor, Dr Michael A. Stubblefield and Tunica-Biloxi Chairman Marshall Pierite in Dubai to study the deployment plan of a regenerative and inclusive Internet infrastructure for HBCUs and Native American communities. We’re thrilled about this potential collaboration, and hope to share more on this exciting opportunity very soon! 🌎 🚀&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold and Take Action Global in the News</title>
		<published>2021-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/12/post-17/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/12/post-17/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;🗞 &lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold in the News&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; 🗞&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The collaboration with ThreeFold is a perfect fit with our shared goal to bring access to the world and inspire change by providing opportunities for students to take action on social good causes through education and technology. We want to raise the bar of education by having experts teach the students and by initiating teacher training with help of their advanced technology,” Koen Timmers, Executive Director of Take Action Global.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ThreeFold and Take Action Global Partner to Bring Internet Access to 1 Billion People Across the Globe, via MarTech Series&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full article &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;martechseries.com&#x2F;technology&#x2F;threefold-and-take-action-global-partner-to-bring-internet-access-to-1-billion-people-across-the-globe&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Learn more about &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.takeactionglobal.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Take Action Global&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Partner TAG Celebrates Climate Action Day</title>
		<published>2021-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/11/post-4/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/11/post-4/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We have some &lt;strong&gt;big plans cooking&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; with our friends and partners at Take Action Global (TAG) – more on that later this month!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, &lt;strong&gt;we invite you to celebrate &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.climate-action.info&#x2F;day&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Climate Action Day&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, hosted by TAG – the culminating celebration of the Climate Action Project, a six-week initiative involving 2.7 million people across 145 countries. 🌍&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around 18:40 CET, &lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold co-founder Adnan Fateyerji will deliver a message&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; to the students and teachers who participated in the program, and TAG Executive Director &lt;strong&gt;Koen Timmers will be sharing about ThreeFold &amp;amp; TAG&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; with their global audience. 🙏&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Climate Action Day will stream live at the blue zone of COP26 and for global audiences online.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;During the event, students and teachers will present questions to speakers such as Prince William, youth activist Elizabeth Wathuti, and representatives from WWF and NASA, and will showcase potential solutions for climate change.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;More information: https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.climate-action.info&#x2F;day&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Event starts at 1pm CET &#x2F; 8am EST.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>A Journey Into ThreeFold</title>
		<published>2021-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/09/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/09/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you’re part of the ThreeFold Movement, we’re sure you’ve seen Scott in a demo, or in the chats or forums. Scott is new-ish to the team but he’s been active in the community for quite a while. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In this video, Sam, based in Turkey, and Scott, based in the Pacific Northwest (USA), have a conversation about Scott’s journey into ThreeFold. They speak about how he found out about the project and started contributing (and how you can do the same), the technology, the mission, vision, and values, the people, and what Scott is most looking forward to in the short, medium, and long-term.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;embed&#x2F;eXpXtHRSji0&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;&#x2F;iframe&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Eager to contribute? Find us on our forums, chats, or on GitHub!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Main Chat&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldfarmers&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Farmers Chat&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldtesting&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Testing Chat&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;threefoldfoundation&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Foundation GitHub&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;threefoldtech&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Tech GitHub&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>This ThreeFold Farm Keeps Veggies Warm</title>
		<published>2021-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/07/post-5/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/07/post-5/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Somewhere in the Netherlands, a ThreeFold Farm is supporting the growth of vegetable crops such as tomatoes, peppers and cucumbers. By directing the excess heat generated from the hardware operations to the greenhouse next door, they are able to achieve an incredible model that benefits both hardware and vegetables. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Jeroen Burks, CEO of Blockheating, tells us everything we need to know about their sustainable farming operations. As far as he can remember, Jeroen has always been a protagonist of the “no waste” approach. He started by recycling material previously used by the tech industry, mainly in the cloud market. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
“By default, most data center operations replace their power supplies every 3 years, no matter the state they are in. They are being replaced to counter any possible downtime.” 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
By refurbishing and repurposing “old” power units from data centers, he gives them a second life as electric tractor chargers, lithium ION pack chargers, and more. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
“You just need to trick the unit into thinking it is still powering servers, add some cables here and there, and it is ready for duty.” 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
His quest towards sustainability started when he was challenged on a pilot project. His friend had bought a new building and was looking for the most sustainable approach to heating it. Jeroen came up with the idea of putting two server racks in the basement and using the heat from that operation, to heat the offices and spaces above. While this project was a success, Jeroen realised that it could be way more efficient, if done with other structures. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
He quickly engaged with a second pilot project where he used two server racks to heat a small greenhouse. This model turned out to be a great combination, which benefited both hardware, as well as farming operations. And so sprouted ‘Blockheating’ – a data center that provides heat for tomatoes, peppers and cucumbers. Why specifically these vegetables? Well, the Netherlands has a fair amount of greenhouses cultivating them, and these ‘veggies’ need that heat during summer nights. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Right now Blockheating has around 400 compute nodes with direct cooling that stores all the heat in a buffer throughout the day, which is then released into the greenhouses during the night hours.
“By doing it the way we do, we grow the internet grid, help grow vegetables and curb fossil fuel usage – in carbon negative compute power!” 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Right now, Blockheating has a portion of their data center dedicated to ThreeFold Farming for a few reasons:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The alignment of values is huge&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ThreeFold Farming is easy to manage&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ThreeFold Farming counters wasteful behavior of internet resources, so it’s a triple win&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Blockheating envisions to scale up-to three data centers of this kind, in an interconnected way, with a fiber ring between them. By doing so, they will be able to increase their offering and have a larger impact on countering the wasteful patterns of the cloud industry. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold is proud to have Blockheating as a ‘State-of-the-Art’ Farmer and Partner, and hopes to see many more people and companies inspired by Blockheating around the world, to expand the ‘People’s Internet’ in a regenerative way. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find out more about Blockheating here: &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;blockheating.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;blockheating.com&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find out more about our partners here: &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;partners&quot;&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;partners&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Into the Fold – The ThreeFold Movement</title>
		<published>2021-07-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-07-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/07/post-4/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/07/post-4/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s not by mistake that you’re here, reading this post. You, like I, understand that today’s systems need to change. You know that decentralization is needed for better wealth distribution and equal opportunities. And that we need better solutions for our planet. You can feel that a global shift is happening. And you want to do something about it. You want to be a part of it.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
You’ve dreamt of a different world. A world where people trust and treat each other with respect – and where everyone has equal chances to learn and to thrive. A world where we’re not just cogs in a machine that serves only the few, rather we work and co-create as part of systems that benefit all. A world where solutions are sustainable for our planet, or even better, regenerative. This world is not just a dream, though – and you’re not alone. Each day, more and more like-minded people are coming together. Welcome into the fold.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;meet-the-movement&quot;&gt;Meet the Movement&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To understand ThreeFold, you should first understand where we came from. Since the late 90’s, some of the ThreeFold co-founders have worked on Internet storage and cloud technology. And after years of building, and many successful launches, they came to understand that they were part of a broken system that was productizing people and damaging the planet. Despite this, they knew that the Internet held and holds the key to a better world, and that the only way to have a truly sovereign, secure, and energy-efficient Internet was to start from scratch. So we did.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
This is how our story began – and over the past four years we have grown and expanded a team of like-minded and passionate people from around the world to bring ThreeFold to life. But for us, we are still in the beginning of something much bigger to come.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We don’t consider ourselves a company, rather a group of humans helping other humans – and our planet. We believe the world needs to change, and we choose to not just talk, but act, to make that change happen. We cannot and would not want to do this alone. There is a strong, passionate, and growing community around us – partners, farmers, ambassadors, technology testers, other contributors, and supporters just like you.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;our-mission-vision-and-values-drive-us-forward&quot;&gt;Our Mission, Vision, and Values Drive us Forward&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our mission is to build and expand a data-sovereign and planet-positive Internet owned by the people, for the people. This will enable equal chances for people around the world to learn, partake and succeed, and will help to heal our planet.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Engrained into the work that we do are three key values or principles:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We believe in &lt;strong&gt;sovereignty&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, and in protecting people. Everyone should own their data, and no one else, not even ThreeFold. Our peer-to-peer technology allows every user to be data sovereign – giving them 100% control over their data.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We believe that everyone should be given &lt;strong&gt;equal chances&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; to learn, partake and succeed. Internet access is a human right, and at ThreeFold we commit to scale our technology to new regions to empower the unconnected.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
And we unify our practices, partnerships, and products around a single mission – to &lt;strong&gt;heal our planet&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. By making our technology actionable, we enable a collective approach to have an impact together.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;together-we-invite-the-world-into-the-fold&quot;&gt;Together, We Invite the World Into the Fold&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s important for others to understand who we are. Thus, we identify with and embody three key attributes as a collective, to show the world what the movement is all about:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold is purposeful.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; We exist to help humanity thrive. Our mission is bold and motivates every step we take. We adapt to our evolving environment and passionately strive for excellence.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold is empowering.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; We help people find themselves and do what they love. We provide support to people and projects that help build a better world, whether they have moonshot visions or down-to-earth ambitions. We aren’t the hero of our story – they are.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold is approachable.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; ThreeFold keeps it real. We’re open and honest, avoiding upstage corporate language and phony marketing spins. We don’t see ourselves as a company, but more like humans helping other humans. So being genuine, friendly, and loving comes naturally.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In its essence, the movement is open and inviting. We’ve created &lt;strong&gt;a participatory Internet economy&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, where anybody around the world can plug in a 3Node and add capacity to the ThreeFold Grid. Together, we’re expanding a data sovereign and planet positive Internet infrastructure, owned by the people, across geographical and cultural borders.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We believe in &lt;strong&gt;collaboration, not competition&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. Our technology serves as a responsible underlying layer on top of which anybody can build and create. We have &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;partners&quot;&gt;beautiful partners&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; already on board – and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;aci&quot;&gt;an alliance&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of conscious people and organizations who share our vision – and we are constantly expanding our ecosystem across industries.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
And while the ThreeFold Foundation is currently the driving force behind the ThreeFold Movement, we believe in &lt;strong&gt;decentralization&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. We have open channels like &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&quot;&gt;a forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;a two-way Telegram chat&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, Github (&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;threefoldfoundation&quot;&gt;Foundation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;threefoldtech&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Tech&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;), and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;threefold_io&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, where people can and do contribute, ask questions and provide feedback that goes into our everyday decision-making and actions.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
As I said at the start, you’ve dreamt of a different world. And so have I. John Lennon once said, “A dream you dream alone is only a dream. A dream you dream together is reality.” Thank you for dreaming with us. Together, this will happen!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Photo by Ahmad Odeh on Unsplash.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>The ThreeFold Grid is by the People, For the People</title>
		<published>2021-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/07/post-2/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/07/post-2/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What do you think of when you hear the word Internet? For many, it’s the websites and applications we consume online as end users. But the Internet is much more than this. And ultimately, every action we take online goes through a complex set of automated processes and protocols to store, run, and transmit data (e.g. photos, videos, messages, other files) across the global Internet infrastructure.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Today, this infrastructure consists of massive, power-hungry data centers, and is largely privatized and owned by tech giants such as Facebook, Google and Amazon – who also happen to own the biggest online “free” platforms. But there’s a catch. By owning both the infrastructure and the digital experiences we consume for free, we were actually turned into products of their business models. Our data is being collected and isn’t owned by us anymore. While data has become the most valuable commodity on earth, don’t you think it’s wrong that we don’t own the value of our data today? 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Today, every individual is worth between US $1,000 and $20,000 online, per year. The Internet and Cloud Industry is worth trillions, yet all this value is centralized to a handful of companies. This has to change.”&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold’s open source technology powers the peer-to-peer Internet revolution that holds the premise to disrupt the global Internet in many ways.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;an-internet-by-the-people&quot;&gt;An Internet By the People&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ThreeFold Grid is formed by people from all around the world that connect Internet capacity to a peer-to-peer Infrastructure owned by humanity. Together, we expand a data-sovereign and planet-positive Internet infrastructure that puts people back in control of their data, and their digital lives. ThreeFold’s infrastructure can store all of humanity’s data – from personal data to public datasets and security archives – and can run all emerging technologies such as blockchain, IoT, and Big Data – with more efficiency and security.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold flips the current data center model upside-down, and allows people around the globe to connect Internet capacity in the form of hardware, and earn income for it. This decentralized approach means that anyone can take part in the world’s largest and fastest growing economy – the Internet and Cloud. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
You can see now how this new Internet is by the people, but how about the latter? What does the ThreeFold Grid enable?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;an-internet-for-the-people&quot;&gt;An Internet For the People&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now anyone, anywhere can connect to the ThreeFold Grid and use capacity with some key advantages:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-world-where-we-own-the-value-of-our-data&quot;&gt;A World Where we Own the Value of Our Data&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, all of the data we create online sits inside of centralized data centers and we do not own it. ThreeFold turns terms &amp;amp; conditions on their head and gives us, the people, full control of our data rather than third parties. We can keep our data private, decide with whom to share it, and even decide on where it’s stored and located. And considering that our personal data is worth between US $1,000 and $20,000 per year, ThreeFold offers a direct way for us to own our digital life and the value attached to it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;we-exchange-value-without-intermediaries&quot;&gt;We Exchange Value Without Intermediaries&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The “People’s Internet” is peer-to-peer. This means connections between senders and recipients are completely end-to-end, eliminating the need for any form of intermediaries from the model. Can you imagine what the world would look like without intermediaries? Let’s take an example like Airbnb.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Today, if you are looking for a place to stay on vacation, you will probably end up using the services of Airbnb. But did you know that Airbnb charges both consumers and property owners for using their service? In a peer-to-peer world, this wouldn’t be necessary. You’d simply access a database of property owners (possibly through a peer-to-peer marketplace) and be able to complete the transaction yourselves. No hidden fees, just a direct exchange of value!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;applications-run-on-the-edge&quot;&gt;Applications Run on the Edge&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In its essence, edge computing brings compute and storage closer to people (and the devices where it’s being gathered) rather than relying on a centralized data centers located on the other side of the planet. This is the essence of the ThreeFold Grid. So, data doesn’t suffer any latency issues (performance) and it’s far more efficient &#x2F; money-saving. Further, the distributed nature of the Grid allows for true privacy and security. Edge computing is not just a growing trend but, because of the growing number of connected devices and global Internet usage, it’s becoming a real necessity.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;but-what-about-the-planet&quot;&gt;But what about the planet?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been following us, you must already know that the Internet is responsible for 10% or more of the world’s energy consumption. And with decades of experience in the Internet and Cloud industry, ThreeFold co-founders knew how to turn this around. We developed a lightweight operating system and infrastructure, removing unnecessary layers of complexity from the traditional and Web3 models (actually, blockchains are making it even more complex). The ThreeFold technology is always geared towards maximum efficiency while maintaing performance. And with these advancements, we can already save up-to 90% energy on storage workloads.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Additionally, the distributed nature of the Grid uses less bandwidth (see above re: edge computing). It’s been reported that Netflix alone takes up 15% of the Internet’s bandwidth. What if Netflix were to leverage the ThreeFold Grid? If stored closer to watchers, we could reduce network usage considerably.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Our commitment to the planet goes beyond the technology. Through a partnership with Take Action Global (TAG), we aim to take three times more CO2 out of the air compared to what we put in. Imagine regenerating the earth while using the Internet?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
At ThreeFold, we believe that it’s time for us to take back control. As the world turns more and more digital due to the pandemic and even just the natural progression of technology, it’s time that we not just realize the problems of today’s Internet, but that we do something about it.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
This will happen! So join in, and spread the word! &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Response - The Internet is Destroying Our Brains, but We Can&#x27;t Quit</title>
		<published>2021-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/07/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/07/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The other day, I came across &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;africa.businessinsider.com&#x2F;strategy&#x2F;the-internet-is-destroying-our-brains-but-we-cant-quit-its-a-factory-were-forced-to&#x2F;z4drxf5&quot;&gt;a poignant article&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; written by &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;_pem_pem&quot;&gt;P.E. Moskowitz&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; entitled “The internet is destroying our brains, but we can’t quit. It’s a factory we’re forced to work in without any pay.” As someone who started out in social media advertising (read: trying to capture peoples’ attention to get them to buy or do something often by using their data against them), worked in influencer marketing in its early days, and has now gone 180º to help to build a decentralized Internet by people and for people (where people are digitally sovereign), it really resonated with me.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
It’s commonly-discussed (see: The Social Dilemma) and quite obvious if you use or have used the Internet and specifically social media, that we are addicted to being online. In fact, we’re actually even chemically triggered by social media and other online experiences. Said Jeff Orlowski, director of The Social Dilemma, “Social media powerhouses like Facebook, Twitter and Instagram are “designed” to exploit users’ brain chemistry in order to keep them glued to their phones… They were designed to get us to come back. It’s to figure out how to reverse-engineer what we’re most vulnerable to, most susceptible to, to come back. And what we are seeing is a dopamine response in the brain.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In their article, Moskowitz points out how the Internet is not just like a toxic relationship or junk food, where you can leave or stop yourself from eating, rather it’s “an all-encompassing technology, our main economic engine, the tool we are forced to use to meet others and mediate our entire lives.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The truth is that the Internet &lt;em&gt;has&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; become more than an addiction, it’s become a necessity to keep up in today’s increasingly-digital world. Yet the Internet is not even accessible to about 40% of the global population – and for those who &lt;em&gt;do&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; have access, it does not serve us. It’s actually the other way around. We are the product.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
“We produce the memes, tweets, posts, and pictures that keep us tethered to the internet, and then that content is monetized in the form of advertisements - revenue users help produce, but do not usually see a penny of,” says Moskowitz. We have become cogs in a machine that uses us for its own benefit. Or as they call it, “a factory we’re forced to work in without any pay.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
“Our entire society has been reformulated around the internet, much like it was centered around the factory during the Industrial Revolution. If there’s an Amazon Web Services outage, much of our society stops functioning. Without the internet, we couldn’t find jobs, or, at this point, even friends.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-what-do-we-do&quot;&gt;So, what do we do?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moskowitz is correct in their thinking when they say the following, “A solution to our current internet-use crisis cannot come at an individual level anymore than one person quitting their job would solve capitalism’s poor working conditions. If we want any hope of making the internet less stressful, less back-breaking, and more fulfilling, content creators, gig economy workers, and even casual internet users need to push for a systemic solution.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Simply pending less time on the Internet or using certain apps instead of others is not going to make much of a difference in the end. There are billions of people on the Internet today to make up for the loss. And the underlying system is still massively flawed and can be manipulated. Bold, widespread, systemic change is indeed what we need. A revolution, perhaps.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As pointed out recently &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;tgdaily.com&#x2F;web&#x2F;6-dfinity-threefold-are-leading-an-internet-decentralization-revolution&#x2F;&quot;&gt;in TGDaily&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, ThreeFold is that revolution.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold is the engine for a &lt;em&gt;new&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; Internet, driven by a movement of people who care about a better future. With more than two decades of direct knowledge of the Internet and Cloud industries, we flipped today’s Internet on its head. We rebuilt the architecture from the ground up, with people and our planet at the center of our focus. Instead of relying on centralized hyper-scale data centers owned by a few private corporations, we provide the opportunity for people across the world with access to a network connection and electricity to plug in hardware and provide local capacity, and earn income while they are at it.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In our model, we prioritize simplicity, security, efficiency, and privacy. The technology runs autonomously, removing human error and malicious intent from the equation. Connections are peer-to-peer, meaning no middlemen get in the way of our content, our transactions, or other data. And importantly, people own their data. What we produce is ours. We decide where it gets stored and we decide who can access it (and for what value). In fact, it’s basically impossible from a technical standpoint for anybody to access someone’s data without their consent – including us.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
On top of the technology, we provide experiences. People will have one single log-in and verifiable identity, and gain access to the tools (experiences) they need for communication and for work. As we are a decentralized movement, soon, anybody will be able to build anything they like on top of ThreeFold – but it is our vision and belief that the Internet should not be addictive. Rather a tool for all of humanity to connect, learn, and prosper – with people at the center, not treated as products.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
To the author’s concern, content creators and gig economy workers would clearly benefit from such a digital world as well. Of course services like Airbnb or Uber or Etsy or even YouTube provide value as they are crowded marketplaces both for providers and customers. That said, they profit from people, typically on both sides of the transaction. In a peer-to-peer world, we can create fair and equal marketplaces where the content or product is owned completely by the person listing it there and the value goes 100% directly from person to person. This means no hidden fees, no uncertainty over ownership, no censorship or control from a third party. Of course it’s not all predetermined at this moment, but what I can say is that our biggest concerns in what we create are and will always be fairness and equality (and sustainability &#x2F; regeneration). So, together, we will bring all of this tolife in the best interest of people.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;join-the-movement&quot;&gt;Join the Movement&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In their article, Moskowitz concluded that “perhaps it is only a matter of time before enough of us say ‘enough,’ and protest the internet’s totalizing grasp on our labor and our lives.” But where does protest lead without a viable solution? Maybe this is the type of systemic change Moskowitz could imagine and could stand behind. It’s not a band-aid approach, rather a total re-imagination and re-execution of today’s flawed and manipulative Internet. It’s an Internet by people, for people. Instead of working in the factory, we become the factory co-owners – and the Internet works for us.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
If you believe in what we are building, we invite you to join the movement:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;farming&quot;&gt;Become a farmer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldnews&quot;&gt;Stay updated on ThreeFold News&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;Join the conversation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldtesting&quot;&gt;Test the technology&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;threefold_io&quot;&gt;Follow us on Twitter&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;threefold__how_to_buy_and_sell&quot;&gt;Buy the ThreeFold Token&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are a growing group of people from around the world who not only believe what many of you believe, but we are doing something about it. Let’s grow the People’s Internet, together.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>How ThreeFold Will Give Internet to 43% of the World’s Population</title>
		<published>2021-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/06/post-3/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/06/post-3/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The United Nations publicly ruled Internet access to be a human right in 2016. Proper access to the Internet helps to protect people’s freedom of speech and thought, as well as other fundamentals such as access to knowledge and information.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Nonetheless, as of 2019, about 43% of humanity remains unconnected to the Internet, creating huge inequalities in access to information and knowledge. It is essential to take the necessary steps to strengthen the relationship between governments and people while still upholding all human rights.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold created an infrastructure that is easily affordable and jointly operated by network peers to make the modern Internet open and fair to everyone. Anybody with a network connection and electricity can add capacity to the ThreeFold Grid. We’re looking for farmers around the globe and we’re also partnering with farming cooperatives to develop localized strategies and meet the specific needs of their region. Plus, the Foundation will incentivize and sponsor the extension and scope to areas that require Internet capacity the most, to ensure a fair and equitable delivery of the Internet to all.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Want to join the biggest internet revolution? &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;farming.threefold.io&quot;&gt;Be part&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of it, today.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>It&#x27;s Time We Stand Up For Our Data</title>
		<published>2021-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/06/post-2/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/06/post-2/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Do a quick search for “data leak” on your search engine of choice, and you’ll likely see headlines like this:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personal Details of Over 3.3M Volkswagen Customers Exposed in Data Leak&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Billions of emails and passwords appear in largest data leak ever&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Here’s How the IRS Could Have Prevented the Tax Data Leak&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time to Change Your Password: Tips on Protecting Yourself from Online Scams
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Week after week, month after month, year after year, companies are being hacked, private consumer data is being compromised and released, and we somehow begin to think that this is the reality of our world, something we just have to deal with.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Internet security, cyber attacks, and data leaks are a global threat – and increasingly so as the world moves more digital, and smart people with malicious intent try to take advantage. But this is not normal, nor should it be. As consumers, we should be able to trust that our data is truly safe and secure. And today, we cannot. It’s time we stand up for what is ours.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
That’s where ThreeFold comes in.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Many of today’s issues around cyber security and data privacy come from the lack of innovation in the IT industry over the last decades and the reliance on centralized hyper-scale data centers. ThreeFold has disrupted this model in a few ways:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
First, we started from the ground up. Some ThreeFold co-founders have been working in the cloud &amp;amp; storage space for over two decades, having built components of the cloud and Internet still used today. They knew that the only way to have a truly secure and data sovereign Internet was to rebuild the architecture and the technology components from scratch. So they did. A few years down the line, we’ve created a new operating system, a smart contract for IT, and a peer-to-peer network that can be scaled to anywhere by anyone.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Second, we removed people from the equation. IT has become so overly-complex that people are required in order to maintain it. Because of this, “backdoors” are needed to allow these gateholders to enter the systems and make necessary fixes. But this can lead to human error, and also allows people with malicious intent to make their way in as well. With Autonomous IT powering the ThreeFold Grid, the technology runs and heals itself, and drastically reduces the opportunity for humans to interfere.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
And lastly, your data is owned by you. Rather than relying on centralized data centers, the ThreeFold Grid is an Internet grid made up by independent ThreeFold “Farmers” from around the world who plug in capacity from their home or office. While they own the hardware, they do not own the data inside. User data is stored across multiple devices, and proprietary data storage algorithms ensure that the data cannot be retrieved by anyone besides the user – not the farmer, and not even us.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
As Einstein said, “We can’t solve our problems with the same level of thinking that created them.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a lot more information in &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;&quot;&gt;our wikis&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; about the technology, but what we want to emphasize here with you is that we don’t have to accept data leaks and hacking. There is an answer to the cybersecurity issues the world is facing. And that answer is ThreeFold.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Has Plans to Go More Green</title>
		<published>2021-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-13/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-13/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;“Traditional industry solutions focus on increasing the use of renewable energies to power data centers. But this is not a viable solution. As per ThreeFold they need to drastically reduce the global internet’s energy consumption, and we must act now.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the coverage from UnlockBC &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.unlock-bc.com&#x2F;news&#x2F;2021-06-13&#x2F;uae-based-decentralized-p2p-internet-platform-goes-green-to-reduce-internet-energy-consumption&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>How ThreeFold offers Data Sovereignty</title>
		<published>2021-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/05/post-3/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/05/post-3/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you’ve seen &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=uaaC57tcci0&quot;&gt;The Social Dilemma&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, you know all too well that today, people are being turned into products. Everything we do online – all of the data we upload and all of our digital activities – is tracked and oftentimes used against us. Targeted advertising is just the beginning.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Personal data is used by algorithms to make incredible important decisions, like whether someone should receive financial or health support or benefits. In China, people are now even receiving “scores” for their behaviors. It sounds like Black Mirror, but it’s real life.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
That’s the scary part. The good news is that things don’t have to be this way. ThreeFold is building the engine for an Internet where people can finally be data sovereign.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
With &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;threefold__why_intro?id=everyone-should-be-autonomous&quot;&gt;today’s Internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, infrastructure is centralized. Companies provide services in exchange for your personal data, which is stored on servers in hyper-scale data centers owned by private companies.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In ThreeFold’s model, those servers are called &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;threefold__3node&quot;&gt;3Nodes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and rather than sitting inside centralized data centers, they sit inside the homes or offices (or small data centers) owned by independent people and organizations called &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;threefold__farming_intro?id=what-is-3node&quot;&gt;Farmers&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. But the data inside is owned by the person or persons who put it there. They maintain access right as well. From a technical standpoint, data is dispersed across 3Nodes by &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold&#x2F;#&#x2F;threefold__part5_ultra_efficient_storage?id=the-space-algorithm-of-storage&quot;&gt;an algorithm&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that makes it such that nobody can access it. In addition, connections are peer-to-peer, meaning data goes directly between sender and recipient rather than passing through intermediaries as it does today – bringing further levels of security.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Thus, people can finally be data sovereign, knowing their data is safe, and truly theirs.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold’s Planet Positive Plan</title>
		<published>2021-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/05/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/05/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There’s no question that climate change is one of the biggest, if not the biggest threats facing humanity today. If we care at all about future generations and the health of our planet, we have no choice but to address these threats, and fast. That’s why one of our biggest aims is to lower the energy usage of our digital lives. But ThreeFold is taking not just a sustainable approach, we’re setting the plan for a planet positive Internet.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Recently, we released information on how our infrastructure saves up-to-90% on energy consumption compared to existing models. We achieve this mainly thanks to an extremely efficient storage system and the concept of a Digital Twin.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
From &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;threefold__energy_savings_storage&quot;&gt;a storage standpoint&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, we reduce energy by avoiding copies, implementing a multi-layer system, not using fast disks, through read&#x2F;write caching, and more. With &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;threefold__energy_savings_digital_twin&quot;&gt;Digital Twin&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, we have taken a very different approach to how we exist in today’s digital world. Rather than existing 100 times in a huge system of client-server architecture, now we exist only once. We believe that we can run 25 Digital Twins with &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;threefold__bulb_comparison_twin&quot;&gt;the same energy&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as used by one light bulb.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Saving energy is one thing, but there will still be remaining energy. This needs to be offset by carbon credits. Now, in order to regenerate our planet, we &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;threefold__carbon_negative&quot;&gt;work together with Take Action Global&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to let students farm carbon credits. This has the potential to offset energy usage 100% by the end of 2021, and we have, as an aim to take 2x more carbon out of the air than we put in.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Our planet needs better solutions across industries. No more talking. Now is the time to act.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Building a Better Solution for Our Planet</title>
		<published>2021-04-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-04-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/04/post-23/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/04/post-23/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today’s Internet consumes approximately 10% of the world’s energy. This is not acceptable.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
So, how to fix this? Start from scratch. Attack the root problems. Build a new infrastructure. Go peer-to-peer. Reduce complexity. Improve efficiency. Work with like-minded partners. &lt;em&gt;No one is taking this approach, apart from ThreeFold.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Learn more about how &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;for_our_planet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ThreeFold is building a better solution&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; for our 🌎.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
And read about &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;why&quot;&gt;our why&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Big update to share in the coming weeks about how ThreeFold is pushing even further in this direction!
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;We commend all projects and individuals out there working to provide more sustainable solutions and systems for the planet.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; 🙏&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>We&#x27;re Tackling Internet Inequalities</title>
		<published>2021-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/03/post-14/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/03/post-14/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Let’s build an Internet for all, together.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Did you know?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold incentivizes the expansion of the ThreeFold Grid in developing regions. 🌏🌍
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We are partnering with Solidaridad to create fair supply chain and fair data for farmers around the world, particularly in the Global South. ✅
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
And we are partnering with Take Action Global to build an educational tool based on Digital Twin technology that will allow children around the world to learn and collaborate in a secure environment. ✏️📖&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>We Need a More Inclusive Internet</title>
		<published>2021-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/01/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/01/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Today, more than 40% of the world is without access to the internet, a tool which brings incredible access to knowledge (education) and important information, communication tools that keep loved ones connected and are crucial for emergencies, and economic opportunities. And over the last year, as the world is spending more time at home, digital economies are booming and education is going remote. With an uncertain future, we need to fix the digital divide or we risk leaving billions of people even further behind.
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-data-center-problem-cost-proximity&quot;&gt;The Data Center Problem: Cost &amp;amp; Proximity&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The centralized data centers that power today’s Internet are located “strategically” mainly in North America, Europe, and select parts of Asia. For populations living in these regions, Internet is accessible and generally relatively affordable. But the further you travel from these data centers, the less available and more expensive the internet becomes. Internet access is mostly an issue Sub-saharan Africa, throughout Asia, and some parts of South America.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Of course some data centers can be and are being built in and near developing and remote regions, but for reasons including cost and audience, this hasn’t been a huge priority to date. Beyond that, the data center model as a whole simply cannot scale to meet the future demands of the internet nor is it sustainable for our planet, so this is not the right option.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-internet-shutdown-problem-control-manipulation&quot;&gt;The Internet Shutdown Problem: Control &amp;amp; Manipulation&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lack of internet access isn’t always just an availability or affordability problem. Today’s internet can be limited or even shut down at any point, by the right people. Take a quick look at &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;netblocks.org&#x2F;reports&quot;&gt;NetBlocks.org&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, an organization that reports on global internet disruptions or outages. Typically governments are enacting these measures during times of unrest or protest or  important political moments. Even in the United States, the Executive Branch of the government has &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.klemchuk.com&#x2F;ip-law-trends&#x2F;government-power-to-shut-down-the-internet&quot;&gt;the power to shut down the internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in a case of a national emergency.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Cutting the internet or restricting certain services based on region (a common practice as well) is not only not right, it’s dangerous. People rely on the internet for information and communication and no government or entity should have the ability to shut the internet down at their discretion.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-threefold-solution-fair-neutral-internet-for-all&quot;&gt;The ThreeFold Solution: Fair &amp;amp; Neutral Internet for All&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2016, the United Nations declared internet access to be a human right, yet today if you are reading this post, you are privileged. All humans deserve access to the internet and ThreeFold has the solution.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
With the ThreeFold model, nodes can be set up anywhere in the world where an existing internet connection and electricity are present. By putting physical infrastructure at the edge (close to users), greater levels of access can be reached.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Further, the ThreeFold Grid cannot be shut down or manipulated. It is a neutral internet owned by the people, where autonomous technology heals and runs itself and requires minimal human intervention.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Today we are working with partners in the clean energy and network &#x2F; connectivity to build the solutions that are needed to provide fair and uninterrupted internet access with all corners of the world.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Of course we will need new safe, secure, and private solutions for people to collaborate online. Many of these are already live and deployable via ThreeFold Now Community Solutions. We are working with partners in the education space as well to build toolsets for students to enrich their lives.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We need a more inclusive internet, and that is what we are building.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>What Is Peer-to-Peer and Why Is It so Important?</title>
		<published>2020-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2020/12/post-2/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2020/12/post-2/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-peer-to-peer&quot;&gt;What is Peer-to-Peer?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peer-to-peer (P2P) is a term that originated from the distributed computer application architecture where tasks and workloads are shared between peers, popularized by &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Napster&quot;&gt;Napster&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, a revolutionary file storing system from the late 1990s.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The concept inspired new structures and philosophies in many areas of human interaction. P2P systems and groups are typically critical of authoritarian and centralized social structures and believe in equality, meritocracy, flat systems, participatory &amp;amp; circular economies, as the concept represents a concrete pathway to these outcomes or visions.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
P2P systems are network, not linear or ‘pyramidal’ hierarchies (though they may share some elements). They are ‘distributed’, though they may have elements of ‘centralization’ and ‘decentralization.’ And intelligence is not located at any center, but everywhere within the system.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-does-threefold-relate-to-peer-to-peer&quot;&gt;How does ThreeFold relate to peer-to-peer?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold’s Peer-to-Peer (P2P) computing network is a distributed architecture that splits tasks and workloads between its peers, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;what_is_farming&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Farmers&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Farmers are equal participants in the network and together they form a peer-to-peer network of nodes, the ThreeFold Grid.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Farmers make their resources, such as processing power, disk storage or network bandwidth, directly available to other network participants, without the need for central coordination by servers or stable hosts. Farmers are both suppliers and consumers of resources, in contrast to the traditional &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Client-server&quot;&gt;client-server&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; model in which the consumption and supply of resources is divided.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In the near future, ThreeFold will create Digital Twin, which will go beyond the era of peers doing similar things while sharing resources. It will actually enable much more than that. Digital Twin will create a complete new digital world with diverse peers that can bring in unique resources and capabilities to a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Virtual_community&quot;&gt;virtual community&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on the ThreeFold Grid. This will empower the network of peers to engage in greater tasks beyond those that can be accomplished by individual peers, and are beneficial to all the peers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-did-threefold-choose-peer-to-peer&quot;&gt;Why did ThreeFold choose peer-to-peer? &lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything starts (or should start) from the why, and the ThreeFold story started a long time ago. Before the inception of ThreeFold, many of the co-founders of the project used to work with the largest IT &amp;amp; Cloud actors. Throughout their experience working in the Industry, they realized that the complexity of the technology and the centralization of knowledge &amp;amp; power led to an inefficient, unsustainable, not scalable and unequally distributed infrastructure. So they decided to redesign the whole Internet and cloud infrastructure bottom-up with the vision of shaping a global internet economy that can scale anywhere efficiently, cost efficiently and sustainably. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-does-the-world-needs-peer-to-peer&quot;&gt;Why does the world needs peer-to-peer? &lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By developing the technology, the conviction that peer-to-peer was the best solution for humanity and the planet strengthened itself. Why? Well, put simply, a peer-to-peer system removes all forms of intermediaries, unnecessary steps and complexity from the picture. Therefore, it simplifies the architecture in an incredible way. The benefits are many but here are the most popular benefits:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Privacy&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;: Our peer-to-peer environment means no middlemen or intermediaries, meaning data travels directly between peers and stored on the nodes of their choice rather than being sent through and stored by a third party.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Security&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;: Data stored in data centers is susceptible to security breaches. In bypassing data centers and exchanging data directly between peers, we can achieve much greater security as it reduces code and back doors significantly. &lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Scalability&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;: In a many-to-many system, scale is essentially unlimited. There is simply no bottleneck. And hardware (nodes) can be added at ease compared to current data center model.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cost-efficiency &amp;amp; Sustainability&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;: End-to-end (direct) connection between peers means a more efficient path for data and less energy is needed. Less energy means less cost, and less harm to our planet.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;in-2021-the-world-is-going-peer-to-peer&quot;&gt;In 2021 the world is going peer-to-peer! &lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re now in 4 years into the project, and it is clear that ThreeFold holds the most advanced technology and is probably the only tech company in the world that can achieve a peer-to-peer network &amp;amp; digital world as envisioned by the concept authors. The ThreeFold Grid is running and already at it’s 2.4 version and 2021 will bring various commercial opportunities for the public to partake in the peer-to-peer network, from hosting IT workloads to experiencing P2P end-user solutions. In other words, in 2021, the world will be able to go peer-to-peer.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>A Better Solution for Our Planet</title>
		<published>2020-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2020/12/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2020/12/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Today, the global Internet and IT infrastructure requires enormous amounts of energy, responsible for about 10% of annual global energy consumption. This makes the IT industry amongst the most pollutive industries in the world (along with the often-discussed airline industry, for comparison).
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We believe IT can be sustainable. Actually, it should be! That&#x27;s why energy efficiency has always been a key focus of ours. With climate change and sustainability as some of the most pressing issues of our times, new green solutions need to be our priority. It has been key to ThreeFold since the very beginning of its story to enable a technological infrastructure that can reduce the Internet’s carbon footprint drastically. 
&lt;h2 id=&quot;simplicity-is-the-key-to-unlock-a-better-future&quot;&gt;Simplicity is the key to unlock a better future&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over time, integration suites, middleware solutions, and enterprise service busses have been invented and implemented to cover integration challenges within the current internet. This has further complicated IT architectures, resulting in a loss of actual end user workload performance.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold reworked the whole approach to IT architectures and eliminated the layers of complexity. The result is a cloud stack that presents minimal overhead and that requires less hardware – reducing heat generation and eventually cooling requirements. By reducing the need for power, the net result is an energy-efficient Internet grid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;improving-resilience-and-efficiency-through-self-healing-it&quot;&gt;Improving resilience and efficiency through Self-Healing IT&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping systems up and running is a major requirement in modern day IT. Leading vendors earn most of their margin by selling maintenance contracts, performance guarantees, and professional services. Their business models bring no incentive to make things simple and efficient for consumers.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Creating a self-healing environment requires only minimal manual intervention to replace broken hardware components. Broken hardware components are inevitable, and the Zero-OS distributed node architecture deals with such failures by turning off broken components and provisioning unused capacity. By removing the need to ship broken parts back and forth, and linking to the corresponding installation knowledge (engineers), a lower carbon footprint can be achieved.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;no-painkiller-approach-we-tackle-the-root-issue&quot;&gt;“No painkiller” approach. We tackle the root issue&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a specific piece of software or hardware is not delivering the required performance or reliability, we should analyze the core design&#x2F;algorithm and its usage of soft&#x2F;hard components to determine the root causes of persistent issues to be solved.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Currently, most storage vendors follow the path of least resistance when trying to improve on performance. Their solution for meeting performance targets is to use faster components (CPU, memory, network card, proprietary acceleration) rather than looking at the core algorithms that drive the utilization of those components. Swapping components for faster ones perpetuates a cycle of cutting corners and focuses reliance on innovation from hardware component providers rather than solving the more fundamental and underlying issues. That’s a “painkiller” approach.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Zero-OS was designed to solve root problem issues by design. While still using high-performance hardware components on the ThreeFold Grid, the algorithm of Zero-OS maximizes utilization possibilities. This enables greater performance and sustainability. Some key examples how this is achieved:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eliminating-unnecessary-elements-from-standard-architectures&quot;&gt;Eliminating unnecessary elements from standard architectures&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Virtualization adds a layer of software between the actual end-user workload and physical hardware. It also allows for multiple workloads to run on the same hardware by using excess capacity. There is definitely merit in building a virtualization solution. Building an effective virtualization solution that does not require abundant context switching is key and this is why Zero-OS has been developed. Zero-OS uses a minimal Linux kernel that allows for a number of user spaces to co-exist. In these user spaces, containerized versions of software can be run, eliminating the need for hypervisors, virtual OS to fuel the virtual machines, and guest operating systems. This also minimizes the required overhead for the host OS.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;minimizing-network-connections-usage&quot;&gt;Minimizing network connections usage&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supercomputing delivered many new technologies. But, not all of them are usable solutions for everyday workloads. One technology invented to make supercomputers performant is the use of Remote Direct Memory Access (RDMA). RDMA allowed physical CPU boards (containing both CPUs and memory) to access other CPU boards in memory stored data over a dedicated channel. This eliminated the need to transport data between CPU nodes over network connections (or other mainstream means to exchange data). The result was a considerable reduction in overhead created when allowing distributed end user workloads to operate over multiple physical cores. The leading server and storage solutions brands have never considered nor implemented such mechanisms. This resulted in an increased need for faster networks - increasing complexity, costs, efforts and resources needed to operate solutions.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
RDMA is only used in certified farms and requires involvement of TFTech.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;minimizing-disk-usage&quot;&gt;Minimizing disk usage&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The storage solution uses slow and big (the bigger the better) HDD disks which drive in rack density. As they spin slower they consume less power and need less cooling. But then, how can you deal with read&#x2F;write intensive workloads? The storage algorithm uses a SSD cache to acknowledge Inputs&#x2F;Outputs coming from the applications, fills the erasure coded data blocks in large (up to 64MB) storage containers and writes the big chunks of data on the big and slow HHDs. If you are familiar with HDD disks, you know they like to be streamed on instead of having a lot of small bits written in a scratchy way.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Continuous innovation in all of these areas are leading to an efficient technology stack.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold&#x27;s Long Story Short</title>
		<published>2020-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2020/05/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2020/05/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-threefold-is-building-a-new-internet-why&quot;&gt;So, ThreeFold is building a new internet. Why?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We strongly believe that a new internet is needed for our planet and for humanity. “If not now, when? If not us, who?”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
What it boils down to is that currently the internet is only available to about 1&#x2F;2 of the world (meaning billions are being left behind), it is centralized (a handful of large corporations own and profit off of our data), and it uses up to 10% of the world’s energy consumption. So, we’re building a new (peer-to-peer) internet that empowers equality (access), autonomy (data ownership, for example), and sustainability (reduces energy consumption). These values drive us forward.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-does-it-work&quot;&gt;How does it work?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything on the internet – websites, apps, photos, videos, etc – uses up capacity and is stored in huge data centers owned by big companies, mainly in North America, Europe, and some in Asia. In our solution, centralized data centers are replaced with a grid of “nodes” distributed around the world.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
These nodes are owned by &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold&#x2F;#&#x2F;what_is_farming&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Farmers&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; – but only the physical hardware – the data inside of the nodes belongs to the people or organizations who put it there. So, “farmers” plug in hardware and start to create capacity that can be used by people.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Farmers come in all shapes and sizes. Some farmers run small data centers while others simply run a node out of their living room.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
When Farmers connect active hardware (add capacity) to the ThreeFold Grid, ThreeFold Tokens are created. Farmers can then sell those tokens to people who want to use capacity (e.g. a developer that wants to build or host a website, or a person who wants to store some photos). More on tokens down below.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;seems-quite-lofty-how-will-you-build-it&quot;&gt;Seems quite lofty. How will you build it?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s true that rebuilding the internet is not so simple. But a lot of infrastructure has already been built and the technology is quite advanced. Over the past 2+ years (as of May 2020), independent ThreeFold Farmers have already plugged in more than 40,000,000 GigaBytes worth of storage and 15,000 CPU Cores across 21+ countries. That might not mean a lot to non-technical folks but it is quite a significant amount.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;21-countries-what-happened-to-equality&quot;&gt;21+ countries? What happened to equality?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far along as we are, we still have work to do. One of our biggest goals in the near future is to expand the grid to Africa, South America, and parts of Asia where currently the Internet is too expensive or not available. Currently, we farming is incentivized around these key geographies.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;and-what-do-you-mean-by-peer-to-peer&quot;&gt;And what do you mean by peer-to-peer?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peer-to-peer means no middlemen – direct exchange of information and&#x2F;or value between equal participants. Peer-to-peer means decentralization – breaking away from pyramid-based systems, greed-based systems – and putting &lt;strong&gt;people&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; back in the center of their own (digital) lives.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-how-can-i-access-use-your-internet-today-what-can-i-do-on-it&quot;&gt;So how can I access &#x2F; use your internet today? What can I do on it?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By June, some of the first experiences will be live. This includes file storage and communication tools and a virtual browser, all with the advantages of being more sustainable for our planet and with full control of your own data. And over time, more and more experiences will come to this internet. We’ll be updating here and on our communication platforms as they come. But don’t worry, as a user it doesn’t change much – no coding required. :)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;will-enter-website-or-app-here-be-available-on-your-internet&quot;&gt;Will [enter website or app here] be available on your internet?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some tremendous reasons for a website or app to use our internet, but that will really be up to the website or the app. In the end, we are providing a responsible solution for responsible people and organizations. We would love to host anybody who believes in what we are doing!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-are-you-making-sure-it-s-safe&quot;&gt;How are you making sure it’s safe?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hacking has become a part of life and is almost impossible to avoid in the current systems – they are too complex and require too many people to operate. This results in less security which results in lots of security breaches. We took a look at the existing Internet (seven layers) and simplified it down to three layers. By simplifying the architecture and instead creating technology that is self-driving &amp;amp; self-healing, we removed the human requirement and therefore vastly minimized the possibility for hacking or human error. Then we also developed a storage algorithm which makes it such that if some of the information gets lost or stolen (somehow) or if some hardware goes down, it is all retrievable. Long story short, we flipped the existing system on its head.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-about-the-data-ownership-part&quot;&gt;What about the data ownership part?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That has a bit to do with the security as well. Since you own your data, you decide who gets access. Which means your data isn’t just out “there” for the taking. Basically, we put you at the center of your digital life, where the applications and experiences you use serve you, not the other way around.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;and-how-is-it-better-for-the-planet&quot;&gt;And how is it better for the planet?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few reasons for us being more sustainable. Data centers are super unsustainable, so the simple (but incomplete) answer is “no more huge data centers.” But if you want more detail:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We use up to 3x less hardware for the same output, and using hardware at least 2x longer while maintaining good performance&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having capacity everywhere, local to where users are – this reduces network requirements (and can even improve security)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using new algorithms (e.g. the one mentioned above for storage) which have dramatic efficiency improvement&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Re-using hardware where possible – let’s not throw away&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-much-will-it-cost&quot;&gt;How much will it cost?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end we want to provide sustainable access to the internet and all of its solutions for less than a dollar per month per person but for now the cost will depend on what you choose to do. Certain experiences will cost money. Storing photos or videos, for example. But all at a fair price.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;speaking-of-money-so-what-s-up-with-the-threefold-token&quot;&gt;Speaking of money – so what’s up with the ThreeFold Token?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we mentioned above, tokens are generated when ThreeFold Farmers adds capacity to the ThreeFold Grid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essentially, the ThreeFold Token is the medium of exchange on the new internet. So, if a developer wants to build something (e.g. a website or an app) or a user wants to store something (e.g. photos), he&#x2F;she&#x2F;they use(s) ThreeFold Tokens.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;need-more-answers&quot;&gt;Need more answers?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope that helps explains things. Obviously there is &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold&#x2F;#&#x2F;&quot;&gt;a whole wiki&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to dive in to. If you don’t find what you’re looking for, please ask us on our &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&quot;&gt;forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Photo by Nong Vang on &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;unsplash.com&#x2F;photos&#x2F;9pw4TKvT3po&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Why We Do What We Do</title>
		<published>2020-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2020/04/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2020/04/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We are growing a green and responsible peer-to-peer Internet that is available everywhere and owned by everyone — across geographical and cultural borders, empowering people to be digitally independent and providing equal chances to learn, partake and succeed.
&lt;h2 id=&quot;values-first&quot;&gt;Values-First&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At ThreeFold, we are driven by three main values:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Equality is the foundation for a fair world where everyone is given the opportunity to be empowered and to achieve their full potential.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Freedom of thought, opinion, creativity and faith are fundamentals to achieve peace and fulfillment of humankind’s potential.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sustainability ensures the future of life on earth. It is about adopting the behavior and mindset to minimize our footprint.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Let’s take a deeper look.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;internet-access-a-human-right&quot;&gt;Internet Access | A Human Right&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2016, the United Nations officially declared Internet access to be a human right. The right to internet access aims to protect people’s freedom of expression and opinion, as well as other fundamentals such as access to knowledge and information.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Yet as of today, about 48% of humanity remains unconnected to the Internet, creating huge inequalities in the access to information and knowledge. It is important that the right steps are taken to improve the relationship between governments and citizens and to uphold all human rights.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
To make the new internet accessible and equal to all, ThreeFold built with ThreeFold Farmers an infrastructure that is affordable to all and collectively owned by the network peers. To ensure a fair and equal distribution of the internet to everyone, fully sponsored capacity will be deployed in remote regions of our world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;digital-freedom-for-everyone&quot;&gt;Digital Freedom | For Everyone&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet evolved to become the world’s largest database of information and knowledge, opening up exponential growth on personal, organizational and economic levels. Yet it is owned by large international companies that exploits users data.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The current approach of many governments and countries is to cut the Internet into pieces by limiting its accessibility and enforcing regulations. We need an internet that protects our digital freedom and fair access to global information for everyone, everywhere.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold is a peer-to-peer internet — owned by the users. All the technology of this new internet is open-source and the whole experience is built around the fundamentals of a peer-to-peer network. On this new internet, everyone owns their data and experiences — digital freedom.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-green-internet-for-our-planet&quot;&gt;A Green Internet | For Our Planet&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current internet consumes about 10% of global energy production. With the imminent boom of emerging technologies such as Blockchain, Internet of Things, Virtual Reality, Artificial Intelligence and 5G, the Internet’s energy consumption is expected to increase exponentially.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The current industry solutions focuses on increasing the use of renewable energies to power data centers. However this is not a viable solution as data centers consume enormous amounts of energy. Therefore, a new solution that can drastically reduce the global internet’s energy consumption is needed.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold is the first true peer-to-peer Internet. It uses pioneering technologies that remove the need for centralized and power-hungry data centers, consumes 90% less energy, and uses 90% less international fibre network capacity.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
If not now, when? If not us, who?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Photo by Yannis H on &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;unsplash.com&#x2F;photos&#x2F;uaPaEM7MiQQ&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Internet is growing wild</title>
		<published>2019-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2019/12/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2019/12/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;you-are-unique&quot;&gt;You are unique&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a gathering with some friends, I noticed something that made me think about how important it is what we’re doing at ThreeFold.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
One of my friends was complaining about how he couldn’t log in to one of his social media platforms, because all of his passwords are different and he forgot which one he used for this particular platform. Another friend was saying how she tagged her sister on a funny meme, but her sister couldn’t find it on Facebook. Turns out she tagged her on Instagram. And then one of them said something that I keep hearing more and more from people, “Why do we have so many apps, I can’t find anything anymore!”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We exist so many times online, but why? There is only one me in the real world. Why should there not be only one me online? Why should I have 25 different profiles on 25 different platforms, with 25 different logins, when I am unique?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
That is another dilemma that ThreeFold has a solution for, with its autonomous technology. 3Bot - a digital avatar like no other, that basically handles your entire online life. The focus lies on digital privacy, where only you can access your data, and no one else. The 3Bot has all the functionalities you need to interact and exchange information and value, there will be no need for that many applications on your device anymore. With 3Bot, everything changes.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The 3Bot is built on the ThreeFold Grid, and has the same values as ThreeFold. Freedom, Equality, and Sustainability. It is important that your data is safe, and what can be safer than you being the only one who not only has access to it, but also the only one who owns that data? Your online world should not be that different from your offline world. In your offline world, you are the center of your own life. That is what ThreeFold is doing with the 3Bot, putting you in the center of your online life, too.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
One decentralized application, one digital wallet, one login and one you. Because you’re unique.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Have questions? Feel free to ask us on our &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&quot;&gt;forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Photo by Jessica Ruscello on &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;unsplash.com&#x2F;photos&#x2F;DoSDQvzjeH0&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>You Are Unique</title>
		<published>2019-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2019/12/post-2/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2019/12/post-2/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;you-are-unique&quot;&gt;You are unique&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a gathering with some friends, I noticed something that made me think about how important it is what we’re doing at ThreeFold.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
One of my friends was complaining about how he couldn’t log in to one of his social media platforms, because all of his passwords are different and he forgot which one he used for this particular platform. Another friend was saying how she tagged her sister on a funny meme, but her sister couldn’t find it on Facebook. Turns out she tagged her on Instagram. And then one of them said something that I keep hearing more and more from people, “Why do we have so many apps, I can’t find anything anymore!”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We exist so many times online, but why? There is only one me in the real world. Why should there not be only one me online? Why should I have 25 different profiles on 25 different platforms, with 25 different logins, when I am unique?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
That is another dilemma that ThreeFold has a solution for, with its autonomous technology. 3Bot - a digital avatar like no other, that basically handles your entire online life. The focus lies on digital privacy, where only you can access your data, and no one else. The 3Bot has all the functionalities you need to interact and exchange information and value, there will be no need for that many applications on your device anymore. With 3Bot, everything changes.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The 3Bot is built on the ThreeFold Grid, and has the same values as ThreeFold. Freedom, Equality, and Sustainability. It is important that your data is safe, and what can be safer than you being the only one who not only has access to it, but also the only one who owns that data? Your online world should not be that different from your offline world. In your offline world, you are the center of your own life. That is what ThreeFold is doing with the 3Bot, putting you in the center of your online life, too.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
One decentralized application, one digital wallet, one login and one you. Because you’re unique.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Have questions? Feel free to ask us on our &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&quot;&gt;forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Photo by Jessica Ruscello on &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;unsplash.com&#x2F;photos&#x2F;DoSDQvzjeH0&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>An escape from the Great Hack</title>
		<published>2019-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2019/11/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2019/11/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-neutrality-of-the-current-internet-is-in-danger&quot;&gt;The neutrality of the current Internet is in danger.&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you seen ‘The Great Hack’ on Netflix? It’s a documentary about the Cambridge Analytica hacking scandal, where personal data of millions of peoples’ Facebook profiles were harvested without their consent and used for political advertising purposes. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
While watching it, I couldn’t help but think how unfair it is that in today’s digital society, people are being treated like products, because there is no such thing as a ‘free’ platform without YOU being the product. What did reassure me, is that people are sick of having their data used this way. But what they might not know, is that the internet problem is bigger than ‘just’ data protection.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The Internet is growing at an exponential rate. To service this demand, a few large companies (Google, Amazon, Alibaba, Facebook, etc.) have built and continue to build supersized, power-hungry and centralized data centers. These data centers make up the majority of all Internet capacity available today. However, the Internet is expanding much faster than datacenters and the planet can cope with. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In addition to that, the Internet is extremely centralized, with most of these data centers being located in the US. Think of it like electricity. If consumers in, for example, Turkey had to use electricity generated in the US, it would be too expensive and inefficient, because it is too far away. The transmission lines would be too strained and losses and repairs would make it unsustainable. Capacity is like electricity. When centralized, it becomes too expensive and wasteful for remote users.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-what-is-the-solution-to-these-problems&quot;&gt;So what is the solution to these problems?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet needs to be more distributed, cost-effective, neutral, and sustainable. ThreeFold has developed such a new technology, the ThreeFold Grid (Grid) and a token which enables all this to happen.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Combining the values of the ThreeFold Foundation (freedom, equality and fairness) with the technology developed by TFTech (Zero-OS, Zero-Chain, 3Bot) and a digital currency called the ThreeFold Token (a decentralized digital currency and means of payment to exchange autonomous and decentralized Internet services)  we believe that we have all the tools in order to actually make a difference in tomorrow’s digital world. Question is, are you ready to join us? 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Please visit &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&quot;&gt;our forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; if you have any questions or would like to continue the conversation!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Datacenter Myths</title>
		<published>2017-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2017-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2017/10/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2017/10/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;hyperscale-realities-are-very-different-from-what-most-people-think&quot;&gt;Hyperscale realities are very different from what most people think&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;myth-1-bigger-data-centers-are-more-efficient&quot;&gt;Myth 1: Bigger data centers are more efficient&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are advantages in building larger-scale data centers, like economies of scale and sheer bulk buying power, but these are not as significant as what people think. The average cost per rack in a hyper-scale data center is $20-35K USD including all energy requirements and safety systems. The cost of hardware per rack is around the $200-300K USD mark.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
What is often forgotten is that anything that is of enormous scale and highly concentrated comes with complexity and specific problems to deal with. For example. resource requirements such as investment, operational costs, knowledge, and people increase significantly with size.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In reality, keeping things simple, small, and distributed is much more cost-effective than large complex environments.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;myth-2-big-data-centers-can-be-sustainable&quot;&gt;Myth 2: Big data centers can be sustainable&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The carbon footprint of a big data center is enormous. To improve the power usage effectiveness (PUE) of most data center farmers have adopted wind, hydro, and&#x2F;or solar power technologies, which indeed helps drop their PUE by an estimated 20%. But is this leading to more sustainability?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
This 20% looks great on paper and in the farmers’ corporate social responsibility reports. However, it just represents an improvement in the cooling technology and sourcing of energy. It doesn’t actually impact the energy consumed by the equipment that runs in their data centers (servers, storage chassis, physical disks, etc.) which is the equipment responsible for the carbon footprint. PUE only refers to overhead power consumption, i.e. cooling the facility, opening, and closing doors, maintaining power security systems, etc.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Real improvement lies in deploying technologies that actually consume less power to deliver the actual Internet capacity to run workloads, real CPU chassis, physical disks, and storage cabinets. Improving on how hardware is being more effectively used can have an impact of up to a thousand percent and lead to ten times more power-efficiency.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;myth-3-redundant-systems-have-better-uptime&quot;&gt;Myth 3: Redundant systems have better uptime&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of us believe that systems need redundancy mechanisms to improve their operational uptime and reliability. While it may make sense to IT experts, let’s translate this for the non-IT world?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
To make a car more reliable we add redundancy (as we do in IT). So for the risk of having a puncture, we add one extra tire for all the tires we use continuously. This adds 4 extra tires to the car. Then a decision needs to be made: Do we put those tires in a structure where they are always running along with the primary tires or do we choose not to have them “online” all the time, wearing and tearing in the same way as the primary tires?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Building such a system would take a large number of engineers to come up with a solution, and would change cars as we know them. Wouldn’t it make more sense to think outside the box and solve the root of the problem by making tires un-deflatable?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The IT industry has gone overboard with the concept of redundancy, having forgotten to look at the root cause issues. This has spawned a whole new industry of itself, which has a financial interest in creating complicated and expensive redundant systems.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;myth-4-big-companies-optimize-better&quot;&gt;Myth 4: Big companies optimize better&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big companies with a certain track record will know better how to optimize as they have more people and resources.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
At first glance, this sounds logical, but in reality, ninety percent of the innovation within the IT space comes from startups. The giant IT companies have a heritage they hardly can overcome. They are locked in old infrastructure designs, and building outside of that infrastructure would be costly, timely, and probably put the breaks on their businesses.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Real innovation gives way to fix the core symptoms rather than taking the problem pain-killer approach.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Creating solutions that respect humanity and the planet</title>
		<published>2017-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2017-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2017/06/post-2/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2017/06/post-2/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Organizations should always respect human rights, human effort and human experience. To enable a sustainable and prosperous civilization and world, we need a strong value system.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
*Ideas and texts were inspired from https:&#x2F;&#x2F;ind.ie&#x2F;ethical-design&#x2F;. We added our own twist to it.*
&lt;h2 id=&quot;respect-human-rights&quot;&gt;Respect Human Rights&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sustainability&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: It is important for a very simple reason: we cannot maintain our quality of life as human beings, the diversity of life on our planet, or Earth’s ecosystems unless we embrace and protect its balance.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Equality&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Everyone should have a right to learn, dream, partake and succeed. Equal access also means affordability, not ownership by big greedy companies.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decentralization&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: To better distribute power, value and opportunities, we need more decentralization. Technologies and solutions should be available everywhere to improve equality and sustainability. &lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Openness &amp;amp; Interoperability&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Allows technologies to work together in an open way, without limitation, and therefore expands the possibilities for innovation and sharing.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accessibility&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Whatever the location or situation, people should benefit from easy and fast access to information and solutions.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security &amp;amp; Privacy&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Protect people from being put in situations of danger or exploitation. People should be empowered to be independent and they should be the sole owners of their experiences.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;respect-human-effort&quot;&gt;Respect Human Effort&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reliability&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Make sure technologies are reliable and last longer.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simplicity&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: We need to keep things simple: no unnecessary complexity - less is more.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transparency&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Let people and companies work together in a 100% transparent way.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Collaboration&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: It’s all about the greater picture. We are stronger together and have to help each other in reaching our common visions.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;respect-human-experience&quot;&gt;Respect Human Experience&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ergonomy&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Products and solutions should empower productivity, safety and comfort, while reducing human error.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusiveness&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Design should always be global and inclusive. We are all equal.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Products should be visually appealing and should achieve it’s purpose.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transparency&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Organisational records and strategies should be accessible to everyone.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Photo by Renee Fisher on Unsplash.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>The need for ThreeFold&#x27;s neutral internet</title>
		<published>2017-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2017-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2017/06/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2017/06/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Internet is growing like crazy and is now a trillion dollar problem. Together we can build a new neutral Internet.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;an-introduction-to-the-problems&quot;&gt;An introduction to the problems&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Internet is no longer the neutral place it used to be. +80% of the Internet capacity is delivered by a handful of companies. This results in a loss of neutrality and openness and breeds inequalities.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To support the continuous growth of the Internet and connect billions to new Internet Of Things devices, 400 million new servers are needed by 2020. The world therefore needs another 4,000 large-scale data centers that each consume 200 MWe of electricity: &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;bit.ly&#x2F;1UPUZYG&quot;&gt;see source&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Today, about 4 billion people have no access to the Internet due to the high costs of connectivity and capacity. We believe these people have the fundamental right to have low-cost access to digital resources such as online identity solutions, education, health information and more. For this to happen, solutions that can lower the cost by a factor of 10 are required.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bandwidth does not follow Moore’s law. The growth of bandwidth required is much higher than the speed at which new capacity can be delivered. This is even more important in emerging markets.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Current blockchain technology is not scalable and not sustainable. Example: the Bitcoin blockchain alone uses more energy today than Croatia.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;current-internet-and-cloud-capacity&quot;&gt;Current Internet and Cloud capacity&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, the cloud computing industry represents a 100 billion dollar industry - mostly owned by about 20 global cooperations. Experts such as Bell Labs and Cisco believe the capacity requirements in the next decade will dramatically exceed existing infrastructure - requiring many more data centers and billions, if not trillions in investments.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The spectacular growth and advancements in cloud computing that occurred over the last decade resulted in large part from “hyper-scale” efficiencies - i.e. centralizing Internet infrastructure in very large billion dollar data centers.  However, demand for Internet capacity already surpassed the available infrastructure with emerging technologies such as Big Data, the Internet of Things (IoT) and Artificial Intelligence (AI) Technology. The existing hyperscale cloud architecture cannot cope with this growing demand as the requirements for land, power and funding are becoming outrageous.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The challenges facing the Internet includes the following:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trillions of Investment Required&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. In the next decade, the global Internet infrastructure requires another 4,000 data centers (250M - 1B dollar investment each) to meet demand which would cost trillions - this money could be better used in education, healthcare, or sustainable innovations. &lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impossible to scale the networks connecting users to the hyperscale data centers&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. Since hyperscale data centers are built in large “central” locations, the network leading to these data centers is congested. Even more, remote regions that are less connected to the Internet cannot benefit from these data centers’ IT services.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Non-local data and capacity&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. Governments around the world are becoming more and more concerned about data leaving their borders. To tackle this centralization issue, they would need local IT infrastructure. Also, IoT workloads need local capacity to deliver constant real-time computing and storage requirements - for certain applications and workloads (e.g. driverless cars), latency is not an option. Hyperscale data centers can simply not match these requirements.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not secure &#x2F; at risk of choke point failures&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. There are plenty of recent well-publicized problems around security, outages and loss of data. The reason for this is that centralized hyperscale architectures are inherently insecure - and failures at a single hyperscale location can cause widespread contagion and outages.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-threefold-solution&quot;&gt;The ThreeFold Solution&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our solution to these trillion dollar problems is to migrate Internet capacity to the Edge (closer to user location) - i.e. a “hyper-distributed” network architecture, located close to users (in cities, schools, offices, homes and even vehicles).
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Edge networks will not necessarily replace the existing hyperscale capacity powering today’s cloud - rather, they will scale to meet the increased capacity demands going forward. However, if the current hyperscale capacity can be decentralized to improve energy consumption and reduce costs, this would be a huge global success.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
By 2025, 60% of new Internet infrastructure will be decentralized and located at the edge of operator networks by using alternative locations which have stable (renewable) power and reliable connectivity.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;threefold-s-technology-main-benefits&quot;&gt;ThreeFold’s technology main benefits:&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: The ThreeFold Grid is distributed and benefits from our ItsYou.Online identity management platform - making it much more secure.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decentralized&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: The solution enables to bring capacity closer to where users are located, enabling a Cloud at the Edge.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sustainability&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: The technology removes the need to build huge power hungry datacenters and by decentralizing the architecture enables up-to 1000% energy savings.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Making IT a true utility&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;:  We always approached IT as Energy. Today we provide 3x more uptime and between 3-10x more cost effectiveness.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neutrality&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: The solution enables 100% neutral &amp;amp; private Internet IT capacity. Our blockchain technology provides security, neutrality &amp;amp; scale.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-threefold-zero-node&quot;&gt;The ThreeFold Zero-Node&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Zero-Node provides compute, network and storage capacity to the internet and ThreeFold’s blockchain. This capacity can be used for any possible workload. Here are some characteristics of ThreeFold’s Zero node:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Modularity&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Scaling from 8 vCPUs and 3.5 TB of storage (smallest) to clusters with 8000 vCPUs and 2 PB of storage (large), there is a range of possibilities at hand.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sustainability&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Storing the hardware uses about 10x less energy, and about 2-3x for other workloads.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decentralized&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: The Zero Operating System (“Zero OS”) is ideally suited for Edge networking - where automation, self-healing and hyper-distribution are must-haves.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Zero-Nodes are deployed as close as possible to the consumers of Internet IT capacity (IoT, residential, business, government, education, …).&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This results in massive bandwidth savings, we estimate to be able to keep 99% of the required bandwidth locally which has a huge impact on cost.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is the only viable solution to be able to provide internet to the 3.2 billion people waiting.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self healing&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: The architecture is designed to ensure that workloads and data can be accessed at all times. &lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neutral &amp;amp; private&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: A lot of work has done using blockchain (technology which powers crypto currency) to guarantee privacy and net neutrality.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed around simplicity to be used by everyone.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The technology provides anyone with the autonomy to deliver complex IT applications without the need for complex integration services.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Empowers equality&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Our technology should be usable by the “other billions” that remain unconnected. Due to the low cost-points, low energy requirements and reduced need of backbone network capacity.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
