<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>ThreeFold - threefold</title>
	<subtitle>Our global digital backbone</subtitle>
	<link href="https://www3.threefold.io/tags/threefold/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://www3.threefold.io"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2022-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://www3.threefold.io/tags/threefold/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold at Consensus: A Decentralized World is in Our Hands</title>
		<published>2022-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/05/post-5/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/05/post-5/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s that time of the year when believers and builders of a decentralized tomorrow  gather to celebrate the festival for the decentralized world. About 15,000 people will attend Consensus 2022 by CoinDesk from June 9 through June 12. Throughout the festival, key topics around decentralization, blockchain, crypto, Web 3 and the metaverse will be explored and discussed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is ThreeFold attending Consensus? Excellent question. The ThreeFold community truly believes that collaboration, decentralization and peer-to-peer systems are the foundation for a better Internet, and subsequently, a better world. And together we are making that world a reality. But we need to grow and extend the community on the ground with the right people, dreamers who choose to act now.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As many consider Consensus the festival for the decentralized world, some questions linger: &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How committed are the projects and participants to decentralization, and for what reasons? How far are they willing to go to bring that world to life?&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s no secret that many projects in the space still rely on centralized infrastructure – at least to some degree. So, are they really delivering on their promise of decentralization? &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-decentralized-world-needs-a-decentralized-foundation&quot;&gt;A decentralized world needs a decentralized foundation&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think we’ve already come to Consensus that decentralization has to start at the foundational level. See what I did there? The ThreeFold co-founders have more than 20 years of experience in setting world records in Internet storage and cloud automation technologies. With ThreeFold, they started from scratch to build a fully decentralized Internet infrastructure that’s peer-to-peer and open source. We’re realizing the promise of an Internet built and owned by the people, back to the vision of Web 1 through the implementation of Web 4 technology. For us, it’s obvious that we simply cannot build a fair and equal digital world on top of today’s old-world infrastructure which is owned by the few. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With our fair, inclusive and decentralized Internet infrastructure, we’re laying the foundation for a better world. Following our ethos of &lt;em&gt;planet first – people second – profit (value) only as a result&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, we’re striving to regenerate our planet and to empower the collective – the many and not the few. By putting our planet and people first, we create real sustainable value. We believe that, together, we’re strong enough to build new regenerative systems powerful enough to enable anyone to have a sovereign, safer and more fulfilling life.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of today, people from 77 countries are connecting thousands of computers (3Nodes) to the ThreeFold Grid – all contributing to ThreeFold’s open-source peer-to-peer Internet infrastructure. And any node or dApp, actually anything that can run on Linux, can run on top of the ThreeFold Grid in a truly decentralized way. With ThreeFold’s infrastructure and thriving ecosystem, there’s an abundance of potential and opportunities – really anything is possible.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;threefold-consensus&quot;&gt;ThreeFold @Consensus&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ThreeFold team and community will soon gather at the Austin Convention Center, 500 E. Cesar Chavez Street, Austin. Meet the ThreeFold team at &lt;strong&gt;Exhibit Booth 310&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; not far from the Networking Lounge. We’ll be there throughout the entire exhibit to connect with participants, share the ThreeFold story and extend the community – Friday, June 10 through Saturday, June 11 from 9am until 6pm.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At our booth, you’ll be able to meet the team, see and hold a Titan 3Node, have the chance to win a free 3Node of your own, find resources that will empower you to get involved, and more.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold will also host a gathering outside of the Convention Center. We will share more via &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldnews&quot;&gt;our Telegram News Channel&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; when the details are finalized, so stay tuned.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold is more than an Internet. It is the foundation for a truly decentralized world. Are you ready to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;join&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; the global ThreeFold movement?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Check out the full &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;events.coindesk.com&#x2F;consensus2022&#x2F;agenda&quot;&gt;Consensus agenda&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and take advantage of &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;events.coindesk.com&#x2F;consensus2022?promo=a7MsHxui&quot;&gt;our 25% discount code&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to buy tickets.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And don’t forget to let us know if you’ll be joining ThreeFold at Consensus – we’d love to connect with you!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
