<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>ThreeFold - farming</title>
	<subtitle>Our global digital backbone</subtitle>
	<link href="https://www3.threefold.io/news-category/farming/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://www3.threefold.io"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2021-11-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://www3.threefold.io/news-category/farming/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Update on Testnet for TF Grid 3.0</title>
		<published>2021-11-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-11-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/11/post-015/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/11/post-015/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;🚨 &lt;strong&gt;Testnet for TF Grid 3.0 is fully available for testing, both for connecting infrastructure and for deploying workloads!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;vimeo.com&#x2F;645664686&#x2F;ae8a2b6833&quot;&gt;Learn how to get started on Grid 3.0&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;vimeo.com&#x2F;645664908&#x2F;fe7cd9b56f&quot;&gt;Get started deploying workloads using Terraform&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;portal.test.grid.tf&#x2F;&quot;&gt;TF Grid 3.0 Portal&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is now available on Testnet, which makes it even easier and more seamless to perform some of the tasks in the videos above.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is an important concrete step in the journey for a decentralized Internet!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you’re want to get involved in testing Grid 3.0, please join &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldtesting&quot;&gt;our testing group&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Your Mid November Titan Update</title>
		<published>2021-11-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-11-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/11/post-15/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/11/post-15/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your mid-November Titan 2.1 update!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;mid-november-titan-2-1-update-where-we-are-whats-coming&#x2F;1477&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve shipped 90% of all European orders that were placed up until early November, and later this month, we’ll begin shipping to the Americas.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inside please find more information and updates related to where we are and where we’re going when it comes to the Titan 2.1 orders.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you have any additional questions, you know how to find us!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Partner TAG Celebrates Climate Action Day</title>
		<published>2021-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/11/post-4/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/11/post-4/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We have some &lt;strong&gt;big plans cooking&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; with our friends and partners at Take Action Global (TAG) – more on that later this month!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, &lt;strong&gt;we invite you to celebrate &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.climate-action.info&#x2F;day&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Climate Action Day&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, hosted by TAG – the culminating celebration of the Climate Action Project, a six-week initiative involving 2.7 million people across 145 countries. 🌍&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around 18:40 CET, &lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold co-founder Adnan Fateyerji will deliver a message&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; to the students and teachers who participated in the program, and TAG Executive Director &lt;strong&gt;Koen Timmers will be sharing about ThreeFold &amp;amp; TAG&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; with their global audience. 🙏&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Climate Action Day will stream live at the blue zone of COP26 and for global audiences online.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;During the event, students and teachers will present questions to speakers such as Prince William, youth activist Elizabeth Wathuti, and representatives from WWF and NASA, and will showcase potential solutions for climate change.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;More information: https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.climate-action.info&#x2F;day&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Event starts at 1pm CET &#x2F; 8am EST.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Announcing DigiThree Labs</title>
		<published>2021-10-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-10-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/10/post-28/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/10/post-28/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;🚨 &lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;digicorplabs.com&quot;&gt;DigiCorp Labs&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; have joined forces to form DigiThree Labs&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, bringing together ThreeFold and DigiByte technologies and strong shared beliefs around decentralization, security, and privacy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DigiThree will deliver secure and private next-level solutions for people and enterprises, for a better tomorrow. Built on the DigiMetaverse, a decentralized foundational layer for the Metaverse.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More to come. 👀&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Find the news &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;threefold_io&#x2F;status&#x2F;1453759609911619591&quot;&gt;on Twitter&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as well! We’d love your support in getting the word out.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Europe&#x27;s Next-Gen Edge Computing Platform</title>
		<published>2021-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/10/post-26/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/10/post-26/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We’ve &lt;strong&gt;joined forces&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; with some incredible European open source projects with the collective ambition &lt;strong&gt;to build Europe’s next-generation edge computing platform&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🌐 &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;sovereignedge.eu&#x2F;MetaOS&#x2F;&quot;&gt;SovereignEdge.EU&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please find &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;threefold_io&#x2F;status&#x2F;1452941932129312774&quot;&gt;the announcement on Twitter&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and show your support. The more noise we make with this application, the more chances for our ecosystem to develop Europe’s edge cloud.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; 🙏&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Business Insider Africa Covers ThreeFold</title>
		<published>2021-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/10/post-13/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/10/post-13/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🗞 ThreeFold in the News 🗞&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“ThreeFold, a disruptive tech project, has recognized an underlying issue and is determined to solve it by providing a decentralized internet infrastructure and peer-to-peer cloud solution…&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any digital workload can be hosted natively on the ThreeFold Grid with minimum migration, including cloud alternatives, blockchains, IoT networks, decentralized organizations and applications.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ambitious startup to disrupt the Internet and Cloud, via Business Insider Africa.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full article &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;africa.businessinsider.com&#x2F;local&#x2F;markets&#x2F;ambitious-startup-to-disrupt-the-internet-and-cloud&#x2F;b38rwj4&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Titan v2.1 Shipping Update</title>
		<published>2021-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/10/post-12/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/10/post-12/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hi all 👋&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re pleased to share that last week, we began shipping Titan v2.1s ordered by September 10 to the European Union*. Many new farmers have already received their 3Nodes! 👩‍🌾&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But many of you still haven’t filled out the information needed to set up your farm(s). Please note we won’t send your 3Node(s) out until we get this information.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you ordered a Titan v2.1 and haven’t done so, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forms.gle&#x2F;p8947F8kytTpcJKW6&quot;&gt;please fill out this short form&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; so we can get you your 3Node without unnecessary delays.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*&lt;em&gt;All other locations will begin shipping in November. Thank you for your patience during this global hardware shortage. 🙏&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>EconoTimes Covers ThreeFold and DFINITY</title>
		<published>2021-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/10/post-7/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/10/post-7/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🗞 ThreeFold in the News 🗞&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“DFINITY and ThreeFold may have the same goal in sight, but their route to achieving the goal differs.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ThreeFold, DFINITY and the race to Decentralize the Internet, via EconoTimes.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full article &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;econotimes.com&#x2F;ThreeFold-DFINITY-and-the-race-to-Decentralize-the-Internet-1618367&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>TechTimes Covers Zero OS</title>
		<published>2021-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-028/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-028/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🗞 ThreeFold in the News 🗞&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The world’s economy is increasingly being plagued by constant cyberattacks” and “the centralized model sets the whole system up for a possible collapse”. Learn how ThreeFold’s infrastructure offers a solution to this alarming global issue.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full article &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.techtimes.com&#x2F;articles&#x2F;265905&#x2F;20210927&#x2F;threefolds-zero-os-promises-unparalleled-levels-of-internet-security-and-efficiency.htm&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ownCloud and ThreeFold Announce Partnership</title>
		<published>2021-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-28/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-28/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Based on their shared commitment to data sovereignty and open alternatives, ownCloud and ThreeFold have agreed to enter into a strategic partnership to advance the decentralization of the consumer cloud. ownCloud is an open-source file sync, share and content collaboration software that lets teams work on data easily from anywhere, on any device. ThreeFold is developing a peer-to-peer Internet platform that aims to liberalize what it labels as a centralized and unequally distributed Internet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;now-available-owncloud-on-the-threefold-grid&quot;&gt;Now available: ownCloud on the ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step in the partnership is &lt;strong&gt;the launch of the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.owncloud.com&quot;&gt;ownCloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; instance on the ThreeFold Grid – &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=2ZkpsG6dQvw&quot;&gt;demoed live&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; at ownCloud Conference 2021&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; – and &lt;strong&gt;the development of  a pilot program (register your interest by emailing testowncloud@threefold.io)&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. The long-term vision is &lt;strong&gt;a full range of file sync, file sharing and content collaboration solutions&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; that combine the strengths of both technologies. ThreeFold and ownCloud are excited to develop complementary offerings that reflect their shared beliefs in open standards and digital sovereignty. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“ownCloud is partnering with ThreeFold to deliver a solution for customers with the demand for data sovereignty, privacy, and ultra-security of their data assets. ownCloud powered by ThreeFold Grid delivers on these exact attributes offering a truly decentralized, secure and scalable infrastructure to complement the proven and globally adopted ownCloud collaboration platform,” Joerg Eberwein, VP Partners &amp;amp; Alliances, ownCloud GmbH.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;decentralized-infrastructure&quot;&gt;Decentralized infrastructure&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&quot;&gt;ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; built the world’s most decentralized, secure and scalable digital infrastructure. They already have the largest decentralized cloud infrastructure in the world with about 80,000,000 GB deployed across 50 countries, and counting. The ThreeFold Cloud represents the first fully comprehensive decentralized cloud and is integrated with industry-leading tools and protocols for a seamless transition towards web3. Anything that runs on Linux can run on ThreeFold, but better.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“ownCloud powered by ThreeFold offers a purposeful use case of the ThreeFold Grid and aligns with our mission to ensure data privacy and sovereignty for everyone. Combining the longstanding credibility of ownCloud and the decentralized cloud technology of ThreeFold results in a 1+1=3 value statement,” Chris Hutton, Co-Founder, ThreeFold Tech.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;hosting-via-smart-contract&quot;&gt;Hosting via smart contract&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold allows people to host their own applications anywhere on their decentralized cloud infrastructure via smart contract. This provides a powerful solution for ownCloud users to host their collaboration tools anywhere they want, independently from conventional, centralized cloud providers, and without having to maintain the servers and software themselves.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;free-from-censorship-and-user-tracking&quot;&gt;Free from censorship and user tracking&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ownCloud can be installed anywhere, providing a secure and sovereign alternative to public cloud providers ​​for more than 200 million users worldwide as of today.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With ownCloud running on the ThreeFold Grid infrastructure, users can manage their “own” cloud on a neutral cloud infrastructure that is free from censorship, user tracking and privacy breaches. This is made possible by Zero-OS, ThreeFold’s stateless and lightweight operating system that allows servers to run autonomously. The self-driving and self-healing features eliminate backdoors and reduce the hacking surface, to keep ownCloud instances secure at all times.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;joining-forces-for-improved-governance-reliability-and-security&quot;&gt;Joining forces for improved governance, reliability and security&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ownCloud and ThreeFold have a history of delivering technical collaborations amongst various projects. While ownCloud excels at delivering secure and private collaboration platforms, ThreeFold offers a robust and flexible large-scale cloud layer. Combining both projects provides new possibilities in regards to governance, reliability and security for users and their data. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the highly anticipated 3rd release of ThreeFold’s technology expected to launch this quarter, &lt;strong&gt;ownCloud and ThreeFold are preparing a pilot program&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; to leverage their infrastructure and software expertise to deliver truly self-sovereign collaboration solutions in the world. ownCloud and ThreeFold are currently working out the details of their pilot program, which will be announced at a future date.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the two are &lt;strong&gt;planning a cross-community event&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, where community members can learn more about the two technologies and hear further details about the collaboration.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Join our beta tester group by sending an email to testowncloud@threefold.io to be amongst the first to try ownCloud on a self-sovereign environment!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-owncloud&quot;&gt;About ownCloud&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ownCloud develops and provides open-source software for content collaboration, allowing teams to easily share and work on files seamlessly regardless of device or location. More than 200 million users worldwide already use ownCloud as an alternative to public clouds - and thereby opt for more digital sovereignty, security and data protection. For further information, please visit &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.owncloud.com&quot;&gt;www.owncloud.com&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or on Twitter &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;ownCloud&quot;&gt;@ownCloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-threefold&quot;&gt;About ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold is developing a peer-to-peer internet platform that aims to liberalize what it labels as a centralized and unequally distributed internet. Its platform, called the ThreeFold Grid, comprises over +1000 servers in 50+ different countries around the world, delivering approximately 80 PB in storage and over 22,000 CPU cores worldwide, making it the largest storage and compute peer-to-peer internet network in the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each server runs ThreeFold’s stateless and lightweight open-source operating system, Zero-OS, and is set up and operated by independent individuals and organisations called Farmers. Farmers earn rewards in TFT - the platform’s native token - for their participation. TFT is the currency of the ThreeFold Grid, with each token representing a unit of storage and compute on the platform. Grid users can use these tokens to reserve the storage and compute they need to store, build and share on the platform’s internet network.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, visit &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&quot;&gt;www.threefold.io&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or follow along on Twitter &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;threefold_io&quot;&gt;@threefold_io&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Not Just a Decentralized Cloud</title>
		<published>2021-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-24/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-24/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Typically we’ve been saying that ThreeFold is the only comprehensive #DeCloud out there but maybe it’s time we start saying that &lt;strong&gt;we are actually the substrate for Decentralized Cloud&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. Well, maybe we’re both. 😉
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📚 Read more &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-is-the-substrate-for-decloud&#x2F;1295&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What do you think about this positioning? We like it – because, well, it’s true – but we’re curious, as always, to hear from the community.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Introducing TF Chain and Updated Billing</title>
		<published>2021-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-20/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-20/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introducing TF Chain and an updated (pay-as-you-go) billing model!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Learn more about why blockchain technology is important within ThreeFold, how the system is operating now, and how things are changing for the better in ThreeFold Grid 3.0.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📚 Full post &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;introducing-tf-chain-an-updated-billing-model&#x2F;1277&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>How ThreeFold Provides a Secure IT Ecosystem</title>
		<published>2021-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-17/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-17/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week, &lt;strong&gt;Apple and Google issued critical security updates&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; due to multiple “zero-day” (read: extremely urgent) vulnerabilities which most likely have already been exploited. And these most recent examples are just the tip of the iceberg.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📚 Learn about the prevalent &amp;amp; growing threat of cyberattacks and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;critical-security-updates-for-apple-and-google-underline-need-for-secure-it-ecosystem&#x2F;1271&quot;&gt;how ThreeFold provides a secure IT ecosystem&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; the world so badly needs.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Calling All Grid 3.0 Testers</title>
		<published>2021-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-15/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-15/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We are now ready to invite a limited group from our community to test an early release of Grid 3.0!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
If you’re interested, please read through &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;join-the-grid-3-0-beta-testers-group&#x2F;1194&quot;&gt;this post&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; and answer three quick questions for us.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>What&#x27;s Possible on Grid 2</title>
		<published>2021-09-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-09-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-9/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-9/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;While we &lt;strong&gt;work to open testing of Grid 3.0&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; to our community, questions are coming in around how to get started testing the Grid today.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;what-you-can-do-on-the-threefold-grid-today&#x2F;1220&quot;&gt;this post&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, Scott outlines &lt;strong&gt;what’s currently available to test on Grid 2&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;If you’re interested in testing on the ThreeFold Grid, please join &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldtesting&quot;&gt;our testing community&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Titan v2.1 Shipping Update</title>
		<published>2021-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-08/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-08/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;🚨 &lt;strong&gt;We have a Titan v2.1 shipping update (action required below)&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, in case you missed it in other channels:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
For all orders received before Friday the 10th of September, we plan to ship as follows:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🌍 Europe: Last week of September&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🌎 USA &amp;amp; Canada: Mid-October&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🌏 All Others: End of October
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📧 &lt;strong&gt;Please check your inbox&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; for an email from farming@threefold.tech (sent on September 7) in which we ask for details we need in order to set up your farm and node!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;You can follow &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;titan-v2-1-shipping-info&#x2F;1223&quot;&gt;this forum thread&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for continued shipping updates or to ask any questions you might have.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Meet the Planetary Network</title>
		<published>2021-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-03/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-03/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Meet &lt;strong&gt;the Planetary Network 🌍 a peer-to-peer end-to-end encrypted global network&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, providing universal connectivity between nodes, Grid deployers, and solution users.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
📚 Learn more about it &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;how-our-planetary-network-works&#x2F;1210&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Background: While it appears to be a cohesive whole, today’s Internet is actually a rather fragmented and fragile system. It’s overly-complex, and liable to large scale outages, censorship, and surveilance…&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>An Interview with Jimber</title>
		<published>2021-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-3/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-3/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently, Scott (from the TF Foundation) interviewed Jonas Delrue from Jimber, the team developing P2P solutions like video chat and office workspace, using the Digital Twin platform. Digital Twin is a use case on top of the ThreeFold Grid.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
💬 You can find the interview &lt;em&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;interview_with_jimber&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
It’s quite a fascinating discussion and gives insight on the technical hurdles and motivations for developing private, decentralized, and open source alternatives to popular products from major corporations.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>September 1 Community Call Recording</title>
		<published>2021-09-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-09-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-02/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-02/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;📹 Here is &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=mc3-y-jT6r4&quot;&gt;the recording of yesterday’s community call&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, which focused on updates around farming and ThreeFold Grid 3.0!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The video is timestamped, so you can move around to the parts which are most relevant or interesting for you.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Grid Utilization Plan – Part 2</title>
		<published>2021-09-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-09-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-2/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-2/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Today, we’re sharing &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;grid-utilization-plan-part-two&#x2F;1203&quot;&gt;part two&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of our ThreeFold Grid Utilization Plan.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
It highlights &lt;strong&gt;some of our main partnerships&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, which together can bring &lt;strong&gt;many millions of users&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; to the grid.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;If you missed part one (TF Grid Solutions), be sure to check it out &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;grid-utilization-plan-part-one&#x2F;1157&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>A First Look at Terraform on TF Grid 3.0</title>
		<published>2021-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-01/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-01/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;youtu.be&#x2F;uPKM1Ta3tvY&quot;&gt;a first look at Terraform&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on ThreeFold Grid 3.0!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In this video, Scott demo’s how easy it is to create, use, and destroy deployments on ThreeFold Grid 3.0 using Terraform.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Fun fact: A man of many talents, Scott also created the flute audio you hear in the video intro!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>TFT on 1inch.io</title>
		<published>2021-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The ThreeFold Token is now available on &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;1inch.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;1inch.io&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;1inch connects many third party DEXes and has its own liquidity pools as well, to provide the best possible pricing for end users. It is an easy entry to the DeFi space.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
🎒 &lt;strong&gt;Learn how to get TFT on the Binance Smart Chain using 1inch &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;how-to-buy-tft-on-binance-smart-chain-using-1inch-io&#x2F;1189&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Grid 3.0 Supports Terraform</title>
		<published>2021-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/08/post-31/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/08/post-31/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;An exciting element of our roadmap to ThreeFold Grid 3.0 is &lt;strong&gt;the integration of Terraform into the TF Grid&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Terraform is a widely used open-source Infrastructure as Code (IaC) software tool which enables developers to build, change, and version infrastructure in a safe and efficient way.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
📚 &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-grid-3-0-supports-terraform&#x2F;1184&quot;&gt;Read about Terraform&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, how it works with the TF Grid, and what it means for grid users.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Keep an eye out for the Terraform demo coming tomorrow. We’ll also discuss on the community call!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>September 1 Community Call Announcement</title>
		<published>2021-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/08/post-30/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/08/post-30/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We’ll host a &lt;strong&gt;community call this Wednesday&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; at 5pm CEST to share updates around &lt;strong&gt;farming&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; and to touch on a few important aspects of &lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold Grid 3.0&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
❗️Here’s &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;meet.jit.si&#x2F;moderated&#x2F;d211ee6bc96b7a4e6424955465c94be15837548e64703afc3c65bd92b61c849a&quot;&gt;the link&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to the call&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;We hope to see you there! If not, we’ll share the recording afterwards.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Liquid Receives $120 Million in Debt Financing From FTX</title>
		<published>2021-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/08/post-26/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/08/post-26/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Related to last week’s Liquid news:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Today, Liquid announced “the closing of a US$120,000,000 debt financing” from FTX Trading Ltd, owner and operator of top tier exchange FTX&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, and “that they have entered good faith discussions in pursuit of further collaborative opportunities.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
While we cannot speculate on what these further collaborative opportunities might be and how they could impact tokens listed on Liquid, it is certainly good news for Liquid to have such support from FTX.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Full coverage &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;liquid-exchange-receives-120-000-000-in-debt-financing-from-top-tier-ftx&#x2F;1159&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Grid Utilization Plan – Part 1</title>
		<published>2021-08-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-08-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/08/post-25/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/08/post-25/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The ThreeFold Foundation’s primary goal is to achieve &lt;strong&gt;sustainable and organic growth of the ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Here’s &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;grid-utilization-plan-part-one&#x2F;1157&quot;&gt;part one&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (of two) of our TF Grid Utilization Plan&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, which focuses primarily on TF Grid Solutions.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;As always, we’d love to have your feedback. And you can look forward to part two, which will cover some of our key partnerships.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Introducing the TFT Development Plan</title>
		<published>2021-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/08/post-23/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/08/post-23/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There have been many questions in the community about &lt;strong&gt;the plan around the ThreeFold Token&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Please take a look at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;tft-development-plan&#x2F;1149&quot;&gt;this post&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; and provide your comments, questions, and feedback.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;We hope you see what we see… Now’s the time to buy TFT. If you need some help getting TFT on BSC, please see the forum post &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;how-to-buy-tft-on-binance-smart-chain-using-pancake-swap-protocol&#x2F;902&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. And as always, we’re here to help!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Liquid Hacked, TFT Not Affected</title>
		<published>2021-08-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-08-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/08/post-019/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/08/post-019/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We wanted to update the community that Liquid, an exchange on which TFT is listed, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;Liquid_Global&#x2F;status&#x2F;1428176357515612165?s=09&quot;&gt;shared this morning&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that warm wallets on the exchange were compromised in a hack.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;It appears that Stellar-based assets (e.g. TFT) were not stolen.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Please take note:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🚫 To ensure safety of funds, please do not deposit any crypto assets to your Liquid wallets until further notice.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🚫 Liquid has halted all crypto withdrawals while we assess the impact.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;✅ Fiat withdrawals and deposits remain available.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;✅ Other services on Liquid, including trading and Liquid Earn, remain available.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
You can find the full incident report &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;blog.liquid.com&#x2F;warm-wallet-incident&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Liquid is investigating and will provide updates as they have them. We’ve also reached out to them directly and will share more as we know. 🙏&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>August 18 AMA Recap</title>
		<published>2021-08-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-08-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/08/post-19/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/08/post-19/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;📹 &lt;strong&gt;For those who are interested in yesterday’s AMA, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=GrW9rbcnRZU&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is the recording.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We discussed farming (3.0), the token, ThreeFold Grid use cases, and the roadmap to ThreeFold Grid 3.0. Note the video is timestamped so you can select the questions you most care about.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>The Road to TF Grid v3.0</title>
		<published>2021-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/08/post-17/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/08/post-17/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Today, we are super excited to share &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;circles.threefold.me&#x2F;project&#x2F;despiegk-product_tfgrid3_roadmap&#x2F;kanban&quot;&gt;the roadmap&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to ThreeFold Grid v3.0!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;As many of you know, the main focus of ThreeFold these days is to get the grid to version 3.0 and ready for production.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Within, you will find various stories within “swimlanes” that show where our attention is and where it is going. We will be sure to elaborate more on what it all means – the priorities, progress, and also where we can use your support.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Be sure to look at &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;circles.threefold.me&#x2F;project&#x2F;despiegk-product_tfgrid3_roadmap&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;home&quot;&gt;the wiki&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; which is tied to our kanban for more context.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Please feel free to dig in and leave comments or questions on &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;our forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;PS: The circles tool (see roadmap), which is based on open source Taiga, will be made available as a workload on top of the TF Grid for everyone to use. It’s an amazing tool! We have many circles in which we collaborate internally, with members of the community, and with partner projects (more than 80 people globally) on a day-to-day basis.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>We&#x27;re Hosting an AMA on August 18th</title>
		<published>2021-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/08/post-16/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/08/post-16/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please join us for an Ask Me Anything this Wednesday at 17:00 CEST!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
This will be a video AMA. We’ll answer questions submitted ahead of time in priority, and if there is time at the end, we will open the floor up for live questions.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
You can submit questions until 12:00 CEST (48 hours) on Wednesday via the link below.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;❓ &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;submit-your-questions-for-the-wednesday-august-18-ask-me-anything-ama&#x2F;1109&quot;&gt;Submit your questions&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📹 &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;us02web.zoom.us&#x2F;j&#x2F;88516114306&quot;&gt;Zoom link&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you can’t join, we’ll share the recording afterwards. And we’ll be hosting community AMAs on a bi-weekly basis going forward!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Additional Context&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We’ve heard you loud and clear lately and we’ve decided to do AMAs on a regular basis with our community to answer all your questions in a more efficient way.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We’re unable to follow up on chats, hence the forum thread. This is the only solution we’ve found to 1. answer all your questions and 2. keep the team focused on progress.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Join Our Team</title>
		<published>2021-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/08/post-9/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/08/post-9/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We’re looking for team members&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; – with operations and developer roles currently open! Join us on our mission to build a planet-positive and data sovereign Internet owned by the people.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;👩‍💻 You can find open positions on our &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;careers&quot;&gt;careers page&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ODE and ThreeFold Announce Partnership</title>
		<published>2021-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/08/post-5/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/08/post-5/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, we’re pleased to announce a partnership between ThreeFold Tech and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;odeinfinity.com&quot;&gt;ODE&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, the world’s first vertically integrated consumer data ecosystem. ODE is creating a future where enterprises become trusted partners to their digital consumers, offering an application platform that enables privacy for digital consumers, lean data science, and compliance for enterprises. Built on blockchain and AI, ODE Infinity defines a new paradigm for digital engagement for enterprises.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ODE recognizes the need for a secure, scalable, and cost-effective global infrastructure platform that complements the key attributes of ODE and furthermore meets the attributes demanded by more and more customers today. Priority attributes include data sovereignty and privacy, true decentralization, no lock-in, scalability, and ultra-security (to name a few).
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold technology and the ThreeFold Grid offers such an infrastructure platform and meets these exact attributes demanded by the customers today. ThreeFold brings a truly decentralized compute and storage network that ensures the privacy and sovereignty of customer data, scalability, cost efficiency, and ultimately a digital infrastructure that is far more sustainable for our planet.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
“The collaboration between ODE and ThreeFold is a tremendous win for enterprises and consumers that are wrestling to find a balance between data privacy, compliance, and business growth to build trust. Our joint offering does exactly that by creating a decentralized data ecosystem that enables enterprises to become trusted partners to their digital consumers. The new world where privacy is by design, usage is by consent, and value realization is unlimited and mutual,” says ODE CEO Sashi Edupuganti. “The synergy between ODE and ThreeFold will accelerate the journey toward a more decentralized and democratic way to manage and use consumer data.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ODE and ThreeFold Tech have now signed a collaborative agreement to deliver solutions that accelerate their collective mission of democratizing data and creating greater data management capabilities for enterprises, and self-determination and sovereignty for all people. We will update as this partnership evolves.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-ode&quot;&gt;About ODE&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Headquartered in Tempe, Arizona with employees around the world, ODE (Open Data Economy) was recently recognized as the Top 100 Company in 2021 at Intercon2021, Las Vegas and the Top 30 most innovative companies of 2020 by CIO Bulletin. As a revolutionary startup that is building a more equitable data economy for all, ODE Infinity is the world’s first vertically integrated consumer data ecosystem. ODE is creating a future where enterprises become trusted partners to their digital consumers and eases the burden of data management for those enterprises. Their application platform, built on blockchain and AI, enables privacy for digital consumers, lean data science, and compliance for enterprises. ODE Infinity defines a new paradigm for digital engagement for enterprises and consumers, alike.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more, visit &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;odeinfinity.com&quot;&gt;odeinfinity.com&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-threefold&quot;&gt;About ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Headquartered in Belgium, and with employees worldwide, ThreeFold Tech has developed a decentralized cloud technology aimed to empower a p2p data economy where sovereignty, privacy, and equality are held paramount.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The ThreeFold Grid (powered by ThreeFold technology) is the largest and most advanced peer-to-peer compute and storage network in the world, which enables individuals and organizations to build and deploy their web2 and web3 applications in a complete decentralized, private, sustainable, and autonomous IT infrastructure through its peer-to-peer cloud capacity and developer tools.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold technology and the ThreeFold Grid offer a decentralized compute and storage network that ensures the privacy and sovereignty of consumer data, a quantum safe file system, scalability, cost efficiency, and ultimately a digital infrastructure that is sustainable and helps organizations address critical technological challenges.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more, visit &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&quot;&gt;threefold.io&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Watch the P2P File Browser Demo!</title>
		<published>2021-07-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-07-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/07/post-29/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/07/post-29/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, we’re excited to share with you &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=oT_dKuvF6Ng&quot;&gt;a demo of the ultra-secure peer-to-peer file browser (storage) solution&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; that’s being built on top of the ThreeFold Grid!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
This is part of a series of demos showcasing a little piece of what we’re building at the ThreeFold – private, secure, peer-to-peer alternatives to many of the tools and experiences we all use today.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Last week, we shared a demo of the self-hosted video solution, which you can find &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;news&#x2F;post&#x2F;video_chat_demo&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
See you next time! 👋&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Grid v2.8.0 Highlights and Release Notes</title>
		<published>2021-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/07/post-22/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/07/post-22/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;📚 &lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold Update&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; 📚
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Recently, &lt;strong&gt;we released ThreeFold Grid 2.8.0&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, which features:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
🤝 Generic VMs Support
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
🔎 ThreeFold Explorer v0.5.1
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
👨‍🌾 Farming &amp;amp; Minting Operational Improvements
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Not sure what this means? 🤔 Scott (who’s on a roll this week) took the time to explain &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;discussing-threefold-grid-2-8-release-highlights&#x2F;1040&quot;&gt;the highlights here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. Feel free to ask questions!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
And you can find &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;threefold__release_notes_grid_2_8_0&quot;&gt;the full release notes here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Watch the Self-Hosted Video Chat Demo!</title>
		<published>2021-07-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-07-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/07/post-20/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/07/post-20/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;👀 &lt;strong&gt;Check out a little piece of what we’re building at ThreeFold!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
This &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;youtu.be&#x2F;VlxLHxEL1WI&quot;&gt;self-hosted video chat solution&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; is just one component of a full suite of tools you’ll be able to deploy for yourself soon on the ThreeFold Grid!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Artheon VR Museum is Coming to the Grid</title>
		<published>2021-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/07/post-15/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/07/post-15/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Artheon and ThreeFold joined forces to create the world’s largest VR database of art 🎨 and cultural heritage – owned by everyone and made for everyone.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
🔜 &lt;strong&gt;Coming to the ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; End of Q3 &#x2F; Beginning Q4.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;youtu.be&#x2F;Ofk22N2Ew1k&quot;&gt;Take a peak&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; at what museum visitors from around the world will soon be able to experience.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Introducing New Farming Rewards</title>
		<published>2021-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/07/post-07/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/07/post-07/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;With the forthcoming launch of ThreeFold Grid 3.0 later this year, the world is set to go peer-to-peer. With many use-cases being lined up, we updated the Farming Rewards to incentivize Farmers to expand the ThreeFold Grid further across the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;new-farming-logic-introducing-network-rewards&quot;&gt;New Farming Logic - Introducing Network Rewards&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new Farming Rewards logic can be found &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;threefold__farming_reward&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HERE&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
You will see that the farming rewards were simplified, and are now calculated according to the compute and storage units (CU &amp;amp; SU) provided to the ThreeFold Grid. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Also, as of this summer, Farmers will be able to earn more TFT for the Network traffic happening on their 3Nodes. The amount of data coming in and out of their CU and SU will determine extra rewards in the form of Network Units (NU).
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Certified NU: 0.3 TFT per GB per month&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DIY NU: 0.2 TFT per GB per month&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-do-i-get-certified&quot;&gt;How do I get Certified?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All 3Nodes bought from ThreeFold after June 5 2021 are eligible for certified farming. We will send instructions to everyone that purchased a Titan v2.1 on how to upgrade to a certified 3Node next week. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
For people that already bought an earlier batch of nodes, we are thinking of a solution for becoming certified, as our hardware partners need the physical 3Node to certify the hardware.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;important-notes&quot;&gt;Important notes&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All certified hardware is 100% dedicated to the ThreeFold Grid. While DIY nodes can be booted with a different Operating System, this is not possible with a Certified 3Node.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All certified hardware is automatically subject to the 3.0 Farming Logic. Read more &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;threefold__farming_reward&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HERE&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;P.s. If you’re already a farmer and would like to be featured on our websites please &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forms.gle&#x2F;cW6uFUhkohSw81KT6&quot;&gt;fill out this form.&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; Let’s introduce the world to the farming community behind this awesome project!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Introducing Certified Farming for a More Secure ThreeFold Grid</title>
		<published>2021-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/07/post-7/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/07/post-7/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last month, we went live with Titan V2.1, and we’re thrilled to count +1,000 orders already from all over the world.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
While orders keep on coming in, we are happy to launch the Certified Farming Program. Certification brings more security to 3Nodes and hence to the ThreeFold Grid, while also providing more rewards to Farmers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;more-security-for-everyone&quot;&gt;More Security For Everyone&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While anyone can connect hardware to the ThreeFold Grid, some workloads require the highest level of security standards. Certified hardware can only be booted by Zero-OS and allows for 100% tamper-proof capacity. With certification, ThreeFold is pushing the limits further and creating a new global standard for hardware security.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
There are key benefits for Farmers to certify their capacity: 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get a certified capacity label: Some developers and enterprises will seek for the highest levels of security. With the certified label, you will be able to provide capacity for their workloads at a higher price.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved hardware security: While DIY farming already provides incredible security, certified farming is 100% tamper-proof. Now you can bring more security to the ThreeFold Grid and to the people using it. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re building a more secure future for our digital lives. This will happen! 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;P.s. If you’re already a farmer and would like to be featured on our websites please &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forms.gle&#x2F;cW6uFUhkohSw81KT6&quot;&gt;fill out this form.&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; Let’s introduce the world to the farming community behind this awesome project!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Coverage in Smartereum</title>
		<published>2021-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-30/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-30/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;🗞 &lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold is Audaciously Building a New Decentralized Internet&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; (via Smartereum)
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
“… The ThreeFold project is led by a 65-[person] team of disruptors with a common goal: to put sovereign control of the internet in everybody’s hand.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
It goes without saying that these visionaries desire a true democracy of the internet: an internet of the people, by the people and for all people everywhere.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full article &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;smartereum.com&#x2F;189750&#x2F;threefold-is-audaciously-building-a-new-decentralized-internet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Coverage in Yahoo! News</title>
		<published>2021-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-26/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-26/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;🗞 &lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold Set To Disrupt Status Quo With a P2P Internet Powered by the People&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; (via Yahoo! News)
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
“Overall, Threefold aims to help humanity thrive, save the planet, and make the internet accessible to everyone, including people living in remote locations.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Now when you factor in their partnerships with other decentralized corporations, this goal seems achievable in no distant time. One can only imagine what they accomplish in the near future given the uniqueness of their project and the quality of the team behind it.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full article &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;news.yahoo.com&#x2F;news&#x2F;threefold-set-disrupt-status-quo-051457787.html?guccounter=1&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Decentralize the DigiByte Blockchain by Deploying a Node on the ThreeFold Grid</title>
		<published>2021-06-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-06-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-24/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-24/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today we are happy to share with you some news from our partnership with the DigiByte Foundation 🤝 &lt;strong&gt;how to decentralize the DigiByte Network by deploying a DigiByte Node on ThreeFold Grid!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
DigiByte Foundation’s Rudy Bouwman joins ThreeFold’s Weynand Kuijpers to discuss what it all means and how to deploy.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;👀 &lt;strong&gt;Watch the full video &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;youtu.be&#x2F;fBEwlfcyxgA&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you’re interested in deploying a DigiByte Node on the ThreeFold Grid, please fill out &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forms.gle&#x2F;NHDNkZppTzwRorz77&quot;&gt;this quick form&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and we will get in touch.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
More to come from DigiByte Foundation and ThreeFold – this is only the beginning! 🌅&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Coverage in Bankless Times</title>
		<published>2021-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-16/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-16/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;🗞 &lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold’s Green Technology Strategy to a Fairer, More Sustainable World&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
“We have the potential to offset energy usage 100 per cent by the end of 2021, and our goal is to take two times more carbon out of the air than we put in,” says, Kristof de Spiegeleer, co-founder of ThreeFold.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full article &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.banklesstimes.com&#x2F;2021&#x2F;06&#x2F;14&#x2F;threefolds-green-technology-strategy-to-a-fairer-more-sustainable-world&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to read more about ThreeFold energy savings, dive into &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;threefold__energy_savings&quot;&gt;our wiki&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Zetako and ThreeFold Join Forces</title>
		<published>2021-06-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-06-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-15/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-15/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For both Zetako and ThreeFold, efficiency and sustainability are key. &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.zetako.ai&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Zetako&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a company dedicated to lossless data compression, and after years of research and development, has created an alternative solution to the regular standards of data compression. And with two decades of relevant experience and a focus on sustainability, ThreeFold has built new peer-to-peer Internet infrastructure and technologies from the ground up – where every aspect is optimized towards maximum efficiency and the least amount of harm to the planet.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both already members of &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;aci&quot;&gt;the Alliance for a Conscious Internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, a planetary movement of people and organizations that take action to shape a conscious digital world, Zetako and ThreeFold have now signed on to merge their technologies to bring forward hyper-efficient, secure, and private data transport and storage solutions for all.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
“The world has been using the same compression technology for the last 30 years, just like the model to deliver IT services has not changed,” says Weynand Kuijpers, ThreeFold Co-Founder. “ThreeFold challenges that status quo, where anybody can now be the Internet by adding capacity to the ThreeFold Grid – and with this, we need a 21st century compression and decompression technology. Zetako delivers that much-needed true innovation.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The ThreeFold Grid is live today, the world’s most advanced peer-to-peer Internet infrastructure. It can scale limitlessly, and brings a more performant, secure and sustainable Internet to host humanity’s data and workloads. ThreeFold technology already consumes 90 percent less energy than today’s solutions. (The company has also recently announced plans to offset energy usage 100 percent by the end of 2021, with the goal of taking two times more carbon out of the air than they put in.)
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
With its quantum safe storage offering, ThreeFold can now integrate with Zetako’s technology to store compressed data, enabling it to become even more efficient and sustainable. Further, ThreeFold can now do compression live on network connections between different parts of what users deploy.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
“We are particularly excited about the opportunity to work with ThreeFold as we believe they represent the future of data transmission &amp;amp; storage,” says Claus Rosenberg Gotthard, CEO of Zetako. “It’s the right place to implement Zetako’s innovative technologies of bit-by-bit compression.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In the short term, Zetako and ThreeFold will work on a project basis to fulfill specific organization requirements. Zetako provides the compression, and ThreeFold provides the compute and storage. As an example, with COVID-19 and the world moving increasingly digital, congesting the network, people and businesses that need a way to transfer large files quickly will now have a much more efficient way to do so. And in the longer term, the two will explore more ways to deeply integrate their technologies and provide broader solutions to the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-zetako&quot;&gt;About Zetako&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zetako is dedicated to reducing energy usage &amp;amp; CO2 emission for the transmission &amp;amp; storage of data by applying a new more efficient lossless data compression technology.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We have developed a new mathematical theory based on Statistical Predictive modeling and applied this to a new lossless data compression technology. The result is a technology that provides higher Compression at higher Speed and uses &amp;gt;70% less energy in the process. In addition to this, the technology is capable of doing bit-by-bit compression allowing for real time bandwidth reduction. The technology does not need a prior knowledge of the dataset to start compression. This means that our technology does not require the data stream to be chopped up into chunks – we apply compression the moment the first bit (1 or 0) comes in.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can learn more about Zetako at &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.zetako.ai&#x2F;&quot;&gt;zetako.ai&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-threefold&quot;&gt;About ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Powered by open source technology, ThreeFold is the engine for a data-sovereign and planet-positive peer-to-peer infrastructure – owned by humanity. ThreeFold is the People’s Internet.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold is formed by individuals and organizations from all around the world that connect 3Nodes (computers) and provide Internet capacity to the ThreeFold Grid. Together, we expand a data-sovereign and planet-positive Internet infrastructure, owned by the people.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone can get involved in the People’s Internet by buying the ThreeFold Token, getting a 3Node, testing the technology, or becoming a contributor or a partner. Visit &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&quot;&gt;threefold.io&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or follow along on &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldnews&quot;&gt;Telegram&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;threefold_io&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Satoshi Street Bets x ThreeFold AMA</title>
		<published>2021-06-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-06-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-14/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-14/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last week, ThreeFold team members Weynand Kuijpers, Maximilian Rang, and Nickolay Babenko joined Satoshi Street Bets for an Ask Me Anything (AMA) to share ThreeFold with their community and expand awareness for the project.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;They covered a wide range of topics including ThreeFold’s beginnings, the vision, some comparisons to other projects, and really went deep into the technology.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can listen to the AMA recording &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=AIDRHaxZmzU&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; And you can find Satoshi Street Bets on Telegram &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;satoshistreetbets&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Has Plans to Go More Green</title>
		<published>2021-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-13/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-13/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;“Traditional industry solutions focus on increasing the use of renewable energies to power data centers. But this is not a viable solution. As per ThreeFold they need to drastically reduce the global internet’s energy consumption, and we must act now.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the coverage from UnlockBC &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.unlock-bc.com&#x2F;news&#x2F;2021-06-13&#x2F;uae-based-decentralized-p2p-internet-platform-goes-green-to-reduce-internet-energy-consumption&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Pre-Order Your Titan v2.1 Now!</title>
		<published>2021-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-011/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-011/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the last 24 hours, we’ve had Titan v2.1 3Node pre-orders from all corners of the globe – six of the seven continents. (Anybody know anyone in Antarctica?)
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;❗️ Pre-orders &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;pre-order.threefold.tech&#x2F;&quot;&gt;are now live&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for the general public!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, please visit &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;nodeshop-pre-order-faq&#x2F;853&quot;&gt;our FAQ&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; first to see if you can find the answer there. If you don’t find what you’re looking for, join our two-way farmer chat &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldfarmers&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>See How ThreeFold Compares to Dfinity</title>
		<published>2021-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-11/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-11/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;🗞 &lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold in the News&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; 🗞
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The Internet revolution is upon us. Kudos to Dfinity for their Internet Computer movement. See how ThreeFold compares and offers “a more holistic environment for developers.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full article &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;tgdaily.com&#x2F;web&#x2F;6-dfinity-threefold-are-leading-an-internet-decentralization-revolution&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Coverage in CoinTelegraph!</title>
		<published>2021-06-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-06-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-10/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-10/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, ThreeFold received some nice coverage in CoinTelegraph:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
“The ThreeFold Grid … can add tangible value to Dfinity or Solid and other similar projects if they want to benefit from a truly decentralized and sovereign infrastructure instead of relying on current data center models.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🗞 Full Article: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cointelegraph-com.cdn.ampproject.org&#x2F;c&#x2F;s&#x2F;cointelegraph.com&#x2F;news&#x2F;is-a-new-decentralized-internet-or-web-3-0-possible&#x2F;amp&quot;&gt;Is a new decentralized internet, or Web 3.0, possible?&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; via CoinTelegraph.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>3,000+ 3Node Pre-Registrations for Batch 3</title>
		<published>2021-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-08/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-08/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Over the past days we have received &lt;strong&gt;more than 3,000 pre-registrations&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; for the Titan V2 3Node!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, pre-registration remains open &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;next3nodebatch.threefold.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For those who have already pre-registered, thank you! We’ll have actions for you to take in the coming days.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Tactical Investing Covers ThreeFold</title>
		<published>2021-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-05/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-05/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, YouTube influencer &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;channel&#x2F;UCPRC2wIfZtAlzCa_6iKE46w&quot;&gt;Tactical Investing&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; posted a video to his account “THIS IS HUGE…Better Than Akash Network? &lt;em&gt;Time Sensitive&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;” to share about the ThreeFold farming opportunity with his community.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
And today, he posted another video comparing ThreeFold with Akash Network and Holo. “With a P2P compute lending device, the titanv2 has the potential to make you quite a bit in passive income over the next few years.” The videos garnered more than 35,000 views (on the date of this post) and led to the Titan v2 3Node to sell out in a matter of hours.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch the videos &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=2ndSPsnRz3U&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=nLfwJNCwnE0&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Q2 3Node Batch is Sold Out! Q3 Pre-registration is Live!</title>
		<published>2021-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-04/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-04/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;😮 Wow!😮
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning our team woke up to 400+ emails to register for our Titan V2 3Node batch after &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;channel&#x2F;UCPRC2wIfZtAlzCa_6iKE46w&quot;&gt;Tactical Investing&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; covered our project.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;All of our Titan V2 3Nodes sold out!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Although our last batch sold out, we are taking new registrations for the next batch already. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pre-register &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;next3nodebatch.threefold.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>3Node Pre-Register Q2 Batch Closing Soon</title>
		<published>2021-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-03/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-03/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Our next batch of Titan V2 3Nodes will ship in a matter of weeks. 
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Cheers!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; 🥂 - to all that have pre-registered already and are making the internet a more sustainable and more private place!
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hurry up!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; 🏃🏽‍♀️ - to all of you still looking for an easy way to become a ThreeFold Farmer.
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
You can order your Titan v2 on our &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;shop.threefold.tech&#x2F;index.php?route=product&#x2F;product&amp;amp;path=59&amp;amp;product_id=53&quot;&gt;pre-register page&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;And yes, all Titan’s come with one of those rad stickers.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>New Nodes In New Parts Of The World</title>
		<published>2021-05-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-05-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/05/post-28/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/05/post-28/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This month, we had new nodes come online in Brazil, Cyprus, the United Kingdom, Belgium, Romania, the United States, Italy, Bulgaria, and more. Welcome to our new farmers!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re a farmer or if you’re interested in farming and have some questions, please join our farmers chat &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldfarmers&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
And you can always explore live grid stats – total capacity, locations, and much more – &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;explorer.threefold.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;via our grid explorer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Co-Founder&#x27;s Message to Blockchains in Dubai</title>
		<published>2021-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/05/post-26/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/05/post-26/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yesterday, ThreeFold co-founder Kristof De Spiegeleer spoke at the AIBC Summit in Dubai.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
“The Internet’s infrastructure is extremely power-hungry, and most blockchains are living on top of that infrastructure. Blockchains represent the movement for decentralization, and they should do better than this. At ThreeFold, we offer an alternative path. Will you take it?”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read the full coverage &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;opinionnigeria.com&#x2F;threefold-takes-on-blockchain-decentralization-and-sustainability-at-aibc-summit-in-dubai&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold is Attending the AIBC Summit in Dubai</title>
		<published>2021-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/05/post-24/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/05/post-24/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tomorrow and Wednesday, ThreeFold is attending &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;aibc.world&#x2F;uae&#x2F;&quot;&gt;the AIBC Summit&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in Dubai.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Our co-founder Kristof de Spiegeleer will be speaking and some of the team will be at the expo to meet with attendees!
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
If you’re in Dubai, we hope to see you. For others, there is the opportunity to join in virtually!
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;AIBC brings together key brands and individuals from the converging sectors of AI, blockchain, IoT, Quantum Tech to discuss and shape the future of emerging tech.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Products &amp; Services Update</title>
		<published>2021-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/05/post-21/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/05/post-21/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold Products &amp;amp; Services Updates 2.7.1&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
Today we present you a round of recent updates to ThreeFold Cloud &amp;amp; Grid Services (live on Testnet), ThreeFold Connect, &amp;amp; ThreeFold Token (live on Production)!
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Highlights&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
☁️ Backend and user experience improvements to the eVDC
🌐 New version of Zero OS
👜 Bitcoin deposit and vesting via TF Connect
🥞 Binance Smart Chain integration (Pancakeswap)
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
What Now?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;info&#x2F;cloud#&#x2F;cloud__release_notes_2_7_1&quot;&gt;Read the full release notes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldtesting&quot;&gt;Join the Grid testing community&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;threefold__threefold_connect_btc&quot;&gt;Info: Get TFT with BTC directly on ThreeFold Connect&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;threefold__tft_binance_defi?id=how-to-get-tft-on-pancakeswap&quot;&gt;Info: Get TFT via Binance Smart Chain&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Moving on to 2.8 Cloud &amp;amp; Grid Services updates!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>TFT is more accessible; now available via PancakeSwap and a BTC Integration on ThreeFold Connect</title>
		<published>2021-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/05/post-12/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/05/post-12/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently, we announced &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;bitcoinist.com&#x2F;peer-to-peer-internet-threefold-goes-multichain-to-accelerate-token-accessibility&#x2F;&quot;&gt;our plans to go “multichain,”&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; bringing the ThreeFold Token (TFT) to three popular DeFi ecosystems: Binance Smart Chain (BSC), Ethereum, and Huobi’s ECO Chain. Today, the bridge to BSC is now live, and TFT is available on PancakeSwap!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
By making TFT more accessible, more of the world is now able to take part in the growth of a peer-to-peer Internet owned by all of us. Members of the ThreeFold community, DeFi enthusiasts, and the Binance community now have another way to access TFT, and can swap it with other BSC-based tokens as they wish.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
As an added bonus, today we are also pleased to share that anyone can now buy TFT with BTC directly on the ThreeFold Connect app.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-threefold-all-about&quot;&gt;What is ThreeFold all about?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold is a quantum-safe peer-to-peer Internet (storage and compute), combining a stateless operating system with autonomous technology on a globally-distributed network of nodes. The technology stack is unstoppable (self-driving and self-healing) and our tamper-proof infrastructure can scale with demand.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Reputed organizations and blockchains (e.g. DigiByte, Polygon, CasperLabs) are joining the ThreeFold ecosystem, as it is best positioned to efficiently and truly decentralize the web through its advanced technology stack.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;token&quot;&gt;TFT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is the official currency of ThreeFold, with each token representing a unit of reservation of capacity (storage and compute) on the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;farming&#x2F;tech&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-time-to-get-tft-is-now&quot;&gt;The time to get TFT is now!&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With TFT, developers and enterprises can reserve compute and storage to build any IT workload and application on the ThreeFold Grid.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Now is the best time for anyone to join ThreeFold’s decentralization movement, as we’re on the verge of releasing the next generation Internet and Cloud to mainnet, through a sequence of events starting next month.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;making-it-easier-to-get-tft&quot;&gt;Making it easier to get TFT&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;tft-is-now-live-on-pancakeswap&quot;&gt;TFT is now live on PancakeSwap&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BSC dApp and DeFi ecosystem has grown significantly over the last few months. In April, it was reported that BSC held up to 9 million transactions per day, outperforming Ethereum’s with (under) 2 million. Further, we have witnessed ongoing innovation in this particular environment, with multiple DeFi, Yield Farming, NFT applications, and other dApps leveraging the Binance Smart Chain and its cost-effective transactions. BSC is making DeFi applications more inclusive and accessible for people around the globe.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Beyond just making TFT more accessible, ThreeFold integrated with Binance Smart Chain to empower BSC developers with its decentralized storage and compute infrastructure. They can now benefit from ThreeFold’s peer-to-peer nature and autonomous IT, with more security, efficiency, cost-effectiveness, sustainability, and decentralization benefits.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
PancakeSwap has become the top Automated Market Maker (AMM) and Decentralized Exchange (DEX) on BSC. Multiple people in the ThreeFold community have requested to have the ability to leverage PancakeSwap’s platform – to easily swap other BSC tokens for TFT, and to utilize its yield farming and other functionalities.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;ultimately-the-bsc-integration-brings-forward-two-major-opportunities&quot;&gt;Ultimately, the BSC integration brings forward two major opportunities:&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It makes TFT more widely accessible, via one of the top smart chains in the world
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Find out how to get TFT on PancakeSwap &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;threefold__tft_binance_defi?id=how-to-get-tft-on-pancakeswap&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s fully inclusive – anybody can now provide liquidity for TFT currency pairs
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Find out how to become a TFT Liquidity Provider on PancakeSwap &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;threefold__liquidity_provider&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We believe in these key advantages of DeFi, where market making and providing liquidity are now decentralized to the people, and not owned or controlled by the few.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;quick-access-to-binance-smart-chain&quot;&gt;Quick Access to Binance Smart Chain&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who have experience with Binance Smart Chain, TFT can be exchanged on BSC via the following contract address: 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;0x8f0fb159380176d324542b3a7933f0c2fd0c2bbf&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; (direct link &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;exchange.pancakeswap.finance&#x2F;#&#x2F;swap?outputCurrency=0x8f0fb159380176d324542b3a7933f0c2fd0c2bbf&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;)
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please note it is very important to use the official contract address (above) and not any other address you may find elsewhere. For your own protection, please do not use contract addresses from unverified sources.​​​​​​&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-btc-tft-integration-on-the-threefold-connect-app&quot;&gt;A BTC-TFT integration on the ThreeFold Connect app&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold Connect (available on the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;apps.apple.com&#x2F;us&#x2F;app&#x2F;threefold-connect&#x2F;id1459845885&quot;&gt;App Store&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;play.google.com&#x2F;store&#x2F;apps&#x2F;details?id=org.jimber.threebotlogin&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;gl=US&quot;&gt;Google Play&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; has long been a way for people to store their TFT. Now, anyone can buy TFT with BTC directly from the app itself. Learn how to buy TFT with BTC &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;threefold__threefold_connect_btc&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The PancakeSwap listing and the BTC integration into the ThreeFold Connect Wallet both aim to make it easier to get TFT for people around the world. We will continue these types of efforts as we go, in the spirit of inclusion and participation in the peer-to-peer Internet.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;With any questions, please head to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&quot;&gt;our forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;our two-way chat&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Update on the Binance Smart Chain Integration</title>
		<published>2021-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/05/post-5/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/05/post-5/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last week we announced our plan to make the ThreeFold Token more accessible through multichain integrations – with Binance Smart Chain up first!
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Today we are happy to update that the BSC integration is going just as planned and next week, TFT will be available there.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Please note that our next announcement will include the official contract address and the pair contract. If you don’t see it from us, it’s not authentic.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
We can’t wait for this integration to be live and to share the good news and details with you, our beautiful community. Thanks for your support!
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;If you have questions, please be reminded of &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;our two-way chat&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;our forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Dragonchain and ThreeFold Announce Collaboration</title>
		<published>2021-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/05/post-03/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/05/post-03/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dragonchain and ThreeFold share a common mission of providing developers and the digital world with a more inclusive and decentralized Internet infrastructure – one where data flows and is stored in a peer-to-peer environment, and where applications are computed by decentralized and community-owned protocols.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Today, Dragonchain and ThreeFold are proud to announce their partnership to further empower developers and enterprises around the world to build scalable dApps on Dragonchain, on ThreeFold’s peer-to-peer cloud.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold presents a more cost-effective, distributed, autonomous, secure, and sustainable alternative to centralized cloud-providers. Now, developers and enterprises building Web3 applications can leverage and deploy Dragonchain’s Blockchain and advanced smart-contracts into their dApps, with the added benefit of utilizing ThreeFold to completely decentralize their cloud computing infrastructure – and deploy their solutions on the edge.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold’s peer-to-peer environment combined with the Dragonchain ecosystem gives communities the ability to build their online presence without worrying about censorship over dissenting opinions, local outages, or unauthorized access to data.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
“It has alway been our belief that developers should have the freedom to build without restraint. We’re happy to partner with ThreeFold to provide the tools necessary to easily build applications for a decentralized environment,” Joe Roets, Chief Architect, Founder, CEO at Dragonchain.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Together, Dragonchain and ThreeFold are decreasing friction and opening more avenues for inclusion. The Dragonchain platform contains sophisticated and lightweight SDKs and enables enterprises to use their existing IT staff to deploy code in any coding language. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Further, the Dragonchain developer community can now build Web3-native and P2P cloud-native applications without the need for prior Blockchain experience. Developers now have access to scalable industry-standard solutions like Docker, Kubernetes, S3 storage – and ThreeFold’s Quantum Safe Filesystem – to build applications for a decentralized environment. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
As stated by Weynand Kuijipers, co-founder at ThreeFold, “dApps need to live outside the market-leading monopolies and we are proud to be able to provide secure, private and sovereign compute and storage capacity for the Dragonchain community.“
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Both ThreeFold and Dragonchain invite and support any and all Web2 and Web3 developers to build decentralized applications that have the potential to change the world and make it a better and more inclusive place for us all.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-dragonchain&quot;&gt;About Dragonchain&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dragonchain is a technology leader in the blockchain space, with security and scalability at the forefront of its operations. We are proudly U.S.-based and part of one of the most technologically rich communities in the country. We help companies break into blockchain faster, without forcing them to change their existing IT infrastructure. As a Blockchain as a Service provider built by seasoned members of the tech industry, Dragonchain understands the needs of enterprises and is designed to handle prevalent issues in several industries. Learn more at &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dragonchain.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Dragonchain.com&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Be sure to stay up to date on the latest at &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;dragonchaingang&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.linkedin.com&#x2F;company&#x2F;dragonchain&#x2F;&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;dragontalk&quot;&gt;Telegram&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;c&#x2F;DragonchainOfficial&quot;&gt;YouTube&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;dragonchain-inc&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-threefold&quot;&gt;About ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold is developing a peer-to-peer Internet platform that aims to liberalize what it labels as a centralized and unequally distributed Internet. Its platform, called the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;threefold__grid_home&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, comprises over +600 servers in 25+ different countries around the world, delivering approximately 80 PB in storage and over 16,000 CPU cores worldwide, making it the largest storage and compute peer-to-peer Internet network in the world. See ThreeFold Grid’s statistics in more detail using their explorer &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;explorer.threefold.io&#x2F;all&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each server runs ThreeFold’s stateless and lightweight open-source operating system, Zero-OS, and is set up and operated by independent individuals and organizations called Farmers. Farmers earn rewards in &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;threefold__token_home&quot;&gt;TFT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; - the platform’s native token - for their participation. TFT is the currency of the ThreeFold Grid, with each token representing a unit of storage and compute on the platform. Grid users can use these tokens to reserve the storage and compute they need to store, build and share on the platform’s internet network.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold’s ultimate vision is to be part of the movement to fully democratize the Internet worldwide. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&quot;&gt;threeFold.io&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to learn more, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&quot;&gt;forum.threefold.io&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to chat with the team, or stay updated &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldnews&quot;&gt;on Telegram&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Announces Plans to go Multichain</title>
		<published>2021-04-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-04-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/04/post-29/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/04/post-29/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peer-to-Peer Internet ThreeFold Goes Multichain to Accelerate Token Accessibility&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;ThreeFold is set to integrate BSC in the next couple of weeks, with Ethereum and Huobi’s ECO Chain following in Q2.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;This will allow ThreeFold to be more accessible to the DeFi world and provide ThreeFold Farmers and users with more platforms to exchange TFT.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;threefold_io&#x2F;status&#x2F;1387762711417786368&quot;&gt;Our tweet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;bitcoinist.com&#x2F;peer-to-peer-internet-threefold-goes-multichain-to-accelerate-token-accessibility&#x2F;&quot;&gt;the full release&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- TODO: Add Tags and Categories --&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Building a Better Solution for Our Planet</title>
		<published>2021-04-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-04-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/04/post-23/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/04/post-23/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today’s Internet consumes approximately 10% of the world’s energy. This is not acceptable.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
So, how to fix this? Start from scratch. Attack the root problems. Build a new infrastructure. Go peer-to-peer. Reduce complexity. Improve efficiency. Work with like-minded partners. &lt;em&gt;No one is taking this approach, apart from ThreeFold.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Learn more about how &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;for_our_planet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ThreeFold is building a better solution&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; for our 🌎.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
And read about &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;why&quot;&gt;our why&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Big update to share in the coming weeks about how ThreeFold is pushing even further in this direction!
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;We commend all projects and individuals out there working to provide more sustainable solutions and systems for the planet.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; 🙏&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Say Hello to the Dispersed Storage</title>
		<published>2021-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/04/post-20/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/04/post-20/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In most distributed systems, data is stored multiple times to guarantee redundancy. This leads to a lot of unnecessary overhead and is also not the most secure mechanism.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Meet &lt;strong&gt;the dispersed storage algorithm&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; – a crucial part of our storage system – which breaks data down into equations that are spread across nodes, leading to increased security, reliability, and efficiency, with much lower overhead.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Read more about the dispersed storage algorithm &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold&#x2F;#&#x2F;threefold__part5_ultra_efficient_storage?id=the-space-algorithm-of-storage&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, which might also explain the image choice. 🛸&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Be the Internet – Become a Farmer!</title>
		<published>2021-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/04/post-18/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/04/post-18/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Now, you can &lt;strong&gt;BE THE INTERNET&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; by becoming a ThreeFold Farmer.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;Br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Electricity + Network + a 3Node&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; = All that you need in order to grow the grid from your home or office – and earn TFT. Provide new capacity on a secure, private, scalable, and sustainable peer-to-peer Internet!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;✅ &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;farm&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Pre-Register today for your 3Node&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📚 &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;threefold__farming_intro&quot;&gt;Learn more about ThreeFold Farming&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold x CasperLabs Community Call Recording</title>
		<published>2021-04-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-04-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/04/post-16/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/04/post-16/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold Highlights at &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;youtu.be&#x2F;WYrARTeY3cY?t=863&quot;&gt;14:23&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and in the Q&amp;amp;A session at &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;youtu.be&#x2F;WYrARTeY3cY?t=2330&quot;&gt;38:50&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks again to the team at Casper for having us on. Looking forward to sharing more about where this partnership is going soon!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Join the ThreeFold Two-Way Chat</title>
		<published>2021-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/04/post-14/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/04/post-14/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We’ve opened up a two-way chat on Telegram&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; for the ThreeFold community! 🌍
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can join &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; – see you there!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;✅ &lt;em&gt;Be kind and respectful of other members. Keep discussions to the grid, its use cases, the tech, farming, deploying, etc.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚫 &lt;em&gt;No token price discussion, speculation, shilling nor hyping. No impersonation of any members or admins. No referral links, spamming, nor advertising (including in username)&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Joins CasperLabs Community Call</title>
		<published>2021-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/04/post-13/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/04/post-13/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Today at 6pm CET &#x2F; 12pm EST,&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; ThreeFold co-founder Kristof de Siegeleer will be joining the Casper community call to introduce ThreeFold to the Casper community and to discuss our collaboration.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The call will be hosted &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=WYrARTeY3cY&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; We hope to see you there. 🙏
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kristof will be joining Ralf Kubli (Casper Association), Medha Parlikar (CTO, CasperLabs), Ashok Ranadive (Director, Pro Services, CasperLabs), and Piotr Dziubecki (Technical Project Manager, CasperLabs).&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Grid 2.7 is Live on Testnet</title>
		<published>2021-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/04/post-12/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/04/post-12/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, that was fast! 👀
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week we announced Grid 2.6 live on testnet, and a week later here &lt;strong&gt;we are announcing Grid 2.7!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find the full release notes &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;info&#x2F;cloud#&#x2F;cloud__release_notes_2_7_0&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We’re also working on a major mainnet upgrade. Stay tuned for more news on that!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As a reminder for active cloud users, please always be sure to back up your workloads before moving to the next upgrade.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And as always, you can join our testing group &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;bit.ly&#x2F;tftesting&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Dive Into the ThreeFold Universe</title>
		<published>2021-04-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-04-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/04/post-10/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/04/post-10/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dive into &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&quot;&gt;threefold.io&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and explore the expanding ThreeFold universe!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;👩‍🌾 &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;farming&quot;&gt;Be The Internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;: Become a ThreeFold Farmer&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;☁️ Test on the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;cloud&quot;&gt;P2P Cloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🛒 Be empowered with the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;marketplace&quot;&gt;P2P Marketplace&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🤝 Learn about our wide array of &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;partners&quot;&gt;amazing partners&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🔄 Get Involved w. &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;token&quot;&gt;TFT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;: The currency of the P2P Internet
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;There are many ways to participate in the project. If you need support, please click the blue chat icon on any of our websites – and with questions or conversations, head to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;the forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Thank you for being a part of the ThreeFold movement! 🙏&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>CasperLabs and ThreeFold Join Forces</title>
		<published>2021-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/04/post-7/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/04/post-7/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;CasperLabs and ThreeFold have a shared belief that decentralization is needed in order to build a better tomorrow. According to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;casperlabs.io&#x2F;en&#x2F;company&quot;&gt;CasperLabs&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, decentralization is “how we will create more open, transparent, permissionless networks powered by people — paving the way for a new era of equitable innovation.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Today, ThreeFold is thrilled to announce a collaborative partnership with CasperLabs. Together, we will further CasperLabs’ decentralization efforts while accelerating a collective mission and vision of more equally distributing global wealth and resources – doing so through creating more opportunity for people and enterprises around the world, without limits.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“ThreeFold and CasperLabs share a commitment to making web3 environments more accessible to all developers,” says Neil Kapoor of CasperLabs. “Now that Casper is live on mainnet, we look forward to collaborating with ThreeFold to deliver a truly scalable, secure and decentralized IT infrastructure for enterprise organizations building innovative, blockchain-based solutions.”&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through the partnership, developers and enterprises building on top of Casper technology will be able to choose to run on ThreeFold’s &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;cloud&quot;&gt;Peer-to-Peer Cloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for storage and compute resources. This will enable them to achieve security and scalability beyond what the centralized cloud providers can offer today.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
On a smaller scale, anyone will be able to contribute to Casper’s blockchain security, resiliency, scalability and decentralization, by deploying a Casper Validator node on the ThreeFold Grid in just a few clicks. The ThreeFold deployment mechanism removes all technical complexity of running Blockchain nodes.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;From ThreeFold co-founder Adnan Fatayerji, “We are extremely excited about our partnership with CasperLabs. Their platform is designed with simplicity and scale to drive global adoption amongst enterprises and developers. ThreeFold fits perfectly as a decentralized substrate (storage and compute) to provide all Casper customers with a truly decentralized, secure, and scalable alternative to current cloud providers.”&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-casperlabs&quot;&gt;About CasperLabs&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CasperLabs, the developer of the Casper Network, provides professional services and support for organizations building on the Casper Network. Guided by open source principles, CasperLabs is committed to supporting the next wave of blockchain adoption among businesses and providing developers with a reliable and secure framework to build private, public and hybrid blockchain applications. Its team possesses deep enterprise technology experience, hailing from organizations including Google, Adobe, AWS, Dropbox and Microsoft.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
CasperLabs recently held a successful token sale on CoinList and announced its mainnet launch.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more, visit &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;casperlabs.io&quot;&gt;casperlabs.io&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-threefold&quot;&gt;About ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold has developed the largest and most advanced peer-to-peer internet grid in the world, which enables individuals and organizations to build and deploy their web2 and web3 applications in a complete decentralized, private, sustainable, and autonomous IT infrastructure through its peer-to-peer cloud capacity and developer tools.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
With a collective and incentivized ecosystem of Farmers around the globe, the ThreeFold Grid has achieved 80+ petabytes of capacity, 18K+ CPU cores, distributed in 21 countries, and is constantly expanding across the edges. ThreeFold has technology partners such as HPE, DigiByte, Stellar, CasperLabs, Neo, Dash, TomoChain, HoloChain Harmony, WaykiChain, SelfKey and many others.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold aims to empower a more equal, autonomous, and sustainable world and does so by providing the necessary peer-to-peer technologies and infrastructure to the world while incentivizing growth in developing regions.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&quot;&gt;threeFold.io&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to learn more, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&quot;&gt;forum.threefold.io&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to chat with the team, or stay updated &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldnews&quot;&gt;on Telegram&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Grid 2.6 is Live on Testnet</title>
		<published>2021-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/04/post-5/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/04/post-5/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What you’ll find in this exciting release (live on testnet): Updates to the eVDC, 3Bot SDK, Quantum Safe Filesystem, Zero-OS, and Digital Twin!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find the &lt;strong&gt;full release notes &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;info&#x2F;cloud#&#x2F;cloud__release_notes_2_6_0&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Join &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;bit.ly&#x2F;tftesting&quot;&gt;our testing community&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, now up to more than 160 members!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Q1 Highlights</title>
		<published>2021-04-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-04-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/04/post-02/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/04/post-02/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here’s a quick look at the first three months of 2021 for ThreeFold:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
🚀 The TF Grid technology made huge steps forward (v2.4, v2.5, eVDC, QSFS, Marketplace, &amp;amp; more)
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
👯‍♀️ Our digital avatar called Digital Twin nears testing phase
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
✅ 3Node Pre-Order Batch 1 of 2021 has closed (welcome, new farmers!)
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find the full update &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;threefold__q12021recap&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, with more details.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold on Corporate Unplugged Podcast</title>
		<published>2021-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/03/post-16/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/03/post-16/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Listen to ThreeFold co-founder Kristof de Spiegeleer &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;corporateunplugged.com&#x2F;kristof-de-spiegeleer&#x2F;&quot;&gt;on the Corporate Unplugged podcast&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Corporate Unplugged puts the light on impact makers in business, with past guests such as Simon Sinek &amp;amp; Seth Godin.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>We&#x27;re Tackling Internet Inequalities</title>
		<published>2021-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/03/post-14/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/03/post-14/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Let’s build an Internet for all, together.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Did you know?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold incentivizes the expansion of the ThreeFold Grid in developing regions. 🌏🌍
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We are partnering with Solidaridad to create fair supply chain and fair data for farmers around the world, particularly in the Global South. ✅
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
And we are partnering with Take Action Global to build an educational tool based on Digital Twin technology that will allow children around the world to learn and collaborate in a secure environment. ✏️📖&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Join Our Forum!</title>
		<published>2021-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/03/post-9/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/03/post-9/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is the place for conversations all about ThreeFold.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;Br&#x2F;&gt;
Some example topics:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;farming-faq-and-some-answers&#x2F;555&quot;&gt;Farming FAQs &amp;amp; Answers&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;how-is-threefold-better-for-the-customer-than-amazon-cloud-or-google-cloud&#x2F;703&quot;&gt;TF vs Centralized Cloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;your-wishlist-threefold-partners&#x2F;682&quot;&gt;Partner Wishlist&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We&#x27;ll see you over there! 👋
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To participate, you’ll first need to download ThreeFold Connect, a multi-purpose app which serves as an authenticator, news channel, wallet, &amp;amp; support platform.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;apps.apple.com&#x2F;us&#x2F;app&#x2F;threefold-connect&#x2F;id1459845885&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Connect | App Store&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;play.google.com&#x2F;store&#x2F;apps&#x2F;details?id=org.jimber.threebotlogin&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;gl=US&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Connect | Google Play&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Digital Twin v1 is Coming!</title>
		<published>2021-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/02/post-19/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/02/post-19/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recreate your digital life with Digital Twin.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; Where only you own your data, and no one else.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The first version of Digital Twin is coming soon and will bring private and secure messaging and video calling. After that, we’ll bring you a way to store your files – and much more.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold x Conscious Communities</title>
		<published>2021-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/02/post-12/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/02/post-12/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We’re in talks with an already-live, large-scale “conscious community” project to create their own independent grid of capacity!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Each home and business property would have its own node or nodes, and capacity would be used for a community-specific platform to improve communication, participation, and ease of life for residents – all in a fully private, secure, &amp;amp; efficient way.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We’re still in the early stages but we’re thrilled to have met this team and to be working towards a partnership that can be an incredible model for many other communities around the world. We will share more as we are able to!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Great Results on Grid 2.4 Testing!</title>
		<published>2021-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/02/post-10/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/02/post-10/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;strong&gt;TF Grid 2.4&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; has now been on testnet for over a month and we are getting good test results – but we need more!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need &lt;strong&gt;more &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;joinchat&#x2F;BwOvOxxgK59GmRoZ2_sM0w&quot;&gt;people who want to test&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, and we need more farmers who are willing to upgrade to the 2.4 (soon 2.5) release and make additional capacity available towards the community.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Anyone who is interested to contribute in writing tests or executing on tests is more than welcome – the more exposure we get, the faster our TF Grid will be usable for a more general audience!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For &lt;strong&gt;an update&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; on progress on &#x2F; features of Grid 2.4, 2.5, &amp;amp; 3.0, please &lt;strong&gt;click &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;grid242530update&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Seeking participation with the TFT plan</title>
		<published>2021-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/02/post-03/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/02/post-03/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We have a good plan in place to stimulate token growth but we have some key decisions to make &amp;amp; we are creating a group to help us finalize. We have already invited &#x2F; included a number of farmers, token holders, ambassadors, and outside industry experts – and now we want to open it up to the wider community.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
If you’re interested in being a part of this guidance committee, please get in touch with @samtaggart on Telegram and he will ask some questions to ensure we get a well-rounded group of people.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Please reply by the end of today 6pm CET, if you’d like to be a part. A call will be scheduled for Friday or Saturday.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Please take note of a few things:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The plan WILL be with the best interest for the long-term growth of the token&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The plan WILL be in the best interest of farmers and token holders&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The plan WILL be in line with our values&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
As a reminder, please know that neither Sam nor any member of the ThreeFold team will ever reach out to you requesting TFT or any other form of currency. 🙏
&lt;p&gt;If you are skeptical about any interaction or need support, please use the live chat function on our website.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Grid 2.4 is coming to mainnet soon!</title>
		<published>2021-02-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-02-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/02/post-2/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/02/post-2/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hi all – we are pleased to share that we are in the final stages of testing Grid 2.4. We have found eVDC, 3Bot SDK, and Marketplace solution deployment &amp;amp; payment to be quite stable.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In the coming days we will have an exact date for mainnet launch and some more details for you to get started on our most exciting release to date!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a reminder, feel free to join our testing community &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;joinchat&#x2F;TSI25Ee-RcQaOmieYJ9Yyg&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Join the Conversation - The Cyber Pandemic is Here</title>
		<published>2021-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/01/post-28/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/01/post-28/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The cyber pandemic is here, but it’s not too late!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Join in on an important discussion next Wednesday with ThreeFold founder, Kristof De Spiegeleer.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Registration: &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;swiss-social.com&#x2F;events&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Related links:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=oe3y-OdNSsw&quot;&gt;The Cyberpandemic has begun&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.interpol.int&#x2F;en&#x2F;News-and-Events&#x2F;News&#x2F;2020&#x2F;INTERPOL-report-shows-alarming-rate-of-cyberattacks-during-COVID-19&quot;&gt;INTERPOL report on COVID-19 cyberattacks&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.gcsp.ch&#x2F;global-insights&#x2F;why-cybersecurity-matters-more-ever-during-coronavirus-pandemic&quot;&gt;Why cybersecurity matters more than ever&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>A 2020 Rewind &amp; Grid 2.4 News!</title>
		<published>2021-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/01/post-12/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/01/post-12/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hi all, we hope your 2021 has been off to a fabulous start!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Grid 2.4 is now live on testnet (and you can start testing tomorrow). This update makes it very simple for people to get started and to feel the power of what the grid can bring.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about the 2.4 update AND catch our 2020 highlights &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;grid24_and_2020&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join our testing community &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;joinchat&#x2F;TSI25Ee-RcQaOmieYJ9Yyg&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Happy Holidays!</title>
		<published>2020-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/12/post-05/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/12/post-05/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;That’s it! :) Soon, we’ll share some highlights from 2020 and some words about 2021.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Get to know TF Meet</title>
		<published>2020-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/12/post-04/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/12/post-04/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Watch &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=C7BH_o9JbW0&amp;amp;t=815s&quot;&gt;the live demo&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ThreeFold Meet ensures end-to-end connection between parties rather than inefficiently going through centralized servers which may be far away and lacking in privacy and security.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Product Demos Are a Must Watch!</title>
		<published>2020-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/12/post-03/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/12/post-03/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Demos of the latest &amp;amp; greatest ThreeFold products &amp;amp; solutions – P2P Video Conferencing, File Browser, 0-DB Filesystem, Edge Virtual Data Center, &amp;amp; more – some of which are available today &amp;amp; some coming soon on testnet.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here is the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;youtu.be&#x2F;C7BH_o9JbW0&quot;&gt;full video&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In the description, you can find timestamps to guide you through, although we recommend watching the entire call.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: This is a recording of an internal team demo from yesterday that we decided to share with the community. We will have more details next week! Enjoy!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Take a look at the Artheon VR Museum!</title>
		<published>2020-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/12/post-02/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/12/post-02/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Artheon Virtual Reality Museum&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; allows visitors to explore and interact with hundreds of thousands of pieces of fine art, with or without a VR headset!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a tour &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=Ofk22N2Ew1k&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Artheon will soon be hosted on top of the ThreeFold Grid, serviced by &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.green-edge.net&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Green Edge&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For early access and information, please join the Artheon Telegram group &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;artheon&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold&#x27;s November 2020 community update</title>
		<published>2020-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/11/post-09/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/11/post-09/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Read about &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;bit.ly&#x2F;tfnov2020update&quot;&gt;what happened&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in the ThreeFold universe this month.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold and Presearch partner to decentralize search nodes and storage</title>
		<published>2020-11-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-11-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/11/post-08/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/11/post-08/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Privacy and decentralization are some of the values shared by both &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.presearch.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Presearch&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&quot;&gt;ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, at the core of their missions to create scalable technologies that can positively impact the lives of millions of individuals and enterprises around the globe.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Presearch and ThreeFold are thrilled to officially announce their collaborative partnership. Presearch is &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;presearch.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;a community-powered, decentralized search engine&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that provides better results while protecting your privacy and rewarding you when you search. And ThreeFold is the world’s largest peer-to-peer cloud, bringing privacy and security, cost-efficiencies, ease-of-use, and true IT decentralization to the market.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Presearch (and its node and storage infrastructure) will benefit from ThreeFold’s peer-to-peer cloud in two different ways:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-powering-presearch-node-operators-with-a-decentralized-cloud-infrastructure&quot;&gt;1. Powering Presearch node operators with a decentralized cloud infrastructure&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Presearch community will be able to deploy their Presearch nodes in a few clicks in a completely decentralized cloud infrastructure, using the ThreeFold peer-to-peer cloud and its developer tools. Thus, they can escape the monopolies of centralized cloud providers, and reduce the technical complexity of running Blockchain nodes. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Colin Pape, Presearch’s CEO, said in a statement, “We are excited to partner with the ThreeFold team to offer our community members an easy way to quickly deploy Presearch Nodes on ThreeFold decentralized peer-to-peer internet grid, the world’s largest server network powered by blockchain technology.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Presearch has recently opened its beta testing program for node operators looking to become part of the revolutionary network that is changing the way individuals around the world can search the web – in a significantly more private, inclusive, and rewarding environment. Anyone who believes in the decentralization of search engines should &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;presearchcommunity.typeform.com&#x2F;to&#x2F;UkDumktm&quot;&gt;sign up to their beta testers list&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and get in touch with Presearch to be one of the early adopters. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-leveraging-threefold-s-decentralized-storage-to-store-the-future-of-the-search-engine-experience&quot;&gt;2. Leveraging ThreeFold’s decentralized storage to store the future of the search engine experience&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presearch and ThreeFold are exploring the usage of ThreeFold’s decentralized storage capacity to store and archive Presearch’s indexes and other data running the search engine. The main goal is to provide an unbreakable data storage and backup infrastructure for the future of the search engine experience that the top-notch team behind Presearch is building.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In addition, ThreeFold looks forward to advocating for Presearch and integrating the decentralized search engine into its current and future solutions for a more private and inclusive internet experience.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;powering-the-threefold-community-s-search-engine-experience-with-presearch&quot;&gt;Powering the ThreeFold community’s search engine experience with Presearch&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold will be establishing Presearch’s decentralized search engine as its main search engine partner, advocating for its usage within its growing community of developers, cloud capacity farmers, enterprises, and users. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
As stated by Weynand Kuijpers, “Presearch is creating a search engine by people for people. The internet has moved from data sharing to centralized data harvesting. Presearch is undoing that by creating user control over data stored, presenting a (digital) return for contributing to the system and improving search results, and making it decentralized. ThreeFold is looking forward to co-creating a decentralized mechanism where the search engine is broken down and operates everywhere, and users are in control of their own identity and data.“
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
More to come as the partnership develops.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-presearch&quot;&gt;About Presearch:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of us are tired of Big Tech companies dominating the internet, censoring content and controlling the social narrative by manipulating information to fit an agenda. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Presearch provides improved access to information and increased search choice with its community-driven search engine that leverages blockchain technology and cryptocurrency to empower and reward users. More than 1.6 million people have already joined the service.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In 2020, Presearch launched its innovative keyword staking sponsorship platform that enables promoters to lock their Presearch PRE cryptocurrency tokens against different keywords in order to have their promotional ads displayed. More than 60 million PRE tokens have already been locked.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Now Presearch is launching a decentralized search engine that rewards node operators with PRE tokens when they run Presearch nodes. Through its partnership with ThreeFold, anyone will be able to easily launch a Presearch node running on the ThreeFold decentralized peer-to-peer internet grid with no technical knowledge required.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Visit &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;presearch.io&quot;&gt;presearch.io&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to learn more or join our Telegram community at &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;presearch&quot;&gt;t.me&#x2F;presearch&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-threefold&quot;&gt;About ThreeFold:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold has developed the largest and most advanced peer-to-peer internet grid in the world, which enables individuals and organizations to build and deploy their web2 and web3 applications in a complete decentralized, private, sustainable, and autonomous IT infrastructure through its peer-to-peer cloud capacity and developer tools.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
With a collective and incentivized ecosystem of Farmers around the globe, the ThreeFold Grid has achieved 80+ petabytes of capacity, 18K+ CPU cores, distributed in 21 countries, and is constantly expanding across the edges. ThreeFold has technology partners such as HPE, DigiByte, Stellar, Neo, Dash, TomoChain, HoloChain Harmony, WaykiChain, SelfKey and many others.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold aims to empower a more equal, autonomous, and sustainable world and does so by providing the necessary peer-to-peer technologies and infrastructure to the world while incentivizing growth in developing regions.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Visit &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&quot;&gt;threeFold.io&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to learn more, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&quot;&gt;forum.threefold.io&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to chat with the team, or stay updated on &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldnews&quot;&gt;Telegram&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>TF Grid 2.3.0 is live!</title>
		<published>2020-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/11/post-07/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/11/post-07/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold Grid 2.3 is LIVE on mainnet!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The release introduces some improvements to the grid’s stability, new features, and testnet resource additions.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;manual.threefold.io&#x2F;#&#x2F;release_notes_2.3.0&quot;&gt;the TF Grid 2.3 official release note&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for more info.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Many thanks to the development team who made this release happen! 👏&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>3Bot Connect renamed to ThreeFold Connect</title>
		<published>2020-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/11/post-06/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/11/post-06/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Quick update!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned as &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;threefold_update_oct2020?id=_3bot-connect-app-updates-coming-in-november&quot;&gt;a preview in our October update&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, 3Bot Connect is now more accurately named ThreeFold Connect across devices.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Note: No action is required, although if you have ThreeFold Connect installed already, you may have to update the app before the name changes on your device.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Sharing the November 2020 AMA recording</title>
		<published>2020-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/11/post-03/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/11/post-03/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Good day, all! ☀️
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
For those who missed the Ask Me Anything on Tuesday evening, you can find the call recording &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=5rxVgwnnFpQ&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Included in the description of the video are:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the timestamps, for easy call navigation &amp;amp;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the presentation that was used during the call.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
With any further questions, please head to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forums.threefold.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;our forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Thanks!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Tech recognized by Deloitte Belgium</title>
		<published>2020-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/11/post-04/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/11/post-04/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to ThreeFold Tech 👏 which was recognized as one of 10 finalists by Deloitte Belgium in its Rising Star competition. ThreeFold Tech is responsible for the technology behind the ThreeFold Grid.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Deloitte will announce the winner on 26 November 2020. 🤞 You can read more about the news &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www2.deloitte.com&#x2F;be&#x2F;en&#x2F;pages&#x2F;technology&#x2F;articles&#x2F;fast50-2020-nominees_press-release.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>November 10 product management highlights</title>
		<published>2020-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/11/post-02/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/11/post-02/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;✨ &lt;strong&gt;New ThreeFold Now Marketplace Solution!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
Video Chat is a Zoom-alternative built on top of the TF Grid. Click &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;marketplace.threefold.io&#x2F;apps&#x2F;video_chat&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to try it out!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
✨ &lt;strong&gt;Testnet 2.3 - Testers WANTED!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
We need your help, dear community, to try our solutions on testnet and give us feedback on your experience. Join the tester group &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;joinchat&#x2F;TSI25Ee-RcQaOmieYJ9Yyg&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; 💪
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
🔥 Try to deploy 3Bot on testnet &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;deploy3bot.testnet.grid.tf&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
🔥 Try to deploy a TF Now solution &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;marketplace.threefold.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
🔥 Manual for deployment &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;sdk&#x2F;#&#x2F;sdk__peer2peer_cloud_intro&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
✨ &lt;strong&gt;Have you seen our new TF Capacity Explorer?&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
We have a new &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;explorer.threefold.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;TF Capacity Explorer site&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; where we showcase ALL nodes from around the world, whether on mainnet, testnet, or devnet. One website for all!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
⚡️ &lt;strong&gt;What’s next?&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
⚡️ &lt;strong&gt;We are gearing up to bring Grid 2.3 to Mainnet!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; 🔥🔥🔥
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
🥘🥘🥘 There are many things cooking in the background, look out for more updates.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>The November 2020 community call recording</title>
		<published>2020-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/11/post-01/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/11/post-01/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For those who missed yesterday’s community call (~30 minutes) or would like to rewatch, you can find the recording &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=KpU7wb2jmyg&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold&#x27;s October 2020 community update is here</title>
		<published>2020-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/10/post-03/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/10/post-03/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s the end of October and a lot has gone on this month – an upgrade to testnet, progress on ThreeFold Now, some notable new team members, and more!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Please find a recap of our October activities &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;threefold_update_oct2020&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&amp;amp; have a great weekend! 🎃&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Announcing the November 2020 community call</title>
		<published>2020-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/10/post-01/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/10/post-01/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mark your calendars!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Next Monday November 2nd at 5pm CET we will host a 30-minute community call to update you on exciting progress and to show you what we’ll be working towards in the coming months. We highly recommend you attend!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The following week we will host an AMA (Ask Me Anything) to answer any questions you might have related or unrelated to the community call.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Call details:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;us02web.zoom.us&#x2F;j&#x2F;89188543322&quot;&gt;Zoom Link&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
Meeting ID: 891 8854 3322
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;calendar.google.com&#x2F;event?action=TEMPLATE&amp;amp;tmeid=NWw4NjQzYnFoZTBpOWhvaDQxZnJuOGNmZXQgdGFnZ2FydHNAaW5jdWJhaWQuY29t&amp;amp;tmsrc=taggarts%40incubaid.com&quot;&gt;Google Calendar Event&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
The room will open 10 minutes prior to the call!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Now Marketplace is coming soon!</title>
		<published>2020-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/10/post-02/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/10/post-02/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold &lt;strong&gt;Now Marketplace&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; is a peer-to-peer alternative to centralized cloud providers, enabling you to deploy independently and keep ownership of your own data. 🙌&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting this November you’ll be able to choose and test the first tools available on Marketplace, such as discourse, gitea, website, and more.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stay tuned!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold partners with SKALE to empower its developer community</title>
		<published>2020-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/08/post-01/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/08/post-01/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;skale.network&#x2F;&quot;&gt;SKALE&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&quot;&gt;ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; are perfectly aligned in their visions to build a truly decentralized internet and a scalable web3 infrastructure. Both focus on creating community-owned and scalable technologies that can positively impact the lives of millions of individuals and enterprises around the globe. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
SKALE and ThreeFold are excited to announce their collaborative partnership that will focus on solving scalability and decentralization limitations faced by Ethereum and Blockchain developers. This collaboration will also empower the SKALE developer community, and web3 developers, with the ThreeFold peer-to-peer cloud, enabling them to:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build highly scalable dApps on Ethereum using SKALE’s elastic Blockchain network.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Completely decentralize their IT infrastructure using ThreeFold’s P2P compute, storage, and networking capacities (providing far more affordability, privacy, and decentralization through its native cloud automation and Smart Contract for IT). 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Adnan Fatayerji, co-founder at ThreeFold said, &lt;em&gt;“SKALE is perfectly positioned to take Ethereum and its dApp developers to the next level while pioneering scaling solutions for the Blockchain industry! ThreeFold and SKALE form such an ideal fit in this regard. By combining SKALE’s modular protocol and ThreeFold’s universal substrate for decentralized storage and compute, developers are able to build highly scalable dApps and deploy workloads that are closer to the source, cost-effective, and easy to manage. We are excited to collaborate with the SKALE ecosystem!“&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The ThreeFold team is inviting node operators around the world to contribute to the SKALE ecosystem by deploying their SKALE validator nodes after Phase 3 Mainnet availability on the ThreeFold Grid and is calling for game-changing, conscious web3 developers to build impactful applications.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;“It’s been exciting to work with the ThreeFolds team as they build their vision for providing node operators with a platform to decentralize their IT infrastructure,”&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; said Christine Perry, VP Solutions Engineering, SKALE Labs. &lt;em&gt;“Not only do we share the mutual goal of a truly decentralized secure, scalable network. SKALE developers will be able use ThreeFold’s peer-to-peer cloud to more easily build highly scalable Ethereum Dapps.”&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-skale&quot;&gt;About SKALE:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SKALE is an elastic blockchain network that gives developers the ability to easily provision highly configurable fully decentralized chains that are instantly compatible with Ethereum. SKALE chains can execute sub-second block times, run up to 2,000 tps per chain, and run full-state smart contracts in addition to decentralized storage, execute Rollups, and machine learning in EVM. The SKALE Network is an open-source project with many contributors including SKALE Labs, Inc. whose offices are in San Francisco, CA, and Kharkiv, Ukraine. The SKALE Network’s supporters include Blockchange, ConsenSys Labs, Hashed, HashKey, Floodgate, Multicoin Capital, Recruit Holdings, Signia VP, and Winklevoss Capital. The SKALE Network is supported by top validators in the world including Blockware, ConsenSys, Chorus One, Dokia, Figment Networks, Hashed, Staked, and StakewithUs, as well as key infrastructure players Bison Trails, Blockdaemon and Ankr. For more information please visit &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.skale.network&quot;&gt;skale.network&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;skalenetwork&quot;&gt;@SkaleNetwork&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on Twitter, and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;skaleofficial&quot;&gt;@skaleofficial&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on telegram.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-threefold&quot;&gt;About ThreeFold:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold has developed the largest and most advanced peer-to-peer internet grid in the world, that enables individuals and organizations  to build and deploy their web2 and web3 applications in a complete decentralized, private, sustainable, and autonomous IT infrastructure through its peer-to-peer cloud capacity and developer tools. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
With a collective and incentivized ecosystem of Farmers around the globe, the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; has achieved 80+ petabytes of capacity, 18K+ CPU cores, distributed in 21 countries, and is constantly expanding across the edges. ThreeFold has a broad array of technology partners such as HPE, DigiByte, Stellar, Neo, Dash, TomoChain,  HoloChain Harmony, WaykiChain, SelfKey  and many others. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold aims to empower a more equal, autonomous, and sustainable world and does so by providing the necessary peer-to-peer technologies and infrastructure to the world while incentivizing growth in developing regions. Visit &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&quot;&gt;Threefold.io&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to learn more, and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&quot;&gt;forum.threefold.io&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to chat with the team. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Dash &amp; Dash NEXT partner with ThreeFold</title>
		<published>2020-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/07/post-01/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/07/post-01/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.dash.org&quot;&gt;Dash&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; &#x2F; &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dashnext.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Dash NEXT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Foundation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; are excited to officially announce their collaboration, effective the end of June 2020.  Dash and ThreeFold are community-driven organizations focused on peer-to-peer solutions that strive for decentralization and the empowerment of humanity.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dash &#x2F; Dash NEXT and ThreeFold will work together on developer projects on the ThreeFold Grid. The Dash developer community, and anyone interested in contributing to the Dash Blockchain, is being invited to use a truly decentralized and  affordable cloud alternative - &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;cloud.threefold.io&quot;&gt;ThreeFold P2P Cloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Developers can now deploy their Dash nodes and IT workloads on the ThreeFold Grid with an autonomous execution via &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;sdk&#x2F;#&#x2F;smart_contract&quot;&gt;Smart Contracts for IT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further, community members are being invited to explore possibilities in using the ThreeFold Grid’s capacity and peer-to-peer cloud for their own personal computing needs and projects. Anyone interested in being a node operator in the Dash Blockchain using the ThreeFold Grid would be highly encouraged to get started in a few steps following this &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;deploy-a-dash-node-in-5-steps-on-the-threefold-grid&#x2F;509&quot;&gt;documentation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Adnan Fatayerji, co-founder at ThreeFold, enthusiastically expressed his excitement working with the Dash developer community, “We are extremely excited about our collaboration with Dash [and Dash NEXT], a global name in decentralized transactions. We look forward to empowering their developer community with access to a global substrate of peer-to-peer storage and compute. Together we will drive financial and Internet inclusion to the edge of the network!”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Dash community and any individual or organization interested in contributing to Dash are now empowered to deploy their Dash MasterNodes and any containerized IT workload using the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;cloud.threefold.io&quot;&gt;ThreeFold P2P Cloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and benefit from  an autonomous execution via &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;sdk&#x2F;#&#x2F;smart_contract&quot;&gt;Smart Contracts for IT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Dash’s community is incentivized to get started with free compute and storage capacities offered by ThreeFold.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Felix Mago, Co-Founder at Dash NEXT shared his enthusiasm around that opportunity: “We are excited to have ThreeFold as a partner as they are enabling us to host Dash Masternodes in a decentralized manner.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;deploy-a-dash-node-in-5-steps-on-the-threefold-grid&#x2F;509&quot;&gt;You can follow this documentation to deploy full Dash nodes and MasterNodes on the ThreeFold grid  in 5 easy steps.&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-dash&quot;&gt;About Dash:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dash is an open source peer-to-peer cryptocurrency with a strong focus on the payments industry. Dash offers a form of money that is portable, inexpensive, divisible and fast. It can be spent securely both online and in-person with only minimal transaction fees. Based on the Bitcoin project, Dash aims to be the most user-friendly and scalable payments system in the world.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to Bitcoin’s feature set, Dash currently also offers instant transactions (&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.dash.org&#x2F;en&#x2F;stable&#x2F;introduction&#x2F;features.html#instantsend&quot;&gt;InstantSend&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;), private transactions (&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.dash.org&#x2F;en&#x2F;stable&#x2F;introduction&#x2F;features.html#privatesend&quot;&gt;PrivateSend&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;) and operates a self-governing and self-funding model that enables the Dash network to pay individuals and businesses for work that adds value to the network. This &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.dash.org&#x2F;en&#x2F;stable&#x2F;governance&#x2F;index.html#governance&quot;&gt;decentralized governance and budgeting system&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; makes it one of the first ever successful decentralized autonomous organizations (DAO).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-threefold&quot;&gt;About ThreeFold:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold has developed the largest and most advanced peer-to-peer Internet grid in the world.  They launched the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;explorer.grid.tf&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; V2.0 in  April 2020 – a  more performant, private &amp;amp; secure, affordable, and sustainable solution than centralized cloud and internet providers. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
With a collective and incentivized ecosystem of Farmers (independent Internet capacity providers) around the globe, the ThreeFold Grid  is now open for developers to build on top of it,  and users can now benefit from all the advantages of the ThreeFold Grid.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The ThreeFold Foundation aims to empower a more equal, autonomous (decentralized) and sustainable world, and does so  by providing the necessary peer-to-peer technologies and infrastructure to the world, while incentivizing growth in developing regions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Why ThreeFold chose Stellar?</title>
		<published>2020-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/06/post-01/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/06/post-01/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;At ThreeFold, together with a beautiful ecosystem of partners, we are co-creating a peer-to-peer Internet that empowers equality, freedom, and sustainability.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
To be honest, we were always focused on building and utilizing &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;threefoldtech&#x2F;rivine&quot;&gt;our own transactional blockchain&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. We wanted to make sure we did it in the right way, upholding our values - but then we realized that the solution was already out there.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Stellar is an open-source network for currencies and payments. Stellar makes it possible to create, send and trade digital representations of all forms of money - dollars, pesos, bitcoin, pretty much anything. It’s designed so all the world’s financial systems can work together on a single network.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Stellar has no owner; if anything it’s owned by the public. The software runs across a decentralized, open network and handles millions of transactions each day. Like Bitcoin and Ethereum, Stellar relies on blockchain to keep the network in sync, but the end-user experience is more like cash - Stellar is much faster, cheaper, and more energy-efficient than typical blockchain-based systems.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In the spirit of collaboration, something we believe in heavily, we knew the right decision was to abandon our own transactional blockchain and to move our ThreeFold Token (TFT) to Stellar.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-did-we-choose-stellar&quot;&gt;Why did we choose Stellar?&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technology-wise it’s a very strong platform - energy-friendly &amp;amp; fast.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is good liquidity on the Stellar Network; it’s super easy to go from XLM to TFT.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By utilizing the Stellar Network, we are part of a large blockchain platform&#x2F;network. There is good integration with other digital currencies.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perhaps most importantly, we share like-minded values.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Stellar Network is supported by the Stellar Development Foundation (SDF). From &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.stellar.org&#x2F;foundation&quot;&gt;their website&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, “SDF and Stellar seek to unlock the world’s economic potential by making money more fluid, markets more open, and people more empowered.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The ThreeFold and Stellar Foundations have very aligned goals, particularly around empowerment of all people around the world - to create equal access to the Internet and to a global, inclusive financial system. Both solutions are built on open-source technology, both aim to unlock the world’s economic potential, and most of all, both empower people in developing countries and all around the globe.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
That is why ThreeFold is proud to be a part of the Stellar Network.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Harmony Integrates with ThreeFold’s Decentralized Grid</title>
		<published>2020-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/05/post-04/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/05/post-04/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;harmony-and-the-threefold-foundation-are-aligned-in-their-focus-on-empowering-an-equal-and-fair-world-doing-good-for-the-planet-and-humanity-is-at-the-core-of-both-organizations-dna-today-harmony-and-threefold-are-pleased-to-officially-announce-their-collaborative-partnership-harmony-and-threefold-will-work-together-on-developer-and-user-projects-on-the-threefold-grid-and-pangaea-harmony-s-developer-community-and-anyone-interested-in-contributing-to-their-blockchain-and-being-a-validator-within-the-harmony-staking-ecosystem-is-being-invited-to-use-a-more-decentralized-performant-and-affordable-peer-to-peer-cloud-solution-brought-by-threefold-developers-can-now-deploy-their-nodes-and-any-it-workloads-on-pangaea-and-the-threefold-grid-with-an-autonomous-execution-via-smart-contracts-for-it-anyone-interested-in-being-a-node-operator-as-a-validator-in-the-harmony-blockchain-using-the-threefold-grid-is-invited-to-get-started-in-a-few-steps-following-this-documentation-from-threefold-co-founder-adnan-fatayerji-we-re-super-excited-about-our-partnership-with-harmony-their-approach-to-decentralization-of-applications-and-transactions-perfectly-couples-with-our-approach-of-trying-to-bring-an-inclusive-internet-together-we-will-form-a-big-powerhouse-for-positive-change-in-this-world-threefold-and-harmony-look-forward-to-the-further-development-of-this-collaboration&quot;&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.harmony.one&quot;&gt;Harmony&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Foundation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; are aligned in their focus on empowering an equal and fair world. Doing good for the planet and humanity is at the core of both organizations’ DNA. Today, Harmony and ThreeFold are pleased to officially announce their collaborative partnership.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Harmony and ThreeFold will work together on developer and user projects on the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;grid_why&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.harmony.one&#x2F;pangaea&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Pangaea&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Harmony’s developer community, and anyone interested in contributing to their Blockchain and being a validator within the Harmony staking ecosystem, is being invited to use a more decentralized, performant and affordable &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cloud.threefold.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Peer-to-Peer Cloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; solution brought by ThreeFold.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Developers can now deploy their nodes and any IT workloads on Pangaea and the ThreeFold Grid with an autonomous execution via &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;sdk&#x2F;#&#x2F;smart_contract&quot;&gt;Smart Contracts for IT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.  Anyone interested in being a node operator, as a validator, in the Harmony Blockchain using the ThreeFold Grid, is invited to get started in a few steps following this &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;setting-up-a-harmony-node-on-the-threefold-grid&#x2F;476&quot;&gt;documentation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
From ThreeFold Co-Founder Adnan Fatayerji,
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;“We’re super excited about our partnership with Harmony. Their approach to decentralization of applications and transactions perfectly couples with our approach of trying to bring an inclusive Internet. Together we will form a big powerhouse for positive change in this world.”&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold and Harmony look forward to the further development of this collaboration.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-harmony&quot;&gt;About Harmony&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.harmony.one&quot;&gt;Harmony&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a fast and open blockchain for decentralized applications. Its protocol has achieved secure and random state sharding, being the first sharded Proof of Stake on production. Harmony’s Mainnet supports thousands of nodes in multiple shards, producing blocks in a few seconds with instant finality. The network’s staking mechanism reduces centralization while supporting stake delegation, reward compounding and double-sign slashing. Harmony aims to build an open network of nodes operated and governed by a large community. Harmony has designed a novel Proof-of-Stake (PoS) mechanism for network security and economics - Effective Proof-of-Stake (EPoS) which reduces centralization and distributes rewards fairly to thousands of validators.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-threefold&quot;&gt;About ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&quot;&gt;ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; has developed the largest and most advanced peer-to-peer Internet grid in the world.  They launched the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;explorer.grid.tf&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; V2.0 in  April 2020 – a  more performant, private &amp;amp; secure, affordable, and sustainable solution than centralized cloud and internet providers. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
With a collective and incentivized ecosystem of Farmers (independent Internet capacity providers) around the globe, ThreeFold Grid - largest peer-to-peer Internet grid on earth, is now open for developers to build on top of it,  and users can now benefit from all the advantages of the ThreeFold Grid.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The ThreeFold Foundation aims to empower a more equal, autonomous, decentralized,  and sustainable internet and does so  by providing the necessary peer-to-peer technologies and infrastructure to individuals and creators, while incentivizing growth in developing regions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold &amp; WaykiChain collaborate to decentralize cloud computing</title>
		<published>2020-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/05/post-03/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/05/post-03/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, ThreeFold and WaykiChain are pleased to officially announce their collaborative partnership. Both ThreeFold and WaykiChain found clear alignment on decentralizing the internet for people and businesses and share the same core values that encompass their respective visions. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Through this collaboration, the WaykiChain developer community will be enabled to deploy and maintain their nodes and any of their IT Workloads using the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;cloud.threefold.io&quot;&gt;Threefold P2P Cloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. This will empower them to decentralize their cloud-computing infrastructures, with far more affordability, and distribution compared to centralized cloud-providers,  and with native cloud automation via ThreeFold’s &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;sdk&#x2F;#&#x2F;smart_contract&quot;&gt;Smart contract for IT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The ThreeFold team invites blockchain enthusiasts, developers, and anyone interested in being part of WaykiChain community to deploy a mainnet node, or to explore building a Dapp on top of WayKiChain.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-waykichain&quot;&gt;About WaykiChain:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WaykiChain is a prominent blockchain platform based in China with a global community,  it is a DPoS ( Delegated proof of stake)  public blockchain that is highly scalable and with high-performance transaction processing capabilities (TPS 3300), with an efficient consensus mechanism.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
WaykiChain has a variety of product lines, with the WaykiChain core wallet, the WaykiTimes and their DeFi-vertical technologies that are built within the core layer of blockchain, i.e. the  crypto-asset backed &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cdp.waykichain.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;stablecoin technology&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as well as its &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dex.waykichain.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;built-in decentralized exchange&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
According to WaykiChain’s core team the upcoming 3.0 release of WaykiChain will support WASM virtual machine technology for smart contract development and deployment. Waykichain’s blockchain enables developers to build performing dApps on top of it using its developer tools, and has throughout these 3 years, built &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dapp.review&#x2F;explore&#x2F;wicc&quot;&gt;an extended ecosystem of Dapps&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-threefold&quot;&gt;About ThreeFold:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&quot;&gt;ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; has developed the largest and most advanced peer-to-peer Internet grid in the world.  They launched the ThreeFold Grid V2.0 in  April 2020 – a  more performant, private &amp;amp; secure, affordable, and sustainable solution than centralized cloud and Internet providers. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
With a collective and incentivized ecosystem of Farmers (independent Internet capacity providers) around the globe, the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;explorer.grid.tf&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is now open for developers to build on top of it,  and users can now benefit from all the advantages of using a truly peer-to-peer environment.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The ThreeFold Foundation aims to empower a more equal, autonomous, decentralized, and sustainable internet, and does so by providing the necessary peer-to-peer technologies and infrastructure to the world while incentivizing growth in developing regions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>DigiByte integrates with ThreeFold’s decentralized Grid</title>
		<published>2020-05-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-05-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/05/post-02/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/05/post-02/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;digibytefoundation.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;DigiByte Foundation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Foundation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; are aligned – both focused on values, working towards their visions and missions in creating a truly decentralized, equal, and sustainable world that empowers humanity. Doing good for the planet is at the core of both organizations’ DNA. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Today, DigiByte and ThreeFold are pleased to officially announce their collaborative partnership.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
DigiByte and ThreeFold will work together on developer and user projects on the ThreeFold Grid. The DigiByte developer community, and anyone interested in contributing to the DigiByte Blockchain, is being invited to use a more decentralized and affordable cloud computing capacity. Developers can now deploy their DigiByte nodes and IT workloads on the ThreeFold Grid with an autonomous execution via &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;sdk&#x2F;#&#x2F;smart_contract&quot;&gt;Smart Contracts for IT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Further, community members are also being invited to explore possibilities in using the ThreeFold Grid’s capacity for their own personal computing needs and projects.  Anyone interested in being a node operator in the DigiByte Blockchain using the ThreeFold Grid would be highly encouraged to get started in a few steps following &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;how-to-deploy-a-digibyte-node-with-your-3bot-in-5-steps&#x2F;379&quot;&gt;the documentation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The ThreeFold team is very proud to welcome The DigiByte Foundation to the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;consciousinternet.org&quot;&gt;Conscious Internet Alliance&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; initiative led by ThreeFold, where together with many other planet and human-centric projects, they will collaborate on making our global Internet neutral again. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-digibyte&quot;&gt;About DigiByte:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;digibyte.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;DigiByte&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a rapidly-growing open-source blockchain created in late 2013 and released in early 2014. After 6 years of forward-thinking development, DigiByte has become one of the safest, fastest, longest and most decentralized UTXO blockchain in existence with one of the most active communities in the Crypto and Blockchain space
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The DigiByte Foundation is a volunteer-managed organization that operates in a non-profit way. They protect and promote the true principles of decentralization and empower DigiByte and its community to establish and maintain a sustainable decentralized world. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-threefold&quot;&gt;About ThreeFold:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold has developed the largest and most advanced peer-to-peer Internet grid in the world.  They launched the ThreeFold Grid V2.0 in  April 2020 – a  more performant, private &amp;amp; secure, affordable, and sustainable solution than centralized cloud and internet providers. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
With a collective and incentivized ecosystem of Farmers (independent Internet capacity providers) around the globe, the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;explorer.grid.tf&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;  is now open for developers to build on top of it,  and users can now benefit from all the advantages of the ThreeFold Grid.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The ThreeFold Foundation aims to empower a more equal, autonomous (decentralized) and sustainable world, and does so  by providing the necessary peer-to-peer technologies and infrastructure to the world, while incentivizing growth in developing regions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>TomoChain &amp; ThreeFold are joining forces to decentralize Cloud Computing</title>
		<published>2020-05-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-05-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/05/post-01/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/05/post-01/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This week marks a big step in the history of TomoChain and ThreeFold as both organizations join forces to work towards a common vision of a more sustainable and decentralized world.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;grid_why&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;’s peer-to-peer nature comes with many advantages for blockchains as it truly decentralizes their IT infrastructures and, enabling better performance, security, affordability, and sustainability, as compared to current centralized cloud alternatives.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;tomochain.com&quot;&gt;TomoChain&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; will invite their developer community and anyone interested in contributing to the TomoChain Blockchain, to connect and use the Threefold Grid. By deploying their Masternodes and workloads on the ThreeFold Grid, their developers will benefit from a more decentralized and affordable cloud offering and benefit from the autonomous execution of their workloads via ThreeFold’s &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;sdk&#x2F;#&#x2F;smart_contract&quot;&gt;Smart Contract for IT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone interested in being part of the TomoChain node ecosystem using the ThreeFold Grid would be highly encouraged to get started in a few steps &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;setting-up-a-tomochain-node-in-5-steps&#x2F;389&quot;&gt;following the documentation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, with the recent announcement of TomoChain’s DEX Protocol, TomoX, released, both organizations will also test the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;sdk&#x2F;#&#x2F;intro&quot;&gt;ThreeFold P2P Cloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; solution to enable developers to build DEXs on top of TomoChain using ThreeFold’s truly decentralized IT infrastructure.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-tomochain&quot;&gt;About Tomochain&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TomoChain is a scalable blockchain, powered via Proof-of-Stake Voting consensus and used commercially by companies globally. The TomoChain blockchain and product ecosystem enable the development of high-performance blockchain projects that focus on decentralizing finance. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Their products include (1) a fast &amp;amp; near-zero Fees: 2000 TPS, 2-second block-time, and EVM  compatible, and (2) an array of original features and protocols designed to support speed, privacy, usability, and liquidity needs all in one platform. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
After a successful ICO in 2018, Tomochain experienced an incredible growth last year to become one of the most reputed blockchains of South East Asia, and globally. They now focus on their mission to accelerate the onboarding of millions of users by empowering today’s applications with technology that masks the friction of Blockchain, all while retaining its underlying benefits.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-threefold&quot;&gt;About ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold has developed the largest and most advanced peer-to-peer Internet grid in the world.  They launched the ThreeFold Grid V2.0 in  April 2020 - a  more performant, private &amp;amp; secure, affordable, and sustainable solution than centralized cloud and internet providers. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
With a collective and incentivized ecosystem of Farmers (independent Internet capacity providers) around the globe, the ThreeFold Grid is now open for developers to build on top of it and benefit from all the advantages that comes with it.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The ThreeFold Foundation aims to empower a more equal, autonomous (decentralized) and sustainable world, and does so  by providing the necessary peer-to-peer technologies and infrastructure to the world, while incentivizing growth in developing regions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold partners with Hewlett Packard Enterprise</title>
		<published>2018-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2018-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2018/10/post-01/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2018/10/post-01/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dubai, UAE. Today at GITEX Technology Week, ThreeFold signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MOU) with Hewlett Packard Enterprise (HPE) to cooperate in the CEEMA region on the implementation of a decentralized grid of computing and storage capacity, which enables a neutral, low cost and low energy internet on a global scale.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
HPE provides their clients in the CEEMA region with the option to connect their computing and storage capacity to ThreeFold’s decentralized grid that supports ThreeFold’s mission to provide a Responsible Internet, accessible to all.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
HPE server and storage hardware has been certified to be used on ThreeFold’s Grid and HPE plans to build services to support the growth and usage of ThreeFold’s Grid which is in line with their edge cloud and blockchain strategy.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold launched a Responsible Internet capacity platform (on March 2018) with the support and collaboration from its community, and has already achieved sizable deployments of decentralized internet compute and storage capacity across the globe. ThreeFold’s open source and localized IT capacity encourage developers; as a result of cost and performance efficiencies, to build all types of decentralized applications on its network to promote the expansion of a new digital responsible economy.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
“This is a monumental step towards a new responsible internet and empowering a new digital economy“, Kristof De Spiegeleer, Visionary Co-Founder of ThreeFold.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;“ThreeFold has created one of the smartest Blockchain solutions we have come across”, said Johannes Koch: Vice President and HPE CEEMA Managing Director. “We are excited about our future cooperation”.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-threefold-foundation&quot;&gt;About ThreeFold Foundation:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold is focused on democratizing internet compute and storage capacity to enable a responsible internet for all. Open source software empowers people to create neutral, green and private capacity for people across the globe that’s blockchain driven and 100% decentralized. (threefold.io)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
