<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>ThreeFold - threefold_token</title>
	<subtitle>Our global digital backbone</subtitle>
	<link href="https://www3.threefold.io/tags/threefold-token/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://www3.threefold.io"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2022-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://www3.threefold.io/tags/threefold-token/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Building the Future We Want to Live In – A Four Step Journey</title>
		<published>2022-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/06/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/06/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What started out as an idea for a better Internet about a decade ago has evolved into a global movement that’s building a decentralized, open and inclusive future through &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;internet_of_internets&#x2F;&quot;&gt;the Internet of Internets&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The journey towards our ultimate vision of a better future for all is a big one, but can be divided into four digestible phases: creation, expansion, Web 4 and velocity.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-the-phase-of-creation&quot;&gt;1 The Phase of Creation&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past six years, we’ve been building up an incredible full-stack, open-source, decentralized Internet infrastructure, all from the ground-up. From creating our own decentralized operating system, to building a Quantum Safe Storage System, a complete far edge cloud computing platform and planetary peer-to-peer network all accessible via a unique Smart Contract for IT on the ThreeFold Blockchain, we’re proud to have the most complete edge infrastructure to power the next-generation Internet era. A new world is coming, and our technology has the potential to revolutionize digitization on a global scale, across sectors. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creation phase was about developing the key tech components and an initial deployment of our infrastructure worldwide. The ThreeFold Grid is now live in its third generation and the stack is fully functional. As of today, people from all across the world have connected more than &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;threefold_io&#x2F;status&#x2F;1529903015938998272&quot;&gt;3,000 nodes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; across +78 countries to create the world’s largest decentralized Internet infrastructure, and new capacity is being connected every day.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to fully comprehensive decentralized edge cloud solutions, the ThreeFold ecosystem is also developing a range of applications and experiences across IoT, metaverse, blockchain, DeFi, banking, education and beyond.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The phase of creation is almost complete. The ThreeFold team is currently working on the Digital Twin solution that will allow the ecosystem to tap into Web 4 principles – a paradigm that overcomes the limitations of Web 2 and the inefficiencies of Web 3. By advancing our technology further, ThreeFold will be in a unique position to open new frontiers and support emerging global trends.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-the-phase-of-expansion&quot;&gt;2 The Phase of Expansion&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second phase is all about the growth of the ThreeFold Grid and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;connecting_the_dots&#x2F;&quot;&gt;connecting the dots&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. From individual farmers and farming cooperatives connecting Internet capacity independently to our global network, to building Community Clouds and Regional Internets for countries, various pathways to Grid growth have been established by the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;internet_of_internets&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Internet of Internets&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; concept.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet of Internets will interconnect us all, while providing us with digital sovereignty, privacy and meaningful experiences. It focuses on incentivizing local communities to build their own resilient Community Clouds to support their city, town or village with the foundation to build their decentralized future.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on their geographic proximity, Community Clouds will be able to form Regional Internets. Each Regional Internet will be equipped with their own blockchain, validators and liquidity providers as well as local digital experiences in order to remain independent from the rest of the world. In that sense, whatever would happen to the Internet infrastructure outside of the borders of that region would not affect local connectivity and digital economies. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, Regional Internets will be interconnected by the ThreeFold Hub on a global level to create the Internet of Internets. This model is infinitely scalable. Instead of relying on one global network and blockchain, ThreeFold will allow for many independent and interoperable Internet infrastructures that support local communities with a platform to build their own blockchain, DeFi, metaverse, IoT, eCommerce solutions, and much more. Each layer has its own distinct purpose and enables seamless ecosystem-wide interactions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;paradise_hills&#x2F;&quot;&gt;the Paradise Hills partnership&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as the first proof of concept for Community Clouds and our team working with governments in multiple countries, we’re following the glocal approach of applying the global Internet of Internets concept locally with regional context. With our growing community and ecosystem supporting us, and building new relationships, we’re well set to turn the Internet of Internets into reality in the upcoming years.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The phase of expansion will probably never end. ThreeFold is infinitely scalable, and there are many reasons to continue growing the ThreeFold Grid as it is best positioned to service the emerging demand for edge computing and sovereign Internet infrastructure for decades to come.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-the-phase-of-web-4&quot;&gt;3 The Phase of Web 4&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In parallel with the expansion phase, the rollout of the Web 4 phase is expected to kick off later this year to re-imagine business, governance, finance, education and more in order to provide better alternatives for people, enterprises and governments. Essentially, the Internet of Internets is laying the foundational infrastructure, and Web 4 technology will open a world of new possibilities around peer-to-peer and self-sovereign systems.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Web 4 phase will empower people to become 100% self-sovereign with a range of decentralized alternatives to Facebook, WhatsApp, YouTube, Chrome, Zoom and much more.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A multitude of valuable and meaningful experiences are being built by the ThreeFold ecosystem and partners to empower people with equal chances to learn, create, and thrive in a decentralized digital economy – what we like to call an abundance-based future for humanity.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key to all of this is ThreeFold’s open-source Digital Twin technology. It provides a unique digital identity that can serve as the key to an open, self-sovereign and complete digital future. The Digital Twin technology allows ThreeFold to flip the current centralized client-server model upside down, empowering people to become the masters of their own destiny. No more data being collected by servers and sold to third-parties – you become the center of your digital life. There will be more on Digital Twin and its potential to change everything coming very soon.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with strategic partnerships being formed across the four corners of the globe, the Web 4 phase will support the ThreeFold Foundation’s vision of providing access to a better Internet paradigm to a billion people by 2030.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-the-phase-of-velocity&quot;&gt;4 The Phase of Velocity&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rise of the Internet of Internets and the build-up of powerful experiences on Web 4 technology will bring the ecosystem to its fourth phase – Velocity. At that moment in time, it will be all about utilization, economic growth and the acceleration of our collective vision.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tokens&#x2F;threefold__tokenomics&quot;&gt;ThreeFold tokenomics&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; have been designed to support a decentralized Internet economy that incentivizes participants to host nodes, validate the blockchain and build applications on the ThreeFold Grid. The moment utilization kicks in at a large scale on Web 4, the ThreeFold Ecosystem will be ready to reach millions – and eventually, billions – of users through powerful digital experiences that provide a better alternative than today’s paradigm. As of today, 35% of ThreeFold Token transactions under Proof of Utilization are burned to create a deflationary economy. This will create additional &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tokens&#x2F;threefold__grid_valuation&quot;&gt;value&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for the token ecosystem as it will reduce the circulating supply in relation to the increasing demand for ThreeFold’s infrastructure. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put, the fourth phase will drive significant utilization of the ThreeFold Token and support in positioning it as the Bitcoin for Internet capacity. It will open up a decentralized Internet economy full of opportunities, empowerment and meaningful experiences for people all around the world. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;bringing-abundance-opportunity-to-the-world&quot;&gt;Bringing Abundance &amp;amp; Opportunity to the World&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“A dream you dream alone is only a dream. A dream you dream together is reality.” – John Lennon&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve reached a pivotal moment in the evolution of ThreeFold to support our world in solving some of its greatest challenges. A complete and resilient Internet infrastructure owned by local communities is an essential way to build a circular and participatory economy. Considering that the Internet is the second largest and fastest growing economy in the world, the Internet of Internets represents a foundation for a decentralized and abundant world. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;internet_of_internets&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Internet of Internets&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; model supports ThreeFold in achieving its vision of providing Internet access to more than a billion people worldwide. And we believe that if we work together, we can connect all of humanity responsibly. Driven by our planet-first, people-first philosophy, the ThreeFold movement is shaping the world we want to live in and laying the foundation for an open, inclusive and abundance-based future.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current phase of expansion is vital to turn our vision into reality and to fulfill our mission. Let’s build this world of opportunity and abundance together.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;Join&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; the ThreeFold movement now&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;what_is_farming&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Be&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; the Internet&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Help us &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;realizing_the_promise&#x2F;&quot;&gt;realize our vision&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for a better future&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>May 2022&#x27;s ThreeFold Product Updates</title>
		<published>2022-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/05/post-05/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/05/post-05/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;📣 &lt;strong&gt;May’s ThreeFold Product Updates&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ThreeFold Grid is currently running on V3.0.0 Alpha-5. In case you missed it on our forum, see what the team is working on for V3.0.0 Alpha-6, including updates to Zero OS, the Playground, the Wallet, Planetary Network, TF Chain, and the Get TFT Platform.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dive into &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-product-updates-tfgrid-v3-a-6-plan-may-2022&#x2F;2808?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;the full update&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Big thanks, as always, to the team for their continuous efforts to enhance and optimize the grid and grid services!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Planting the Seeds: ThreeFold&#x27;s Plans to Regenerate the Planet</title>
		<published>2022-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/05/post-2/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/05/post-2/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘Being sustainable’ has become a buzzword – a claim to boost our image rather than an honest endeavour. It is hard to trust people and brands today when we fear to fall into the trap of greenwashing. However, we have no choice but to change our collective behaviour, consumption patterns and business practices if we want to combat climate change and the collapse of biodiversity.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last November, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.nature.com&#x2F;articles&#x2F;d41586-021-03431-4&quot;&gt;COP26&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; shed light on how indecisive our global institutions and governments are in the face of an unprecedented climate crisis. We now have to come to terms with the fact that carbon neutrality is no longer enough. Rising carbon emissions have been linked to an increasing amount of heat waves, droughts, floods and hurricanes globally. It is our collective responsibility to reverse the unintended consequences of our actions. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you know that warnings about the risks and harms of excessive carbon emissions date back as far as the 1960s to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.climatefiles.com&#x2F;climate-change-evidence&#x2F;presidents-report-atmospher-carbon-dioxide&#x2F;&quot;&gt;a report&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; by former US President Johnson’s Science Advisory Committee? We’ve clearly been inactive and ignorant for far too long. There’s always another crisis, another challenge to tackle. But we cannot afford to ignore climate change and biodiversity loss any longer.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;blog&#x2F;waves_of_crises.png&quot; alt=&quot;Waves of Crises&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need to tackle the climate crisis with the same urgency, force and determination we do with other crises. And we finally need to face the reality and severity of the climate crisis! After all, Greta Thunberg is right: “Nature does not bargain and you cannot compromise with the laws of physics.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The time has come for us to put our planet first. It is our duty to regenerate our planet and to support the right practices and organizations aligned with our vision of tomorrow. Now’s the time for regenerative action.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-save-our-planet&quot;&gt;How to save our planet&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The greatest threat to our planet is the belief that someone else will save it.” – Robert Swan&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By taking action and making the right choices for our planet and humanity, we can prevent the truly &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.technologyreview.com&#x2F;2021&#x2F;12&#x2F;23&#x2F;1042973&#x2F;climate-change-action-progress-clean-energy&#x2F;&quot;&gt;severe levels of global warming&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and restore the health of our planet. Once emitted, carbon dioxide can persist in the atmosphere for several hundreds, possibly thousands, of years. So, it all starts with reducing global emissions to the lowest level possible. In addition to that, we’ll need to compensate for those emissions that cannot be avoided as well as for all of the carbon and other greenhouse gases we’ve emitted in the past.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As most technological solutions for carbon removal remain expensive and early stage, nature-based solutions are the way forward. And trees, as the world’s largest plants, are an effective way to store carbon.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what are we doing at ThreeFold? How are we contributing to restoring the health of our planet? How are we taking climate action?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;our-commitment&quot;&gt;Our commitment&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe our planet needs regenerative solutions at a large scale. Our motto is: planet first, people second, profit as a result. Without a healthy planet, humanity can’t survive and no economy can exist.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;threefold__tfgrid_home&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is already much more &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;for_our_planet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;energy efficient&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; than the traditional Internet, there will always be energy consumption and emissions that cannot be avoided – and thus have to be compensated for. We’re not just going for the carbon neutrality of the ThreeFold Grid but for carbon negativity (or as we prefer to call it, planet positivity), i.e. offsetting its emissions three times through planting and protecting trees.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we decided to empower our community to take part in our regeneration efforts in a low-threshold way. ThreeFold Farmers will automatically compensate for their 3Nodes’ carbon footprint three times, and everybody will be able to use the ThreeFold Grid’s regenerative Internet capacity while simultaneously supporting impact initiatives.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we shared in our Planet-Positive Farming Series, we’re setting the plan for a planet-positive Internet by implementing a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-on-track-to-be-planet-positive&#x2F;2097?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;Voluntary Carbon Credits&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (VCC) system and supporting &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;supporting-initiatives-to-regenerate-the-planet&#x2F;2110?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;planet-positive initiatives&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; with our trusted partners from &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;driving-regeneration-with-tag&#x2F;2120?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;Take Action Global&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (TAG). &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;driving-regeneration-with-take-action-global&quot;&gt;Driving regeneration with Take Action Global&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re aiming to realize the initial promise of the Internet while also regenerating the planet. Our decentralized Internet infrastructure is already highly &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;internet_energy_consumption&#x2F;&quot;&gt;energy efficient&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; – we’re using about 10 times less energy than any comparable alternative. In December 2021, we &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.prnewswire.com&#x2F;news-releases&#x2F;threefold-and-take-action-global-partner-to-bring-internet-access-to-1-billion-people-across-the-globe-301446693.html&quot;&gt;announced&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; our commitment to achieve a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;c&#x2F;ecosystem-developments&#x2F;sustainability&#x2F;90&quot;&gt;carbon double win&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for the ThreeFold Grid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together with &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;partners&#x2F;take_action_global&#x2F;&quot;&gt;TAG&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; – experts on climate action and education who were &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;threefold_io&#x2F;status&#x2F;1493980240275812352?s=20&amp;amp;t=uW8aclYr82-xqQkEsCeGWw&quot;&gt;acknowledged&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for their incredible work by the Anthem Awards – we kicked off a pilot program for tree planting. After measuring the carbon footprint of the Grid and individual &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;farm&quot;&gt;3Nodes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, we knew what it would take to go beyond climate neutrality and fulfill our planet-positive commitment.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With our tree planting initiatives in Sierra Leone, Malawi and Cambodia, we’re planting enough trees in 2022 to lay the foundation for achieving and sustaining a carbon double win for our Internet infrastructure. Already, students and teachers in the three countries have planted more than 5,300 trees. Find out more about the pilot program &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;driving-regeneration-with-tag&#x2F;2120?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and head to the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;earthproject.org&#x2F;treeplanting&quot;&gt;EarthProject&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; page for the tree-planting details and how you yourself can get involved.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;blog&#x2F;tree_planting_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tree Planting 1&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;blog&#x2F;tree_planting_2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tree Planting 2&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we’ve laid the foundation for the ThreeFold Grid’s carbon double win, we will continue to produce Voluntary Carbon Credits to finance further impact initiatives, such as fostering climate education and renewable energy grid developments to enhance the life of communities.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-regenerative-internet-for-the-planet-and-the-people&quot;&gt;A regenerative Internet for the planet and the people&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all need to take responsibility and to pull our own weight. But we’re in this together. And together, this will happen. After kicking off our &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;driving-regeneration-with-tag&#x2F;2120?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;pilot program&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; a month ahead of schedule, we’re well set to achieve the carbon double win for the ThreeFold Grid – driving the regeneration of our planet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are pioneering the creation of an &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;internet_energy_consumption&#x2F;&quot;&gt;energy-efficient&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and regenerative Internet built and owned by the people. The ThreeFold ecosystem consists of like-minded individuals and partners that share our values and support us in our mission. United in our shared beliefs in open source, peer-to-peer, equality and inclusion, we come together to build a better Internet. And we’re being acknowledged for our work – we’re &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;evenements.optionfinance.fr&#x2F;les-debats-finance-impact-rse&#x2F;content&#x2F;candidats-sia&quot;&gt;nominated&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for the Sustainable Investment in Action &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;sustainableinvestmentinaction.com&#x2F;awards-conferences-2022&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Awards&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in the category “Basic Needs”.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re making it easy for everyone to join us – all you have to do is connect a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;farm&quot;&gt;3Node&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to the ThreeFold Grid and you’ll effortlessly regenerate the earth through providing Internet capacity – a process we call ‘farming’ because it’s a greener, purposeful &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;farming_a_greener_alternative_to_crypto_mining&#x2F;&quot;&gt;alternative&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to crypto mining.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you ready to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;join us&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in our mission?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And don’t forget:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“What we do today will determine what the world looks like tomorrow.” – Marie von Ebner-Eschenbach&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;P.S.: If you have ideas or suggestions for further planet-positive initiatives or potential partnerships, let us know on our &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;c&#x2F;ecosystem-developments&#x2F;sustainability&#x2F;90&quot;&gt;forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Looking for TFT Fiat Gateway Beta Testers</title>
		<published>2022-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/04/post-11/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/04/post-11/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;📣 &lt;strong&gt;TFT Fiat Gateway Beta Testing Program&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In ongoing efforts to make the ThreeFold Token (TFT) more accessible, it will now be possible to buy TFT with a credit or debit card via the Get TFT platform!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The beta testing program incentivizes the validation of the experience, from the community. As a gesture of gratitude, participants will earn a 500 TFT “cash back,” provided by ThreeFold.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get involved &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;tft-fiat-gateway-beta-testing-program&#x2F;2746&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; 🙏&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>April 2022&#x27;s ThreeFold Product Updates</title>
		<published>2022-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/04/post-07/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/04/post-07/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;📣 &lt;strong&gt;April 2022’s ThreeFold Product Updates&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;We are happy to announce that ThreeFold Grid V3.0.0 Alpha-5 is officially released! There are a many upgrades, improvements and fixes to various TF Grid components including the TFT shop, the Playground, Zero-OS, the wallet, and more.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dive into the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-product-updates-tfgrid-v3-a-5-april-2022&#x2F;2713&quot;&gt;full update&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Major kudos to the developer team and all those involved in building, project managing, testing, and bringing these updates live!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; 👏&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Farming – A Greener Alternative to Crypto Mining</title>
		<published>2022-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/04/post-5/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/04/post-5/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cointelegraph.com&#x2F;bitcoin-for-beginners&#x2F;the-history-of-bitcoin-when-did-bitcoin-start&quot;&gt;October 2008&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, when the financial crisis was in full swing, an anonymous individual or group under the pseudonym ‘Satoshi Nakamoto’ published a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;bitcoin.org&#x2F;bitcoin.pdf&quot;&gt;white paper&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on Bitcoin, a “peer-to-peer electronic cash system” that ended up disrupting the financial system and sparked the creation of an entirely new industry: crypto mining.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering that many people view Bitcoin as a commodity, similar to gold, it only makes sense that the process of generating new Bitcoins would become referred to as ‘mining’. In a way, mining is an incentive mechanism to reach consensus in the verification of transactions in a decentralized network. While crypto mining originated from Bitcoin, the system has spread quite widely across the blockchain space.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than a decade later, Bitcoin keeps intriguing individuals and organizations all around the world, and has become &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cointelegraph.com&#x2F;news&#x2F;is-bitcoin-a-waste-of-energy-pros-and-cons-about-bitcoin-mining&quot;&gt;one of the most popular&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; financial assets. Nevertheless, criticism and doubts around Bitcoin and crypto mining remain. The most popular cryptocurrency is also frequently brought to the spotlight around its potential affiliations to money laundering, financing of terrorism and cybercrime, as well as the energy the mining process of its cryptocurrency consumes. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cbeci.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Electricity Consumption Index&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of the University of Cambridge, the annual consumption of Bitcoin is currently estimated to amount to nearly 140 TWh. The United Arab Emirates (113 TWh) or the Netherlands (109 TWh) had a lower annual energy consumption than Bitcoin &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;blog.zorinaq.com&#x2F;bitcoin-electricity-consumption&#x2F;&quot;&gt;in 2020&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Moreover, news outlets like &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.theguardian.com&#x2F;technology&#x2F;2017&#x2F;nov&#x2F;27&#x2F;bitcoin-mining-consumes-electricity-ireland&quot;&gt;The Guardian&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.bbc.com&#x2F;news&#x2F;technology-56012952&quot;&gt;BBC News&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; reported on Bitcoin exceeding the energy consumption of further countries, including Ireland and Argentina. Within the last year, headlines like “&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.nytimes.com&#x2F;interactive&#x2F;2021&#x2F;09&#x2F;03&#x2F;climate&#x2F;bitcoin-carbon-footprint-electricity.html&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Uses More Electricity Than Many Countries&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;” in the New York Times or “&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.ft.com&#x2F;content&#x2F;1aecb2db-8f61-427c-a413-3b929291c8ac&quot;&gt;Bitcoin’s growing energy problem: ‘It’s a dirty currency’&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;” in the Financial Times were in no short supply.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the most popular quotes on the topic is Bill Gates’ statement in the New York Times in &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.nytimes.com&#x2F;2021&#x2F;03&#x2F;09&#x2F;business&#x2F;dealbook&#x2F;bill-gates-bitcoin.html&quot;&gt;March 2021&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;: “Bitcoin uses more electricity per transaction than any other method known to mankind, and so it’s not a great climate thing.” Not that this statement or the awareness of the issue would have prevented Microsoft from launching &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;identity.foundation&#x2F;ion&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ION&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, a decentralized digital identity system, to run on the Bitcoin network.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;but-why-is-bitcoin-mining-so-energy-intensive-anyways&quot;&gt;But why is Bitcoin mining so energy intensive anyways?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the heart of Bitcoin’s energy-intensive model is the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.coindesk.com&#x2F;learn&#x2F;2020&#x2F;12&#x2F;16&#x2F;what-is-proof-of-work&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Proof-of-Work (PoW)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; protocol. &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.investopedia.com&#x2F;tech&#x2F;how-does-bitcoin-mining-work&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Bitcoin mining&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, the process of creating new Bitcoins using PoW, requires solving complex cryptographic equations to receive the rewards associated with the creation of the next block in the blockchain. PoW is carried out by computers, known as ‘miners’. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the early days, a simple computer was enough to mine Bitcoin. However, the difficulty of the mining algorithm increased as the network grew larger and more people started competing to earn the next block’s rewards. On average, it takes &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;bitcoin.org&#x2F;bitcoin.pdf&quot;&gt;about 10 minutes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to solve such an equation and to mine a new block. Today, Bitcoin mining has become a costly and elaborate endeavour – accessible only to large investors that can support powerful supercomputers – at the cost of &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.technologyreview.com&#x2F;2022&#x2F;04&#x2F;18&#x2F;1049331&#x2F;bitcoin-cryptocurrency-cryptomining-new-york&#x2F;&quot;&gt;local communities&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s only sensible that miners are beefing up their machines to increase their chances. In fact, the sector became so competitive that &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.linkedin.com&#x2F;pulse&#x2F;sustainable-crypto-mining-becoming-reality-nameet-potnis&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Intel created&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; dedicated chips and specialized manufacturers for mining servers like &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.bitmain.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Bitmain&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; were established. With up to 32,500 Watts indicated by manufacturers, the power consumption of such devices averages 28,470 kWh per year if operated continuously. In comparison, the annual consumption of a freezer is estimated between 200 and 500 kWh per year. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, operating a single mining machine is hardly the way to succeed. The biggest Bitcoin miners have fleets of hundreds of machines in so-called ‘mining farms’, carefully maintained and constantly ventilated, to prevent them from overheating. Some of the largest, like &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.rockdalemdd.org&#x2F;news&#x2F;whinstone-us-breaks-ground-build-world%E2%80%99s-largest-bitcoin-mining-facility-rockdale-texas&quot;&gt;Northern Data&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in Texas, have an energy consumption of 1 GWh per year, the equivalent of the energy produced by about &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.energy.gov&#x2F;eere&#x2F;articles&#x2F;how-much-power-1-gigawatt&quot;&gt;3.1 million&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; photovoltaic (solar) panels. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In critical times where humanity is facing serious global challenges in relation to climate change and the collapse of biodiversity, we must rethink the basics of how to decentralize our world. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;are-there-more-energy-conscious-solutions&quot;&gt;Are there more energy-conscious solutions?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.coindesk.com&#x2F;learn&#x2F;2020&#x2F;12&#x2F;30&#x2F;what-is-proof-of-stake&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Proof-of-Stake (PoS)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; mechanisms have proven to be &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.investopedia.com&#x2F;tech&#x2F;how-does-bitcoin-mining-work&#x2F;#toc-downsides-of-mining&quot;&gt;less energy intensive&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; than PoW. With PoS, miners lock up (‘stake’) a blockchain’s cryptocurrency on escrow accounts to be granted mining rights. In exchange for this participation, miners receive an interest proportional to their stake as reward. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PoS-based blockchains are faster and much more energy efficient than PoW-based blockchains. However, the implementation of a PoS protocol poses its own challenges. For example, it is known for incentivizing hoarding, rather than utilization, and driving centralization. The mining industry is attempting to shift perceptions and move away from its climate-polluting, power-hungry image by powering large mining activities with renewable energies or by offsetting their emissions with carbon credits.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this might sound great at first, it does not resolve the underlying issue of incredibly high energy consumption. Should we really allocate relatively scarce renewable energy resources to such energy-intensive endeavours? Or should we rather look for more efficient alternatives – considering we have all the technology to create more energy-efficient models from scratch – and then support what energy consumption remains with renewable energy? &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;threefold-farming-offers-a-greener-paradigm&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Farming offers a greener paradigm&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;what_is_farming&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Farming&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a decentralized, energy-efficient and meaningful alternative to mining. &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;the-potential-of-the-threefold-token-tft&#x2F;1796&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Tokens&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (TFT) are minted whenever new Internet capacity in terms of compute, storage or network is added to the ThreeFold Grid by connecting computers, known as 3Nodes. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By contributing decentralized Internet capacity to the ThreeFold Grid, independent people and organizations called ‘farmers’ earn TFT in return – based on a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;farming&#x2F;threefold__proof_of_capacity?id=why-proof-of-capacity&quot;&gt;Proof-of-Capacity&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;  (PoC) algorithm. PoC is autonomously carried out by ThreeFold’s &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;for_our_planet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;extremely efficient&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; operating system. First, Zero-OS scans the computer’s resources. Then the operating system registers the computing power and Internet storage on the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;tf_chain&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Blockchain&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, making the resources available to the entire network – thereby creating a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;coincheckup.com&#x2F;blog&#x2F;threefold-is-the-decentralized-web-the-future-of-the-internet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;decentralized model&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for Internet capacity provisioning. The &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.docsend.com&#x2F;view&#x2F;wsru3f9tmeaq62wq&quot;&gt;energy consumption&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of a 3Node can vary, depending on the amount of Compute Units (CUs) and Storage Units (SUs) it holds. “The average consumption for a Titan 3Node is around 26.71 KwH per hour”, says ThreeFold’s &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;people&#x2F;alexandre_hannelas&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Alexandre Hannelas&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farming supports the realization of an open-source peer-to-peer Internet free from centralized servers and authorities. Similarly to Bitcoin, the management of transactions and the issuing of TFT is carried out collectively by the network to create a decentralized Internet economy. In a way, what &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;bitcoin_threefold&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Bitcoin did to money&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, ThreeFold does to the Internet – while using much &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;for_our_planet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;less energy&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“By using blockchain for what it’s good at and other pioneering technologies, such as peer-to-peer networking, to complement it, we built the most efficient Internet infrastructure in the world, and by far.” – Kristof de Spiegeleer.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developing sustainable solutions for our planet is essential to ThreeFold’s ethos which puts our planet and people first. A famous quote, we love and frequently refer to at ThreeFold, is Albert Einstein’s “We cannot solve our problems with the same thinking we used when we create them.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our planet needs regenerative solutions at a large scale, and ThreeFold aims to deliver on our promise providing better solutions for our planet and people through our technology. Based on the ThreeFold Grid’s average energy consumption, we’re planting trees with our partner &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;driving-regeneration-with-tag&#x2F;2120?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;Take Action Global&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to offset the Grid’s carbon emissions three times in the form of &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-on-track-to-be-planet-positive&#x2F;2097?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;Voluntary Carbon Credits&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (VCC). Our VCC system was implemented in the PoC algorithm, so every 3Node mints additional TFT to offset its own carbon emissions based on the power utilization of the individual 3Node per month. The &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-on-track-to-be-planet-positive&#x2F;2097&quot;&gt;process&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is fully automated and executed by the ThreeFold Blockchain.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold’s global community of farmers is on a mission to regenerate our planet through the planet-positive ThreeFold Farming which supports tree planting and other &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;supporting-initiatives-to-regenerate-the-planet&#x2F;2110?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;impact initiatives&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; by default. We’re on track to provide a planet-positive Internet and support our partners in their initiatives in fields like climate education, climate action and economic inclusion worldwide.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farming is about so much more than crypto mining. It’s about building a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;medium.com&#x2F;authority-magazine&#x2F;the-future-is-now-kristoff-de-spiegeleer-of-threefold-on-how-their-technological-innovation-will-7acc0e51c365&quot;&gt;better Internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and shaping the world we want to live in. Together with a community of like-minded people, we’re taking action for a better world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If not us, who? If not now, when?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join the global ThreeFold &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;movement&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;farming&#x2F;threefold__farming_intro&quot;&gt;Start farming&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; today and become a part of the new Internet while regenerating the planet.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>April 19th Community Call Recording</title>
		<published>2022-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/04/post-06/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/04/post-06/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;🚨 &lt;strong&gt;This Week’s Community Call Recording!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;For anyone who missed the community call earlier this week, please find the recording and slides &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-april-19-2022-community-call-recording-presentation&#x2F;2714&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many thanks to those who were able to be there with us in-person!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please note the content of this call is for information purposes only and is subject to change as the project evolves.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>GetTFT.com is Live</title>
		<published>2022-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/01/post-15/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/01/post-15/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;🚨 &lt;strong&gt;Get TFT Directly with BTC!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our ongoing efforts to make TFT more accessible to the world, we’re happy to share that anyone can now buy TFT directly with the world’s most popular cryptocurrency, BTC (Bitcoin).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;get-tft-directly-with-btc&#x2F;1825&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;There’s been lots of positive attention around TFT over the last weeks despite the downward market. People are waking up to ThreeFold and showing their belief in the People’s Internet!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Get to Know the ThreeFold Token</title>
		<published>2022-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/01/post-12/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/01/post-12/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;🤝 &lt;strong&gt;Get to know the ThreeFold Token (TFT)&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TFT is the utility token of the People’s Internet, backed by the continuous growth of the ThreeFold Grid and driven by strong tokenomics. It has real-world value that meet real-world demands. And the world is starting to take notice.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;the-potential-of-the-threefold-token-tft&#x2F;1796&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Now’s the time to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tokens&#x2F;threefold__how_to_buy&quot;&gt;get TFT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;! This post is a great share for anyone interested in getting involved in the project!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>New Year Deep Dive Session 6</title>
		<published>2022-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/01/post-09/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/01/post-09/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Today, we hosted our final deep dive meeup for now. We’ll pick up community sessions in a few weeks. In the meantime, we’ll catch you on the chats and in the forum!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tuesday January 18 2022&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Session 6: ThreeFold DAO, Validator Nodes, &amp;amp; COSMOS&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recording &amp;amp; Presentation Link: &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;tf-deep-dive-session-6-threefold-dao-validator-nodes-cosmos&#x2F;1784&quot;&gt;Here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>New Year Deep Dive Sessions 4 &amp; 5</title>
		<published>2022-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/01/post-06/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/01/post-06/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This week we continued with two more deep dive meetups. Don’t miss our final deep dive next week, covering the ThreeFold DAO, Validator Nodes, &amp;amp; the COSMOS integration!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wednesday January 12 2022&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Session 4: Deplpying Decentralized Solutions on TF Grid 3&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recording &amp;amp; Presentation Link: &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;tf-deep-dive-session-4-deploying-decentralized-solutions-on-tf-grid-3&#x2F;1751&quot;&gt;Here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thursday January 13 2022&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Session 5: ThreeFold Grid Architecture&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recording &amp;amp; Presentation Link: &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;tf-deep-dive-session-5-threefold-grid-architecture&#x2F;1756&quot;&gt;Here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Crypto Daily Calls ThreeFold a Hidden Gem</title>
		<published>2022-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/01/post-07/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/01/post-07/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;🗞 &lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold in the News&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; 🗞&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“With ThreeFold’s plans for 2022, we can expect major developments in the blockchain industry and beyond to happen on their infrastructure this year.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like Bitcoin is decentralizing global financial systems, ThreeFold will decentralize the Internet and cloud at large. With a solid team of cloud experts behind and many partners looking at building on top of their decentralized Internet with their mainnet launch, the moment to buy TFT is now.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;While The Market Is Struggling, This Hidden Gem Is About To Take Off, via Crypto Daily.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full article &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cryptodaily.co.uk&#x2F;2022&#x2F;01&#x2F;while-the-market-is-struggling-this-hidden-gem-is-about-to-take-off&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking for ways to get TFT, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold&#x2F;#&#x2F;tokens&#x2F;threefold__how_to_buy&quot;&gt;look no further&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>New Year Deep Dive Sessions 1, 2, &amp; 3</title>
		<published>2022-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/01/post-03/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/01/post-03/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A lot happened in 2021 and many things are changing! To kick the year off, we’re hosting six community meetups to deep dive into key topics related to ThreeFold. Here are the first three sessions from this week.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tuesday January 4 2022&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Session 1: TF Grid 3.0, Weblets, And Demos&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recording &amp;amp; Presentation Link: &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;tf-deep-dive-session-1-tf-grid-3-weblets-demos&#x2F;1673&#x2F;3&quot;&gt;Here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wednesday January 5 2022&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Session 2: TF Grid &amp;amp; TFT Growth Simulator + Tokenomics&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recording &amp;amp; Presentation Link: &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;tf-deep-dive-session-2-tf-grid-tft-growth-simulator-tokenomics&#x2F;1682&#x2F;2&quot;&gt;Here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thursday January 6 2022&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Session 3: TF Grid 3.x Launch Plan&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recording &amp;amp; Presentation Link: &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;tf-deep-dive-session-3-tf-grid-3-x-launch-plan&#x2F;1694&quot;&gt;Here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>2021 Review, 2022 Preview</title>
		<published>2022-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/01/post-02/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/01/post-02/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;🎆 &lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold’s 2021 Review &amp;amp; 2022 Preview!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefolds-2021-review-and-2022-preview&#x2F;1641&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As 2022 kicks off, let’s take a look back at the year that was and what to expect throughout Q1 – TF Grid 3 Mainnet, validator nodes, the ThreeFold DAO, and more!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>A Journey through the Decentralization and Blockchain Space – Part Two: Akash</title>
		<published>2021-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/10/post-3/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/10/post-3/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As announced in &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;project_comparison_1_dfinity&#x2F;&quot;&gt;the first episode of this series&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, I’d like to shed some light on the complex decentralization and blockchain space and look into what fellow projects have to offer. There are various projects decentralizing parts of the internet. So in this second blog post, we’ll be exploring Akash and their solutions to find out what we have in common and where we differ. Follow me on the second step of my journey to better understand the space we operate in and how ThreeFold stands out.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;akash-how-the-project-compares-to-threefold&quot;&gt;Akash &amp;amp; how the project compares to ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2015, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;akash.network&quot;&gt;Akash&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is an open-source and blockchain-based cloud computing platform. They &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;akash.network&#x2F;about#vision&quot;&gt;strive&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for an open, permissionless, and sovereign cloud that allows anyone to reserve computing resources without any intermediaries. Their cloud platform provides a simple way for deploying and scaling cloud applications. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Akash Network is a decentralized, on-chain marketplace for leasing cloud computing resources, while the Akash Container Platform is an off-chain platform for cloud management services (deployment, hosting, and management of workloads) on Kubernetes, the industry standard for container orchestration. We also integrated Kubernetes into our &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;info&#x2F;cloud#&#x2F;cloud__cloud_intro&quot;&gt;P2P Cloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; solution, but we didn’t stop there. On ThreeFold’s cloud solution, developers additionally have the option to deploy virtual machines or to discover the future of cloud computing with &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tech&#x2F;zflist&quot;&gt;ZFlist&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; – a game-changing Docker-compatible solution that is distributed across many mini VMs, positioning itself as the ideal infrastructure for edge workloads. And all data produced by these workloads can be stored in our &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tech&#x2F;zdbfs&quot;&gt;Quantum Safe File System&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; solution that is highly compatible with most storage tools (e.g. S3) and protocols (e.g. IPFS).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Akash, developers would get access to what is probably the best decentralized computing cloud on the market, whereas ThreeFold offers a full stack cloud infrastructure that unites compute, storage, and network. Having integrated all leading industry-standard tools, ThreeFold’s &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cloud.threefold.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;cloud solution&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; allows for a seamless migration of any digital workload – even from centralized cloud providers like &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;threefold_cloud_vs_centralized_providers_like_aws_azure&#x2F;&quot;&gt;AWS or Microsoft Azure&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. This empowers developers from all over the world to deploy their applications and workloads on a fully decentralized infrastructure, without having to learn new tools. Developers using Akash, however, may still need to rely on other decentralized projects to decentralize the storage and network components of their solutions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Akash sees their &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.akash.network&quot;&gt;USP&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in hosting containers that allow any type of cloud-native application to be hosted without vendor lock-in or having to learn new protocols, a vision shared and extended by ThreeFold as the project is already compatible with most of the industry standards. With the integration of &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-grid-3-0-supports-terraform&#x2F;1184&quot;&gt;Terraform&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; into the upcoming third release of the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.forbes.com&#x2F;sites&#x2F;johnkoetsier&#x2F;2020&#x2F;06&#x2F;20&#x2F;largest-distributed-peer-to-peer-grid-on-the-planet-laying-foundation-for-a-decentralized-internet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, developers will be capable of hosting any existing or future Linux workload seamlessly.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;network-and-development-possibilities&quot;&gt;Network and development possibilities&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Akash is one of the most robust decentralized compute solutions out there and is one of the key players in driving the DeCloud movement. On its platform, computing resources can be leased on the Akash Marketplace, driven by its blockchain based on the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;cosmos&#x2F;cosmos-sdk&quot;&gt;Cosmos SDK&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It’s already being used by a range of blockchains and applications. On their marketplace, users can determine the terms and price for their deployments and have cloud providers bid for the opportunity in a reversed auction. Nevertheless, the project still relies on centralized data centers as they seek to prevent unutilized capacity &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;blog.orchid.com&#x2F;akash-networks-greg-osuri-on-decentralizing-cloud-computing&#x2F;&quot;&gt;from centralized cloud computing services&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to go to waste, leveraging about 85% of this underutilized cloud capacity from data centers. So, while Akash is preventing capacity from being wasted, they also highly depend on centralized capacity – and so do the workloads using their platform.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With ThreeFold, developers are enabled to tailor the terms for storing their workloads to fit their needs, benefiting from full decentralization and edge possibilities. Moreover, developers get access to the most distributed peer-to-peer infrastructure in the world – the ThreeFold, currently present in &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;explorer.grid.tf&quot;&gt;more than 50 countries&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Another unique attribute of the ThreeFold Grid is that the capacity within the network is provided by many people and organizations, forming an infrastructure that can be described as the “&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;tf_grid_peoples_internet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;People’s Internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.” It is the first full-stack blockchain-enabled cloud to be made open source, allowing anyone to connect cloud capacity to the network by downloading &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tech&#x2F;zero-os&quot;&gt;Zero-OS&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, our stateless and lightweight operating system powering the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;grid&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Once booted, the servers run and can’t be accessed physically. As they’re self-healing, they don’t require any maintenance. All in all, this model flips traditional IT upside down, allowing anyone to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;join_the_peoples_internet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;join&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; the ThreeFold ecosystem. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both projects also reward their communities for providing capacity. Akash planned to launch a limited edition for an own node device, called Supermini, with plug-and-play functionalities similar to our &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;technology?id=_3nodes&quot;&gt;3Node&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;However, Akash &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;akash.network&#x2F;blog&#x2F;supermini-update&quot;&gt;just announced&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that they’ll be postponing the launch of their Supermini indefinitely, meaning they won’t be offering anything comparable to our 3Node anytime soon.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; Our &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;farm&quot;&gt;3Node&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a general purpose computer that acts as  a low-level provider for IT capacity. It is booted with our unique operating system Zero-OS and enables even people without technical skills to participate. We’re collaborating with certified hardware partners and plan to extend our reach in the near future to allow even more people to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;join_the_peoples_internet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;join&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; the ThreeFold Grid. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;tokenomics-and-incentive-models&quot;&gt;Tokenomics and incentive models&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both, Akash Token (AKT) and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tft&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Token&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (TFT), are utility tokens fuelling an open-source cloud. While the Akash Tokens (AKT) represent a unit of compute on the Akash Network, ThreeFold Tokens (TFT) represent a unit of compute, storage or network on the ThreeFold Grid. Akash’s payment model allows users to pay for what they need, when they need it, using a reverse auction. In order to create a deployment, users have to provide a deposit first. As payments are effected passively, it is crucial for users to keep their deposits funded to maintain the lease of their capacity reservations. With our &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tech&#x2F;tf-chain&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Blockchain&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, which will be released on Testnet 3.0 soon, a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;introducing-tf-chain-an-updated-billing-model&#x2F;1277&quot;&gt;new billing model&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is being introduced. This model allows users to authorize &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tech&#x2F;smart-contract&quot;&gt;smart contracts&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to automatically deduct their wallets (similarly to a direct debit transaction), depending on how much capacity they use. Additionally, we’re implementing a new discount model, which will provide users with discounted capacity pricings according to the amount of ThreeFold Tokens stored in a user’s wallet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, Akash does a great job with regards to decentralizing cloud capacity. However, it doesn’t challenge the status-quo in terms of &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;security-privacy-on-the-threefold-grid-and-second-best-alternatives-out-there-today&#x2F;1290&quot;&gt;data privacy&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. At ThreeFold, we’re determined to empower users, to give them back control and ownership of their data in an &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;critical-security-updates-for-apple-and-google-underline-need-for-secure-it-ecosystem&#x2F;1271&quot;&gt;entirely secure&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, peer-to-peer IT ecosystem. While Akash and ThreeFold seem like competitors on a cloud level, we see ourselves more as a potential &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-is-the-substrate-for-decloud&#x2F;1295&quot;&gt;decentralized substrate&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for Akash to scale to the edges of our world. Akash developers would surely benefit from the lightweight and stateless features of our Zero-OS which could provide them with a more efficient and private infrastructure to test, build, and collaborate on workloads. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Akash and ThreeFold share the same goal – to bring secure, performant, and data-sovereign cloud solutions for humanity to thrive. As Sam &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-is-the-substrate-for-decloud&#x2F;1295&quot;&gt;put in a nutshell&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;: ThreeFold is the ideal substrate for projects like Akash to run on, instead of depending on traditional cloud providers – as we provide the low-level primitives for a decentralized world. So, we believe &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;how-is-threefold-different-from-akash-and-holochain&#x2F;804&#x2F;2&quot;&gt;Akash and ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; are complementary in many ways and could  join forces to further push the boundaries of &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;africa.businessinsider.com&#x2F;local&#x2F;markets&#x2F;ambitious-startup-to-disrupt-the-internet-and-cloud&#x2F;b38rwj4&quot;&gt;cloud decentralization&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; together.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we truly believe in collaboration, we invite all other projects in the space to join us in our quest to decentralize the entire Internet and Cloud stack to restore the neutrality we once took for granted. Thanks for taking this journey with me and don’t forget to stay tuned for the next stop: &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;project_comparison_3_filecoin&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Filecoin&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>TFT on 1inch.io</title>
		<published>2021-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The ThreeFold Token is now available on &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;1inch.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;1inch.io&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;1inch connects many third party DEXes and has its own liquidity pools as well, to provide the best possible pricing for end users. It is an easy entry to the DeFi space.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
🎒 &lt;strong&gt;Learn how to get TFT on the Binance Smart Chain using 1inch &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;how-to-buy-tft-on-binance-smart-chain-using-1inch-io&#x2F;1189&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Liquid Receives $120 Million in Debt Financing From FTX</title>
		<published>2021-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/08/post-26/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/08/post-26/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Related to last week’s Liquid news:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Today, Liquid announced “the closing of a US$120,000,000 debt financing” from FTX Trading Ltd, owner and operator of top tier exchange FTX&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, and “that they have entered good faith discussions in pursuit of further collaborative opportunities.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
While we cannot speculate on what these further collaborative opportunities might be and how they could impact tokens listed on Liquid, it is certainly good news for Liquid to have such support from FTX.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Full coverage &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;liquid-exchange-receives-120-000-000-in-debt-financing-from-top-tier-ftx&#x2F;1159&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Introducing the TFT Development Plan</title>
		<published>2021-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/08/post-23/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/08/post-23/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There have been many questions in the community about &lt;strong&gt;the plan around the ThreeFold Token&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Please take a look at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;tft-development-plan&#x2F;1149&quot;&gt;this post&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; and provide your comments, questions, and feedback.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;We hope you see what we see… Now’s the time to buy TFT. If you need some help getting TFT on BSC, please see the forum post &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;how-to-buy-tft-on-binance-smart-chain-using-pancake-swap-protocol&#x2F;902&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. And as always, we’re here to help!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Liquid Hacked, TFT Not Affected</title>
		<published>2021-08-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-08-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/08/post-019/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/08/post-019/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We wanted to update the community that Liquid, an exchange on which TFT is listed, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;Liquid_Global&#x2F;status&#x2F;1428176357515612165?s=09&quot;&gt;shared this morning&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that warm wallets on the exchange were compromised in a hack.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;It appears that Stellar-based assets (e.g. TFT) were not stolen.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Please take note:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🚫 To ensure safety of funds, please do not deposit any crypto assets to your Liquid wallets until further notice.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🚫 Liquid has halted all crypto withdrawals while we assess the impact.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;✅ Fiat withdrawals and deposits remain available.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;✅ Other services on Liquid, including trading and Liquid Earn, remain available.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
You can find the full incident report &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;blog.liquid.com&#x2F;warm-wallet-incident&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Liquid is investigating and will provide updates as they have them. We’ve also reached out to them directly and will share more as we know. 🙏&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Update on the Binance Smart Chain Integration</title>
		<published>2021-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/05/post-5/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/05/post-5/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last week we announced our plan to make the ThreeFold Token more accessible through multichain integrations – with Binance Smart Chain up first!
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Today we are happy to update that the BSC integration is going just as planned and next week, TFT will be available there.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Please note that our next announcement will include the official contract address and the pair contract. If you don’t see it from us, it’s not authentic.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
We can’t wait for this integration to be live and to share the good news and details with you, our beautiful community. Thanks for your support!
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;If you have questions, please be reminded of &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;our two-way chat&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;our forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Announces Plans to go Multichain</title>
		<published>2021-04-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-04-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/04/post-29/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/04/post-29/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peer-to-Peer Internet ThreeFold Goes Multichain to Accelerate Token Accessibility&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;ThreeFold is set to integrate BSC in the next couple of weeks, with Ethereum and Huobi’s ECO Chain following in Q2.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;This will allow ThreeFold to be more accessible to the DeFi world and provide ThreeFold Farmers and users with more platforms to exchange TFT.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;threefold_io&#x2F;status&#x2F;1387762711417786368&quot;&gt;Our tweet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;bitcoinist.com&#x2F;peer-to-peer-internet-threefold-goes-multichain-to-accelerate-token-accessibility&#x2F;&quot;&gt;the full release&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- TODO: Add Tags and Categories --&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Q1 Highlights</title>
		<published>2021-04-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-04-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/04/post-02/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/04/post-02/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here’s a quick look at the first three months of 2021 for ThreeFold:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
🚀 The TF Grid technology made huge steps forward (v2.4, v2.5, eVDC, QSFS, Marketplace, &amp;amp; more)
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
👯‍♀️ Our digital avatar called Digital Twin nears testing phase
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
✅ 3Node Pre-Order Batch 1 of 2021 has closed (welcome, new farmers!)
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find the full update &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;threefold__q12021recap&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, with more details.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Seeking participation with the TFT plan</title>
		<published>2021-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/02/post-03/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/02/post-03/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We have a good plan in place to stimulate token growth but we have some key decisions to make &amp;amp; we are creating a group to help us finalize. We have already invited &#x2F; included a number of farmers, token holders, ambassadors, and outside industry experts – and now we want to open it up to the wider community.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
If you’re interested in being a part of this guidance committee, please get in touch with @samtaggart on Telegram and he will ask some questions to ensure we get a well-rounded group of people.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Please reply by the end of today 6pm CET, if you’d like to be a part. A call will be scheduled for Friday or Saturday.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Please take note of a few things:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The plan WILL be with the best interest for the long-term growth of the token&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The plan WILL be in the best interest of farmers and token holders&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The plan WILL be in line with our values&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
As a reminder, please know that neither Sam nor any member of the ThreeFold team will ever reach out to you requesting TFT or any other form of currency. 🙏
&lt;p&gt;If you are skeptical about any interaction or need support, please use the live chat function on our website.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Why ThreeFold chose Stellar?</title>
		<published>2020-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/06/post-01/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/06/post-01/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;At ThreeFold, together with a beautiful ecosystem of partners, we are co-creating a peer-to-peer Internet that empowers equality, freedom, and sustainability.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
To be honest, we were always focused on building and utilizing &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;threefoldtech&#x2F;rivine&quot;&gt;our own transactional blockchain&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. We wanted to make sure we did it in the right way, upholding our values - but then we realized that the solution was already out there.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Stellar is an open-source network for currencies and payments. Stellar makes it possible to create, send and trade digital representations of all forms of money - dollars, pesos, bitcoin, pretty much anything. It’s designed so all the world’s financial systems can work together on a single network.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Stellar has no owner; if anything it’s owned by the public. The software runs across a decentralized, open network and handles millions of transactions each day. Like Bitcoin and Ethereum, Stellar relies on blockchain to keep the network in sync, but the end-user experience is more like cash - Stellar is much faster, cheaper, and more energy-efficient than typical blockchain-based systems.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In the spirit of collaboration, something we believe in heavily, we knew the right decision was to abandon our own transactional blockchain and to move our ThreeFold Token (TFT) to Stellar.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-did-we-choose-stellar&quot;&gt;Why did we choose Stellar?&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technology-wise it’s a very strong platform - energy-friendly &amp;amp; fast.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is good liquidity on the Stellar Network; it’s super easy to go from XLM to TFT.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By utilizing the Stellar Network, we are part of a large blockchain platform&#x2F;network. There is good integration with other digital currencies.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perhaps most importantly, we share like-minded values.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Stellar Network is supported by the Stellar Development Foundation (SDF). From &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.stellar.org&#x2F;foundation&quot;&gt;their website&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, “SDF and Stellar seek to unlock the world’s economic potential by making money more fluid, markets more open, and people more empowered.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The ThreeFold and Stellar Foundations have very aligned goals, particularly around empowerment of all people around the world - to create equal access to the Internet and to a global, inclusive financial system. Both solutions are built on open-source technology, both aim to unlock the world’s economic potential, and most of all, both empower people in developing countries and all around the globe.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
That is why ThreeFold is proud to be a part of the Stellar Network.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>An Intro to the ThreeFold Token</title>
		<published>2020-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2020/01/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2020/01/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The ThreeFold Token is the currency of the new Internet. It is a decentralized digital currency that represents a unit of reservation of capacity (compute, storage) on the largest peer-to-peer network of capacity on earth.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Capacity is a new high-demand market, and the TFT will be the medium of exchange for this commodity on the peer-to-peer internet brought by ThreeFold. TFT synergistically connects the world of cloud and blockchain markets to the most scalable universal substrate without compromising, performance, security and privacy.
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-are-threefold-tokens-created&quot;&gt;How are ThreeFold Tokens created?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No ThreeFold Tokens have ever been minted. ThreeFold Tokens are generated through a process called “Farming”. Farming happens when active internet capacity is added to the ThreeFold Grid. Independent farmers earn ThreeFold Tokens (TFT) by providing neutral and decentralized internet capacity, thus expending the usable Grid. Therefore no central entity controls the internet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-good-reasons-to-buy-threefold-tokens&quot;&gt;5 good reasons to buy ThreeFold Tokens&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TFTs are exclusively generated when new capacity is added to the TF Grid. There are no centralized issuers. Tokens have not been created out of thin air.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While the ThreeFold Grid can expand, a maximum of 4 Billion TFTs can ever be in circulation. This limit ensures stability of value and incentivization for all stakeholders.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TFT lives on the Stellar Blockchain. TFT holders benefit from a big ecosystem of proven wallets and mediums of exchange.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By employing Stellar technology, TFT transactions and smart contracts are powered by one of the most energy-efficient blockchains available. Furthermore, TFT is the medium of exchange on the greenest internet network in the world.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The market for farming, cultivating and trading TFT is open to all. Anyone with internet connection, power supply and necessary hardware can become a Farmer or trade ThreeFold tokens (TFT).&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By buying, holding, and utilizing ThreeFold Tokens, you are actively supporting the expansion of the ThreeFold Grid and its use cases — creating a more sustainable, fair, and equally accessible Internet.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To learn more about the token, please dive into &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;token&quot;&gt;our wiki&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Important note: TFTs are not an investment instrument. It is the medium of exchange on the ThreeFold Grid, and is a mechanism to enable the Internet we believe is possible.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Co-create the new Internet. Participate with TFT!</title>
		<published>2019-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2019/06/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2019/06/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;do-you-believe-that-the-world-needs-change&quot;&gt;Do you believe that the world needs change?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you believe in decentralization? Equality? Sustainability?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Do you believe in circular economies, where everyone is invited to partake and succeed?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The ThreeFold Token is the currency of the new Internet and brings true solutions to all the above questions. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
It supports the ThreeFold Foundation - an open ecosystem that is shaping a better world by empowering game-changing technology. ThreeFold is growing a green and conscious peer-to-peer Internet that is available everywhere and owned by everyone – across geographical and cultural borders, empowering people to be autonomous, and providing equal chances to learn, partake and succeed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;ready-to-support-a-new-internet&quot;&gt;Ready to support a new Internet?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By buying and holding TFT, anyone can support the ThreeFold Foundation’s ability to achieve its next technological and growth milestones (see &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;tdeoverview&quot;&gt;Token Distribution Event&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for use-cases). From funding the next technological innovations to supporting the growth of ThreeFold use-cases built on top of the ThreeFold Grid, TFT powers the expansion of the new Internet. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The time has come for us to step up and shape the world we believe is possible. Join us and lets co-create our futures together.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Get TFT on &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;app.liquid.com&#x2F;exchange&#x2F;TFTBTC&quot;&gt;Liquid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; now.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Get TFT on &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;btc-alpha.com&#x2F;en&#x2F;exchange&#x2F;TFT_BTC&quot;&gt;BTC-Alpha&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; now.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
On behalf of our planet, humanity and the ThreeFold Community, we thank you for considering empowering a better world.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you need more guidance on buying TFT, please head &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;how_to_buy&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>The need for a sustainable digital currency</title>
		<published>2019-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2019/03/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2019/03/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-world-needs-a-new-stable-green-digital-currency-which-is-usable-globally&quot;&gt;The world needs a new stable &amp;amp; green digital currency, which is usable globally&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digital currencies are on the way to global adoption. Today, there are approximately 130+ billion dollars worth of digital currencies in circulation and approximately 1 billion dollars traded on a daily basis on open market exchanges. Benefits of digital currencies include direct peer-to-peer transactions (requiring no intermediaries such as banks), greater trust (secured by cryptography and mathematics), lower friction charges, faster transaction times, and no single point of failure.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
However, cryptocurrencies commonly face some major problems, such as:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lack of scalability&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: The main blockchains today are based on “proof of work” - generating very large and complex prime numbers called “hashes” to record ledger transactions. These proof of work blockchains cannot scale to meet the increasing blockchain transaction volumes. In fact, Ethereum, one of the most popular and well known blockchains has announced it will change from “proof of work” to “proof of stake.”&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crazy energy requirements&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Computing complex proof of work hashes requires enormous amounts of processing power. Actually, a large portion of today’s hashrate is produced by very large dedicated billion dollar data centers called miners. It is estimated that the energy consumed by digital currency mining is approximately equivalent to the power consumption of the entire country of Denmark.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Certain perceived reputational issues&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Numerous commentators - particularly in the early years of bitcoin - speculated that unregulated digital currencies could be used to fund illicit activities.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A general absence of intrinsic value&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: The major digital currencies today are not backed by real assets - therefore their value is more surrounded by hype.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Limited utility&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Today digital currencies are predominantly held by miners and investors. There is very limited use of digital currencies to buy goods and services.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
These are some of the problems we see with cryptocurrencies. The world needs a new stable and green digital currency, which is usable globally. Enter ThreeFold Token.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To learn more about the token, please dive into &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;token&quot;&gt;our wiki&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>The need for ThreeFold&#x27;s neutral internet</title>
		<published>2017-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2017-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2017/06/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2017/06/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Internet is growing like crazy and is now a trillion dollar problem. Together we can build a new neutral Internet.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;an-introduction-to-the-problems&quot;&gt;An introduction to the problems&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Internet is no longer the neutral place it used to be. +80% of the Internet capacity is delivered by a handful of companies. This results in a loss of neutrality and openness and breeds inequalities.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To support the continuous growth of the Internet and connect billions to new Internet Of Things devices, 400 million new servers are needed by 2020. The world therefore needs another 4,000 large-scale data centers that each consume 200 MWe of electricity: &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;bit.ly&#x2F;1UPUZYG&quot;&gt;see source&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Today, about 4 billion people have no access to the Internet due to the high costs of connectivity and capacity. We believe these people have the fundamental right to have low-cost access to digital resources such as online identity solutions, education, health information and more. For this to happen, solutions that can lower the cost by a factor of 10 are required.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bandwidth does not follow Moore’s law. The growth of bandwidth required is much higher than the speed at which new capacity can be delivered. This is even more important in emerging markets.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Current blockchain technology is not scalable and not sustainable. Example: the Bitcoin blockchain alone uses more energy today than Croatia.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;current-internet-and-cloud-capacity&quot;&gt;Current Internet and Cloud capacity&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, the cloud computing industry represents a 100 billion dollar industry - mostly owned by about 20 global cooperations. Experts such as Bell Labs and Cisco believe the capacity requirements in the next decade will dramatically exceed existing infrastructure - requiring many more data centers and billions, if not trillions in investments.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The spectacular growth and advancements in cloud computing that occurred over the last decade resulted in large part from “hyper-scale” efficiencies - i.e. centralizing Internet infrastructure in very large billion dollar data centers.  However, demand for Internet capacity already surpassed the available infrastructure with emerging technologies such as Big Data, the Internet of Things (IoT) and Artificial Intelligence (AI) Technology. The existing hyperscale cloud architecture cannot cope with this growing demand as the requirements for land, power and funding are becoming outrageous.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The challenges facing the Internet includes the following:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trillions of Investment Required&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. In the next decade, the global Internet infrastructure requires another 4,000 data centers (250M - 1B dollar investment each) to meet demand which would cost trillions - this money could be better used in education, healthcare, or sustainable innovations. &lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impossible to scale the networks connecting users to the hyperscale data centers&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. Since hyperscale data centers are built in large “central” locations, the network leading to these data centers is congested. Even more, remote regions that are less connected to the Internet cannot benefit from these data centers’ IT services.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Non-local data and capacity&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. Governments around the world are becoming more and more concerned about data leaving their borders. To tackle this centralization issue, they would need local IT infrastructure. Also, IoT workloads need local capacity to deliver constant real-time computing and storage requirements - for certain applications and workloads (e.g. driverless cars), latency is not an option. Hyperscale data centers can simply not match these requirements.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not secure &#x2F; at risk of choke point failures&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. There are plenty of recent well-publicized problems around security, outages and loss of data. The reason for this is that centralized hyperscale architectures are inherently insecure - and failures at a single hyperscale location can cause widespread contagion and outages.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-threefold-solution&quot;&gt;The ThreeFold Solution&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our solution to these trillion dollar problems is to migrate Internet capacity to the Edge (closer to user location) - i.e. a “hyper-distributed” network architecture, located close to users (in cities, schools, offices, homes and even vehicles).
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Edge networks will not necessarily replace the existing hyperscale capacity powering today’s cloud - rather, they will scale to meet the increased capacity demands going forward. However, if the current hyperscale capacity can be decentralized to improve energy consumption and reduce costs, this would be a huge global success.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
By 2025, 60% of new Internet infrastructure will be decentralized and located at the edge of operator networks by using alternative locations which have stable (renewable) power and reliable connectivity.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;threefold-s-technology-main-benefits&quot;&gt;ThreeFold’s technology main benefits:&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: The ThreeFold Grid is distributed and benefits from our ItsYou.Online identity management platform - making it much more secure.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decentralized&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: The solution enables to bring capacity closer to where users are located, enabling a Cloud at the Edge.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sustainability&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: The technology removes the need to build huge power hungry datacenters and by decentralizing the architecture enables up-to 1000% energy savings.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Making IT a true utility&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;:  We always approached IT as Energy. Today we provide 3x more uptime and between 3-10x more cost effectiveness.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neutrality&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: The solution enables 100% neutral &amp;amp; private Internet IT capacity. Our blockchain technology provides security, neutrality &amp;amp; scale.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-threefold-zero-node&quot;&gt;The ThreeFold Zero-Node&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Zero-Node provides compute, network and storage capacity to the internet and ThreeFold’s blockchain. This capacity can be used for any possible workload. Here are some characteristics of ThreeFold’s Zero node:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Modularity&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Scaling from 8 vCPUs and 3.5 TB of storage (smallest) to clusters with 8000 vCPUs and 2 PB of storage (large), there is a range of possibilities at hand.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sustainability&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Storing the hardware uses about 10x less energy, and about 2-3x for other workloads.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decentralized&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: The Zero Operating System (“Zero OS”) is ideally suited for Edge networking - where automation, self-healing and hyper-distribution are must-haves.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Zero-Nodes are deployed as close as possible to the consumers of Internet IT capacity (IoT, residential, business, government, education, …).&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This results in massive bandwidth savings, we estimate to be able to keep 99% of the required bandwidth locally which has a huge impact on cost.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is the only viable solution to be able to provide internet to the 3.2 billion people waiting.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self healing&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: The architecture is designed to ensure that workloads and data can be accessed at all times. &lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neutral &amp;amp; private&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: A lot of work has done using blockchain (technology which powers crypto currency) to guarantee privacy and net neutrality.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed around simplicity to be used by everyone.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The technology provides anyone with the autonomy to deliver complex IT applications without the need for complex integration services.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Empowers equality&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Our technology should be usable by the “other billions” that remain unconnected. Due to the low cost-points, low energy requirements and reduced need of backbone network capacity.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
