<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>ThreeFold - partner</title>
	<subtitle>Our global digital backbone</subtitle>
	<link href="https://www3.threefold.io/tags/partner/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://www3.threefold.io"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2022-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://www3.threefold.io/tags/partner/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold in Paradise</title>
		<published>2022-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/04/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2022/04/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s January 2022. ThreeFold co-founder Adnan Fatayerji sits in the office of Shaher Mousli, CEO of Paradise Hills Development, along with Suhaib Sheikh, COO of the project. Shaher and Adnan are long-time friends and in fact Shaher gave Adnan his first internship in Dubai about two decades ago, while Adnan was in his final year at university.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shaher is well-known in the Dubai real-estate market,  for his open-heartedness and transparency, and has a history of always looking for ways to stand out and differentiate himself and his projects. Paradise Hills in itself came from the idea of creating a “paradise” themed model for residents that could even serve as a tropical resting place for birds in Dubai.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-aha-moment&quot;&gt;The “aha” moment&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past twenty years, Adnan and Shaher have maintained a strong relationship, and on this day, they are gathering to find a way to work together – to bring things full circle. They discuss how the real estate market is making a strong comeback, and various types of value propositions for future Paradise Hills residents, when the incredible “aha” moment drops. Instead of a standard one-time gift or fee write-off, why don’t we add a 3Node to each residence? A gift that keeps on giving! The room is filled with excitement. They realize that a new dawn in the property and homeownership market is born, combining the unified empowerment of digital and physical assets.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;blog&#x2F;paradise_hills_3node.png&quot; alt=&quot;Paradise Hills 3Node&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together, ThreeFold and Paradise Hills will collaborate on a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;news&#x2F;post&#x2F;paradise_hills&#x2F;&quot;&gt;historic partnership&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to create the world’s first neighborhood cloud network, living on top of the ThreeFold Grid. Dedicated servers called 3Nodes will be installed into 170 homes, providing the edge computing and Internet storage needed to run decentralized applications and Internet services. This will give residents, businesses, developers, and the government a secure and highly-available sovereign cloud infrastructure to store and process their data locally. And homeowners will be rewarded in the form of ThreeFold Tokens (TFT) simply by having these 3Nodes connected.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;no-time-to-waste&quot;&gt;No time to waste&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quickly the team puts the idea to paper, and by February the deal is done. In March, the collaboration is announced and makes the rounds in publications like &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;finance.yahoo.com&#x2F;news&#x2F;paradise-hills-property-development-threefold-090000146.html&quot;&gt;Yahoo! Finance&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and on plenty of regional properties. Adnan even begins training the Paradise Hills sales team on how to present the opportunity to potential residents. The speed of the collaboration is proof of a collective commitment to take this leap of faith, and a high-level of trust in each other and the possibilities. Another big reason for confidence: once the modeling was done, it was clear that this could be a massive financial opportunity for residents, one which could even pay off the cost of the house in a relatively short number of years.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;blog&#x2F;paradise_hills_connected.png&quot; alt=&quot;Paradise Hills Connected&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ThreeFold &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;farm&quot;&gt;3Node&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; will be a standard “appliance” in each Paradise Hills residence, much like a refrigerator or an oven. But this appliance is anything but “standard” – it provides and connects decentralized Internet capacity owned by the Paradise Hills community, and comes with an onboarding guide to welcome each resident into the much larger ThreeFold community.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further, Paradise Hills is adamant about building tools on top of the ThreeFold Grid – digital storefronts for local businesses, peer-to-peer marketplaces and forums or chats for the residents, and whatever else is deemed to be needed. The collaboration with ThreeFold essentially turns Paradise Hills into a sovereign “smart” community, where even the footage from the security cameras on premise can be stored locally and privately.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-community-comes-together&quot;&gt;The community comes together&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flash forward to a few weeks ago, the early Paradise Hills community gathers together for a gala. ThreeFold co-founder and tech guru Weynand Kuijpers has the chance to speak in front of the group. He speaks about the early days of the Internet, how it was hijacked by Big Tech turning people into products, and how now there is a new model for the Internet by people, for people. “You are some of the first to do this,” he says to the crowd.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;blog&#x2F;paradise_hills_partners.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Partners of Paradise Hills&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afterwards, residents come up and express their excitement, even if they don’t quite understand all the details. One woman in particular asks, “Can you please explain to me how having this device in my home won’t impact my privacy or security?” Adnan goes on to describe how the 3Node is actually there to preserve privacy and security. “A 3Node is just like a solar panel, only instead of electricity, it provides Internet capacity for local usage. In fact, any data that’s in your home is just a fragment of a piece of a puzzle, so it’s inaccessible to you or anyone else for that matter.” Overall, there is a clear feeling that contributing to this new Internet Grid will bring a unifying force to the community, and a deeper sense of meaning for what it means to be a resident of Paradise Hills.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;bringing-paradise-to-the-world&quot;&gt;Bringing Paradise to the world&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paradise Hills is a first of its kind partnership, but it is only the first. We at ThreeFold see incredible opportunities to scale this model across the world, and not only in real estate developments. Imagine if we apply this to lower-income and affordable housing communities, or colleges and universities. Hardware gifted to residents that connect together to form a localized part of a truly sovereign Internet Grid, on top of which useful community tools can be built – all while generating passive token rewards for the residents. A ground-up model. A global concept, applied locally.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the Paradise Hills story inspires you, and you have an idea for how to bring this model elsewhere, we invite you to take action. Head to the ThreeFold Forum, create a topic under the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;about-the-paradise-hills-model-category&#x2F;2632&quot;&gt;Paradise Hills Model&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; category, and let’s spread this to the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Coverage in Crypto Daily</title>
		<published>2022-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/03/post-04/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/03/post-04/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;🗞 &lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold in the News&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; 🗞&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Through this historic partnership, Paradise Hills and ThreeFold will provide every homeowner of the gated residence with a pre-installed 3Node, a dedicated server that provides the edge computing and internet storage needed to run decentralized applications and internet services.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ThreeFold Is Bringing The Power Of Blockchain And The Decentralized Cloud To A Dubai Neighborhood, via Crypto Daily.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full article &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cryptodaily.co.uk&#x2F;2022&#x2F;03&#x2F;threefold-is-bringing-the-power-of-blockchain-and-the-decentralized-cloud-to-a-dubai-neighborhood&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;More to come, as we’re in talks with other communities to scale this model across the globe.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; 🌍&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Tree-Planting is Underway for a Planet-Positive Internet</title>
		<published>2022-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/03/post-03/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/03/post-03/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;🌳 &lt;strong&gt;Tree-Planting is underway to enable a planet-positive Internet&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three big Take Action Global and ThreeFold sponsored tree-planting initiatives have gotten started in Malawi 🇲🇼, Cambodia 🇰🇭, and Sierra Leone 🇸🇱 – and soon in the Philippines 🇵🇭 – with &lt;strong&gt;more than 5,000 trees planted so far&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;newsroom&#x2F;students_trees.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Students&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These actions will help to enable ThreeFold as &lt;strong&gt;the first planet-positive peer-to-peer Internet&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; infrastructure on earth. Sending so much love to the children and teachers involved in this project. 💚&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For project details and to get involved, visit https:&#x2F;&#x2F;earthproject.org&#x2F;treeplanting&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More updates to come.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In case you missed it, check out &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-on-track-to-be-planet-positive&#x2F;2097&quot;&gt;our previously-shared plans&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to enable a regenerative Internet for all! You can find plenty of details in our three-part series.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Paradise Hills Property Development and ThreeFold to Establish the World’s First Neighborhood Cloud in Dubai</title>
		<published>2022-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/03/post-01/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/03/post-01/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;DUBAI, United Arab Emirates | Real Estate developer Paradise Hills and ThreeFold have announced today their plans to add dedicated servers (3Nodes) to approximately 170 homes in the Paradise Hill project, creating the world’s first neighborhood Cloud Network on the ThreeFold Grid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through this historic partnership, Paradise Hills Development and ThreeFold aim to provide every homeowner of the gated residence with a pre-installed 3Node, a dedicated server that provides the edge computing and internet storage needed to run decentralized applications and internet services. The initiative will provide residents, businesses, developers and the government with a secure and highly available sovereign cloud infrastructure to store and process their data locally.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;newsroom&#x2F;3nodehands.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3Node&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Paradise Hills is set to become the region’s center for true decentralization and the future of tomorrow’s Internet, essentially setting the standard for real estate developments and homeownership globally,” CEO Shaher Mousli of Paradise Hills Development said about the partnership.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This historic collaboration is the first pilot in a series of initiatives by ThreeFold to help expand the digital landscape of the United Arab Emirates (UAE),” says Adnan Fatayerji, co-founder of ThreeFold. “It will support the development of edge computing, smart cities and IoT, showcasing the power of the private sector to build and drive digital empowerment initiatives in support of the Digital Dubai vision set by the Emirates leadership.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last decade, “data sovereignty” became a key topic globally, with many countries insisting that any data produced locally should be stored on Internet infrastructures within their borders. By bringing ThreeFold’s decentralized Internet infrastructure to real estate properties such as Paradise Hills, the UAE will be home to the first-of-its-kind, self-sovereign, smart city development in the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Through simple, secure, and scalable technology, ThreeFold empowers millions to invent and explore new experiences,” added ThreeFold co-founder Kristof de Spiegeleer. “We want to empower local businesses, creators, and communities to build a more sustainable and inclusive future.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You and your communities can participate in the expansion and interconnection of the decentralized Internet as well! More information &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;farm&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>A Conversation with Jeroen Douglas</title>
		<published>2022-02-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-02-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/02/post-08/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/02/post-08/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;👂 &lt;strong&gt;Lend us your ear!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Is it possible to make a password-free Internet for one dollar owned by data smallholders? How to overcome the digital divide and reclaim the Internet from big tech?&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An enlightening conversation between ThreeFold co-founder Weynand Kuijpers and Solidaridad Network (ThreeFold partner) Executive Director Jeroen Douglas. 👇&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.buzzsprout.com&#x2F;1733439&#x2F;10113617&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Recently, we re-engaged with Solidaridad around their Fair Data initiative. &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;solidaridad-revival&#x2F;2158&quot;&gt;Take a look&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Realizing a Planet-Positive Internet</title>
		<published>2022-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/02/post-03/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2022/02/post-03/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;🧳 &lt;strong&gt;Grid V2 to Grid V3 Migration Update&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Together with Take Action Global 🤝 we are taking real action to make the ThreeFold Grid the first planet-positive 🌍 Internet infrastructure in the world.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a look at our three-part series to explore these efforts:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-on-track-to-be-planet-positive&#x2F;2097&#x2F;3&quot;&gt;Pt I: ThreeFold on track to be planet-positive&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;supporting-initiatives-to-regenerate-the-planet&#x2F;2110&quot;&gt;Pt II: Supporting initiatives to regenerate the planet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;driving-regeneration-with-tag&#x2F;2120&quot;&gt;Pt III: Driving regeneration with Take Action Global&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can support a planet-positive Internet by becoming a farmer! All you have to do is connect capacity to the grid and you’re effortlessly contributing to the regeneration of our planet, as this model will allow all farms to become planet positive by default.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;shop.threefold.tech&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Buy a Certified 3Node&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;farming&#x2F;threefold__diy_guide&quot;&gt;Build a DIY 3Node&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Mentioned in the News</title>
		<published>2021-12-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-12-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/12/post-021/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/12/post-021/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;🗞 &lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold in the News&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; 🗞&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, data processing infrastructure is in short supply throughout Africa… ”700 new data centers“ would have to be built to meet current demand in Africa… &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To connect end-users in Africa&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; to a pipeline of instantaneous processing capacity, Computecoin is &lt;strong&gt;joining forces&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; with a few other key players such as Crust and ThreeFold. CCN’s unique protocol will optimize computing resources provided by Crust’s Web3.0 storage platform and &lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold’s p2p network&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;ensure the computing resources are efficiently deployed&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; through the CCN network.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;via Bloomberg Business&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full article &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.bloomberg.com&#x2F;press-releases&#x2F;2021-12-21&#x2F;helping-africa-go-digital-a-metaverse-startup-is-working-with-an-ngo-to-expand-digital-infrastructure-in-africa&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold and Take Action Global in the News</title>
		<published>2021-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/12/post-17/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/12/post-17/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;🗞 &lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold in the News&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; 🗞&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The collaboration with ThreeFold is a perfect fit with our shared goal to bring access to the world and inspire change by providing opportunities for students to take action on social good causes through education and technology. We want to raise the bar of education by having experts teach the students and by initiating teacher training with help of their advanced technology,” Koen Timmers, Executive Director of Take Action Global.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ThreeFold and Take Action Global Partner to Bring Internet Access to 1 Billion People Across the Globe, via MarTech Series&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full article &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;martechseries.com&#x2F;technology&#x2F;threefold-and-take-action-global-partner-to-bring-internet-access-to-1-billion-people-across-the-globe&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Learn more about &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.takeactionglobal.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Take Action Global&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>DigiThree Labs is live!</title>
		<published>2021-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/11/post-18/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/11/post-18/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DigiThree Labs is live!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; 🚀&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DigiThree combines ThreeFold’s peer-to-peer technology and the vast benefits of the DigiByte blockchain to protect and elevate enterprises into the metaverse, our digital future.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🌐 https:&#x2F;&#x2F;digithreelabs.com&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Partner TAG Celebrates Climate Action Day</title>
		<published>2021-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/11/post-4/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/11/post-4/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We have some &lt;strong&gt;big plans cooking&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; with our friends and partners at Take Action Global (TAG) – more on that later this month!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, &lt;strong&gt;we invite you to celebrate &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.climate-action.info&#x2F;day&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Climate Action Day&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, hosted by TAG – the culminating celebration of the Climate Action Project, a six-week initiative involving 2.7 million people across 145 countries. 🌍&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around 18:40 CET, &lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold co-founder Adnan Fateyerji will deliver a message&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; to the students and teachers who participated in the program, and TAG Executive Director &lt;strong&gt;Koen Timmers will be sharing about ThreeFold &amp;amp; TAG&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; with their global audience. 🙏&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Climate Action Day will stream live at the blue zone of COP26 and for global audiences online.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;During the event, students and teachers will present questions to speakers such as Prince William, youth activist Elizabeth Wathuti, and representatives from WWF and NASA, and will showcase potential solutions for climate change.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;More information: https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.climate-action.info&#x2F;day&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Event starts at 1pm CET &#x2F; 8am EST.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Announcing DigiThree Labs</title>
		<published>2021-10-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-10-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/10/post-28/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/10/post-28/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;🚨 &lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;digicorplabs.com&quot;&gt;DigiCorp Labs&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; have joined forces to form DigiThree Labs&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, bringing together ThreeFold and DigiByte technologies and strong shared beliefs around decentralization, security, and privacy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DigiThree will deliver secure and private next-level solutions for people and enterprises, for a better tomorrow. Built on the DigiMetaverse, a decentralized foundational layer for the Metaverse.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More to come. 👀&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Find the news &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;threefold_io&#x2F;status&#x2F;1453759609911619591&quot;&gt;on Twitter&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as well! We’d love your support in getting the word out.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Why is ThreeFold P2P Cloud the better solution for customers than Amazon Web Services or Microsoft Azure?</title>
		<published>2021-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/10/post-6/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/10/post-6/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As we’ve recently been exploring decentralized &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;project_comparison_1_dfinity&#x2F;&quot;&gt;projects&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to see where ThreeFold is in the space and where we stand out, we thought it’s a good time to also look into how we compare to traditional, centralized cloud providers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cloud market is a highly complex and competitive one, currently &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.srgresearch.com&#x2F;articles&#x2F;amazon-and-microsoft-maintain-their-grip-market-others-are-also-growing-rapidly&quot;&gt;dominated&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; by the market leaders Amazon Web Services (AWS) and Microsoft Azure who account for more than half of the worldwide cloud revenues. This centralized nature of today’s cloud as well as its hyper-scale data center model are the cause for various issues, ranging from the monopolistic power of the few big market players and vendor lock-in effects to the incredibly high energy consumption of data centers and the limited scalability of the current model. Moreover, traditional data centers are more prone to outages and cyber attacks. We believe the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;grid&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; built by independent farmers around the globe and our &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cloud.threefold.io&quot;&gt;ThreeFold P2P Cloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; provide a solution to all of these issues.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While centralized cloud providers do offer some benefits, such as robust feature sets and huge customer service teams, there are a few key and important differences we think any customer would care about:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;decentralization&quot;&gt;Decentralization&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the biggest and most obvious difference. Today, big tech holds a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.srgresearch.com&#x2F;articles&#x2F;amazon-and-microsoft-maintain-their-grip-market-others-are-also-growing-rapidly&quot;&gt;monopoly&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on the Internet and Cloud markets, meaning they somehow became the gatekeepers of what was originally intended to be a distributed, neutral Internet. When using AWS or Google Cloud, the data is stored in centralized data centers owned by private corporations. These data centers are susceptible to hacking and outages that can take down massive chunks of the Internet. In this system, people have become products, as they exchange their &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;data_leaks&#x2F;&quot;&gt;data&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for “free” online experiences. With &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;mission&quot;&gt;ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, data is stored fully decentralized on the peer-to-peer ThreeFold Grid, where the physical hardware is owned by independent ThreeFold &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;farm&quot;&gt;Farmers&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and the data is owned by as well as only accessible to the person(s) who put it there. So, hackers can’t get in and due to the decentralized nature of the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;grid&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, large-scale outages would be much less likely as well. Further, no organization or entity needs to be trusted and people are not treated as products – with ThreeFold’s infrastructure, the Internet is owned &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;tf_grid_peoples_internet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;by the people&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;limitless-scalability-at-the-edge&quot;&gt;Limitless Scalability at the Edge&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our lightweight operating system &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tech&#x2F;zero-os&quot;&gt;Zero-OS&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; makes it possible and even easy to install a node close to where the data is being consumed. There is no need for large servers, nor for heavy power supply installations. Together with our hardware partner, we’re offering &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;farm&quot;&gt;3Nodes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; with plug-and-play functionalities, allowing &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;join_the_peoples_internet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;anyone to participate&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. This makes our model infinitely scalable at the edge. Hyper-scale data centers are not able to provide these levels of scalability and edge benefits. In order to scale their operations, centralized cloud providers need to build more data centers and take care of the related maintenance which takes time and costs billions. The traditional data center model also isn’t well suited for the edge, as this requires flexibility and close proximity to the respective data.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;security&quot;&gt;Security&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Centralized clouds are secure, but vulnerable. At ThreeFold, we pride ourselves on the levels of security we’re providing. The &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tech&#x2F;peer-to-peer&quot;&gt;peer-to-peer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; nature of our technology means end-to-end transmission of data between parties (with no middlemen). This is a big one: Nothing is being stored or copied in central servers. Moreover, ThreeFold’s self-driving and self-healing IT removes the need for human intervention and eliminates the many back doors present in current architecture. So, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;critical-security-updates-for-apple-and-google-underline-need-for-secure-it-ecosystem&#x2F;1271&quot;&gt;security issues&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; caused by human error and hacking possibilities both diminish greatly. In addition to that, there is the distributed storage algorithm which makes it nearly impossible for data to be lost. And much more. You can find more info on our &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;threefold__usp_secure?id=network-security&quot;&gt;wiki&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or in this &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;security-privacy-on-the-threefold-grid-and-second-best-alternatives-out-there-today&#x2F;1290&quot;&gt;forum post&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;privacy&quot;&gt;Privacy&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact that you &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;threefold_data_sovereignty&#x2F;&quot;&gt;own your data&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and nobody – not even us – can get access to it is key to making ThreeFold much more private than centralized cloud providers. On top of that, connections within our global overlay network, the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;how-our-planetary-network-works&#x2F;1210&quot;&gt;Planetary Network&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, are peer-to-peer and end-to-end encrypted.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;affordability&quot;&gt;Affordability&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, the centralized cloud is quite expensive, whereas our ThreeFold P2P Cloud is much more cost-effective. Learn more about this in our cloud pricing comparison &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;pricing&#x2F;threefold__cloud_pricing_compare&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;energy-efficiency&quot;&gt;Energy Efficiency&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While electricity for storing and transporting data, administration, human resources, and even gas (to transport physical data-holding devices) lead to a very high energy consumption, our dispersed storage model and peer-to-peer infrastructure allow for &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;sustainability&#x2F;threefold__energy_savings_storage&quot;&gt;significant energy savings&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. So, another big difference between ThreeFold and centralized cloud providers is that we’re up to 100x more &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;new.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;for_our_planet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;energy-efficient&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, the combination of our &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;grid&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cloud.threefold.io&quot;&gt;ThreeFold P2P Cloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; provide significant advantages over centralized cloud providers with their hyper-scale data centers. From decentralization and infinite scalability at the edge to considerable energy savings and cost effectiveness as well as data privacy and security, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;africa.businessinsider.com&#x2F;local&#x2F;markets&#x2F;ambitious-startup-to-disrupt-the-internet-and-cloud&#x2F;b38rwj4&quot;&gt;our solution&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; has much more value to offer, while solving critical issues related to centralized clouds. If you’d like to test our cloud solution yourself, take a look &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;info&#x2F;cloud#&#x2F;cloud__evdc_getting_started&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. You can also start participating in our decentralized ecosystem by becoming a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;shop.threefold.tech&#x2F;index.php?route=common&#x2F;home&quot;&gt;3Node&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on our ThreeFold Grid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>How to Deploy ownCloud on the ThreeFold Grid</title>
		<published>2021-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-30/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-30/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Following up on recent news:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We wanted to share &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=2ZkpsG6dQvw&quot;&gt;the demo&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of how to deploy ownCloud on top of the ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; – which was first showcased to the ownCloud ecosystem this Monday at ownCloud Conference 2021.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The demo itself starts at 13:30, and takes under ten minutes.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ownCloud and ThreeFold Announce Partnership</title>
		<published>2021-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-28/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-28/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Based on their shared commitment to data sovereignty and open alternatives, ownCloud and ThreeFold have agreed to enter into a strategic partnership to advance the decentralization of the consumer cloud. ownCloud is an open-source file sync, share and content collaboration software that lets teams work on data easily from anywhere, on any device. ThreeFold is developing a peer-to-peer Internet platform that aims to liberalize what it labels as a centralized and unequally distributed Internet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;now-available-owncloud-on-the-threefold-grid&quot;&gt;Now available: ownCloud on the ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step in the partnership is &lt;strong&gt;the launch of the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.owncloud.com&quot;&gt;ownCloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; instance on the ThreeFold Grid – &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=2ZkpsG6dQvw&quot;&gt;demoed live&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; at ownCloud Conference 2021&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; – and &lt;strong&gt;the development of  a pilot program (register your interest by emailing testowncloud@threefold.io)&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. The long-term vision is &lt;strong&gt;a full range of file sync, file sharing and content collaboration solutions&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; that combine the strengths of both technologies. ThreeFold and ownCloud are excited to develop complementary offerings that reflect their shared beliefs in open standards and digital sovereignty. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“ownCloud is partnering with ThreeFold to deliver a solution for customers with the demand for data sovereignty, privacy, and ultra-security of their data assets. ownCloud powered by ThreeFold Grid delivers on these exact attributes offering a truly decentralized, secure and scalable infrastructure to complement the proven and globally adopted ownCloud collaboration platform,” Joerg Eberwein, VP Partners &amp;amp; Alliances, ownCloud GmbH.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;decentralized-infrastructure&quot;&gt;Decentralized infrastructure&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&quot;&gt;ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; built the world’s most decentralized, secure and scalable digital infrastructure. They already have the largest decentralized cloud infrastructure in the world with about 80,000,000 GB deployed across 50 countries, and counting. The ThreeFold Cloud represents the first fully comprehensive decentralized cloud and is integrated with industry-leading tools and protocols for a seamless transition towards web3. Anything that runs on Linux can run on ThreeFold, but better.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“ownCloud powered by ThreeFold offers a purposeful use case of the ThreeFold Grid and aligns with our mission to ensure data privacy and sovereignty for everyone. Combining the longstanding credibility of ownCloud and the decentralized cloud technology of ThreeFold results in a 1+1=3 value statement,” Chris Hutton, Co-Founder, ThreeFold Tech.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;hosting-via-smart-contract&quot;&gt;Hosting via smart contract&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold allows people to host their own applications anywhere on their decentralized cloud infrastructure via smart contract. This provides a powerful solution for ownCloud users to host their collaboration tools anywhere they want, independently from conventional, centralized cloud providers, and without having to maintain the servers and software themselves.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;free-from-censorship-and-user-tracking&quot;&gt;Free from censorship and user tracking&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ownCloud can be installed anywhere, providing a secure and sovereign alternative to public cloud providers ​​for more than 200 million users worldwide as of today.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With ownCloud running on the ThreeFold Grid infrastructure, users can manage their “own” cloud on a neutral cloud infrastructure that is free from censorship, user tracking and privacy breaches. This is made possible by Zero-OS, ThreeFold’s stateless and lightweight operating system that allows servers to run autonomously. The self-driving and self-healing features eliminate backdoors and reduce the hacking surface, to keep ownCloud instances secure at all times.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;joining-forces-for-improved-governance-reliability-and-security&quot;&gt;Joining forces for improved governance, reliability and security&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ownCloud and ThreeFold have a history of delivering technical collaborations amongst various projects. While ownCloud excels at delivering secure and private collaboration platforms, ThreeFold offers a robust and flexible large-scale cloud layer. Combining both projects provides new possibilities in regards to governance, reliability and security for users and their data. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the highly anticipated 3rd release of ThreeFold’s technology expected to launch this quarter, &lt;strong&gt;ownCloud and ThreeFold are preparing a pilot program&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; to leverage their infrastructure and software expertise to deliver truly self-sovereign collaboration solutions in the world. ownCloud and ThreeFold are currently working out the details of their pilot program, which will be announced at a future date.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the two are &lt;strong&gt;planning a cross-community event&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, where community members can learn more about the two technologies and hear further details about the collaboration.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Join our beta tester group by sending an email to testowncloud@threefold.io to be amongst the first to try ownCloud on a self-sovereign environment!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-owncloud&quot;&gt;About ownCloud&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ownCloud develops and provides open-source software for content collaboration, allowing teams to easily share and work on files seamlessly regardless of device or location. More than 200 million users worldwide already use ownCloud as an alternative to public clouds - and thereby opt for more digital sovereignty, security and data protection. For further information, please visit &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.owncloud.com&quot;&gt;www.owncloud.com&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or on Twitter &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;ownCloud&quot;&gt;@ownCloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-threefold&quot;&gt;About ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold is developing a peer-to-peer internet platform that aims to liberalize what it labels as a centralized and unequally distributed internet. Its platform, called the ThreeFold Grid, comprises over +1000 servers in 50+ different countries around the world, delivering approximately 80 PB in storage and over 22,000 CPU cores worldwide, making it the largest storage and compute peer-to-peer internet network in the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each server runs ThreeFold’s stateless and lightweight open-source operating system, Zero-OS, and is set up and operated by independent individuals and organisations called Farmers. Farmers earn rewards in TFT - the platform’s native token - for their participation. TFT is the currency of the ThreeFold Grid, with each token representing a unit of storage and compute on the platform. Grid users can use these tokens to reserve the storage and compute they need to store, build and share on the platform’s internet network.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, visit &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&quot;&gt;www.threefold.io&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or follow along on Twitter &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;threefold_io&quot;&gt;@threefold_io&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Grid Utilization Plan – Part 2</title>
		<published>2021-09-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-09-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-2/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/09/post-2/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Today, we’re sharing &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;grid-utilization-plan-part-two&#x2F;1203&quot;&gt;part two&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of our ThreeFold Grid Utilization Plan.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
It highlights &lt;strong&gt;some of our main partnerships&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, which together can bring &lt;strong&gt;many millions of users&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; to the grid.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;If you missed part one (TF Grid Solutions), be sure to check it out &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;grid-utilization-plan-part-one&#x2F;1157&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Art &amp; Culture in VR: Coming to the ThreeFold Grid</title>
		<published>2021-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/08/post-2/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/blog/2021/08/post-2/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last year at a ThreeFold gathering, a few of us on the team had the pleasure to meet a man named Vasily, a creative mind with a big heart and proud founder of Artheon. Artheon, in its essence, was a virtual reality museum experience focused on bringing fine art and culture from around the world directly to people. The concept was immediately captivating, and the demo brought it to life for us. The graphics were already solid, and being able to walk around a museum and interact with the artwork was a unique experience to say the least. We talked about the implications and his greater vision around access and education, and it was very clear we needed to partner up. Not long after, Artheon and ThreeFold joined forces.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-what-is-the-partnership-all-about&quot;&gt;So what is the partnership all about?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together with ThreeFold, Artheon aims to create the world’s largest open art database – made for everyone, and owned by everyone. We will provide access to art and cultural heritage to people around the world, without borders. Not just access, but a high-quality and high-resolution virtual reality experience where people can really immerse themselves in their surrounding environment. With Artheon, people can now even touch and hold paintings or artifacts, something that would clearly not be possible in real life. And while today, only a select few (relative to the total global population) have the opportunity to travel and to experience museums and cultural &amp;amp; sacred sites, Artheon will change that!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
It’s not only about experience, though, it’s also about community and education and providing a more equal access to art and cultural objects. We’ll bring together a global community of museums, artists, and art seekers who can not only enjoy, but also teach and learn about the art and cultural objects housed within the Artheon universe. For Artheon, it’s imperative
that people are able to access information about the artists and the art itself, and then make and share their own perceptions as well. No need or pressure to follow the direction of the current system’s ideology. This is a different angle from how we traditionally learn at school, where narrow or accepted views and concepts are imposed upon us. A key aim of Artheon is to bring different perspectives through collective, participatory, and experiental teaching and learning.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Looking ahead, the vision is that people will be able to create their own virtual spaces and expose them on Artheon. They can create something from scratch or even re-imagine a historical site as it was long ago and share it with the community.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-does-threefold-benefit-artheon&quot;&gt;How does ThreeFold benefit Artheon?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the start, there was a clear connection between Artheon and ThreeFold from a vision, values, and ethos perspective. But there are also some more specific reasons why Artheon chose and benefits from ThreeFold, which mainly revolve around the decentralized nature of the ThreeFold Grid.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Virtual and augmented reality (VR and AR) provide significant benefits to our new digital reality. These technologies open new ways of sharing information in areas such as the arts in the case of Artheon, allowing for upgraded and immersive experiences for users.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Decentralized clouds have been associated with the promise of new digital applications and services that come with a hyper-connected life. Because the graphics of VR&#x2F;AR experiences require heavy rendering, on-device processes are augmented by splitting workloads between the VR&#x2F;AR device and a decentralized cloud. So, graphics rendering on a decentralized cloud like what the ThreeFold Grid provides would be significantly improved by achieving a much lower latency. Another advantage of the ThreeFold Grid is that it provides an extremely high level of security and privacy, empowering Artheon and its users with real data sovereignty.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
And finally, Artheon experienced an unfortunate event earlier this summer where their servers suffered from an intense heat wave and essentially burned up. There was no backup, and this would have been catastrophic in the scenario of them having millions of users. Good thing they aren’t live yet, but this is a great example of how centralized models fail. With a decentralized infrastructure like ThreeFold, this type of situation would not have occured, as data would be hosted on many locations.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
So, by distributing the computing power closer to their users, a VR experience such as Artheon would not only improve their latency speed, security, and privacy, but also the resilience of their business model. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-the-status-of-artheon-and-its-partnership-with-threefold&quot;&gt;What is the status of Artheon (and its partnership with ThreeFold)?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past year, Artheon has been making incredible improvements to the graphics and experience, and adding as many new pieces of art as possible into the universe. As you can imagine, the possibilities really are endless, but here are some of the milestones planned for the rest of this year:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Planning to add partial DLC (downloadable content) support and photogrammetry-scanned locations for users to experience&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New UI for desktop (Windows, MacOS, Linux)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implementation of desired social features such as follower and friend system&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People will be able to see who of their friends or people they follow are online – from that, they can connect to a server and join them to share experiences together&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People will also be able to see how many people are online at the moment and where they are located on the globe (if permissions are allowed)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow the possibility for museums to host free or closed paid exhibitions&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Artheon will be hosted on the ThreeFold Grid!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-can-you-do-now-to-get-involved&quot;&gt;What can you do now to get involved?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re reading this section, we’re thrilled you are interested in what is happening with Artheon! We are, too! As Artheon is not yet live, the best option for you is to join &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;artheon&quot;&gt;the Artheon Early Access chat on Telegram&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; where you can stay tuned there for updates and ask questions directly to Artheon’s creators and contributors.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ODE and ThreeFold Announce Partnership</title>
		<published>2021-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/08/post-5/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/08/post-5/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, we’re pleased to announce a partnership between ThreeFold Tech and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;odeinfinity.com&quot;&gt;ODE&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, the world’s first vertically integrated consumer data ecosystem. ODE is creating a future where enterprises become trusted partners to their digital consumers, offering an application platform that enables privacy for digital consumers, lean data science, and compliance for enterprises. Built on blockchain and AI, ODE Infinity defines a new paradigm for digital engagement for enterprises.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ODE recognizes the need for a secure, scalable, and cost-effective global infrastructure platform that complements the key attributes of ODE and furthermore meets the attributes demanded by more and more customers today. Priority attributes include data sovereignty and privacy, true decentralization, no lock-in, scalability, and ultra-security (to name a few).
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold technology and the ThreeFold Grid offers such an infrastructure platform and meets these exact attributes demanded by the customers today. ThreeFold brings a truly decentralized compute and storage network that ensures the privacy and sovereignty of customer data, scalability, cost efficiency, and ultimately a digital infrastructure that is far more sustainable for our planet.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
“The collaboration between ODE and ThreeFold is a tremendous win for enterprises and consumers that are wrestling to find a balance between data privacy, compliance, and business growth to build trust. Our joint offering does exactly that by creating a decentralized data ecosystem that enables enterprises to become trusted partners to their digital consumers. The new world where privacy is by design, usage is by consent, and value realization is unlimited and mutual,” says ODE CEO Sashi Edupuganti. “The synergy between ODE and ThreeFold will accelerate the journey toward a more decentralized and democratic way to manage and use consumer data.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ODE and ThreeFold Tech have now signed a collaborative agreement to deliver solutions that accelerate their collective mission of democratizing data and creating greater data management capabilities for enterprises, and self-determination and sovereignty for all people. We will update as this partnership evolves.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-ode&quot;&gt;About ODE&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Headquartered in Tempe, Arizona with employees around the world, ODE (Open Data Economy) was recently recognized as the Top 100 Company in 2021 at Intercon2021, Las Vegas and the Top 30 most innovative companies of 2020 by CIO Bulletin. As a revolutionary startup that is building a more equitable data economy for all, ODE Infinity is the world’s first vertically integrated consumer data ecosystem. ODE is creating a future where enterprises become trusted partners to their digital consumers and eases the burden of data management for those enterprises. Their application platform, built on blockchain and AI, enables privacy for digital consumers, lean data science, and compliance for enterprises. ODE Infinity defines a new paradigm for digital engagement for enterprises and consumers, alike.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more, visit &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;odeinfinity.com&quot;&gt;odeinfinity.com&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-threefold&quot;&gt;About ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Headquartered in Belgium, and with employees worldwide, ThreeFold Tech has developed a decentralized cloud technology aimed to empower a p2p data economy where sovereignty, privacy, and equality are held paramount.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The ThreeFold Grid (powered by ThreeFold technology) is the largest and most advanced peer-to-peer compute and storage network in the world, which enables individuals and organizations to build and deploy their web2 and web3 applications in a complete decentralized, private, sustainable, and autonomous IT infrastructure through its peer-to-peer cloud capacity and developer tools.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold technology and the ThreeFold Grid offer a decentralized compute and storage network that ensures the privacy and sovereignty of consumer data, a quantum safe file system, scalability, cost efficiency, and ultimately a digital infrastructure that is sustainable and helps organizations address critical technological challenges.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more, visit &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&quot;&gt;threefold.io&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Artheon VR Museum is Coming to the Grid</title>
		<published>2021-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/07/post-15/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/07/post-15/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Artheon and ThreeFold joined forces to create the world’s largest VR database of art 🎨 and cultural heritage – owned by everyone and made for everyone.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
🔜 &lt;strong&gt;Coming to the ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; End of Q3 &#x2F; Beginning Q4.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;youtu.be&#x2F;Ofk22N2Ew1k&quot;&gt;Take a peak&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; at what museum visitors from around the world will soon be able to experience.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Decentralize the DigiByte Blockchain by Deploying a Node on the ThreeFold Grid</title>
		<published>2021-06-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-06-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-24/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-24/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today we are happy to share with you some news from our partnership with the DigiByte Foundation 🤝 &lt;strong&gt;how to decentralize the DigiByte Network by deploying a DigiByte Node on ThreeFold Grid!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
DigiByte Foundation’s Rudy Bouwman joins ThreeFold’s Weynand Kuijpers to discuss what it all means and how to deploy.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;👀 &lt;strong&gt;Watch the full video &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;youtu.be&#x2F;fBEwlfcyxgA&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you’re interested in deploying a DigiByte Node on the ThreeFold Grid, please fill out &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forms.gle&#x2F;NHDNkZppTzwRorz77&quot;&gt;this quick form&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and we will get in touch.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
More to come from DigiByte Foundation and ThreeFold – this is only the beginning! 🌅&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Zetako and ThreeFold Join Forces</title>
		<published>2021-06-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-06-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-15/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/06/post-15/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For both Zetako and ThreeFold, efficiency and sustainability are key. &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.zetako.ai&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Zetako&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a company dedicated to lossless data compression, and after years of research and development, has created an alternative solution to the regular standards of data compression. And with two decades of relevant experience and a focus on sustainability, ThreeFold has built new peer-to-peer Internet infrastructure and technologies from the ground up – where every aspect is optimized towards maximum efficiency and the least amount of harm to the planet.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both already members of &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;aci&quot;&gt;the Alliance for a Conscious Internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, a planetary movement of people and organizations that take action to shape a conscious digital world, Zetako and ThreeFold have now signed on to merge their technologies to bring forward hyper-efficient, secure, and private data transport and storage solutions for all.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
“The world has been using the same compression technology for the last 30 years, just like the model to deliver IT services has not changed,” says Weynand Kuijpers, ThreeFold Co-Founder. “ThreeFold challenges that status quo, where anybody can now be the Internet by adding capacity to the ThreeFold Grid – and with this, we need a 21st century compression and decompression technology. Zetako delivers that much-needed true innovation.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The ThreeFold Grid is live today, the world’s most advanced peer-to-peer Internet infrastructure. It can scale limitlessly, and brings a more performant, secure and sustainable Internet to host humanity’s data and workloads. ThreeFold technology already consumes 90 percent less energy than today’s solutions. (The company has also recently announced plans to offset energy usage 100 percent by the end of 2021, with the goal of taking two times more carbon out of the air than they put in.)
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
With its quantum safe storage offering, ThreeFold can now integrate with Zetako’s technology to store compressed data, enabling it to become even more efficient and sustainable. Further, ThreeFold can now do compression live on network connections between different parts of what users deploy.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
“We are particularly excited about the opportunity to work with ThreeFold as we believe they represent the future of data transmission &amp;amp; storage,” says Claus Rosenberg Gotthard, CEO of Zetako. “It’s the right place to implement Zetako’s innovative technologies of bit-by-bit compression.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In the short term, Zetako and ThreeFold will work on a project basis to fulfill specific organization requirements. Zetako provides the compression, and ThreeFold provides the compute and storage. As an example, with COVID-19 and the world moving increasingly digital, congesting the network, people and businesses that need a way to transfer large files quickly will now have a much more efficient way to do so. And in the longer term, the two will explore more ways to deeply integrate their technologies and provide broader solutions to the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-zetako&quot;&gt;About Zetako&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zetako is dedicated to reducing energy usage &amp;amp; CO2 emission for the transmission &amp;amp; storage of data by applying a new more efficient lossless data compression technology.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We have developed a new mathematical theory based on Statistical Predictive modeling and applied this to a new lossless data compression technology. The result is a technology that provides higher Compression at higher Speed and uses &amp;gt;70% less energy in the process. In addition to this, the technology is capable of doing bit-by-bit compression allowing for real time bandwidth reduction. The technology does not need a prior knowledge of the dataset to start compression. This means that our technology does not require the data stream to be chopped up into chunks – we apply compression the moment the first bit (1 or 0) comes in.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can learn more about Zetako at &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.zetako.ai&#x2F;&quot;&gt;zetako.ai&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-threefold&quot;&gt;About ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Powered by open source technology, ThreeFold is the engine for a data-sovereign and planet-positive peer-to-peer infrastructure – owned by humanity. ThreeFold is the People’s Internet.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold is formed by individuals and organizations from all around the world that connect 3Nodes (computers) and provide Internet capacity to the ThreeFold Grid. Together, we expand a data-sovereign and planet-positive Internet infrastructure, owned by the people.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone can get involved in the People’s Internet by buying the ThreeFold Token, getting a 3Node, testing the technology, or becoming a contributor or a partner. Visit &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&quot;&gt;threefold.io&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or follow along on &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldnews&quot;&gt;Telegram&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;threefold_io&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Dragonchain and ThreeFold Announce Collaboration</title>
		<published>2021-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/05/post-03/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/05/post-03/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dragonchain and ThreeFold share a common mission of providing developers and the digital world with a more inclusive and decentralized Internet infrastructure – one where data flows and is stored in a peer-to-peer environment, and where applications are computed by decentralized and community-owned protocols.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Today, Dragonchain and ThreeFold are proud to announce their partnership to further empower developers and enterprises around the world to build scalable dApps on Dragonchain, on ThreeFold’s peer-to-peer cloud.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold presents a more cost-effective, distributed, autonomous, secure, and sustainable alternative to centralized cloud-providers. Now, developers and enterprises building Web3 applications can leverage and deploy Dragonchain’s Blockchain and advanced smart-contracts into their dApps, with the added benefit of utilizing ThreeFold to completely decentralize their cloud computing infrastructure – and deploy their solutions on the edge.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold’s peer-to-peer environment combined with the Dragonchain ecosystem gives communities the ability to build their online presence without worrying about censorship over dissenting opinions, local outages, or unauthorized access to data.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
“It has alway been our belief that developers should have the freedom to build without restraint. We’re happy to partner with ThreeFold to provide the tools necessary to easily build applications for a decentralized environment,” Joe Roets, Chief Architect, Founder, CEO at Dragonchain.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Together, Dragonchain and ThreeFold are decreasing friction and opening more avenues for inclusion. The Dragonchain platform contains sophisticated and lightweight SDKs and enables enterprises to use their existing IT staff to deploy code in any coding language. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Further, the Dragonchain developer community can now build Web3-native and P2P cloud-native applications without the need for prior Blockchain experience. Developers now have access to scalable industry-standard solutions like Docker, Kubernetes, S3 storage – and ThreeFold’s Quantum Safe Filesystem – to build applications for a decentralized environment. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
As stated by Weynand Kuijipers, co-founder at ThreeFold, “dApps need to live outside the market-leading monopolies and we are proud to be able to provide secure, private and sovereign compute and storage capacity for the Dragonchain community.“
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Both ThreeFold and Dragonchain invite and support any and all Web2 and Web3 developers to build decentralized applications that have the potential to change the world and make it a better and more inclusive place for us all.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-dragonchain&quot;&gt;About Dragonchain&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dragonchain is a technology leader in the blockchain space, with security and scalability at the forefront of its operations. We are proudly U.S.-based and part of one of the most technologically rich communities in the country. We help companies break into blockchain faster, without forcing them to change their existing IT infrastructure. As a Blockchain as a Service provider built by seasoned members of the tech industry, Dragonchain understands the needs of enterprises and is designed to handle prevalent issues in several industries. Learn more at &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dragonchain.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Dragonchain.com&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Be sure to stay up to date on the latest at &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;dragonchaingang&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.linkedin.com&#x2F;company&#x2F;dragonchain&#x2F;&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;dragontalk&quot;&gt;Telegram&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;c&#x2F;DragonchainOfficial&quot;&gt;YouTube&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;dragonchain-inc&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-threefold&quot;&gt;About ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold is developing a peer-to-peer Internet platform that aims to liberalize what it labels as a centralized and unequally distributed Internet. Its platform, called the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;threefold__grid_home&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, comprises over +600 servers in 25+ different countries around the world, delivering approximately 80 PB in storage and over 16,000 CPU cores worldwide, making it the largest storage and compute peer-to-peer Internet network in the world. See ThreeFold Grid’s statistics in more detail using their explorer &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;explorer.threefold.io&#x2F;all&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each server runs ThreeFold’s stateless and lightweight open-source operating system, Zero-OS, and is set up and operated by independent individuals and organizations called Farmers. Farmers earn rewards in &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;threefold__token_home&quot;&gt;TFT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; - the platform’s native token - for their participation. TFT is the currency of the ThreeFold Grid, with each token representing a unit of storage and compute on the platform. Grid users can use these tokens to reserve the storage and compute they need to store, build and share on the platform’s internet network.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold’s ultimate vision is to be part of the movement to fully democratize the Internet worldwide. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&quot;&gt;threeFold.io&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to learn more, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&quot;&gt;forum.threefold.io&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to chat with the team, or stay updated &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldnews&quot;&gt;on Telegram&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold x CasperLabs Community Call Recording</title>
		<published>2021-04-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-04-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/04/post-16/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/04/post-16/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold Highlights at &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;youtu.be&#x2F;WYrARTeY3cY?t=863&quot;&gt;14:23&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and in the Q&amp;amp;A session at &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;youtu.be&#x2F;WYrARTeY3cY?t=2330&quot;&gt;38:50&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks again to the team at Casper for having us on. Looking forward to sharing more about where this partnership is going soon!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold Joins CasperLabs Community Call</title>
		<published>2021-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/04/post-13/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/04/post-13/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Today at 6pm CET &#x2F; 12pm EST,&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; ThreeFold co-founder Kristof de Siegeleer will be joining the Casper community call to introduce ThreeFold to the Casper community and to discuss our collaboration.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The call will be hosted &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=WYrARTeY3cY&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; We hope to see you there. 🙏
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kristof will be joining Ralf Kubli (Casper Association), Medha Parlikar (CTO, CasperLabs), Ashok Ranadive (Director, Pro Services, CasperLabs), and Piotr Dziubecki (Technical Project Manager, CasperLabs).&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>CasperLabs and ThreeFold Join Forces</title>
		<published>2021-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/04/post-7/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/04/post-7/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;CasperLabs and ThreeFold have a shared belief that decentralization is needed in order to build a better tomorrow. According to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;casperlabs.io&#x2F;en&#x2F;company&quot;&gt;CasperLabs&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, decentralization is “how we will create more open, transparent, permissionless networks powered by people — paving the way for a new era of equitable innovation.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Today, ThreeFold is thrilled to announce a collaborative partnership with CasperLabs. Together, we will further CasperLabs’ decentralization efforts while accelerating a collective mission and vision of more equally distributing global wealth and resources – doing so through creating more opportunity for people and enterprises around the world, without limits.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“ThreeFold and CasperLabs share a commitment to making web3 environments more accessible to all developers,” says Neil Kapoor of CasperLabs. “Now that Casper is live on mainnet, we look forward to collaborating with ThreeFold to deliver a truly scalable, secure and decentralized IT infrastructure for enterprise organizations building innovative, blockchain-based solutions.”&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through the partnership, developers and enterprises building on top of Casper technology will be able to choose to run on ThreeFold’s &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;cloud&quot;&gt;Peer-to-Peer Cloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for storage and compute resources. This will enable them to achieve security and scalability beyond what the centralized cloud providers can offer today.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
On a smaller scale, anyone will be able to contribute to Casper’s blockchain security, resiliency, scalability and decentralization, by deploying a Casper Validator node on the ThreeFold Grid in just a few clicks. The ThreeFold deployment mechanism removes all technical complexity of running Blockchain nodes.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;From ThreeFold co-founder Adnan Fatayerji, “We are extremely excited about our partnership with CasperLabs. Their platform is designed with simplicity and scale to drive global adoption amongst enterprises and developers. ThreeFold fits perfectly as a decentralized substrate (storage and compute) to provide all Casper customers with a truly decentralized, secure, and scalable alternative to current cloud providers.”&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-casperlabs&quot;&gt;About CasperLabs&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CasperLabs, the developer of the Casper Network, provides professional services and support for organizations building on the Casper Network. Guided by open source principles, CasperLabs is committed to supporting the next wave of blockchain adoption among businesses and providing developers with a reliable and secure framework to build private, public and hybrid blockchain applications. Its team possesses deep enterprise technology experience, hailing from organizations including Google, Adobe, AWS, Dropbox and Microsoft.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
CasperLabs recently held a successful token sale on CoinList and announced its mainnet launch.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more, visit &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;casperlabs.io&quot;&gt;casperlabs.io&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-threefold&quot;&gt;About ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold has developed the largest and most advanced peer-to-peer internet grid in the world, which enables individuals and organizations to build and deploy their web2 and web3 applications in a complete decentralized, private, sustainable, and autonomous IT infrastructure through its peer-to-peer cloud capacity and developer tools.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
With a collective and incentivized ecosystem of Farmers around the globe, the ThreeFold Grid has achieved 80+ petabytes of capacity, 18K+ CPU cores, distributed in 21 countries, and is constantly expanding across the edges. ThreeFold has technology partners such as HPE, DigiByte, Stellar, CasperLabs, Neo, Dash, TomoChain, HoloChain Harmony, WaykiChain, SelfKey and many others.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold aims to empower a more equal, autonomous, and sustainable world and does so by providing the necessary peer-to-peer technologies and infrastructure to the world while incentivizing growth in developing regions.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&quot;&gt;threeFold.io&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to learn more, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&quot;&gt;forum.threefold.io&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to chat with the team, or stay updated &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldnews&quot;&gt;on Telegram&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>We&#x27;re Tackling Internet Inequalities</title>
		<published>2021-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/03/post-14/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/03/post-14/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Let’s build an Internet for all, together.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Did you know?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold incentivizes the expansion of the ThreeFold Grid in developing regions. 🌏🌍
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We are partnering with Solidaridad to create fair supply chain and fair data for farmers around the world, particularly in the Global South. ✅
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
And we are partnering with Take Action Global to build an educational tool based on Digital Twin technology that will allow children around the world to learn and collaborate in a secure environment. ✏️📖&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold x Conscious Communities</title>
		<published>2021-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/02/post-12/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2021/02/post-12/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We’re in talks with an already-live, large-scale “conscious community” project to create their own independent grid of capacity!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Each home and business property would have its own node or nodes, and capacity would be used for a community-specific platform to improve communication, participation, and ease of life for residents – all in a fully private, secure, &amp;amp; efficient way.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We’re still in the early stages but we’re thrilled to have met this team and to be working towards a partnership that can be an incredible model for many other communities around the world. We will share more as we are able to!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Take a look at the Artheon VR Museum!</title>
		<published>2020-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/12/post-02/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/12/post-02/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Artheon Virtual Reality Museum&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; allows visitors to explore and interact with hundreds of thousands of pieces of fine art, with or without a VR headset!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a tour &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=Ofk22N2Ew1k&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Artheon will soon be hosted on top of the ThreeFold Grid, serviced by &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.green-edge.net&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Green Edge&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For early access and information, please join the Artheon Telegram group &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;artheon&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold and Presearch partner to decentralize search nodes and storage</title>
		<published>2020-11-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-11-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/11/post-08/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/11/post-08/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Privacy and decentralization are some of the values shared by both &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.presearch.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Presearch&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&quot;&gt;ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, at the core of their missions to create scalable technologies that can positively impact the lives of millions of individuals and enterprises around the globe.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Presearch and ThreeFold are thrilled to officially announce their collaborative partnership. Presearch is &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;presearch.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;a community-powered, decentralized search engine&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that provides better results while protecting your privacy and rewarding you when you search. And ThreeFold is the world’s largest peer-to-peer cloud, bringing privacy and security, cost-efficiencies, ease-of-use, and true IT decentralization to the market.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Presearch (and its node and storage infrastructure) will benefit from ThreeFold’s peer-to-peer cloud in two different ways:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-powering-presearch-node-operators-with-a-decentralized-cloud-infrastructure&quot;&gt;1. Powering Presearch node operators with a decentralized cloud infrastructure&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Presearch community will be able to deploy their Presearch nodes in a few clicks in a completely decentralized cloud infrastructure, using the ThreeFold peer-to-peer cloud and its developer tools. Thus, they can escape the monopolies of centralized cloud providers, and reduce the technical complexity of running Blockchain nodes. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Colin Pape, Presearch’s CEO, said in a statement, “We are excited to partner with the ThreeFold team to offer our community members an easy way to quickly deploy Presearch Nodes on ThreeFold decentralized peer-to-peer internet grid, the world’s largest server network powered by blockchain technology.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Presearch has recently opened its beta testing program for node operators looking to become part of the revolutionary network that is changing the way individuals around the world can search the web – in a significantly more private, inclusive, and rewarding environment. Anyone who believes in the decentralization of search engines should &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;presearchcommunity.typeform.com&#x2F;to&#x2F;UkDumktm&quot;&gt;sign up to their beta testers list&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and get in touch with Presearch to be one of the early adopters. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-leveraging-threefold-s-decentralized-storage-to-store-the-future-of-the-search-engine-experience&quot;&gt;2. Leveraging ThreeFold’s decentralized storage to store the future of the search engine experience&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presearch and ThreeFold are exploring the usage of ThreeFold’s decentralized storage capacity to store and archive Presearch’s indexes and other data running the search engine. The main goal is to provide an unbreakable data storage and backup infrastructure for the future of the search engine experience that the top-notch team behind Presearch is building.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In addition, ThreeFold looks forward to advocating for Presearch and integrating the decentralized search engine into its current and future solutions for a more private and inclusive internet experience.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;powering-the-threefold-community-s-search-engine-experience-with-presearch&quot;&gt;Powering the ThreeFold community’s search engine experience with Presearch&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold will be establishing Presearch’s decentralized search engine as its main search engine partner, advocating for its usage within its growing community of developers, cloud capacity farmers, enterprises, and users. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
As stated by Weynand Kuijpers, “Presearch is creating a search engine by people for people. The internet has moved from data sharing to centralized data harvesting. Presearch is undoing that by creating user control over data stored, presenting a (digital) return for contributing to the system and improving search results, and making it decentralized. ThreeFold is looking forward to co-creating a decentralized mechanism where the search engine is broken down and operates everywhere, and users are in control of their own identity and data.“
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
More to come as the partnership develops.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-presearch&quot;&gt;About Presearch:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of us are tired of Big Tech companies dominating the internet, censoring content and controlling the social narrative by manipulating information to fit an agenda. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Presearch provides improved access to information and increased search choice with its community-driven search engine that leverages blockchain technology and cryptocurrency to empower and reward users. More than 1.6 million people have already joined the service.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In 2020, Presearch launched its innovative keyword staking sponsorship platform that enables promoters to lock their Presearch PRE cryptocurrency tokens against different keywords in order to have their promotional ads displayed. More than 60 million PRE tokens have already been locked.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Now Presearch is launching a decentralized search engine that rewards node operators with PRE tokens when they run Presearch nodes. Through its partnership with ThreeFold, anyone will be able to easily launch a Presearch node running on the ThreeFold decentralized peer-to-peer internet grid with no technical knowledge required.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Visit &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;presearch.io&quot;&gt;presearch.io&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to learn more or join our Telegram community at &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;presearch&quot;&gt;t.me&#x2F;presearch&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-threefold&quot;&gt;About ThreeFold:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold has developed the largest and most advanced peer-to-peer internet grid in the world, which enables individuals and organizations to build and deploy their web2 and web3 applications in a complete decentralized, private, sustainable, and autonomous IT infrastructure through its peer-to-peer cloud capacity and developer tools.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
With a collective and incentivized ecosystem of Farmers around the globe, the ThreeFold Grid has achieved 80+ petabytes of capacity, 18K+ CPU cores, distributed in 21 countries, and is constantly expanding across the edges. ThreeFold has technology partners such as HPE, DigiByte, Stellar, Neo, Dash, TomoChain, HoloChain Harmony, WaykiChain, SelfKey and many others.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold aims to empower a more equal, autonomous, and sustainable world and does so by providing the necessary peer-to-peer technologies and infrastructure to the world while incentivizing growth in developing regions.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Visit &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&quot;&gt;threeFold.io&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to learn more, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&quot;&gt;forum.threefold.io&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to chat with the team, or stay updated on &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldnews&quot;&gt;Telegram&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold partners with SKALE to empower its developer community</title>
		<published>2020-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/08/post-01/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/08/post-01/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;skale.network&#x2F;&quot;&gt;SKALE&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&quot;&gt;ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; are perfectly aligned in their visions to build a truly decentralized internet and a scalable web3 infrastructure. Both focus on creating community-owned and scalable technologies that can positively impact the lives of millions of individuals and enterprises around the globe. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
SKALE and ThreeFold are excited to announce their collaborative partnership that will focus on solving scalability and decentralization limitations faced by Ethereum and Blockchain developers. This collaboration will also empower the SKALE developer community, and web3 developers, with the ThreeFold peer-to-peer cloud, enabling them to:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build highly scalable dApps on Ethereum using SKALE’s elastic Blockchain network.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Completely decentralize their IT infrastructure using ThreeFold’s P2P compute, storage, and networking capacities (providing far more affordability, privacy, and decentralization through its native cloud automation and Smart Contract for IT). 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Adnan Fatayerji, co-founder at ThreeFold said, &lt;em&gt;“SKALE is perfectly positioned to take Ethereum and its dApp developers to the next level while pioneering scaling solutions for the Blockchain industry! ThreeFold and SKALE form such an ideal fit in this regard. By combining SKALE’s modular protocol and ThreeFold’s universal substrate for decentralized storage and compute, developers are able to build highly scalable dApps and deploy workloads that are closer to the source, cost-effective, and easy to manage. We are excited to collaborate with the SKALE ecosystem!“&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The ThreeFold team is inviting node operators around the world to contribute to the SKALE ecosystem by deploying their SKALE validator nodes after Phase 3 Mainnet availability on the ThreeFold Grid and is calling for game-changing, conscious web3 developers to build impactful applications.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;“It’s been exciting to work with the ThreeFolds team as they build their vision for providing node operators with a platform to decentralize their IT infrastructure,”&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; said Christine Perry, VP Solutions Engineering, SKALE Labs. &lt;em&gt;“Not only do we share the mutual goal of a truly decentralized secure, scalable network. SKALE developers will be able use ThreeFold’s peer-to-peer cloud to more easily build highly scalable Ethereum Dapps.”&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-skale&quot;&gt;About SKALE:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SKALE is an elastic blockchain network that gives developers the ability to easily provision highly configurable fully decentralized chains that are instantly compatible with Ethereum. SKALE chains can execute sub-second block times, run up to 2,000 tps per chain, and run full-state smart contracts in addition to decentralized storage, execute Rollups, and machine learning in EVM. The SKALE Network is an open-source project with many contributors including SKALE Labs, Inc. whose offices are in San Francisco, CA, and Kharkiv, Ukraine. The SKALE Network’s supporters include Blockchange, ConsenSys Labs, Hashed, HashKey, Floodgate, Multicoin Capital, Recruit Holdings, Signia VP, and Winklevoss Capital. The SKALE Network is supported by top validators in the world including Blockware, ConsenSys, Chorus One, Dokia, Figment Networks, Hashed, Staked, and StakewithUs, as well as key infrastructure players Bison Trails, Blockdaemon and Ankr. For more information please visit &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.skale.network&quot;&gt;skale.network&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;skalenetwork&quot;&gt;@SkaleNetwork&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on Twitter, and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;skaleofficial&quot;&gt;@skaleofficial&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on telegram.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-threefold&quot;&gt;About ThreeFold:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold has developed the largest and most advanced peer-to-peer internet grid in the world, that enables individuals and organizations  to build and deploy their web2 and web3 applications in a complete decentralized, private, sustainable, and autonomous IT infrastructure through its peer-to-peer cloud capacity and developer tools. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
With a collective and incentivized ecosystem of Farmers around the globe, the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; has achieved 80+ petabytes of capacity, 18K+ CPU cores, distributed in 21 countries, and is constantly expanding across the edges. ThreeFold has a broad array of technology partners such as HPE, DigiByte, Stellar, Neo, Dash, TomoChain,  HoloChain Harmony, WaykiChain, SelfKey  and many others. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold aims to empower a more equal, autonomous, and sustainable world and does so by providing the necessary peer-to-peer technologies and infrastructure to the world while incentivizing growth in developing regions. Visit &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&quot;&gt;Threefold.io&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to learn more, and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&quot;&gt;forum.threefold.io&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to chat with the team. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Dash &amp; Dash NEXT partner with ThreeFold</title>
		<published>2020-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/07/post-01/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/07/post-01/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.dash.org&quot;&gt;Dash&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; &#x2F; &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dashnext.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Dash NEXT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Foundation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; are excited to officially announce their collaboration, effective the end of June 2020.  Dash and ThreeFold are community-driven organizations focused on peer-to-peer solutions that strive for decentralization and the empowerment of humanity.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dash &#x2F; Dash NEXT and ThreeFold will work together on developer projects on the ThreeFold Grid. The Dash developer community, and anyone interested in contributing to the Dash Blockchain, is being invited to use a truly decentralized and  affordable cloud alternative - &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;cloud.threefold.io&quot;&gt;ThreeFold P2P Cloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Developers can now deploy their Dash nodes and IT workloads on the ThreeFold Grid with an autonomous execution via &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;sdk&#x2F;#&#x2F;smart_contract&quot;&gt;Smart Contracts for IT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further, community members are being invited to explore possibilities in using the ThreeFold Grid’s capacity and peer-to-peer cloud for their own personal computing needs and projects. Anyone interested in being a node operator in the Dash Blockchain using the ThreeFold Grid would be highly encouraged to get started in a few steps following this &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;deploy-a-dash-node-in-5-steps-on-the-threefold-grid&#x2F;509&quot;&gt;documentation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Adnan Fatayerji, co-founder at ThreeFold, enthusiastically expressed his excitement working with the Dash developer community, “We are extremely excited about our collaboration with Dash [and Dash NEXT], a global name in decentralized transactions. We look forward to empowering their developer community with access to a global substrate of peer-to-peer storage and compute. Together we will drive financial and Internet inclusion to the edge of the network!”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Dash community and any individual or organization interested in contributing to Dash are now empowered to deploy their Dash MasterNodes and any containerized IT workload using the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;cloud.threefold.io&quot;&gt;ThreeFold P2P Cloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and benefit from  an autonomous execution via &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;sdk&#x2F;#&#x2F;smart_contract&quot;&gt;Smart Contracts for IT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Dash’s community is incentivized to get started with free compute and storage capacities offered by ThreeFold.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Felix Mago, Co-Founder at Dash NEXT shared his enthusiasm around that opportunity: “We are excited to have ThreeFold as a partner as they are enabling us to host Dash Masternodes in a decentralized manner.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;deploy-a-dash-node-in-5-steps-on-the-threefold-grid&#x2F;509&quot;&gt;You can follow this documentation to deploy full Dash nodes and MasterNodes on the ThreeFold grid  in 5 easy steps.&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-dash&quot;&gt;About Dash:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dash is an open source peer-to-peer cryptocurrency with a strong focus on the payments industry. Dash offers a form of money that is portable, inexpensive, divisible and fast. It can be spent securely both online and in-person with only minimal transaction fees. Based on the Bitcoin project, Dash aims to be the most user-friendly and scalable payments system in the world.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to Bitcoin’s feature set, Dash currently also offers instant transactions (&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.dash.org&#x2F;en&#x2F;stable&#x2F;introduction&#x2F;features.html#instantsend&quot;&gt;InstantSend&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;), private transactions (&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.dash.org&#x2F;en&#x2F;stable&#x2F;introduction&#x2F;features.html#privatesend&quot;&gt;PrivateSend&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;) and operates a self-governing and self-funding model that enables the Dash network to pay individuals and businesses for work that adds value to the network. This &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.dash.org&#x2F;en&#x2F;stable&#x2F;governance&#x2F;index.html#governance&quot;&gt;decentralized governance and budgeting system&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; makes it one of the first ever successful decentralized autonomous organizations (DAO).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-threefold&quot;&gt;About ThreeFold:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold has developed the largest and most advanced peer-to-peer Internet grid in the world.  They launched the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;explorer.grid.tf&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; V2.0 in  April 2020 – a  more performant, private &amp;amp; secure, affordable, and sustainable solution than centralized cloud and internet providers. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
With a collective and incentivized ecosystem of Farmers (independent Internet capacity providers) around the globe, the ThreeFold Grid  is now open for developers to build on top of it,  and users can now benefit from all the advantages of the ThreeFold Grid.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The ThreeFold Foundation aims to empower a more equal, autonomous (decentralized) and sustainable world, and does so  by providing the necessary peer-to-peer technologies and infrastructure to the world, while incentivizing growth in developing regions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Harmony Integrates with ThreeFold’s Decentralized Grid</title>
		<published>2020-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/05/post-04/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/05/post-04/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;harmony-and-the-threefold-foundation-are-aligned-in-their-focus-on-empowering-an-equal-and-fair-world-doing-good-for-the-planet-and-humanity-is-at-the-core-of-both-organizations-dna-today-harmony-and-threefold-are-pleased-to-officially-announce-their-collaborative-partnership-harmony-and-threefold-will-work-together-on-developer-and-user-projects-on-the-threefold-grid-and-pangaea-harmony-s-developer-community-and-anyone-interested-in-contributing-to-their-blockchain-and-being-a-validator-within-the-harmony-staking-ecosystem-is-being-invited-to-use-a-more-decentralized-performant-and-affordable-peer-to-peer-cloud-solution-brought-by-threefold-developers-can-now-deploy-their-nodes-and-any-it-workloads-on-pangaea-and-the-threefold-grid-with-an-autonomous-execution-via-smart-contracts-for-it-anyone-interested-in-being-a-node-operator-as-a-validator-in-the-harmony-blockchain-using-the-threefold-grid-is-invited-to-get-started-in-a-few-steps-following-this-documentation-from-threefold-co-founder-adnan-fatayerji-we-re-super-excited-about-our-partnership-with-harmony-their-approach-to-decentralization-of-applications-and-transactions-perfectly-couples-with-our-approach-of-trying-to-bring-an-inclusive-internet-together-we-will-form-a-big-powerhouse-for-positive-change-in-this-world-threefold-and-harmony-look-forward-to-the-further-development-of-this-collaboration&quot;&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.harmony.one&quot;&gt;Harmony&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Foundation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; are aligned in their focus on empowering an equal and fair world. Doing good for the planet and humanity is at the core of both organizations’ DNA. Today, Harmony and ThreeFold are pleased to officially announce their collaborative partnership.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Harmony and ThreeFold will work together on developer and user projects on the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;grid_why&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.harmony.one&#x2F;pangaea&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Pangaea&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Harmony’s developer community, and anyone interested in contributing to their Blockchain and being a validator within the Harmony staking ecosystem, is being invited to use a more decentralized, performant and affordable &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cloud.threefold.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Peer-to-Peer Cloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; solution brought by ThreeFold.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Developers can now deploy their nodes and any IT workloads on Pangaea and the ThreeFold Grid with an autonomous execution via &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;sdk&#x2F;#&#x2F;smart_contract&quot;&gt;Smart Contracts for IT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.  Anyone interested in being a node operator, as a validator, in the Harmony Blockchain using the ThreeFold Grid, is invited to get started in a few steps following this &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;setting-up-a-harmony-node-on-the-threefold-grid&#x2F;476&quot;&gt;documentation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
From ThreeFold Co-Founder Adnan Fatayerji,
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;“We’re super excited about our partnership with Harmony. Their approach to decentralization of applications and transactions perfectly couples with our approach of trying to bring an inclusive Internet. Together we will form a big powerhouse for positive change in this world.”&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold and Harmony look forward to the further development of this collaboration.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-harmony&quot;&gt;About Harmony&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.harmony.one&quot;&gt;Harmony&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a fast and open blockchain for decentralized applications. Its protocol has achieved secure and random state sharding, being the first sharded Proof of Stake on production. Harmony’s Mainnet supports thousands of nodes in multiple shards, producing blocks in a few seconds with instant finality. The network’s staking mechanism reduces centralization while supporting stake delegation, reward compounding and double-sign slashing. Harmony aims to build an open network of nodes operated and governed by a large community. Harmony has designed a novel Proof-of-Stake (PoS) mechanism for network security and economics - Effective Proof-of-Stake (EPoS) which reduces centralization and distributes rewards fairly to thousands of validators.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-threefold&quot;&gt;About ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&quot;&gt;ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; has developed the largest and most advanced peer-to-peer Internet grid in the world.  They launched the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;explorer.grid.tf&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; V2.0 in  April 2020 – a  more performant, private &amp;amp; secure, affordable, and sustainable solution than centralized cloud and internet providers. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
With a collective and incentivized ecosystem of Farmers (independent Internet capacity providers) around the globe, ThreeFold Grid - largest peer-to-peer Internet grid on earth, is now open for developers to build on top of it,  and users can now benefit from all the advantages of the ThreeFold Grid.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The ThreeFold Foundation aims to empower a more equal, autonomous, decentralized,  and sustainable internet and does so  by providing the necessary peer-to-peer technologies and infrastructure to individuals and creators, while incentivizing growth in developing regions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold &amp; WaykiChain collaborate to decentralize cloud computing</title>
		<published>2020-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/05/post-03/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/05/post-03/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, ThreeFold and WaykiChain are pleased to officially announce their collaborative partnership. Both ThreeFold and WaykiChain found clear alignment on decentralizing the internet for people and businesses and share the same core values that encompass their respective visions. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Through this collaboration, the WaykiChain developer community will be enabled to deploy and maintain their nodes and any of their IT Workloads using the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;cloud.threefold.io&quot;&gt;Threefold P2P Cloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. This will empower them to decentralize their cloud-computing infrastructures, with far more affordability, and distribution compared to centralized cloud-providers,  and with native cloud automation via ThreeFold’s &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;sdk&#x2F;#&#x2F;smart_contract&quot;&gt;Smart contract for IT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The ThreeFold team invites blockchain enthusiasts, developers, and anyone interested in being part of WaykiChain community to deploy a mainnet node, or to explore building a Dapp on top of WayKiChain.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-waykichain&quot;&gt;About WaykiChain:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WaykiChain is a prominent blockchain platform based in China with a global community,  it is a DPoS ( Delegated proof of stake)  public blockchain that is highly scalable and with high-performance transaction processing capabilities (TPS 3300), with an efficient consensus mechanism.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
WaykiChain has a variety of product lines, with the WaykiChain core wallet, the WaykiTimes and their DeFi-vertical technologies that are built within the core layer of blockchain, i.e. the  crypto-asset backed &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cdp.waykichain.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;stablecoin technology&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as well as its &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dex.waykichain.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;built-in decentralized exchange&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
According to WaykiChain’s core team the upcoming 3.0 release of WaykiChain will support WASM virtual machine technology for smart contract development and deployment. Waykichain’s blockchain enables developers to build performing dApps on top of it using its developer tools, and has throughout these 3 years, built &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dapp.review&#x2F;explore&#x2F;wicc&quot;&gt;an extended ecosystem of Dapps&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-threefold&quot;&gt;About ThreeFold:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&quot;&gt;ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; has developed the largest and most advanced peer-to-peer Internet grid in the world.  They launched the ThreeFold Grid V2.0 in  April 2020 – a  more performant, private &amp;amp; secure, affordable, and sustainable solution than centralized cloud and Internet providers. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
With a collective and incentivized ecosystem of Farmers (independent Internet capacity providers) around the globe, the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;explorer.grid.tf&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is now open for developers to build on top of it,  and users can now benefit from all the advantages of using a truly peer-to-peer environment.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The ThreeFold Foundation aims to empower a more equal, autonomous, decentralized, and sustainable internet, and does so by providing the necessary peer-to-peer technologies and infrastructure to the world while incentivizing growth in developing regions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>DigiByte integrates with ThreeFold’s decentralized Grid</title>
		<published>2020-05-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-05-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/05/post-02/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/05/post-02/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;digibytefoundation.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;DigiByte Foundation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Foundation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; are aligned – both focused on values, working towards their visions and missions in creating a truly decentralized, equal, and sustainable world that empowers humanity. Doing good for the planet is at the core of both organizations’ DNA. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Today, DigiByte and ThreeFold are pleased to officially announce their collaborative partnership.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
DigiByte and ThreeFold will work together on developer and user projects on the ThreeFold Grid. The DigiByte developer community, and anyone interested in contributing to the DigiByte Blockchain, is being invited to use a more decentralized and affordable cloud computing capacity. Developers can now deploy their DigiByte nodes and IT workloads on the ThreeFold Grid with an autonomous execution via &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;sdk&#x2F;#&#x2F;smart_contract&quot;&gt;Smart Contracts for IT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Further, community members are also being invited to explore possibilities in using the ThreeFold Grid’s capacity for their own personal computing needs and projects.  Anyone interested in being a node operator in the DigiByte Blockchain using the ThreeFold Grid would be highly encouraged to get started in a few steps following &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;how-to-deploy-a-digibyte-node-with-your-3bot-in-5-steps&#x2F;379&quot;&gt;the documentation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The ThreeFold team is very proud to welcome The DigiByte Foundation to the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;consciousinternet.org&quot;&gt;Conscious Internet Alliance&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; initiative led by ThreeFold, where together with many other planet and human-centric projects, they will collaborate on making our global Internet neutral again. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-digibyte&quot;&gt;About DigiByte:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;digibyte.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;DigiByte&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a rapidly-growing open-source blockchain created in late 2013 and released in early 2014. After 6 years of forward-thinking development, DigiByte has become one of the safest, fastest, longest and most decentralized UTXO blockchain in existence with one of the most active communities in the Crypto and Blockchain space
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The DigiByte Foundation is a volunteer-managed organization that operates in a non-profit way. They protect and promote the true principles of decentralization and empower DigiByte and its community to establish and maintain a sustainable decentralized world. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-threefold&quot;&gt;About ThreeFold:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold has developed the largest and most advanced peer-to-peer Internet grid in the world.  They launched the ThreeFold Grid V2.0 in  April 2020 – a  more performant, private &amp;amp; secure, affordable, and sustainable solution than centralized cloud and internet providers. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
With a collective and incentivized ecosystem of Farmers (independent Internet capacity providers) around the globe, the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;explorer.grid.tf&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;  is now open for developers to build on top of it,  and users can now benefit from all the advantages of the ThreeFold Grid.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The ThreeFold Foundation aims to empower a more equal, autonomous (decentralized) and sustainable world, and does so  by providing the necessary peer-to-peer technologies and infrastructure to the world, while incentivizing growth in developing regions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>TomoChain &amp; ThreeFold are joining forces to decentralize Cloud Computing</title>
		<published>2020-05-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-05-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/05/post-01/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2020/05/post-01/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This week marks a big step in the history of TomoChain and ThreeFold as both organizations join forces to work towards a common vision of a more sustainable and decentralized world.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;grid_why&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;’s peer-to-peer nature comes with many advantages for blockchains as it truly decentralizes their IT infrastructures and, enabling better performance, security, affordability, and sustainability, as compared to current centralized cloud alternatives.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;tomochain.com&quot;&gt;TomoChain&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; will invite their developer community and anyone interested in contributing to the TomoChain Blockchain, to connect and use the Threefold Grid. By deploying their Masternodes and workloads on the ThreeFold Grid, their developers will benefit from a more decentralized and affordable cloud offering and benefit from the autonomous execution of their workloads via ThreeFold’s &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;sdk&#x2F;#&#x2F;smart_contract&quot;&gt;Smart Contract for IT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone interested in being part of the TomoChain node ecosystem using the ThreeFold Grid would be highly encouraged to get started in a few steps &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;setting-up-a-tomochain-node-in-5-steps&#x2F;389&quot;&gt;following the documentation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, with the recent announcement of TomoChain’s DEX Protocol, TomoX, released, both organizations will also test the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;sdk&#x2F;#&#x2F;intro&quot;&gt;ThreeFold P2P Cloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; solution to enable developers to build DEXs on top of TomoChain using ThreeFold’s truly decentralized IT infrastructure.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-tomochain&quot;&gt;About Tomochain&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TomoChain is a scalable blockchain, powered via Proof-of-Stake Voting consensus and used commercially by companies globally. The TomoChain blockchain and product ecosystem enable the development of high-performance blockchain projects that focus on decentralizing finance. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Their products include (1) a fast &amp;amp; near-zero Fees: 2000 TPS, 2-second block-time, and EVM  compatible, and (2) an array of original features and protocols designed to support speed, privacy, usability, and liquidity needs all in one platform. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
After a successful ICO in 2018, Tomochain experienced an incredible growth last year to become one of the most reputed blockchains of South East Asia, and globally. They now focus on their mission to accelerate the onboarding of millions of users by empowering today’s applications with technology that masks the friction of Blockchain, all while retaining its underlying benefits.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-threefold&quot;&gt;About ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold has developed the largest and most advanced peer-to-peer Internet grid in the world.  They launched the ThreeFold Grid V2.0 in  April 2020 - a  more performant, private &amp;amp; secure, affordable, and sustainable solution than centralized cloud and internet providers. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
With a collective and incentivized ecosystem of Farmers (independent Internet capacity providers) around the globe, the ThreeFold Grid is now open for developers to build on top of it and benefit from all the advantages that comes with it.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The ThreeFold Foundation aims to empower a more equal, autonomous (decentralized) and sustainable world, and does so  by providing the necessary peer-to-peer technologies and infrastructure to the world, while incentivizing growth in developing regions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>ThreeFold partners with Hewlett Packard Enterprise</title>
		<published>2018-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2018-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2018/10/post-01/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www3.threefold.io/newsroom/2018/10/post-01/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dubai, UAE. Today at GITEX Technology Week, ThreeFold signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MOU) with Hewlett Packard Enterprise (HPE) to cooperate in the CEEMA region on the implementation of a decentralized grid of computing and storage capacity, which enables a neutral, low cost and low energy internet on a global scale.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
HPE provides their clients in the CEEMA region with the option to connect their computing and storage capacity to ThreeFold’s decentralized grid that supports ThreeFold’s mission to provide a Responsible Internet, accessible to all.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
HPE server and storage hardware has been certified to be used on ThreeFold’s Grid and HPE plans to build services to support the growth and usage of ThreeFold’s Grid which is in line with their edge cloud and blockchain strategy.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold launched a Responsible Internet capacity platform (on March 2018) with the support and collaboration from its community, and has already achieved sizable deployments of decentralized internet compute and storage capacity across the globe. ThreeFold’s open source and localized IT capacity encourage developers; as a result of cost and performance efficiencies, to build all types of decentralized applications on its network to promote the expansion of a new digital responsible economy.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
“This is a monumental step towards a new responsible internet and empowering a new digital economy“, Kristof De Spiegeleer, Visionary Co-Founder of ThreeFold.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;“ThreeFold has created one of the smartest Blockchain solutions we have come across”, said Johannes Koch: Vice President and HPE CEEMA Managing Director. “We are excited about our future cooperation”.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-threefold-foundation&quot;&gt;About ThreeFold Foundation:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold is focused on democratizing internet compute and storage capacity to enable a responsible internet for all. Open source software empowers people to create neutral, green and private capacity for people across the globe that’s blockchain driven and 100% decentralized. (threefold.io)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
